<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Elf, Aereni (Wood) (UA)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Elves are a magical people of otherworldly grace, living in places of ethereal beauty, in the midst of ancient forests or in silvery spires glittering with faerie light, where soft music drifts through the air and gentle fragrances waft on the breeze. Elves love nature and magic, art and artistry, music and poetry.

As an Aereni Elf, you were born into a world shaped by magic and honed by tradition. Whether you have a keen mind or are driven by deep faith, you've spent your youth perfecting one of the skills prized by your ancestors.

Source:	Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increases</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2. Increase either your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Although elves reach physical maturity at about the same age as humans, the elven understanding of adulthood goes beyond physical growth to encompass worldly experience. An elf typically claims adulthood and an adult name around the age of 100 and can live to be 750 years old.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Elves love freedom, variety, and self-expression, so they lean strongly toward the gentler aspects of chaos. They value and protect others' freedom as well as their own, and they are more often good than not.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Elves range from under 5 to over 6 feet tall and have slender builds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d10
Height = 4 feet + 6 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 90 + (1d4 × your size modifier)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Senses</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.

If you meditate during a long rest, you finish the rest after only 4 hours. You otherwise obey all the rules for a long rest; only the duration is changed.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aereni Expertise</name>
      <text>Choose one skill or tool proficiency granted by your race, class or background. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make using this chosen proficiency.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cantrip</name>
      <text>You know one cantrip of your choice from the cleric or wizard spell list. Your spellcasting ability depends on the class you chose: Wisdom for cleric or Intelligence for wizard.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Extra Language</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write one extra language of your choosing.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  
  
  <race>
    <name>Goblin (Eberron)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency />
    <spellAbility />
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Goblins occupy an uneasy place in a dangerous world, and they react by lashing out at any creatures they believe they can bully. Cunning in battle and cruel in victory, goblins are fawning and servile in defeat, just as in their own society lower castes must scrape before those of greater status and as goblin tribes bow before other goblinoids.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 26,
		Explorer's Guide to Wildemount p. 174</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Goblins reach adulthood at age 8 and live up to 60 years.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>In Eberron, goblins are usually neutral. They tend to look out for themselves, preferably without drawing unwanted attention from any larger, more powerful people.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Goblins are between 3 and 4 feet tall and weigh between 40 and 80 pounds. Your size is Small.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d4
Height = 3 feet + 5 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 35 + your size modifier</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fury of the Small</name>
      <text>When you damage a creature with an attack or a spell and the creature's size is larger than yours, you can cause the attack or spell to deal extra damage to the creature. The extra damage equals your level. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Nimble Escape</name>
      <text>You can take the Disengage or Hide action as a bonus action on each of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Goblin.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>

</compendium>