<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Ranger</name>
    <!-- Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Horizon Walker (UA)</name>
        <text>Rangers of the Horizon Conclave guard the world against threats that originate from other planes. They seek out planar portals and keep watch over them, venturing to the outer and inner planes as needed to defeat threats.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Planar Magic (Horizon Walker (UA))</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Horizon Walker Spells table. The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, and it doesn't count against the number of ranger spells you know.

Horizon Walker Spells:
Ranger Level | Spells
3rd | protection from evil and good
5th | alter self
9th | protection from energy
13th | banishment
17th | teleportation circle

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Planar Warrior (Horizon Walker (UA))</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you learn to draw on the energy of the planes to augment your attacks.
	As a bonus action, choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of you. Until the end of this turn, your attacks against that creature ignore its damage resistances, and the next time you hit it on this turn, it takes an additional 1d6 force damage.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Portal Lore (Horizon Walker (UA))</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to detect the presence of planar portals. As an action, you detect the distance and direction to any planar portals within 1,000 feet of you. You also sense which plane of existence each portal leads to. However, if magic obscures any details of a portal, this feature doesn't reveal them.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. Alternatively, you can use the feature again if you expend a spell slot of 2nd level or higher.
	See the "Planar Travel" section in chapter 2 of the Dungeon Master's Guide for examples of planar portals.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 1</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ethereal Step (Horizon Walker (UA))</name>
        <text>At 7th level, you learn to step through the Ethereal Plane. As a bonus action on your turn, you can cast the etherealness spell with this feature, but the spell ends at the end of the current turn. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 1</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Distant Strike (Horizon Walker (UA))</name>
        <text>At 11th level, you gain the ability to step between the planes in a blink of an eye. When you use the Attack action, you can teleport up to 10 feet before each attack. You must be able to see the destination of the teleportation.
	If you attack at least two different creatures with the action, you can make one additional attack with it against a third creature.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 1</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Spectral Defense (Horizon Walker (UA))</name>
        <text>At 15th level, your ability to move between planes becomes even more finely tuned. As a reaction when you take damage, you can halve that damage against you. For a moment, you slip into the planar boundary to lessen the harm.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 1</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <class>
    <name>Rogue</name>
    <!-- Roguish Archetype: Scout (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Roguish Archetype: Scout (UA)</name>
        <text>You are skilled in woodcraft and stealth, allowing you to range ahead of your companions during expeditions. Rogues who embrace this archetype are at home in the wilderness and among barbarians and fighters, as they serve as the eyes and ears of war bands across the world. Compared to other rogues, you are skilled at surviving in the wilds.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Skirmisher (Scout (UA))</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you are difficult to pin down during a fight. You can move up to half your speed as a reaction when an enemy ends its turn within 5 feet of you. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Survivalist (Scout (UA))</name>
        <text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Nature and Survival skills. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those proficiencies.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Superior Mobility (Scout (UA))</name>
        <text>At 9th level, your walking speed increases by 10 feet. If you have a climbing or swimming speed, this increase applies to that speed as well.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 2</text>
        <modifier category="bonus">speed + 10</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ambush Master (Scout (UA))</name>
        <text>Starting at 13th level, you excel at leading ambushes. If any of your foes are surprised, you can use a bonus action on your turn in the first round of the combat to grant each ally who can see you a +5 bonus to initiative that lasts until the combat ends. If the initiative bonus would increase an ally's initiative above yours, the ally's initiative instead equals your initiative.

Each of the allies also receives a 10-foot increase to speed that lasts until the end of the ally's next turn.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sudden Strike (Scout (UA))</name>
        <text>Starting at 17th level, you can strike with deadly speed. If you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack as a bonus action. This attack can benefit from your Sneak Attack even if you have already used it this turn, but only if the attack is the only one you make against the target this turn.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Ranger And Rogue p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Protection from Evil and Good</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Horizon Walker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Alter Self</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Horizon Walker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Protection from Energy</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Horizon Walker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Banishment</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Horizon Walker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Teleportation Circle</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Horizon Walker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
