<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Orc (Wildemount)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Str 2, Con 1</ability>
    <proficiency/>
    <spellAbility/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>To feel the thunder of orcish war drums outside the gate and to hear a chorus of voices growling, "Gruumsh!" is the nightmare of every civilized place in the world. For no matter how thick its walls, skilled its archers, or brave its knights, few settlements have ever withstood a full-scale onslaught of orcs.

Every soldier who lives through a fight with orcs tells of confronting a hulking foe that can cleave through a warrior with a single blow, part of a force that can cut down enemies as though they were trembling stalks of wheat before the scythe. Only a skilled and determined hero can hope to survive single combat with an orc.

Savage and fearless, orc tribes are ever in search of elves, dwarves, and humans to destroy. Motivated by their hatred of the civilized races of the world and their need to satisfy the demands of their deities, the orcs know that if they fight well and bring glory to their tribe, Gruumsh will call them home to the plane of Acheron. It is there in the afterlife where the chosen ones will join Gruumsh and his armies in their endless extraplanar battle for supremacy.

Source:	Explorer's Guide to Wildemount p. 178</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Orcs reach adulthood at age 16, and live up to 80 years.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Orcs fear the curse of ruin that is said to plague their race, and tend strongly toward either chaos (accepting their fate), or toward law (rejecting it).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Orcs stand easily 8 feet tall and corded with powerful muscles, weighing up to 280 pounds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d8
Height = 5 feet + 4 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 175 + (2d6 × your size modifier)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aggressive</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your movement speed toward a hostile creature you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Primal Intuition</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Perception, and Survival.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</text>
      <special>powerful build</special>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Orc.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Dragonborn, Draconblood</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Int 2, Cha 1</ability>
    <proficiency/>
    <spellAbility/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The dragonborn walk proudly through a world that greets them with fearful incomprehension. Shaped by the dragons themselves, dragonborn originally hatched from dragon eggs as a unique race, combining the best attributes of dragons and humanoids.

Draconbloods possess long tails and a knack for social manipulation. They remember the days when they were once mighty conquerors.

Source:	Explorer's Guide to Wildemount p. 168</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Young dragonborn grow quickly. They walk hours after hatching, attain the size and development of a 10-year-old human child by the age of 3, and reach adulthood by 15. They live to be around 80.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Dragonborn tend towards extremes, making a conscious choice for one side or the other in the cosmic war between Good and Evil (represented by Bahamut and Tiamat, respectively). More side with Bahamut than Tiamat (whose non-dragon followers are mostly kobolds), but villainous dragonborn can be quite terrible indeed. Some rare few choose to devote themselves to lesser dragon deities, such as Chronepsis (Neutral), and fewer still choose to worship Io, the Ninefold Dragon, who is all alignments at once.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Dragonborn are taller and heavier than humans, standing well over 6 feet tall and averaging almost 250 pounds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d8
Height = 5 feet + 6 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 175 + (2d6 × your size modifier)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Draconic Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have draconic ancestry. Choose one type of dragon from the Draconic Ancestry table. Your breath weapon and damage resistance are determined by the dragon type, as shown in the table.

Draconic Ancestry:
Dragon | Damage Type | Breath Weapon
Black | Acid | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Blue | Lightning | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Brass | Fire | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Bronze | Lightning | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Copper | Acid | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Gold | Fire | 15 ft. cone (Dex. save)
Green | Poison | 15 ft. cone (Con. save)
Red | Fire | 15 ft. cone (Dex. save)
Silver | Cold | 15 ft. cone (Con. save)
White | Cold | 15 ft. cone (Con. save)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Breath Weapon</name>
      <text>You can use your action to exhale destructive energy. Your draconic ancestry determines the size, shape, and damage type of the exhalation.

When you use your breath weapon, each creature in the area of the exhalation must make a saving throw, the type of which is determined by your draconic ancestry. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus. A creature takes 2d6 damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one. The damage increases to 3d6 at 6th level, 4d6 at 11th level, and 5d6 at 16th level.

After you use your breath weapon, you can't use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Damage Resistance</name>
      <text>You have resistance to the damage type associated with your draconic ancestry.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Forceful Presence</name>
      <text>When you make a Intimidation or Persuasion check, you can do so with advantage once per long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Draconic. Draconic is thought to be one of the oldest languages and is often used in the study of magic. The language sounds harsh to most other creatures and includes numerous hard consonants and sibilants.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Dragonborn, Ravenite</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Str 2, Con 1</ability>
    <proficiency/>
    <spellAbility/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The dragonborn walk proudly through a world that greets them with fearful incomprehension. Shaped by the dragons themselves, dragonborn originally hatched from dragon eggs as a unique race, combining the best attributes of dragons and humanoids.

Ravenites have no tails and a hearty physique. They remember the days when they were slaves to the draconblood, as well as the day when they overthrew their masters.

Source:	Explorer's Guide to Wildemount p. 168</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Young dragonborn grow quickly. They walk hours after hatching, attain the size and development of a 10-year-old human child by the age of 3, and reach adulthood by 15. They live to be around 80.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Dragonborn tend towards extremes, making a conscious choice for one side or the other in the cosmic war between Good and Evil (represented by Bahamut and Tiamat, respectively). More side with Bahamut than Tiamat (whose non-dragon followers are mostly kobolds), but villainous dragonborn can be quite terrible indeed. Some rare few choose to devote themselves to lesser dragon deities, such as Chronepsis (Neutral), and fewer still choose to worship Io, the Ninefold Dragon, who is all alignments at once.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Dragonborn are taller and heavier than humans, standing well over 6 feet tall and averaging almost 250 pounds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d8
Height = 5 feet + 6 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 175 + (2d6 × your size modifier)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Draconic Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have draconic ancestry. Choose one type of dragon from the Draconic Ancestry table. Your breath weapon and damage resistance are determined by the dragon type, as shown in the table.

Draconic Ancestry:
Dragon | Damage Type | Breath Weapon
Black | Acid | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Blue | Lightning | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Brass | Fire | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Bronze | Lightning | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Copper | Acid | 5 by 30 ft. line (Dex. save)
Gold | Fire | 15 ft. cone (Dex. save)
Green | Poison | 15 ft. cone (Con. save)
Red | Fire | 15 ft. cone (Dex. save)
Silver | Cold | 15 ft. cone (Con. save)
White | Cold | 15 ft. cone (Con. save)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Breath Weapon</name>
      <text>You can use your action to exhale destructive energy. Your draconic ancestry determines the size, shape, and damage type of the exhalation.

When you use your breath weapon, each creature in the area of the exhalation must make a saving throw, the type of which is determined by your draconic ancestry. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus. A creature takes 2d6 damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one. The damage increases to 3d6 at 6th level, 4d6 at 11th level, and 5d6 at 16th level.

After you use your breath weapon, you can't use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Damage Resistance</name>
      <text>You have resistance to the damage type associated with your draconic ancestry.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Vengeful Assault</name>
      <text>When you take damage from a creature in range of a weapon you are wielding, you can use your reaction to make an attack against that creature. You can do this once per short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Draconic. Draconic is thought to be one of the oldest languages and is often used in the study of magic. The language sounds harsh to most other creatures and includes numerous hard consonants and sibilants.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Elf, Pallid</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dex 2, Wis 1</ability>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Elves are a magical people of otherworldly grace, living in places of ethereal beauty, in the midst of ancient forests or in silvery spires glittering with faerie light, where soft music drifts through the air and gentle fragrances waft on the breeze. Elves love nature and magic, art and artistry, music and poetry.

Pallid elves are a subrace of elves distinctive by their pale skin, which is said to be as pale as the moon. The race became pale from living underground away from all light for a long time following the destruction of their home.

The pallid elves are a mystical and insightful people with skin as pale as the surface of Exandria's largest moon. They emerged from the Pallid Grove this century and wander the world with childlike curiosity.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2014) p. 23,
		Explorer's Guide to Wildemount p. 163</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Although elves reach physical maturity at about the same age as humans, the elven understanding of adulthood goes beyond physical growth to encompass worldly experience. An elf typically claims adulthood and an adult name around the age of 100 and can live to be 750 years old.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Elves love freedom, variety, and self-expression, so they lean strongly toward the gentler aspects of chaos. They value and protect others' freedom as well as their own, and they are more often good than not.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Elves range from under 5 to over 6 feet tall and have slender builds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d10
Height = 4 feet + 6 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 90 + (1d4 × your size modifier)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Senses</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.

If you meditate during a long rest, you finish the rest after only 4 hours. You otherwise obey all the rules for a long rest; only the duration is changed.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Incisive Sense</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) and Wisdom (Insight) checks.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Blessing of the Moon Weaver</name>
      <text>You know the light cantrip.

When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the sleep spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.

When you reach 5th level, you can cast the invisibility spell (targeting yourself only) once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.

Casting these spells with this trait doesn't require material components. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Halfling, Lotusden</name>
    <ability>Dex 2, Wis 1</ability>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <proficiency/>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The comforts of home are the goals of most halflings' lives: a place to settle in peace and quiet, far from marauding monsters and clashing armies. Others form nomadic bands that travel constantly, lured by the open road and the wide horizon to discover the wonders of new lands and peoples. Halflings work readily with others, and they are loyal to their friends, whether halfling or otherwise. They can display remarkable ferocity when their friends, families, or communities are threatened.

Long tied to the natural heart of the Lotusden Greenwood, these halflings have adapted to live synergistically with the chaotic laws of the wilds.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2014) p. 28,
		Explorer's Guide to Wildemount p. 164</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>A halfling reaches adulthood at the age of 20 and generally lives into the middle of his or her second century.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Most halflings are lawful good. As a rule, they are good-hearted and kind, hate to see others in pain, and have no tolerance for oppression. They are also very orderly and traditional, leaning heavily on the support of their community and the comfort of their old ways.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Halflings average about 3 feet tall and weigh about 40 pounds. Your size is Small.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d4
Height = 2 feet + 7 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 35 + your size modifie</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Lucky</name>
      <text>When you roll a 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Brave</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Halfling Nimbleness</name>
      <text>You can move through the space of any creature that is of a size larger than yours.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Children of the Woods</name>
      <text>You know the Druidcraft Cantrip.

At 3rd level, you can cast the Entangle spell once per long rest.

At 5th level, you can cast Spike Growth spell once per long rest.

These spells don't require the material components normally required. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Timberwalk</name>
      <text>Ability checks made to track you are at disadvantage and you can move through difficult terrain made of non-magical plants and overgrowth without expending extra movement.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Halfling. The Halfling language isn't secret, but halflings are loath to share it with others. They write very little, so they don't have a rich body of literature. Their oral tradition, however, is very strong. Almost all halflings speak Common to converse with the people in whose lands they dwell or through which they are traveling.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
