<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Satyr (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>35</speed>
    <proficiency>Performance, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Satyrs are lively and mischievous fey creatures, known for their boundless energy, love of revelry, and irresistible charm. Standing between 3 and 5 feet tall, they possess the legs and horns of a goat and an unshakable zest for life. Though often seen as carefree wanderers, Satyrs are deeply connected to the Feywild and its magic, granting them a natural resistance to enchantment and illusion.
	Whether playing enchanting melodies, dancing through combat, or weaving magic into their movements, Satyrs bring joy and chaos in equal measure. Their natural charisma makes them skilled performers and persuasive speakers, but their fey nature ensures they remain unpredictable.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (3-5 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>35 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Performance, Persuasion</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Ram</name>
      <text>Your head and horns are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal 1d6 + your Strength modifier bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <roll description="Unarmed Bludgeoning Damage">1d6+%1</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Resistance</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Melody</name>
      <text>You perform an enchanting song that targets a creature of your choice within 60 feet. The target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw (DC = 10 + your Performance bonus) or be affected by one of the following conditions (your choice when you use this ability):

	• Charming. The target gains the Charmed and Incapacitated conditions until the end of your next turn and must use all its movement to move toward you.

	• Frightening. The target gains the Frightened and Incapacitated conditions and must use all its movement to safely move as far away from you as possible.

Once you use this trait, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Mirthful Movement</name>
      <text>You can cast Jump and Longstrider (with a duration of 1 minute).
	You always have these spells prepared. You can cast each of them at will without expending a spell slot, only targeting yourself when you do so. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level, targeting creatures other than yourself.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
