<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Gnoll (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <displayname>Gnoll  (HB)</displayname>
    <ancestry>Gnoll  (HB)</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Gnolls are savage, hyena-headed raiders born of a fiendish curse. Created by Yeenoghu, the Demon Lord of Slaughter, they exist to hunt, kill, and consume in an endless frenzy. Their bodies are lean and powerful, built for endurance and violence, with sharp claws and a bone-crushing bite. While most gnolls are consumed by their hunger for bloodshed, a rare few break free of their master's will, forging their own paths in defiance of their dark origins.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Playing as a Fiend</name>
      <text>Being a fiend does not mean your character is inherently evil. While many gnolls embrace their violent origins, some struggle against their nature, seeking redemption or a purpose beyond slaughter. A gnoll adventurer may strive to atone for past horrors, carve out a life free from their demonic heritage, or prove they are more than a mindless killer.

If you're playing a good- or neutrally-aligned gnoll, consider one of the following drives:

Fiend Drives:
Drive | Description
Defier of Fate | You refuse to be a pawn of Yeenoghu and will forge your own destiny, no matter the cost.
Seeker of Redemption | Haunted by past actions, you now strive to protect others and make amends.
Warden of the Wilds | You have turned away from destruction, dedicating yourself to defending nature from true evils.
Packbuilder | You wish to prove that gnolls can create, not just destroy, by forming bonds and building a better future.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fiend</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (6-7 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Survival</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Languages</name>
      <text>Abyssal</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Your bite is a natural melee weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. It deals 1d6 piercing damage and uses Strength for attack and damage rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Rampage</name>
      <text>When you score a critical hit with a melee attack on your turn, you can move up to half your speed and make a Bite attack as a bonus action.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Fiendish Vigor</name>
      <text>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with your Bite attack, you gain temporary hit points equal to that creature's Challenge Rating (minimum 1).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Push On</name>
      <text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points, you do not gain the Unconscious until the end of your next turn. If you receive healing or stabilize before then, you remain conscious.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Gnoll, Repentant (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <displayname>Gnoll Repentant</displayname>
    <ancestry>Gnoll</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Not all gnolls succumb to Yeenoghu's hunger. Some are cursed with awareness of their own monstrous nature and seek to defy their demonic origins. These repentant gnolls struggle to overcome their bloodlust, often living in isolation or small, reclusive communities far from civilization. Though their monstrous appearance ensures they are rarely trusted, they fight to prove themselves as something more than mere killers.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Playing as a Fiend</name>
      <text>Being a fiend does not mean your character is inherently evil. While many gnolls embrace their violent origins, some struggle against their nature, seeking redemption or a purpose beyond slaughter. A gnoll adventurer may strive to atone for past horrors, carve out a life free from their demonic heritage, or prove they are more than a mindless killer.

If you're playing a good- or neutrally-aligned gnoll, consider one of the following drives:

Fiend Drives:
Drive | Description
Defier of Fate | You refuse to be a pawn of Yeenoghu and will forge your own destiny, no matter the cost.
Seeker of Redemption | Haunted by past actions, you now strive to protect others and make amends.
Warden of the Wilds | You have turned away from destruction, dedicating yourself to defending nature from true evils.
Packbuilder | You wish to prove that gnolls can create, not just destroy, by forming bonds and building a better future.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fiend</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (6-7 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Survival</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Your bite is a natural melee weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. It deals 1d6 piercing damage and uses Strength for attack and damage rolls.</text>
      <roll description="Unarmed Piercing Damage">1d6</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Rampage</name>
      <text>When you score a critical hit with a melee attack on your turn, you can move up to half your speed and make a Bite attack as a bonus action.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Defiant</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws to avoid or remove the Frightened or Charmed condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Tenacity</name>
      <text>When you finish a short or long rest, you regain additional hit points equal to your proficiency bonus.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
