<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Carouser [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Deception, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You grew to adulthood in the beating heart of a large city, such as Baldur's Gate. You spent countless evenings in taverns, playhouses, parlors, and gambling dens, savoring all the city had to offer. You're a natural at interacting with people to learn their secrets, whether over a high-stakes game or at a high-class soiree. You might have been thrown out of establishment or ten, but only by people who don't know how to party.

Source:	Astarion's Book of Hungers</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Intelligence, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Tireless Reveler</name>
      <text>When an ally you can see within 60 feet of yourself expends Heroic Inspiration, you can gain Heroic Inspiration if you lack it. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Short or Long Rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Gaming Set</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Dagger, Gaming Set (same as above), Fine Clothes, Glass Bottle, Mirror, Perfume, Pouch, Tinderbox, 19 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Vampire Devotee [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Persuasion, Stealth</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You were in service to a vampire or a small group of vampires lairing together. The Undead drank your blood more times than you can count. You might have served willingly, perhaps with aspirations of one day becoming a vampire yourself. Or you might have been magically charmed and retain only a few muddled memories of your time as a vampire familiar. In either case, your time in the vampire den is over.

Source:	Astarion's Book of Hungers</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Constitution, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Vampire's Plaything</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Decanting. When you finish a Long Rest, you can create one Potion of Healing or an Antitoxin, as long as you have an empty vial or flask. These liquids evaporate when you finish another Long Rest.

Timely Retreat. You can take a Bonus Action to take the Dash action or the Disengage action. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you recover all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Vampiric Connection. The DM determines the fate of your former vampire master. While you and your former vampire master are on the same plane of existence, the vampire can communicate with you telepathically, and you can choose to allow the vampire to perceive through your senses.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Cook's Utensils</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Cook's Utensils, Fine Clothes, 2 Glass Bottles, Healer's Kit, Perfume, Lamp, Oil (3 flasks), Waterskin, 19 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Vampire Survivor [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Religion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You witnessed or survived a vampire attack. You might have been directly involved in this confrontation, or perhaps you were frozen in terror by what you saw. Regardless, you remain vigilant for monster attacks and pride yourself on being ready for anything. No vampire will catch you or your allies by surprise again.

Source:	Astarion's Book of Hungers</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Constitution, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Vampire Hunter</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Adroit Escape. You have Advantage on checks to escape from nonmagical restraints or the Grappled condition.

Vitality Ward. When you take Necrotic damage, you can take a Reaction to mitigate the damage. Roll a number of d6s equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and add them together. Reduce the Necrotic damage you take by this total. Once you use this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Woodcarver's Tools
</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Equipment: Choose A or B:
	• (A) Woodcarver's Tools, Crowbar, Hooded Lantern, Holy Symbol (reliquary), Holy Water, Mirror, Oil (3 flasks), Tinderbox, Traveler's Clothes, Waterskin, 4 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
