<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <item>
    <name>Abbor Alz's Brooch of Warning [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>The barbarians of the hills value alertness in battle highly. While you wear this magic brooch, you can never be surprised.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Amulet of the Cairn Hills [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this magic amulet, you can use a Magic Action to spend one charge to gain for 1 minute the following benefits:

	• Undead that target you with an attack have disadvantage on their attack rolls.
	• You have resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage dealt by Undead.

	Recharge. The amulet has 3 charges and regains 1d3 spent charges daily at dawn. If you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the amulet crumbles to dust.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Amulet of Furyondy [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>When you hang this amulet around the neck of a creature that is not Hostile to you, the amulet glows, spending one charge and ending a Curse on that creature. The amulet has 7 charges and when you spend the last charge it becomes non magical.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Amulet of Neutrality [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement by creature of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this magic amulet, you hide your evil alignment to any means of detection.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Amulet of Spinecastle [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this golden amulet, you can use a Magic Action to create a magical Emanation within 30 feet of you that lasts for 1 minute. When the Emanation appears, each creature Hostile to you makes a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it has the Frightened condition. An Hostile creature also makes this save when the Emanation moves into its space and when it moves into the Emanation. On a successful save, that creature is immune to this effect for the next 24 hours. Each creature within the Emanation that makes an attack against you has disadvantage on the attack roll. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Amulet of the Spirit [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this magic amulet, you have advantage on any saving throw against spells and other magical effects.
	If you die while wearing this amulet, you can't be resurrected by any magic because your essence is held in stasis by the amulet until it is freed. To free the essence, the amulet must be removed from the body and the bless, protection from evil, and raise dead spells must be cast over the body.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Amulet of Weakening [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this magic amulet, you can use a Magic Action to create a magical Emanation within 30 feet of you that lasts for 1 minute. When the Emanation appears, each creature Hostile to you makes a DC 15 Strength saving throw. On a failed save, it has disadvantage on any Strength Tests. An Hostile creature also makes this save when the Emanation moves into its space and when it moves into the Emanation. On a successful save, that creature is immune to this effect for the next 24 hours.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Anvil of the Lortmil Mountains [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This blacksmith tool is enchanted by Moradin, king of the dwarven gods. When you use this anvil, you are automatically proficient with the Smith's Tools. If you are already proficient, then your proficiency bonus is doubled.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Apprentice Ring [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this magic ring, you gain a +2 bonus to your AC, and you have advantage on any Ability Check to find a trap. Additionally, you can use a Magic Action to cast the knock spell. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Axe of Grounding [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>battleaxe, very rare (requires attunement by a dwarf)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

When you take Lightning damage you can use a Reaction to absorb the damage through this magic weapon. This magic weapon can store up to 25 Lightning damage.
	When it is storing Lightning damage, on a successful hit made with this magic weapon, you can use a Bonus Action to release all or part of that Lighting damage, dealing an additional equal damage to the target.

Topple (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, you can force the creature to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 plus the ability modifier used to make the attack roll and your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, the creature has the Prone condition.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, battleaxe
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bag of Fool's Gold [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic leather bag radiates magic of Illusion school if under the effect of a detect magic spell. It was originally created by gnome clerics of the deity Garl Glittergold.
	As a Magic Action, you can put out from the bag up to 5,000 gp in gold coins. The gold coins last for 1 hour then disappear.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Baphomet's Bardiche [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>halberd, very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <property>M,H,R,2H</property>
    <dmg1>1d10</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. On a successful hit against a creature that is wearing a nonmagical armor or holding a nonmagical shield, you can choose to destroy that armor or shield instead of dealing damage. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Short Rest.

Cleave (Mastery): If you hit a creature with a melee attack roll using this weapon, you can make a melee attack roll with the weapon against a second creature within 5 feet of the first that is also within your reach. On a hit, the second creature takes the weapon's damage, but don't add your ability modifier to that damage unless that modifier is negative. You can make this extra attack only once per turn.

Heavy: You have Disadvantage on attack rolls with a Heavy weapon if it's a Melee weapon and your Strength score isn't at least 13 or if it's a Ranged weapon and  your Dexterity score isn't at least 13.

Reach: A Reach weapon adds 5 feet to your reach when you attack with it, as well as when determining your reach for Opportunity Attacks with it.

Two-Handed: A Two-Handed weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Proficiency: martial, halberd
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bead of Force [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>These small, black spheres might be mistaken for common beads or perhaps unusually lusterless black pearls. As a Magic Action, you can hurl one bead to a point that you can see within 60 feet of you. Upon impact, the bead sends a bust of force in a sphere of 10-foot radius. Each creature within the sphere must make a DC 15 Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 5d4 force damage and has the Paralyzed condition. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and no other ill effects. At the end of each of its next turns, a creature can make another saving throw, ending the Paralyzed condition on itself on a success.
	Usually, 2d4+1 beads are found.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Force Damage">5d4</roll>
    <roll description="Beads">2d4+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bear Cloak of the Sulhaut Mountains [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this magic cloak, you gain the following benefits:

	• You can cast the speak with animals spell. Once cast, you must finish a Long Rest before you can cast again.
	• You have advantage on any Strength check.
	• You have advantage on any Wisdom (Survival) and Intelligence (Nature) check.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bisselite Wand of Peace [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This item is usually found among the border guards of the March of Bissel. While you hold this wand, you can use a Magic Action to target up to 6 creatures that are Hostile within 60 feet of you and force them to make a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target's Attitude becomes Indifferent. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Black Arrow of Iuz [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by a creature of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>A</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic arrow. When you successfully hit a creature with this magic arrow, you can use a Bonus Action to invoke the favor of Iuz. If the target has 50 or fewer hit points, it immediately dies.
	Once used this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ranged attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">ranged damage +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Black Mirror [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>As a Magic Action, when you look into this magic mirror, your image blurs and then appears in ancient Olman garb, as if reflecting a previous incarnation. You then can ask three questions, each one up to 15 words. The image truthfully answers these questions by nodding or shaking its head.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Black Sails of Schnai [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Enchanted in the land of Snow Barbarians and blessed by their shamans, these square sails are hoisted only on the funeral ships of great heroes and lords. The deceased's body is burned along with the ship and all but a small piece of the sail, that contains the spirit of the deceased.
	While you hold this piece of sail, as a Magic Action you can conjure a Medium spirit to a point that you can see within 30 feet of you. that you can see within 10 feet of you. The spirit lasts for 1 minute or earlier if you dismiss it as a Bonus Action. When you are within 30 feet of the spirit, you deal 2d12 additional psychic damage on any successful weapon attack. As a Bonus Action on your later turns, you can teleport the spirit to an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Psychic Damage">2d12</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Blackstaff [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by a cleric of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>ST</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <property>V</property>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>This ghastly blackwood staff is shod with silver bands and topped by a carned head that is banded and decorated with runes of Iuz's cult.
	When you hold this magic staff, you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic staff.

	• When you make a melee weapon attack with this magic staff, you score a critical hit on a roll of 18 or higher.

	• As a Magic Action, you can cast the command, fear, inflict wounds, finger of death spell (Spell Save DC 17, Spell Attack Bonus +9). Once you cast one of these spells, you can't cast it again until you finish a Long Rest.

	• As a Magic Action, you can create an acid vortex. Each creature in a 10-foot-radius and a 40-foot high Cylinder centered on a point within 120 feet of you must make a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking 6d8 Acid damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">6d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bronzewood Cudgel [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>morningstar, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	The first time you hit a Humanoid with a successful attack made with this magic weapon, the target must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or has the Charmed condition for 1 minute or until you or your allies damage it. The Charmed creature is Friendly to you. At the end of each of its next turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw, ending the condition on itself on a success. On a successful save, the target is immune to this Bronzewood Cudgel's effect for the next 24 hours.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Proficiency: simple, morningstar
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Boccob's Blessed Book [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by a bard, cleric, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This book is always of small size, durante, waterproof, silver-bound, and locked. When you are attuned to this magic book, you gain the following benefits.

	• Your Wisdom and Intelligence score increases by 1 up to a maximum of 22.

	• You have advantage on any Intelligence Test.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bone Wand [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This slender, sharp-edged wand looks like it was crafted from a femur of a Humanoid. Necromantic runes are etched along one surface, and the opposite side is blank. Many minions of Iuz carry this magic wand.
	As a Magic Action, you can spend two or more charges to activate one of the following properties.

	• You create a 60-foot long and 5-foot wide Line that originates from the tip of the wand and is formed by razor-sharp bone shards. Each creature in the Line must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 5d6 Slashing damage, or half as much damage on a successful save (2 charges).

	• You cast the animate dead spell (3 charges).

If you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the wand crumbles to dust.

	Recharge. The wand has 5 charges, and recharges 1d4+1 spent charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Slashing Damage">5d6</roll>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Book of Recording [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic book is usually thick, bound with leather, and decorated with gold or silver embossing. As a Magic Action, you can record in the book anything spoken within 60 feet of the book for 1 hour, and as a Bonus Action, you can stop the recording earlier. When you record something again, you erase what was previously recorded. The book knows and records in Common plus other 5 languages, which are decided by the DM.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cap of Reason [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>The church of Rao originally created this magic item a long time ago. The church often recreates this item, and the cap is never ornate, usually being crafted from dented and well-used helms that have been discarded by experienced soldiers.
	While you wear this magic cap, you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +2 bonus to your AC.

	• You have advantage on any Wisdom saving throw.

	• You have advantage on any Wisdom (Insight) and Charisma (Persuasion) check.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Casket of Furyondy [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Priests of Furyondy first enchanted this finely engraved, wooden coffin to preserve the bodies of the honorably deceased.
	When a corpse of a Humanoid is put inside this coffin, it has the same effects of the gentle repose spell but the duration is 1 year.
	You can't put more than one creature at a time inside the coffin.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cheetah Cloak of Amedio [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This yellow, black spotted cheetah hide is enchanted by the original tribesmen of the Amedio jungle.
	While you wear this magic cloak you gain the following benefits.

	• You have advantage on and Dexterity check.

	• Your base speed is 45.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Clawed Gauntlets [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement by a cleric or a fighter)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>These gauntlets appear as strong, tough, but unusually flexible, steel gauntlets. As a Bonus Action, the fingers of the gauntlets sprout viciously curved talons, several inches in length until the start of your next turn. You can use the Attack Action to make a melee weapon attack with these gauntlets, using Strength or Dexterity plus your proficiency bonus. The attack is magical. On a successful hit, you deal 2d8 Slashing damage plus your Dexterity or Strength bonus.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Slashing Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cloak of the Hellfurnaces [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Originally created by a wizard who sought treasure in the volcanic mountains, this magical red garment provides you protection against fire. While you wear this magical cloak you have Resistance to Fire damage.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cloak of Polymorphing [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this magic cloak, you can use a Magic Action to cast the polymorph spell, but you can only target yourself. Once used this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Collar of Tusmit [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This adamantine neck shield was originally enchanted by a wizard who held an unnatural fear of decapitation. While you wear this collar you are immune to decapitation, even by the effect of a vorpal sword.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Coin of Almor [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This platinum coin was created to benefit those in need. When you touch this magic item, you take a Curse. As long as you have this Curse, you are overcome with great feelings of philanthropy, you can keep with you at least 50 gp worth value in coins or other treasure, and you must donate any extra treasure to the first creature that is in need of money (e.g. a beggar, a poor, …). The Curse can be removed with a remove curse spell or greater magic.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cord of Ekbir [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common (requires attunement by a rogue)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magical garrote appears usually in the hands of Ekbiran murderers. While you hold this magic item, you can use a Bonus Action to strangle a Humanoid creature within 5 feet of you that you can see. The target must make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it has the Stunned condition until the end of its next round.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Coruskian Stone [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Set in a golden necklace, this green stone was originally enchanted by a Nyrondese wizard who sought to control the griffons of the Coruskian Mountains. While you wear this magic item, you can use a Magic Action to magically conjure a griffon within 1 mile of you. The griffon appears in an unoccupied space within 60 feet of you, has the Charmed condition and is Friendly to you and your allies. You can ride the griffon and you are proficient in it. The griffon disappears after 1 hour or earlier if you dismiss it as a Bonus Action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. If there aren't griffons within 1 mile of you, nothing happens, but you haven't used this property.
	The DM has the statistics for the griffon.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cursed Ring of the Great Kingdom [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>cursed, uncommon</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This cursed magical item was originally created by a wizard who was loyal to the Great Kingdom. Though the ring has only limited power, its use to plague the diplomats of the Iron League is well known.
	The first time you wear this ring, you get a Curse. Though you can immediately remove the ring, the Curse remains. Until the Curse remains, you have disadvantage on any Charisma check. The Curse can be removed with a remove curse spell or greater magic.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Dark Wand of the Sulhaut Mountains [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you hold this ebony wand in your hand, you can use a Magic Action to locate each creature of a type of your choice (e.g., Humanoid or Undead) within 120 feet of you. Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Diplomacy Rod of Furyondy [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>RD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This rod was originally created for use by the Prince of Furyondy. While you hold in your hand this magic rod, you gain the following benefits.

	• When you take the Influence Action, and you roll a number lower than 10, you can take 10 as the number rolled. Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

	• As a Magic Action, you can cast the suggestion spell (Spell Save DC 17). Once used this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ebon Skull [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by cleric, sorcerer, warlock, or wizard of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This sinister, black Humanoid skull, bearing glinting rubies in its eye sockets, is a potent magic item. While attuned to this magic item you gain the following benefits.

	• As a Magic Action, you can cast the animate dead spell. Once you cast this spell three times, you can't cast it again until you finish a Long Rest.

	• You gain Darkvision 120 feet.

	• You have Resistance to Cold and Necrotic damage.

	• As a Magic Action, you can create a 20-foot radius Sphere centered on a point within 60 feet of you. The Sphere is composed of a chilling black mist. Each creature in the Sphere must make a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking 2d10 Cold damage and 2d10 Necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.

	• A creature must make this saving throw when the Sphere moves into its space and when it enters the Sphere or ends its turn there. A creature makes this save only once per turn. On each of your subsequent turns, you can use a Magic Action to move the Sphere up to 30 feet. The Sphere lasts for 1 minute or earlier if you dismiss it as a Bonus Action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Cold Damage">2d10</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage">2d10</roll>
    <roll description="Cold and Necrotic Damage">4d10</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ehlonna's Orb of the Earth [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a druid)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>The orb is a fist-sized sphere made from polished petrified wood. It was created for the first time by the deity Ehlonna herself, who donated this magic item to one of her favorite druids. While you hold the ora, you can spend one or more charges to cast one of the following spells (Spells Save DC 17):

	• meld into stone (1 charge)

	• stone shape (3 charges)

	• wall of stone (5 charges) When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the orb disappears.

	Recharge. The orb has 6 charges and recharges 1d6+1 spent charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll>1d6+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Eyepatch of Tehn [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This black patch is often in possession of priests and judges because of its power. When you wear it over an undamaged eye, as a Magic Action you gain Truesight (60 feet) for 1 minute. Once you use this property three times, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Flaming Mirror of Tenh [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>The Flaming Mirror of Tenh is a silvery, oval-shaped magical item approximately six feet in height and three feet at its widest point. A planewalking wizard, enamored of the Elemental Plane of Fire, created this item in order to provide easy access to her favorite plane.
	As a Magic Action, the mirror becomes a portal from the Elemental Plane of Fire to Oerth and vice versa. When you create the portal, roll a d20. On a 5 or lower, 2d4 fire elementals appear within 30 feet of you. They are Hostile to you and your allies. The portal closes after 1 hour or earlier if you close it as a Bonus Action. When you close the portal, roll a d20. On a 1, the mirror is drained of its magic and shatters.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll>2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gauntlets of Gruumsh [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by an orc)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Orcs were inspired by the god Gruumsh to advance the deity's ideals. These magic gauntlets appear to be gauntlets of blackened steel with Gruumsh's symbol engraved on top of the hand and lacquered red. While you wear these magic gauntlets you gain the following benefits.

	• Your Strength score increases by 2 up to a maximum of 22.

	• As a Bonus Action, you can have advantage on any Strength Test for 1 minute. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gemcutter's Tools of Sunndi [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>artisan tools, common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Ability: Intelligence
Utilize: Discern a gem's value (DC 15)
Craft: Arcane Focus, Holy Symbol

This magical set of Jeweler's Tools was originally enchanted by the dwarves who work the gemstone mines in the County of Sunndi. You are proficient in this magical set of Jeweler's Tools and when you use them, you have advantage on any check roll.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gem of Musing (Common) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>As a Magic Action, you contemplate this magic gem and instantly regain 1 used spell slot of your choice of level 1. You can't use your movement while contemplating the gem. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gem of Musing (Uncommon) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>As a Magic Action, you contemplate this magic gem and instantly regain 1 used spell slot of your choice of level 2 or lower. You can't use your movement while contemplating the gem. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gem of Musing (Rare) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>As a Magic Action, you contemplate this magic gem and instantly regain 1 used spell slot of your choice of level 4 or lower. You can't use your movement while contemplating the gem. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gem of Musing (Very Rare) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>As a Magic Action, you contemplate this magic gem and instantly regain 1 used spell slot of your choice of level 5 or lower. You can't use your movement while contemplating the gem. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ghastrobe [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a cleric, sorcerer, warlock, or wizard of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>AsThis magic vest is usually black or bloodstainedwhite and often is worn by followers of Iuz. While you wear this magic robe, you gain the following benefits.

	• Your AC becomes 15.

	• Undead can't be Hostile to you or your allies.

	• When you successfully hit a creature with an Unarmed Strike, you can use a Bonus Action to force the target to make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, that creature has the Paralyzed condition for 1 minute. At the end of each of its next turns, an affected creature can make another Constitution saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success. On a successful save, the target is immune to this effect for the next 24 hours.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Girdle of Breath Weapon Resistance [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic item was originally created by the god Kord, who has a deep hatred of dragons.
	The church of Kord has created several copies of it since then. Constructed from bronze, an engraving of the front depicts a dragon's face belching fire.
	While you wear this magic item, you can use a Magic Action to target up to 6 creatures that you can see within 120 feet of you.
	As long as a target creature is within 120 feet of you, for 1 minute that creature gains advantage on any saving throw against a Dragon's effect, and Resistance to any damage caused by any Dragon's attack or effect.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Goblet of the Great Kingdom [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic goblet was commissioned on order of nobles of the Great Kingdom of Aerdy who had good reason to fear assassination. This magic goblet appears to be a normal drinking vessel made of polished oak. However, when you store a liquid within it, you can use a Magic Action to neutralize any poison or venom within the liquid.
	Once you use this property three times, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Goblin Shield of the Pomarji [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>S</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <ac>2</ac>
    <text>This metal shield bears the coat of arms of goblins in the Pomarji — the red face of a medusa. While you wear this magic shield, you gain the following benefits.
	You gain a +2 bonus to your AC. As a Magic Action, you can cast the flesh to stone spell. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Utilize Action to Don or Doff.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Golden Girdle of Urnst [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic girdle was created to protect wizards in melee combat. It is made of red silk strewn with golden flakes.
	While you wear this magic item, you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +1 bonus to your AC.

	• You have Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Golden Pool [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This basin holds a magical fluid.
	As a Magic Action, you can put an object that weighs up to 1 lbs. The object becomes golden for 1 minute. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Golemblight [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>dagger, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <property>F,L,T</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>20/60</range>
    <text>You have a +1 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you successfully hit a Construct, you deal additional 2d12 damage.

Nick (Mastery): When you make the extra attack of the Light property, you can make it as part of the Attack action in· stead of as a Bonus Action. You can make this extra attack only once per turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Proficiency: simple, dagger
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Extra Damage">2d12</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Greater Ring of the Pomarji [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This black ring was originally created by a wizard from the Wild Coast. When you wear this magic ring, you can use a Magic Action to conjure orc spirits that appear as a Large pack of spectral intangible orcs in an unoccupied space within 60 feet of you. While you are within 5 feet of the pack, you have advantage on any Strength Test, and when you move on your turn, you can also move the pack up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. The pack disappears after 1 minute, or earlier if you dismiss it as a Bonus Action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">saving throws +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Greater Sulmish Robe of Magical Enhancement [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This black robe, embroidered with complex patterns in red and gold, was originally crafted by Sulmish wizards to improve their casting abilities and protections.
	While you wear this magic robe, you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +2 bonus to your AC and saving throws.
	• You have one more spell slot for the 1st, 2nd, 3rd level, 4th, and 5th level.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">saving throws +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Healing Cap of Veluna [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a cleric)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This small cloth cap is enchanted by clerics of Veluna to help the wounded and dying.
	While you wear this cap and you heal hit points through a spell of 1st-level or higher, the amount of hit points that you heal is doubled.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Headband of the Corusk Mountains [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic headband is carved from the skulls of white dragons. While you wear this magic headband, you have Resistance to Cold damage and you can't suffer Exhaustion from cold, snow, or icy temperature.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Headband of the Jotens [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic item is made of a strip of elk fur and was originally enchanted to insure the safety of travelers in the Jotens.
	While you wear this magic item, you have advantage when you make an Influence Action and the target of the action is a Giant.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 17 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Helmet of Selnor [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a fighter, paladin, or ranger)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic helmet is made of sculpted bronze, has a large amethyst set above the brow, and stag horns.
	When you wear this magic helmet, you gain the following benefits.
	You gain a +1 bonus to your AC. You can use a Magic Action to cast the charm monster spell (Spell Save DC 17). Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 17 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Hextor's Skin [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>plate armor, very rare (requires attunement by a cleric, fighter, or paladin)</detail>
    <type>HA</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>65</weight>
    <ac>18</ac>
    <stealth>YES</stealth>
    <strength>15</strength>
    <text>Hextor believes in conquering for the sake of domination and tyranny. and this magic armor of black steel embodies that belief.

	• When you wear this magic armor, you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +2 bonus to your AC.

	• You have advantage on any Charisma (Intimidation) check.

	• As a Bonus Action you can create a 15-foot Emanation around you for 1 minute. Each creature within the Emanation, and whenever the Emanation enters a creature's space, and whenever a creature enters the Emanation or ends its turn there, that creature must succeed on a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw or has the Frightened condition for 1 minute. At the end of each of its next turn, an affected creature can make another saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success. On a successful save, that creature is immune to this effect for the next 24 hours. Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

The wearer has disadvantage on Stealth (Dexterity) checks.

If the wearer has a Strength score lower than 15, their speed is reduced by 10 feet.

Proficiency: heavy armor
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 17 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Hoarfrost Blade [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>longsword, very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon, and the first time you hit a creature on a turn you deal 1d8 additional Cold damage.
	When you target an Aberration or a Fiend with a melee weapon attack with this magic weapon, you have advantage on the attack roll.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, longsword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 17 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
    <roll description="Extra Cold Damage">1d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Holy Medallion of Almor [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic item was originally created while Almor was under the Great Kingdom's rule.
	The priests of Almor foresaw great evil coming to the Flanaess, so they enchanted this item to help keep peace.
	When you wear this magic medallion, you can target up to 6 creatures that you can see within 60 feet of you. Each creature must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target can't take the Attack or Magic Action for 1 minute. At the end of each of its next turns, an affected creature can make another Wisdom saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Holy Star of the Bright Desert [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This copper star is marked with the symbol of the deity Heironeous the Invincible. You have advantage on any saving throw against having the Frightened condition.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Holy Symbol of Greyhawk [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Hung from a golden chain, this golden symbol was enchanted to symbolize the power of its home city. When you wear this magic item, you can use a Magic Action to cast one of the following spells:

	• bless
	• protection from evil and good

Once you cast one of these spells, you can't cast it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Horn of the Barrier Peaks [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a dwarf)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This iron horn was originally enchanted by a master dwarven smith to cement friendship between dwarves and the spirits beasts of the Barrier Peaks. As a Magic Action, when you blow the horn you can cast the conjure animals spell.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Inquisitor's Whip [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>whip, uncommon (requires attunement by a creature of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <property>M,F,R</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>This magic whip is often created by the church of Iuz, either for its followers or under commission. You gain a +1 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. On a successful hit, you can use a Bonus Action to force the target creature to make a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target has the Frightened condition until the end of its next turn.

Slow (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon and deal damage to it, you can reduce its Speed by 10 feet until the start of your next turn. If the creature is hit more than once by weapons that have this property, the Speed reduction doesn't exceed 10 feet.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Reach: A Reach weapon adds 5 feet to your reach when you attack with it, as well as when determining your reach for Opportunity Attacks with it.

Proficiency: martial, whip
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Iron Pin of the Icy Sea [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This pin is set in a circular container of transparent crystal, and was originally used by barbarian hunters and raiders sailing the Icy Sea in foggy summer. When you are attuned to this magic item, you can never get lost.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Iron Gauntlet of Urnst [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This item was originally created by an iron-fisted wizard who wanted a magical item to symbolize his philosophy of life. It is a leather gauntlet covered with flat iron plates on the upper surface. When you make a Unarmed Strike with this magic gauntlet, on a successful hit, roll a d20 and apply the result according to the table below.

Unarmed Strike effect:
d20 | Effect
1-10 | Glancing Blow. The target takes 2d4 bludgeoning damage
11-16 | Solid Punch. The target takes 3d4 bludgeoning damage
17-19 | Hard Punch. The target takes 3d6 damage and has the Stunned condition until the end of its next round
20 | Crushing Blow. The target takes 4d6 damage and has the Stunned condition for 1 minute. At the end of each of its next turns, the target can make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw, ending the condition on itself on a success.

Stunned:
	• A stunned creature is incapacitated, meaning it can't take actions or reactions, can't move, and can speak only falteringly.
	• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Effect">1d20</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage">2d4</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage">3d4</roll>
    <roll description="Damage">3d6</roll>
    <roll description="Damage">4d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Jewel of Attacks [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This gleaming gem radiates magic and appears to be a valuable item. When you attune to this magic gem, you suffer a Curse. When you have this Curse, the chance that a random encounter occurs is doubled.
	For example, if a random encounter happens on a 1820 on a d20 roll, with this Curse it happens on a 1520. This Curse is removed by a remove curse spell or greater magic.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Keolandish Plate Mail of the Seas [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>plate armor, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>HA</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <ac>18</ac>
    <stealth>YES</stealth>
    <strength>15</strength>
    <text>This magic armor was originally created as a gift of the King of Keoland to an admiral who had fought successfully against the Sea Princes.
	While you wear this magic armor, you gain a +1 bonus to your AC and you have a Swim Speed 30 feet.

The wearer has disadvantage on Stealth (Dexterity) checks.

If the wearer has a Strength score lower than 15, their speed is reduced by 10 feet.

Proficiency: heavy armor
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Larder of Holding [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This is a magic door that when it is packed it can normally be contained in a backpack and has the Encumbrance of 2 lbs.
	As a Magic Action, you can unpack this magic item upon any wall as high and wide enough to host a door as high and wide enough for a Medium creature. The door leads to an extra-dimensional space that can preserve corpses at the same time when they are put in that space. For example, that means that you can open the door, put inside a corpse of a creature that died a round before, pull out the corpse after 1 year and then bring back the creature to life by a revivify spell instead of a resurrection spell.
	When the magic door is upon a wall, you can pack it through a Utilize Action.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Lantern of Greyhawk [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This hooded lantern was found for the first time in the abandoned castle of Zazyg Yragerne, the Mad Mage. When you hold this magic item, you can use a Magic Action to activate a 30-foot Cone's that originates from the lantern. You gain Truesight within the Cone' space. The Cone lasts for 1 minute or earlier if you dismiss it as a Bonus Action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Lesser Ring of the Pomarji [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This black ring was originally created by a wizard from the Wild Coast. When you wear this magic ring, you can use a Magic Action to conjure goblin spirits that appear as a Large pack of spectral intangible goblins in an unoccupied space within 60 feet of you. While you are within 5 feet of the pack, you can use the Dash or Disengage Action as a Bonus Action, and when you move on your turn, you can also move the pack up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. The pack disappears after 1 minute, or earlier if you dismiss it as a Bonus Action.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Lesser Sulmish Robe of Magical Enhancement [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This black robe, embroidered with complex patterns in red and gold, was originally crafted by Sulmish wizards to improve their casting abilities and protections.
	While you wear this magic robe, you gain the following benefits.

	* You gain a +1 bonus to your AC and saving throws.
	* You have one more spell slot for the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd level.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">saving throws +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Locket of the Great Kingdom [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic item was originally created by a wizard who greatly feared death. When you wear this magic locket and reach 0 hp, you can use a Reaction to instantly regain 4d8+4 hit points up to your maximum.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Heal">4d8+4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Lucky Ring of the Wild Coast [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magical ring was originally created by a wizard who liked to gamble, and quickly it became a common tool for any gambler of the Wild Coast.
	When you wear this magic ring, you gain advantage on any Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check that you make in order to gamble at a game you are playing.
	After you made the check, roll a d20. On a 1, the ring magically glows, revealing its magic to each creature that can see you within 20 feet.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Medegian Bracelet of Lost Ships [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This silver bracelet contains a zircon stone that was enchanted by a greedy wizard who used it to attain great wealth before he was captured and hung by pirates.
	The stone in the bracelet glows red on the side that faces the nearest sunken ship within 1 mile of you. When you are within 50 feet horizontally of a sunken ship, the stone glows blue. Then you can use a Magic Action to spend one or more charges and the sunken ship rises to the surface for 1 hour.
	The bracelet has 25 charges, and raising a sunken ship costs a number of charges depending on size, as per the table below

Types of Ships:
Ships | Charge
Small boat or barge | 1
Small galley | 4
Large galley | 4
Small merchant ship | 5
Warship | 6
Large Merchant Ship | 7

Each ship has a 75% chance of being inhabited by monsters. The DM chooses which monsters.
	The bracelet can't be recharged, and once the last charge is spent, it crumbles to dust.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Medallion of Malog [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Hung on a golden necklace, this magic medallion was originally created by an evil wizard from the capital of the Horned Society. When you wear this magic medallion you can spend two or more charges to cast one of the following spells:

	• conjure animals (2 charge)
	• conjure minor elementals (3 charge)
	• conjure elementals (4 charges)
	• conjure celestial (6 charges)

If you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the medallion disappears.

	Recharge. This magic medallion has 7 charges and recharges 1d6+1 spent charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d6+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Meersalm Salve [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Legends tell that when he was born, the skin of the deity Heironeous was imbued with a salve called meersalm, which made him impervious to all but magic weapons. Over the years, the church of Heironeous has produced quantities of a weaker of this salve to protect the warriors in battle.
	As a Magic Action, you apply this magic salve on a part of your body, and you gain Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage for 1 hour.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Mirror of the Past [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic mirror is made of platinum. As a Magic Action, when you look into this magic mirror and concentrate on a creature that you have seen or heard of, you can see 1 minute of your choice of that creature's past. You have the Incapacitated condition as long as you're viewing the past of that creature.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oracles of Greyhawk [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a bard or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>An oracle is a crystal ball with slight tinges of color. Many oracles were created in the past, for the thenLord Mayor of Greyhawk, but no one knows how many oracles are still in the City of Greyhawk's possessions, and how many have been lost or stolen. There are seven different type of oracles, each one with a different color and associated to a different area, as per the table below.

Type of Oracles:
Experience Points | Area
Blue | Shield Lands
Brown | Cairn Hills
Green | Gnarley Forest
Orange | Wild Coast
Red | Horned Society
Violet | City of Greyhawk
Yellow | Kingdom of Furyondy

As a Magic Action, you can look inside the oracle and ask a question of no more than 15 words about something related to the oracle's area. The question can be something that would normally imply an Arcana, Nature, or History check. The oracle will provide the correct answer with no more than 25 words.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 22 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Pelor's Wrath [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by a cleric or a paladin of good alignment)</detail>
    <type>ST</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <property>V</property>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>During the years, the leaders of the various churches dedicated to Pelor have developed several versions of this magic weapon.
	This magic staff is made from bleached darkwood and bears a golden starburst symbol at its top. In the center of this symbol is a large, multifaceted crystal. The other end of the staff is tipped by a brilliant ray of light.
	You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Additionally, as a Magic Action, you can spend one or more charges to cast one of the following spells:

Type of Spells:
Spells | Charges
Bless | 1
Prayer of healing | 2
Beacon of hope | 3
Heal | 4

When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, this magic staff becomes nonmagical.

	Recharge. This magic staff has 5 charges. It recharges 1d4+1 spent charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 22 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Black Sight [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.5</weight>
    <text>When you drink this Potion as a Bonus Action, you gain Darkvision 120 feet for 1 hour.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Intensity [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.5</weight>
    <text>When you drink this potion as a Bonus Action, for 1 minute you gain the following benefits.

	• You have advantage on any spell attack.

	• Each creature that must make a saving throw against a spell cast by you has disadvantage on its roll.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Magic Resistance [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.5</weight>
    <text>When you drink this potion as a Bonus Action, you gain advantage on any saving throw against spells or other magical effects for 1 minute.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Superheroism [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.5</weight>
    <text>When you drink this potion as a Bonus Action, you gain 30 temporary hit points that last for 1 hour. For the same duration, you are under the effect of a bless spell (no concentration required).

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Purple Gem of the Vesve Forest [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by an elf)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.1</weight>
    <text>This magical gemstone is set in a silver bracelet and was originally created by elven wizards. As a Magic Action, you can spend one or more charges to cast one of the following spells:

Conjure animals (1 charge)
Conjure woodland beings (2 charges)
Conjure fey (3 charges)

When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the gem becomes a blossoming flower.

	Recharge. The gem has 4 charges and recharges 1d4 spent charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll>1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Razor Claws of Chakyik [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>These magic claws were created by a wizard loyal to the Tiger Lord of the northwest. Each claw consists of four curved daggers attached to a leather gauntlet. When you wear these magic claws you can make an Unarmed Strike using Dexterity or Strength (your choice) and your proficiency bonus. The attack is magical. On a hit, you deal 4d4 slashing damage plus your Dexterity or Strength bonus.
	Additionally you have disadvantage on any Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, and you can't pick or hold any item.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Strength Unarmed Slashing Damage">4d4+%1</roll>
    <roll description="Dexterity Unarmed Slashing Damage">4d4+%2</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ring of Leadership [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.1</weight>
    <text>This silver ring is usually given to creatures in return to loyal friendship or unexpected favor. While wearing this magic ring, you have advantage on any Charisma while dealing with creatures Indifferent to you.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ring of Stone [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.1</weight>
    <text>This golden ring contains a magic rock. As a Magic Action, you can spend one charge to cast the flesh to stone spell (Spell Save DC 17). The ring has 3 charges and cannot be recharged. When you spend the last charge, the ring becomes solid rock.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Rod of Electrification [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>mace, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>This rod is made of a copper-nickel alloy. You gain a +1 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	On a successful hit, you can use a Bonus Action to deal an additional 1d8 Lightning damage.
	Once you use this property three times, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Proficiency: simple, mace
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Lightning Damage">1d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Rod of Entropy [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>mace, very rare (requires attunement by a creature of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>This magic weapon is a short, blackened iron shaft topped by three skulls sculpted to look as though they have melted together.
	You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	As a Magic Action, you can create a 15-foot Emanation of a black aura. Each creature within the Emanation must make a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking 3d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature must make the Constitution saving throw whenever the Emanation enters the creature's space, or whenever a creature enters the Emanation's space for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Proficiency: simple, mace
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage">3d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Rod of Onwal [5.5e] </name>
    <detail>spellcasting focus, very rare (requires attunement by a creature of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>RD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <text>This magic rod was originally crafted to protect the inhabitants of Onnwal against the fierce storms that regularly lash the Sea of Gearnat.
	While you are within a nonmagical storm that can potentially cause you one or more Hazards, you can use a Magic Action to calm the storm to a point that is no more dangerous.
	Once used this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Rod of the Aerdi Sea [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>RD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic rod was originally crafted for use by merchants who sail the pirate-infested waters between Hepmonaland and the Great Kingdom.
	As a Magic Action, you can spend one or more charges to cast one of the following spells (Spell Save DC 17):

	• fog cloud (1 charge)
	• hallucinatory terrain (2 charges)
	• programmed illusion (3 charges)

When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the rod disappears.

	Recharge. The rod has 5 charges and recharges 1d4+1 spent charges daily at dawn.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Rod of the Wellwood [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>RD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Fashioned from an oaken branch, this magic rod was originally crafted by druids who inhabited the majestic forest of Welkwood.
	While you hold this magic rod in your hand, you gain the following benefits:

	• You can use the rod as a magical staff +1. You are proficient in this weapon.

	• As a Magic Action, you can spend one or more charges to cast one of the following spells (Spell Save DC 17): entangle (1 charge), plant growth (2 charges), wall of thorns (3 charges)

When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the rod disappears.

	Recharge. The rod has 5 charges and recharges 1d4+1 spent charges daily at dawn.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Scant Wand of Storms [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic wand was originally created in the capital city of Onnwal, and has been used against raiding warships from the South Province. Its first creator was undoubtedly influenced by observing the furious weather in the Sea of Gearnat.
	While you hold this magic wand, you can use a Magic Action to create a 30–foot radius Sphere centered on a point that you can see within range. Since that area is filled by heavy rain and lightning, it's Lightly Obscured and is a Difficult Terrain. When a creature that starts its turn there or enters the Sphere for the first time on a turn, it must make a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking 8d8 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage and no other ill effects on a successful one.
	The Sphere lasts for 1 minute or earlier if you dismiss it with a Bonus Action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Lightning Damage">8d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Scroll of the Death Servant [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>SC</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This scroll reads "For you, the greatest gift of all".
	When you read this scroll, the scroll crumbles to dust and you feel a chill and then a warmth drifts across your back. A death servant has merged into your shadow. The first time you are about to die, the death servant dies instead of you, dissipating in a cloud of black vapor.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Scroll of the Efreeti [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>SC</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Upon this magic scroll there are many flaming runes and sigils. While you carry this magic scroll you have Resistance to Fire damage. As a Magic Action, you can read the scroll and cast the conjure elemental spell (only Fire Elemental). Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Silver Key of Portals [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic item is a regular-sized silver skeleton key. As a Utilize Action, you can place the skeleton key on any locked door (either magically or not), immediately unlocking the door. Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 26 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Skull-Staff of Hepmonaland [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>ST</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <property>V</property>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>This magic staff is a 7-foot-long pole topped with a skull with a wild mane of white hair and sharp, demonic features.
	You gain a +1 bonus to your AC while you hold that staff. Additionally, you can use a Magic Action to force a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you to look at the school. The target must succeed on a Wisdom DC 15 saving throw or has the Frightened condition for 1 minute. At the end of each of its next turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.
	Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 26 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Spider's Boots of Stealth [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common (requires attunement by a rogue)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Spider was the nickname of the premier thief of the city of Rel Astra. No one knew anything else about him. Spider was a loner elf who never formed a close relationship with anyone in the Rel Astran Thieves' Guild.
	These magic boots are black, calf-length suede boots with a criss crossing pattern of silver webs. While you wear these magic boots, you gain the following effects:

	• You can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.

	• You ignore movement restrictions caused by webbing.

	• You are immune to any effect caused by webbing.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 26 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Staff of Hornwood [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>ST</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <property>V</property>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>This magic staff was originally created by a wizard who wanted to make her travel in the wilderness less dangerous.
	As a Magic Action, you create a 10-foot Emanation from you. This Emanation prevents any creature with an Intelligence score of 4 from passing or reaching through it. If you move and the Emanation enters the space of one of such creatures, that creature must use its Reaction to move away from the Emanation's area.
	The Emanation lasts for 1 hour or earlier if you dismiss it as a Bonus Action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 27 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Staff of Celene [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Set on a silver necklace, this golden medallion is usually given as a gift to those who performed great services for high elves in Celene.
	When you openly wear this magic necklace, you have Advantage on any Influence Action against elves.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 27 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Starburst Insignia [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a cleric or paladin of good alignment)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This insignia has rubies embedded with them and were created by the church of St. Cuthbert.
	When you wear this magic item around your neck you have advantage on any Wisdom saving throw and ability check.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 27 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Stonefist [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>greatsword, very rare (requires attunement by a fighter)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <property>M,H,2H</property>
    <dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>This magic greatsword is also known as the Sword of Rage, and was enchanted during the reign of Vlek Col Vlekzed. You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Additionally, when you make an attack with this magic weapon, you can choose to have advantage on that attack. If you choose so, however, attacks made against you have advantage until the start of your next turn.

Proficiency: martial, greatsword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 27 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Sulward's Axe [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>battleaxe, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>This magic axe is magically sharpened to aid woodsmen in cutting rare woods to be exported from the Lordship of the Isles. You gain a +1 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon, and if the target is a Plant the bonus becomes +2. Additionally, you gain advantage on any Wisdom (Survival) check.

Topple (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, you can force the creature to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 plus the ability modifier used to make the attack roll and your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, the creature has the Prone condition.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, battleaxe
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Symbol of True Death [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic item is a small amulet that looks like a red skull, usually carved from bone, in front of a circular fan of fire made of steel but plated in gold.
	While you wear this magic amulet, you have advantage on any Death saving throw.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Thillonrian Shield [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you hold this magic shield, you gain a +2 bonus on your AC. This magic shield helps you to inspire your allies. As a Magic Action, each creature Allied to you within 120 feet that can hear you has advantage on any saving throw against the Charmed, Frightened, Paralyzed, and Stunned condition.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Timeglass of the Wizard [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by a wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic item appears to be a 1-foot-tall hourglass. As a Magic Action, you can spend two or more charges to cast on the following spells (Spell Save DC17):

	• haste (2 charges)
	• slow (2 charge)
	• time stop (3 charges)

When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the hourglass disappears.

	Recharge. The hourglass has 3 charges and recharges 1d2 charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d2</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Tiger Cloak of Chalyik [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic cloak is fashioned from the complete hide of an adult tiger. It includes head, skin, and claws, dangling at the sides.
	When you wear this magic cloak, you gain the ability to enter in Rage, as the Barbarian class, as a Magic Action. If you have a level in the Barbarian class, then you have one more use of this ability.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Trident of the Oljatt Sea [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>trident, very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic weapon is rumored to be a weapon of sahuagin fighters. You gain a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	As a Magic Action, you can unleash a jet of steam that forms a Line 60-foot-long and 10-foot-wide originating from the trident.
	Each creature in the Line makes a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw, taking 6d8 Force damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Proficiency: simple, trident
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>
    <roll description="Force Damage">6d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Tusmit Battle's Crescent [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>trident, uncommon (requires attunement by a barbarian, fighter, paladin, or ranger)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Set in a golden necklace studded with gems, this magic medallion is a prized possession among warriors.
	As a Bonus Action, you have advantage on all your weapon attacks for 1 minute. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of Force [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you hold this magic wand, you gain the following benefits.

	• As a Magic Action, you can create a 60-foot long and 5-foot wide Line that originates from the tip of the wand. Each creature in the Line must make a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d10 force damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

	• As a Magic Action, you can cast the wall of force spell(Spell Save DC17). Once you cast this spell, you can't cast it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of Highfolk [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic wand was originally created by high elves in the northwest.
	While you hold this magic wand, you can use a Magic Action to target up to 6 creatures that are allies with each other. Each target makes a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target has the Charmed condition and becomes Hostile to the other targets and sees them as Hostile. The condition lasts for 1 minute. At the end of each of its next turns, an affected creature can make another Wisdom saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of Secret Door &amp; Trap Detection [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>As a Magic Action, while you hold this magic wand, you can find any secret door or trap within 120 feet of you. Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Werebane [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>dagger, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <property>F,L,T</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>20/60</range>
    <text>You have a +1 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	When you successfully hit a Shapechanger, you deal additional 2d12 damage.

Nick (Mastery): When you make the extra attack of the Light property, you can make it as part of the Attack action in· stead of as a Bonus Action. You can make this extra attack only once per turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Proficiency: simple, dagger
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Damage">2d12</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Whip of Zeif [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>whip, very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,F,R</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>You have a +2 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. As a Magic Action, you can crack the whip in the air. Each creature within 120 feet that can hear the crack must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or has the Deafened condition for 1 minute. At the end of each of its next turns, an affected creature can make another Constitution saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.
	Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Slow (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon and deal damage to it, you can reduce its Speed by 10 feet until the start of your next turn. If the creature is hit more than once by weapons that have this property, the Speed reduction doesn't exceed 10 feet.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Reach: A Reach weapon adds 5 feet to your reach when you attack with it, as well as when determining your reach for Opportunity Attacks with it.

Proficiency: simple, whip
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Whistle of Axewood [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This silver instrument was originally created by elven wizards to deal with Fey.
	When you play this magic instrument as a Bonus Action, you gain advantage on any Influence Action made while dealing with Fey.
	Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Whiteshiver Elixir [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This small glass vial contains a thick, milky elixir with a foul smell reminiscent of rotting mushrooms.
	When you drink this magic potion as a Bonus Action, you gain the following benefits for 1 hour.

	• You are a Plant. You maintain your Humanoid Type.

	• You have Resistance to Poison damage and you are Immune to the Poisoned condition.

	• You have Darkvision 120 feet.

	• As a Magic Action, you can release spores in a 30foot Sphere centered on you. Each creature within the Sphere must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw, taking 2d8 Poison Damage and having the Poisoned condition for 1 minute on a failed save, or half as much damage and no other ill effects on a successful one. An affected creature must make another Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its next turns, ending the effect on itself on a successful save, Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Poison Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wings of the Rakers [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This white cloak was originally enchanted by a wizard who found a welcome home among the Griff Mountains and the Rakers.
	While you wear this magic cloak, as a Bonus Action the cloak takes the appearance of white seagull wings and you gain Fly Speed 30 feet. Additionally, when you are flying and you dive at least 20 feet straight toward a target and then hit it with a melee weapon attack, you deal an extra 2d8 damage to the target. The white seagull wings disappear after 1 hour or earlier if you dismiss them as a Bonus Action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 30 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wizard's Robe [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While you wear this magic robe, you can spend one or more charges to cast one of the following spells (Spell Save DC 15):

	• charm person (1 charge)
	• hold person (2 charges)
	• charm monster (3 charges)
	• hold monster (4 charges)
	• polymorph (4 charges)

When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the robe crumbles to dust.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 30 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wolf Cloak of Wegwiur [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magical cloak is made from the hide of a winter wolf, and includes a wolf's head, pelt, claws, and tail. Originally, it was enchanted by priests of the Wolf Nomads.
	When you wear this magic cloak, you gain the following benefits.

	• You have Resistance to Cold damage.

	• As a Magic Action, you can have advantage on any Wisdom and Dexterity Test for 1 minute. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 30 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Woodworker's Tools of Dyvers [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>artisan tools, common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <text>Ability: Dexterity
Utilize: Carve a pattern in wood (DC 10)
Craft: Club, Greatclub, Quarterstaff, Ranged weapons (except Pistol, Musket, and  Sling), Arcane Focus, Arrows, Bolts, Druidic Focus, Ink Pen, Needles

This magical set of Woodcarver's Tools was originally enchanted for a carpenter in the City of Dyvers. You are proficient in this magical set of Woodcarver's Tools and when you use them, you have advantage on any check roll.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 30 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Zazyg's Spell Component Pouch</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This item is a normal belt pouch of unremarkable sort. The famous archmage Zazyg is rumored to be the first crafter of this magic item. When you wear this magic pouch and you are casting a spell you pick from the pouch a desired material spell component of a value up to 100 gp. The component always disappears after you cast the spell.
	Once used this property three times, you must finish a Long Rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 30 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <!-- Legendary Items -->
  <item>
    <name>Black Crown of Aerdy [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This evil headgear was worn by one of the first Overkings of House Naelax in the ancient Great Kingdom. Whether the crown was enchanted by an evil wizard or whether it merely became a receptacle for the Overking's cruel spirit is not known. The powers of the crown exist only to recreate the greatness and wickedness of that Overking.
	When you attune to this magic item by donning it, your Intelligence and Wisdom score raise by 4 up to a maximum of 24, and you gain one Epic Boon of your choice, even if your level is lower than 19, and your alignment becomes lawful evil.
	Each time you finish a Long Rest you must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save your Constitution score permanently lowers by 1. When your Constitution score becomes 0, you die and become a specter guarding the crown.
	After the attunement to this magic item, donning it, you don't voluntarily remove it.
	The crown can be removed only by a wish spell.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 32 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Blade of Chaos [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>longsword, legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>The blade of this iron longsword is laced with thin lines of mithral that seem to shift and move constantly. Two twisted pieces of silver that end in large emeralds serve as its quillons. The handle is wrapped in green leather, and the pommel consists of a third emerald set into silver talons.

You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has the following additional properties.

	Binding Strike: When you successfully hit a creature with a melee attack, the target must succeed on a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw or has the Paralyzed condition for 1 minute. At the end of each of its next turns, an affected creature can make another Wisdom saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.
	On a successful save, target creature is immune to this effect for the next 24 hours. Spells: as a Magic Action, you can cast the darkness and the ray of enfeeblement spell (Spell Save DC 17). Once you cast one of those spells, you can't cast that spell again until you finish a Long Rest.

	Sentience: Blade of Chaos is a sentient chaotic neutral weapon with an Intelligence of 17, a Wisdom of 10, and a Charisma of 17. It has hearing and Darkvision out of a range of 120 feet. The weapon can speak, read, and understand Common, and can communicate with its wielder telepathically. Its voice is arrogant and harsh. While you are attuned to it, Blade of Chaos also understands every language you know.

	Personality: Blade of Chaos speaks with an arrogant voice, expecting to be obeyed and considering its wielders as inferior beings. The weapon's purpose is to add unpredictability to any situation while avoiding the boundaries of rules and laws.

Proficiency: simple, longsword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 32 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Blue Armor of the Crystalmist Mountains [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>scale mail, legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>MA</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>45</weight>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <stealth>YES</stealth>
    <text>This scale armor is cut from the hide of adult or ancient blue dragons and it is crafted by the mountain dwarves of the Cystalmist range. While you wear this magic scale armor you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +3 bonus to your AC.

	• You gain Resistance to Lightning damage.

The wearer has disadvantage on Stealth (Dexterity) checks.

Proficiency: medium armor
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 33 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Chalice of the Shield Lands [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement by a creature of good alignment who is not a paladin)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This golden chalice was enchanted in response to the growing menace of the Horned Society.
	When you drink as a Magic Action from this chalice, you can gain the abilities of a Paladin of Devotion of the same level as you (Minimum level 3) for 1 hour. You retain all the abilities of your class.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until 7 days have passed.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 33 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Dreamsinger [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>rapier, legendary (requires attunement by a bard)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>M,F</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <text>Dreamsinger is one of the Five Blades of Corusk. It has a blade of white steel and is set with moonstones.
	When you are not attuned to it, you gain a +1 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

	• When you are attuned to it, you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +3 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

	• You have a +2 bonus to your AC and to any saving throw.

	• You can sense automatically the exact position of another Blade of Corusk as long as it is within 1 mile of you.

Vex (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon and deal damage to the creature, you have Advantage on your next attack roll against that creature before the end of your next turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Proficiency: martial, rapier
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 34 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Equalizer of Gran March [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>longsword, legendary (requires attunement by a creature of neutral alignment)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <text>This silver longsword was created to be a tool for the balancing powers of the Multiverse. While you hold this magic weapon, you have a +3 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	When you successfully hit a creature of a non-neutral alignment or that's not unaligned, you can use a Bonus Action to invoke the balancing powers. The target must succeed on DC 19 Charisma saving throw or it is completely disintegrated. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: simple, longsword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 34 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Fire Wand of the Sueloise [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <text>This magic wand may have been the device that caused the destruction of the Suel Empire.
	While you hold this magic wand, you can use a Magic Action to spend 3 charges and create a 60-foot Cube to a point that you can see within 120 feet of you. The Cube contains a rain of magical fire that burns everyone and everything. Each creature within the Cube must make a DC 19 Dexterity saving throw, taking 12d8 Fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. On each of your next turns, you can spend a Bonus Action to maintain the Cube, and each creature that starts its turn there or enters the Cube for the first time on a turn must make a DC 19 Dexterity saving throw, taking 12d8 Fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Objects not carried or worn within the cube other than those made of mithral and adamantine take 12d8 Fire damage at the end of each of your turns as long as the Cube lasts.
	When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 10 or lower, the wand explodes in a Sphere of 60-foot radius centered on you. Each creature within the sphere must make a DC 21 Dexterity saving throw, taking 24d8 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.

	Recharge. The wand has 6 charges and recharges 1d6 spent charges daily at dawn.

Proficiency: simple, wand
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 34 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">12d8</roll>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">12d8</roll>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">12d8</roll>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">24d8</roll>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Greenswathe [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>scimitar, legendary (requires attunement by a druid)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,F,L</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>Greenswathe is one of the Five Blades of Corusk. It is made of a gold-colored alloy as hard as adamantine. When you are not attuned to it, you gain a +1 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	When you are attuned to it, you gain a +3 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Additionally, when you successfully hit a target with this magic weapon, as a Bonus Action you deal 2d6 additional damage. Once you use this property three times, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Nick (Mastery): When you make the extra attack of the Light property, you can make it as part of the Attack action in· stead of as a Bonus Action. You can make this extra attack only once per turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Proficiency: martial, scimitar
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 36 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +3</modifier>
    <roll description="Extra Damage">2d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Harmonizer [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>shortsword, legendary (requires attunement by a rogue)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>M,F,L</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <text>Harmonizer is one of the Five Blades of Corusk. Across the shiny surface of this magic weapon are etched images of a wizard performing a ritual over five swords. You gain a +3 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	When you attune to this magic item, the sword creates a clone of you and each creature Allied to you within 120 feet of you. The clones are Fey, appear in an unoccupied space within 30 feet of you and they are Hostile to you and your allies.

Vex (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon and deal damage to the creature, you have Advantage on your next attack roll against that creature before the end of your next turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Proficiency: martial, shortsword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 36 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +3</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Horn of the Azure Sea [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement by a creature of evil alignment)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This magic horn was originally created by an evil cleric. This magic item functions only at night on the open sea.
	As a Magic Action, you can blow the horn and a Huge ghost ship appears in an unoccupied space on the sea within 360 feet of you. Each creature other than you and your allies that can see that ghost ship must succeed on a DC 19 Wisdom saving throw or has the Frightened condition for 1 minute. The ghost ship disappears after 1 minute or earlier if you dismiss it as a Bonus Action. When the ship disappears, the condition ends on the affected creatures.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 37 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Iron Crown of the Bandit Kingdom [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement by a fighter)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This metal headgear was fashioned for fighters. When you wear this magic crown, you have Immunity to the Charmed and Frightened condition.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 37 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Mace of St. Cuthbert [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>mace, legendary (requires attunement by a cleric or paladin of a lawful good alignment)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>This magic mace is known to be a relic created by St.Cuthbert himself. You gain a +3 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	When you hit a Fiend or an Undead with this magic weapon, that creature takes an extra 2d6 radiant damage. If the target has 25 hit points or fewer, it must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be destroyed. On a successful save, that creature has the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn. While you hold this weapon, it sheds Bright Light in a 20-foot radius, and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet.
	As a Magic Action, you can spend one or more charges to cast one of the following spells:

	• bless (1 charge)
	• remove curse (2 charge)
	• heal (3 charges)
	• resurrection (5 charges)

When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, your Intelligence score lowers by 1. If your Intelligence score reaches 3 in such a manner, you become an NPC Celestial servant of St.Cuthbert.

	Recharge. This magic mace has 5 charges and recharges 1d4+1 spent charges daily at dawn

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Proficiency: simple, mace
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 37 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +3</modifier>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d6</roll>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Prism of Greyhawk [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement by a bard, sorcerer, or wizard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <text>This crystal tool was originally enchanted to enhance the prism's ability to create dazzling colors.
	As a Magic Action, you can cast the prismatic ray or the prismatic wall spells(Spell Save DC 19). Once you cast one of these two spells, you can't use this property again until you finish a Long Rest.
	This magic item functions only if you are in sunlight.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 37 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Red Armor of the Hellfurnaces [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>scale mail, legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>MA</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>45</weight>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <stealth>YES</stealth>
    <text>This scale armor was cut from the back plates of adult or ancient red dragons. Many warriors from the Yeomanry died in battle to kill those creatures, and the best armorers were hired to rework the plates into a wearable armor. While wearing this magic scale armor you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +3 bonus to your AC.
	• You gain Resistance to Fire damage.

The wearer has disadvantage on Stealth (Dexterity) checks.

Proficiency: medium armor
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 38 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 219</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Scepter of the Forgotten City [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>scale mail, legendary (requires attunement by a cleric or wizard)</detail>
    <type>RD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>45</weight>
    <text>A relic of a lost civilization, this wandlike scepter is a 2-foot-long shaft of silver with a large red gem at the tip. It was used by some of the original lords of the Suel Empire; when that kingdom was turned into the Sea of Dust, the wand was lost. A recent expedition from the Yeomanry rediscovered the wand, and those explorers claimed that it came from the Forgotten City itself. Whether or not that claim is true, the scepter certainly contains some of the greatness that built the lost empire, and much of the madness that destroyed it.
	As a Magic Action, you can spend one charge to raise your Intelligence and Wisdom scores to 25 for the next 24 hours. Each time you spend one charge, you must make a DC 20 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, your Constitution score lowers by 1. When your Constitution reaches 0, you die and your corpse raises as a wraith in the next 24 hours.
	When you spend the last charge, the scepter disappears.

	Recharge. The Scepter has 25 charges and cannot be recharged.

Proficiency: simple, rod
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 38 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Shield of Greyhawk [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>shield, legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>S</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <ac>2</ac>
    <text>This magic shield bears Greyhawk's coat of arms and was originally created by the Society of the Magi. It now hangs in the audience hall of the Lord Mayor's mansion.
	While you hold this magic shield, you gain the following benefits.

	• You gain a +3 bonus to your AC.

	• You can cast the dispel evil and good spell. Once you use this property twice, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Utilize Action to Don or Doff.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 38 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 219</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Silver Crown of Veluna [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>shield, legendary (requires attunement by a cleric of good alignment)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <text>Encrusted with small green gems, this silver crown recently appeared among the ruling clerics of Veluna. The Canon himself has often worn it, though he may sometimes loan it to trusted agents of Veluna when they embark on important, holy missions.
	While you wear this magic item, you gain the following benefits.

	• Your Wisdom score increases by 2 up to a maximum of 22.
	• You are under the permanent effect of a protection from good and evil spell, but you are protected only by Aberrations, Elementals, Fiends, and Undead.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Soul Gem [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>shield, legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <text>This glowing magic gem floats in the air, slowly rotating around you. As a Magic Action, you can spend 1 charge and the gem makes a blast of negative energy towards a creature that you can see within 60 feet. The target must make a DC 21 Constitution saving throw, taking 10d10 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. If the target reaches 0 hp, it immediately dies, its soul is entrapped within the gem, and it can't be resurrected, unless the gem is broken. This magic gem has AC 20, 50 hit points, and has Immunity to Poison, Necrotic, Psychic damage, and to Bludgeoning, Piercing and Slashing damage made with non magical attacks.
	Each time you spend a charge, you consume a soul trapped within the gem. The DM chooses which soul is consumed. If its soul is consumed, that creature can be resurrected only by a wish spell.

	Recharge. This magic gem recharges 1 charge each time a soul is trapped within.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage">10d10</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Stalker [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>longsword, legendary (requires attunement by a ranger)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>Stalker is a one of the Five Blades of Corusk. It is a longsword with a blue steel blade and a hilt, pommel, and crosspiece of black adamantine. Wisps of shadowstuff seem to move silently across its surface.
	When you are not attuned to it, you gain a +1 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	When you are attuned to it, you gain a +3 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon, and you gain advantage on any Dexterity (Stealth) and Wisdom (Survival) check.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, longsword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 41 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +3</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Sword of Azor'alq [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>longsword, legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has the following additional properties.

	Crush Evil: When you successfully hit an Aberration or a Fiend, the target must succeed on DC 19 Constitution saving throw or it is disintegrated. Once you successfully use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

	Detect Evil: As a Magic Action, you can exactly locate any Aberration or Fiend within 1 mile of you. When you use this property three times, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

	Spells: As a Magic Action, you can cast the fly spell. Once you cast this spell, you can't cast it again until you finish a Long Rest.

	Sentience: The Sword of Azor'alq is a sentient neutral good weapon with an Intelligence of 17, a Wisdom of 10, and a Charisma of 16. It has hearing and Darkvision out of a range of 120 feet. The weapon can speak, read, and understand Common and Elvish, and can communicate with its wielder telepathically. Its voice is proud and noble. While you are attuned to it, the weapon also understands every language you know.

	Personality: The Sword of Azor'alq is very proud and does not wish to serve anyone who is not an important baron or king. It also expect its owner to provide it with a new scabbard, with gems fixed to it. In general, the sword thinks it is in charge of any owner. The sword especially hates Fiends and Aberrations and actively seeks out to destroy them.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, longsword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 41 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Talisman of Zagy [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>longsword, cursed, legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <text>This magic item is an oddly-shaped bit of extrusive rock, shaped and roughly polished.
	When you attune to this magic item, roll a d20. On a 10 or lower, this magic item gives you a Curse. As long as you have that Curse, your Speed is halved and you have Disadvantage on any Strength Test.
	The Curse can be removed by a greater restoration spell or greater magic. On a 11 or higher, this magic item grants you the ability to cast the wish spell as a Magic Action.
	Once you cast the spell, the talisman disappears.

Proficiency: martial, longsword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 41 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>The Edge [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>bastard sword, legendary (requires attunement by a fighter)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>The Edge is one of the Five Blades of Corusk. This magic weapon is a bastard sword whose blade is made of graysh steel. The hilt of the sword is covered in soft suede leather. Jutting from the pommel, three blackened daggers point outward like venomous fango.
	You gain a +3 bonus to your attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.
	As a Magic Action, you can order the three blackened daggers to fly and hit a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you. You can direct the daggers to one or more targets. For each time that is hit by a dagger, the target must make on a DC 19 Constitution saving throw, taking 4d10 Poison damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, bastard sword
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 41 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +3</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Weeping Hexagram [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement by a clericsorcerer this magic item is a black iron ring inlaid with a</detail>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <text>bowed hexagram. It seeps blood when exposed to sunlight. It was created by clerics of Tharizdun. While you wear this magic ring, you can spend one or more charges to cast one of the following spells (Spell Save DC 19):

	• animate dead (1 charge)
	• darkness (1 charge)
	• Evard's black tentacles (2 charges)
	• creation (3 charges)
	• gate (5 charges)

When you spend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the ring disappears.

	Recharge. The ring has 6 charges and recharges 1d6+1 spent charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 42 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d6+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>White Armor of the Griff Mountains [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>scale mail, legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>MA</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>45</weight>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <stealth>YES</stealth>
    <text>This scale armor is cut from the hide of adult or ancient white dragons and crafted into armor by master armorers. While you wear this magic scale armor, you gain the following effects:

	• You gain a +3 bonus to your AC.
	• You gain resistance to cold damage.

The wearer has disadvantage on Stealth (Dexterity) checks.

Proficiency: medium armor
Source:	Treasures from Oerth p. 42 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 219</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
  </item>
</compendium>
