<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <feat>
    <name>Atmokinesis (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Lightning Jolt. Once per turn when you cast a spell or hit with an attack roll and deal Bludgeoning, Piercing, Slashing, or Psychic damage, you can change the damage type to Lightning damage.

Psionic Talent. You know the Shocking Grasp cantrip. You also always have the Fog Cloud spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast these spells, they require no Verbal or Material components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for them (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Gust of Wind spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Biokinesis (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Bend Life Energy. When a spell you cast restores Hit Points to a creature, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the total Hit Points restored. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Psionic Talent. You know the Spare the Dying cantrip. You also always have the Healing Word spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast these spells, they require no Verbal or Material components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for them (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Arcane Vigor spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Clairsentience (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Minor Foreknowledge. When you take the Search action, you can give yourself Advantage on any ability check made as part of that action. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Psionic Talent. You know the Guidance cantrip. You also always have the Detect Evil and Good spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast these spells, they require no Verbal or Material components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the See Invisibility spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Cryokinesis (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ice Manipulation. Once per turn when you cast a spell or hit with an attack roll and deal Bludgeoning, Piercing, Slashing, or Psychic damage, you can change the damage type to Cold damage.

Psionic Talent. You know the Ray of Frost cantrip. You also always have the Armor of Agathys and Ice Knife spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have.
	When you cast these spells, they require no Verbal or Material components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for them (choose when you select this feat).

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Empath (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Emotional Sense. When you take the Influence action, you can give yourself Advantage on any ability check made as part of that action. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Psionic Talent. You always have the Charm Person spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast the spell, it requires no Verba components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spell casting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Calm Emotions spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Flesh Morpher (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Flexible Flesh. When you make a Dexterity (Acrobatics or Sleight of Hand) check, you gain a bonus equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1). You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Psionic Talent. You always have the Longstrider spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast the spell, it requires no Verbal components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Alter Self spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mind Whisperer (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Limited Telepathy. As a Magic action, choose one creature you can see within 120 feet of yourself. You form a telepathic connection to that creature. For 1 hour, you and the chosen creature can communicate telepathically with each other while within 120 feet of each other. To understand each other, you each must mentally use a language the other knows.
	Once you use this benefit, you can't do so again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Psionic Talent. You know the Mind Sliver cantrip. You also always have the Dissonant Whispers spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. When you cast these spells, they require no Verbal or Material components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for them (choose when you select this feat).

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Psi Trickster (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Cunning Mind. When you make a Charisma (Deception or Persuasion) check, you gain a bonus equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum bonus of +1). You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Psionic Talent. You know the Minor Illusion cantrip. You also always have the Disguise Self spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. When you cast these spells, they require no Verbal or Material components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for them (choose when you select this feat).

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Psikineticist (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Psi Boost. When you take the Dash action, you can increase your Speed by 10 feet until the start of your next turn. You can do this a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Psionic Talent. You know the Telekinetic Fling cantrip (included in this UA). You also always have the Thunderwave spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. When you cast these spells, they require no Verbal components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for them (choose when you select this feat).

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Pyrokinesis (UA)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wild Talent Feat; Can't Have Another Wild Talent Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Firestarter. Once per turn when you cast a spell or hit with an attack roll and deal Bludgeoning, Piercing, Slashing, or Psychic damage, you can change the damage type to Fire damage.

Psionic Talent. You know the Produce Flame cantrip. You also always have the Burning Hands spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast these spells, they require no Verbal or Material components, and Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for them (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Scorching Ray spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 13</text>
  </feat>
</compendium>
