<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Aberrant Heir [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>History, Intimidation</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Your aberrant dragonmark has made life challenging since it manifested. You might have hidden it successfully for most of your life or managed to avoid notice. Alternatively, you might have encountered suspicion and fear, perhaps coupled with the outright antagonism of one or more dragonmarked houses. You might have formed an association with the House Tarkanan criminal organization (named for one of the most notorious leaders of the aberrant dragonmarked in the War of the Mark twenty-five centuries ago). Or you might struggle to find your own way in the world, relying on your wits and the power of your mark.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Constitution, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Aberrant Dragonmark</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. You bear an aberrant dragonmark. These rare marks appear on members of all species. Aberrant dragonmarks disturb the houses—you would be wise to avoid their attention.

You gain the following benefits.

Aberrant Fortitude. When you fail a Constitution saving throw, you can take a Reaction to roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the save, potentially turning the failure into a success. Once you've used this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Aberrant Magic. You know one cantrip of your choice from the Sorcerer spell list. Also, choose a level 1 spell from that spell list. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Short or Long Rest. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have. Constitution is your spellcasting ability for this spell.

Aberrant Surge. When you cast the level 1 spell from this feat, you can expend one of your Hit Point Dice and roll it. If you roll an even number, you gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to the number rolled. If you roll an odd number, one creature within 30 feet of you (not including you) takes Force damage equal to the number rolled. If no other creatures are in range, you take the damage.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
      <roll description="Flaw">1d8</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Disguise Kit</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Disguise Kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Dagger, Disguise Kit, Costume, Traveler's Clothes, 16 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Archaeologist [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>History, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You've made a lifelong study of the lost and fallen cultures of the past, visiting their ruins, deciphering their written records, and examining their surviving masterworks. Perhaps you studied at Morgrave University or a similar institution, supplementing your time in the library with fieldwork amid ancient ruins in remote locations. Some archaeologists plunder the treasures of the past in search of wealth or fame, but most consider it their calling to learn from the past. In any case, the archaeologists of Eberron combine the qualities of learned historians with the grit of treasure hunters.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Skilled</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in any combination of three skills or tools of your choice.

Repeatable. You can take this feat more than once.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Cartographer's Tools</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in Cartographer's Tools.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Cartographer's Tools, Bullseye Lantern, Map, Map or Scroll Case, Shovel, Tent, Traveler's Clothes, 17 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Agent [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Investigation, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are connected to one of the dragonmarked houses, but you haven't (yet) manifested a dragonmark. You might be a member of the family by birth or an employee of the house with no familial connection. You've earned your living by doing the business of the house, serving as the hands, feet, and eyes of house leadership in the world. You might have many old friends, mentors, and rivals in the house you serve, plus allies or enemies in other houses.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Intelligence, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Lucky</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Luck Points. You have a number of Luck Points equal to your Proficiency Bonus and can spend the points on the benefits below. You regain your expended Luck Points when you finish a Long Rest.

Advantage. When you roll a d20 for a D20 Test, you can spend 1 Luck Point to give yourself Advantage on the roll.

Disadvantage. When a creature rolls a d20 for an attack roll against you, you can spend 1 Luck Point to impose Disadvantage on that roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Artisan's Tools</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in your choice of Artisan's Tools.

At character creation, you may replace your Artisan's Tools proficiency with a tool proficiency related to your house.

House Tool Proficiencies:
Your House | Alternative Tool Proficiency
Deneith | Gaming Set
Ghallanda | Cook's Utensils
Jorasco | Herbalism Kit
Kundarak | Thieves' Tools
Lyrandar | Navigator's Tools
Medani | Disguise Kit
Orien | Cartographer's Tools
Phiarlan | Disguise Kit
Sivis | Calligrapher's Supplies
Tharashk | Gaming Set
Thuranni | Musical Instrument
Vadalis | Herbalism Kit</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Artisan's Tools (same as above), Fine Clothes, 20 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Cannith Heir (Human) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Investigation, Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>As a scion of House Cannith, you carry a proud legacy. Cannith creates wonders of the modern world, and you're expected to contribute to the ongoing success of the house through invention, scholarship, business, or diplomacy. The only thing that can stand in your way is the deep rift within your own house. The sooner the three barons sort out which of them is the true head of the house (and you, no doubt, have your preference), the sooner House Cannith can claim its rightful position of leadership among all the dragonmarked houses.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Dexterity, Intelligence</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Making</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Artisan's Intuition. When you make an Intelligence (Arcana) check or an ability check using Artisan's Tools, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Spellsmith. You know the Mending cantrip. You also always have the Magic Weapon spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Making Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Making Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Identify, Tenser's Floating Disk
2 | Continual Flame, Spiritual Weapon
3 | Conjure Barrage, Elemental Weapon
4 | Fabricate, Stone Shape
5 | Creation</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Artisan's Tools</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in your choice of Artisan's Tools.

Artisan's tools:
Tools | Cost | Weight
Alchemist's supplies | 50 gp | 8 lb.
Brewer's supplies | 20 gp | 9 lb.
Calligrapher's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Carpenter's tools | 8 gp | 6 lb.
Cartographer's tools | 15 gp | 6 lb.
Cobbler's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Cook's utensils | 1 gp | 8 lb.
Glassblower's tools | 30 gp | 5 lb.
Jeweler's tools | 25 gp | 2 lb.
Leatherworker's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Mason's tools | 10 gp | 8 lb.
Painter's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Potter's tools | 10 gp | 3 lb.
Smith's tools | 20 gp | 8 lb.
Tinker's tools | 50 gp | 10 lb.
Weaver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.
Woodcarver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Artisan's Tools (same as above), Crowbar, Fine Clothes, 2 Pouches, 17 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Deneith Heir (Human) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>As an heir of House Deneith, you've been trained for combat — not to seek it out, but not to shy from it either. You've learned the importance of duty, honor, and the laws used to govern society when duty and honor fail. As you established your name in the house, you might have worked as a bodyguard for some minor dignitary, as a mercenary, or as a marshal hunting fugitives. Now you're prepared to claim your rightful standing in the mightiest of the dragonmarked houses.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Constitution, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Sentinel</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Sentinel's Intuition. When you make a Wisdom (Insight or Perception) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Guardian's Shield. You always have the Shield spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

Vigilant Guardian. When a creature you can see within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to swap places with that creature, and you are hit by the attack instead. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus and regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Sentinel Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Sentinel Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Compelled Duel, Shield of Faith
2 | Warding Bond, Zone of Truth
3 | Counterspell, Protection from Energy
4 | Death Ward, Guardian of Faith
5 | Bigby's Hand

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Gaming Set</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in your choice of Gaming Set.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Spear, Shortbow, 20 Arrows, Gaming Set (same as above), Fine Clothes, Healer's Kit, Quiver, 1 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Ghallanda Heir (Halfling) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Thanks to your connections to House Ghallanda, you grew up accustomed to creature comforts, lively conversation, good drink, and delicious food. You might be a charming and witty scion of the house who loves nothing more than a pleasant evening beside a warm hearth. Or you could be a schemer who exploits bonds of trust and friendship to bend others to your will. You might pursue an adventuring career to master the cuisines of other cultures and ages, expand your network of useful contacts, or earn enough money to open your own inn.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Hospitality</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Ever Hospitable. When you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check or an ability check using Brewer's Supplies or Cook's Utensils, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Innkeeper's Magic. You always have the Purify Food and Drink and Unseen Servant spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Calm Emotions spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Hospitality Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Hospitality Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Goodberry, Sleep
2 | Aid, Enhance Ability
3 | Create Food and Water, Leomund's Tiny Hut
4 | Aura of Purity, Mordenkainen's Private Sanctum
5 | Hallow

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Cook's Utensils</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in Cook's Utensils.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Cook's Utensils, Fine Clothes, Iron Pot, Lamp, Oil (5 flasks), Perfume, 26 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Jorasco Heir (Halfling) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Medicine, Stealth</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>House Jorasco teaches that illness and injury stalk the living like ghosts, robbing people of health and longevity. You've been taught ways to combat these scourges, both magically and medically. You're trained to use those skills in the service of others—and to ascertain that you are always appropriately compensated for this service, ensuring the health and longevity of House Jorasco. You might be a kindly healer with no stomach for combat or a dispassionate specialist who knows exactly how to incapacitate or kill an enemy with precise strikes.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Constitution, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Healing</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.

Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.
	
Medical Intuition: When you make a Wisdom (Medicine) check or an ability check using a Herbalism Kit, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Healing Touch: You always have the Cure Wounds spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.
	• Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).
	• When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Lesser Restoration spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark: If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Healing Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Healing Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | False Life, Healing Word
2 | Arcane Vigor, Prayer of Healing
3 | Aura of Vitality, Mass Healing Word
4 | Aura of Life, Aura of Purity
5 | Greater Restoration

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Herbalism Kit</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Herbalism Kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Herbalism Kit, Fine Clothes, Healer's Kit, 25 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Kundarak Heir (Dwarf) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana, Investigation</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>As an heir of House Kundarak, you take great pride in your family and its work of safeguarding the valuables of Khorvaire. Your house has always been a leader among the clans of the Mror Holds. Though it has never held the crown, it has a reputation for professionalism, honor, and order. You might strive to uphold that reputation, you might place your own sense of honor over your family's, or you could rebel against the house's expectations and flout the demands of honor.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Constitution, Intelligence</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Warding</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Warder's Intuition. When you make an Intelligence (Investigation) check or an ability check using Thieves' Tools, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Wards and Seals. You always have the Alarm and Mage Armor spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Arcane Lock spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Warding Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Warding Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Armor of Agathys, Sanctuary
2 | Knock, Nystul's Magic Aura
3 | Glyph of Warding, Magic Circle
4 | Leomund's Secret Chest, Mordenkainen's Faithful Hound
5 | Antilife Shell

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Thieves' Tools</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in Thieves' Tools.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Thieves' Tools, Fine Clothes, 10 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Lyrandar Heir (Khoravar) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics, Nature</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>As an heir of House Lyrandar, the wind is your ally, the sea and sky your dominion. Despite the devastation of the Last War, your house is on the ascendancy, buoyed by its mastery of the new airship technology. You might have spent your early career on the sea as a sailor or navigator; as a shipwright; or as a member of the Raincallers' Guild, manipulating the weather and assisting with irrigation and similar public works. Or you might have been among the first in your house to take to the skies as part of an airship crew. Service to the house might call you to hunt pirates in the Lhazaar Sea, to explore ancient ruins in search of magical technology to bind elemental forces, or to salvage a wrecked airship in the Mournland.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Dexterity, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Storm</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Windwright's Intuition. When you make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check or an ability check using Navigator's Tools, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Storm's Boon. You have Resistance to Lightning damage.

Storm Magic. You know the Thunderclap cantrip. When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Gust of Wind spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Storm Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Storm Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Feather Fall, Fog Cloud
2 | Levitate, Shatter
3 | Sleet Storm, Wind Wall
4 | Conjure Minor Elemental, Control Water
5 | Conjure Elemental

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Navigator's Tools</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in Navigator's Tools.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Navigator's Tools, Fine Clothes, 10 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Medani Heir (Human) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Investigation</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>As a member of House Medani, your life revolves around subterfuge—not engaging in it, but preventing others from doing so. You see the world around you as an intricate web of schemes, plots, and counterplots. Assessing the range of possibilities, you use instinct to predict threats to your clients and defend against them well before those threats can turn into danger. Defending against an assassin's blade is a job any Deneith sellsword or Tharashk enforcer can do—making sure no one ever draws that blade is the Medani way.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Detection</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Deductive Intuition. When you make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Insight) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Magical Detection. You always have the Detect Magic and Detect Poison and Disease spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

When you reach character level 3, you also always have the See Invisibility spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Detection Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Detection Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Detect Evil and Good, Identify
2 | Detect Thoughts, Find Traps
3 | Clairvoyance, Nondetection
4 | Arcane Eye, Divination
5 | Legend Lore

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Disguise Kit</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Disguise Kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Disguise Kit, Fine Clothes, 10 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Orien Heir (Human) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics, Athletics</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Before the Last War, Orien's influence covered Khorvaire, and its trade roads and lightning rails were the lifeblood of a vibrant kingdom. But the war cut those arteries, leaving Galifar dead and House Orien bloodied. While the house's couriers and shippers still keep goods moving on both sides of the continent, finding a way to reestablish routes across the Mournland remains the house's top priority. In the meantime, Orien adventurers can serve their house by investigating missing couriers, recovering goods stolen from caravans, and troubleshooting disruptions to the lightning rail.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Constitution, Intelligence</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Passage</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Courier's Speed. Your Speed increases by 5 feet.

Intuitive Motion. When you make a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Magical Passage. You always have the Misty Step spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Passage Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Passage Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Expeditious Retreat, Jump
2 | Find Steed, Pass without Trace
3 | Blink, Phantom Steed
4 | Dimension Door, Freedom of Movement
5 | Teleportation Circle

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Cartographer's Tools</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in Cartographer's Tools.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Cartographer's Tools, Fine Clothes, Map, Map or Scroll Case, 18 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Phiarlan Heir (Elf) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Deception, Stealth</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Though you have seen wealth, fame, and beauty as a child of House Phiarlan, you consider knowledge (and the power it brings) the greatest treasure of all. You might pursue that power as an artist or performer, always alert for secrets even as you regale the world with story, song, acrobatics, or art. Or you might foster ties to the secretive espionage arm of your house: the Serpentine Table.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Shadow</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Cunning Intuition. When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) or Charisma (Performance) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Shape Shadows. You know the Minor Illusion cantrip. You also always have the Invisibility spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Shadow Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Shadow Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Disguise Self, Silent Image
2 | Darkness, Pass without Trace
3 | Clairvoyance, Major Image
4 | Greater Invisibility, Hallucinatory Terrain
5 | Mislead

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Disguise Kit</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Disguise Kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Disguise Kit, Fine Clothes, 10 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Sivis Heir (Gnome) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>History, Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>For nearly thirty centuries, your family has worked to maintain order. Communication is the cord that binds civilization together, and your ancestors settled the disputes of sovereigns and helped the dragonmarked houses find a place in the world. Few people realize the influence House Sivis has had on the shape of the modern age — just as few know how often a royal adviser holds more power than the actual ruler. While the other dragonmarked houses fight for fame and recognition, House Sivis plays a long game of subtle influence behind the scenes, keeping order amid the chaos of unending intrigue.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Intelligence, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Scribing</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Gifted Scribe. When you make an Intelligence (History) check or an ability check using Calligrapher's Supplies, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Scribe's Insight. You know the Message cantrip. You also always have the Comprehend Languages spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Magic Mouth spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Scribing Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Scribing Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Command, Illusory Script
2 | Animal Messenger, Silence
3 | Sending, Tongues
4 | Arcane Eye, Confusion
5 | Dream

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Calligrapher's Supplies</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in Calligrapher's Supplies.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Calligrapher's Supplies, Fine Clothes, Ink, 5 Ink Pens, Paper (30 sheets), Parchment (9 sheets), 8 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Tharashk Heir (Orc) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Perception, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Heirs of other houses lead lives of luxury, but in House Tharashk you learned self-reliance from an early age. What your young house lacks in resources, it makes up for in spirit and determination. Tharashk has a destiny to fulfill, and you have a part in it. Whether in combat or in social interaction, you have learned to play the role of the hunter: study your enemies, exploit their weaknesses, and do whatever it takes to achieve victory.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Constitution, Intelligence, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Finding</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Hunter's Intuition. When you make a Wisdom (Perception or Survival) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Finder's Magic. You always have the Hunter's Mark spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Locate Object spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Finding Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Finding Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Faerie Fire, Longstrider
2 | Locate Animals or Plants, Mind Spike
3 | Clairvoyance, Speak with Plants
4 | Divination, Locate Creature
5 | Commune with Nature

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Gaming Set</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in your choice of Gaming Set.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Gaming Set (same as above), Climber's Kit, Fine Clothes, Hunting Trap, Manacles, 2 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Thuranni Heir (Elf) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Performance, Stealth</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Given House Thuranni's short history and focus on espionage, its leaders expect you to further the interests of the house at every opportunity. During the house's formative years as an independent entity, every move you make has been watched closely. This isn't to say that every Thuranni heir must actively spy at the behest of house elders. But even the house's most insular artists and artisans must keep up with current political events and pass on or collect information when asked.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Intelligence, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Shadow</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Cunning Intuition. When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) or Charisma (Performance) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Shape Shadows. You know the Minor Illusion cantrip. You also always have the Invisibility spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Shadow Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Shadow Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Disguise Self, Silent Image
2 | Darkness, Pass without Trace
3 | Clairvoyance, Major Image
4 | Greater Invisibility, Hallucinatory Terrain
5 | Mislead

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
      <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Musical Instrument</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in your choice of Musical Instrument.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Musical Instrument (same as above), Costume, Fine Clothes, 13 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>House Vadalis Heir (Human) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Animal Handling, Nature</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You have grown up with respect for both family and nature. You understand the culture of the Five Nations, but you don't get drawn into the games of ambition and status that others play. You know the beauty and power inherent in life, the mysteries of birth and death, and the miracles that happen in between. Your insights into the natural world allow you to see through the lies and deception of city folk — and never let on how much of their subterfuge you recognize.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Constitution, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Mark of Handling</name>
      <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.
	Dragonmarks typically appear for the first time in situations of stress or peril where the power of the mark could prove useful, heirs of the dragonmarked houses undergo a rite of passage called the Test of Siberys in adolescence. Each house's test is different, but they all involve some danger designed to evoke the power of the house's mark. Usually, a dragonmark appears during the test, if it ever manifests at all, but heirs sometimes manifest their marks years after failing the Test of Siberys.

You gain the following benefits.

Wild Intuition. When you make an Intelligence (Nature) or Wisdom (Animal Handling) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Primal Connection. You always have the Animal Friendship and Speak with Animals spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Monstrous Connections. When you reach character level 3, you can target a Monstrosity when you cast Animal Friendship or Speak with Animals if the creature's Intelligence score is 3 or lower.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Handling Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Handling Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Command, Find Familiar
2 | Beast Sense, Calm Emotions
3 | Beacon of Hope, Conjure Animals
4 | Aura of Life, Dominate Beast
5 | Awaken

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Herbalism Kit</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Herbalism Kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Herbalism Kit, Fine Clothes, Net, 29 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Inquisitive [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Investigation</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You have honed your talents of investigation and deduction—fueled by a boundless curiosity—to explore mysteries, find missing people, recover stolen goods, unearth corruption and conspiracies, and solve crimes. As an inquisitive, you might have pursued freelance work, signed on with an inquisitive agency (perhaps one licensed by a dragonmarked house such as Medani or Tharashk), reported for a broadsheet, or worked for a police force.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Constitution, Intelligence, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Alert</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Initiative Proficiency. When you roll Initiative, you can add your Proficiency Bonus to the roll.

Initiative Swap. Immediately after you roll Initiative, you can swap your Initiative with the Initiative of one willing ally in the same combat. You can't make this swap if you or the ally has the Incapacitated condition.</text>
      <modifier category="bonus">initiative+prof</modifier>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Thieves' Tools</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in Thieves' Tools.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B:
	• (A) Thieves' Tools, Bullseye Lantern, Crowbar, Oil (10 flasks), Traveler's Clothes, 10 GP
	• (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
