<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <monster>
    <name>Eldritch Cannon [2024]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>object</type>
    <ac>18</ac>
    <hp>5</hp>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>Poison, Psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small or Tiny</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5 × your Artificer level (casting Mending on the cannon restores 2d6 Hit Points to it)</text>
      <attack>Heal||2d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Activate Cannon (Requires You to be within 60 Feet of the Cannon)</name>
      <text>As a Bonus Action, you order the cannon to use the Flamethrower, Force Ballista, or Protector option below; you can direct the cannon to move up to 15 feet before or after that option.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Flamethrower</name>
      <text>The cannon blasts fire in a 15-foot Cone. Each creature in that area makes a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 2d8 Fire damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. Flammable objects in the Cone that aren't being worn or carried start burning.</text>
      <attack>Fire||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Force Ballista</name>
      <text>Make a ranged spell attack originating from the cannon at one creature or object within 120 feet of it. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 Force damage, and if the target is a creature, it is pushed up to 5 feet away from the cannon.</text>
      <attack>Force||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Protector</name>
      <text>The cannon emits a burst of positive energy that grants itself and each creature of your choice within 10 feet of the cannon a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d8 plus your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).</text>
      <attack>Temporary Hit Points||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Homunculus Servant [2024]</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <type>construct</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>10</hp>
    <speed>20 ft., Fly 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>4</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Telepathy 1 mile (works only with you)</languages>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>Poison</immune>
    <conditionImmune>Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5 + 5 per spell level. (the homunculus has a number of Hit Dice [d4s] equal to the spell's level)</text>
      <attack>Hit Dice||2d4</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Evasion</name>
      <text>If the homunculus is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, the homunculus instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the save and only half damage if it fails. It can't use this trait if it has the Incapacitated condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Bond</name>
      <text>Add the spell's level to any ability check or saving throw the homunculus makes.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Force Strike</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: Bonus equals your spell attack modifier, reach 5 ft. or range 30 ft. Hit: 1d6 plus the spell's level of Force damage.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage|+5|1d6</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Channel Magic</name>
      <text>Trigger: You cast a spell that has a range of touch while the homunculus is within 120 feet of you.
Response: The homunculus delivers the spell through its touch.</text>
    </reaction>
    <description>Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Steel Defender [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>construct</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>12</ac>
    <hp>10</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>4</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Understands the languages you know</languages>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>Poison</immune>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>PB equals your Proficiency Bonus</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Class</name>
      <text>12 + your Intelligence modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5 + five times your Artificer level (the defender has a number of Hit Dice [d8s] equal to your Artificer level).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Steel Bond</name>
      <text>Add your Proficiency Bonus to any ability check or saving throw the defender makes.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Force-Empowered Rend</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: Bonus equals your spell attack modifier, reach 5 ft. Hit: 1d8 + 2 + your Intelligence modifier Force damage.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage|+5|1d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Repair (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The defender, or one Construct or object it can see within 5 feet of it, regains a number of Hit Points equal to 2d8 + your Intelligence modifier.</text>
      <attack>Repair||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Deflect Attack</name>
      <text>Trigger: A creature the defender can see within 5 feet of it makes an attack roll against a creature other than the defender.
Response: The triggering creature makes the attack roll with Disadvantage.</text>
    </reaction>
    <description>Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Boromar Smuggler [2024]</name>
    <sortname>Boromar, Smuggler</sortname>
    <ancestry>Boromar</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>humanoid (halfling)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>13</ac>
    <hp>27 (6d6+6)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <init>+4</init>
    <str>11</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>11</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <skill>Perception +2, Sleight of Hand +6, Stealth +6</skill>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages>Common, Halfling, Thieves' Cant</languages>
    <cr>1/2</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Leather Armor, Pistol, Shortsword</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hustle</name>
      <text>The smuggler can move through the space of any creature that is of a larger size, but it can't stop there.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Shortsword</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +4, reach 5 ft. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) Piercing damage plus 2 (1d4) Poison damage.</text>
      <attack>Shortsword|+4|(1d6+2)+(1d4)</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+4|1d6+2</attack>
      <attack>Poison Damage||1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Pistol</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +4, range 30/90 ft. Hit: 7 (1d10 + 2) Piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+4|1d10+2</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Boromar Underboss [2024]</name>
    <sortname>Boromar, Underboss</sortname>
    <ancestry>Boromar</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>humanoid (halfling)</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (studded leather)</ac>
    <hp>104 (19d6+38)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+7</init>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>18</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>17</cha>
    <save>Dex +7, Con +5, Wis +5</save>
    <skill>Insight +5, Perception +8, Sleight of Hand +10</skill>
    <passive>18</passive>
    <languages>Common, Halfling, Thieves' Cant</languages>
    <cr>8</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>Poison</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Studded Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hustle</name>
      <text>The underboss can move through the space of any creature that is of a larger size, but it can't stop there.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The underboss makes three attacks, using Poisoned Blade or Arcane Firearm in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Poisoned Blade</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (2d8+4) Slashing damage plus 7 (2d6) Poison damage, and the target has the Poisoned condition until the start of the underboss's next turn. If the target is already Poisoned, it instead takes an extra 7 (2d6) Poison damage.</text>
      <attack>Poisoned Blade|+7|(2d8+4)+2d6</attack>
      <attack>Poisoned Blade (Already Poisoned)|+7|(2d8+4)+4d6</attack>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+7|2d8+4</attack>
      <attack>Poison Damage||2d6</attack>
      <attack>Extra Poison Damage||4d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Arcane Firearm</name>
      <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 30/90 ft., one target. Hit: 26 (4d10+4) Force damage.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage|+7|4d10+4</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
      <text>Trigger: The underboss is hit by an attack roll.
Response: The underboss halves the damage (round down) it takes from that attack.</text>
    </reaction>
    <description>The Boromar Clan

The Boromar Clan is the most powerful criminal organization in Sharn, with a reach that includes the city council, the Sharn Watch, House Jorasco, the elite social circles of Skyway, the shipping trade, and a wide array of illegal activity to boot — particularly extortion, gambling, smuggling, and thievery. The clan began as a family of halfling immigrants from the Talenta Plains, and its headquarters and key holdings lie in the Little Plains district of Middle Menthis, where many such migrants dwell.

Goals of the Boromar Clan.

For generations, the goals of the Boromar Clan have been simple: to maintain an iron grip on shady and illegal activities in Sharn. The Boromars extend their influence into places of power and bribe offi­cials of the Sharn Watch, all to maximize profits and power. Short-term goals come and go in service of these overarching objectives — blackmailing a councilor here, purchasing a shipping company there. But with the rise of Daask, the Boromars have the new and urgent goal of eliminating their upstart rival once and for all.

The fierce enmity between the Boromar Clan and Daask creates interesting options for inquisitive characters who stand (at least nominally) on the side of the law against both criminal organizations. Will they accept help from the Boromars against the much more obviously dangerous Daask? Or might they disregard Daask operations clearly meant to undermine the Boromars? The inquisitives might even «nd a way to ensure the conflict between the two criminal groups weakens them both, making Sharn safer in the process.

A Boromar Clan Arc.

The conflict between inquisitives and The Boromar Clan might follow this broad outline.
	• Levels 1–4. The characters investigate petty crimes — pickpocketing, burglary, blackmail, and such — and help bring several Boromar Clan members to justice. The inquisitives find the Sharn Watch unhelpful in dealing with these criminals, though, and some legitimate businesses and law-abiding citizens start shunning or insulting the characters, angry at their interference with the "hometown heroes" of the Boromar Clan.
	• Levels 5–10. Ostensibly trying to mend the poor relationship between the Sharn Watch and the inquisitives, a Watch o­fficer recruits the characters to bring a Daask gang to justice. The Watch helps, and the characters catch several Daask criminals. However, the characters' Watch allies don't seem concerned about whether any Daask members are hurt or killed in the final confrontation. Indeed, it turns out that the Boromar Clan arranged the operation to remove a dangerous group of rivals.
	• Levels 11–16. Boromar leaders try to recruit the characters to their side, offering exorbitant fees and extravagant gifts as payment for simple jobs. If bribery doesn't work, the gang tries to coerce the characters into helping them, using friends, family members, or contacts as leverage. Along the way, the characters learn that a trusted NPC ally is firmly in the pocket of the Boromar Clan.
	• Levels 17–20. Assuming the characters haven't joined the Boromars, the clan leadership tries to eliminate them. The Boromars can't muster a physical threat to challenge characters of this level, so they wield their political power instead. Under pressure from Boromar leaders, the city council declares the adventurers a threat to Sharn's safety and security. O­fficials revoke their inquisitive agency's operations permit and ask the characters to leave Sharn.

Boromar Operatives.

The Boromar Clan began as a single family of halflings. Though its influence has expanded widely, its key operatives are still family members. Boromar operatives prefer deception and bribery over outright violence, though they defend their interests when necessary. Besides those described here, other Boromar operatives include bandits, commoners, spies, toughs, and warriors.

Boromar Underboss.
Underbosses supervise larger clan operations, such as gambling halls and warehouses of smuggled goods awaiting transport. Accustomed to the criminal lifestyle,
these hardy individuals (mostly halflings) dismiss and dispose of threats with calculated ease.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Daask Bruiser [2024]</name>
    <sortname>Daask, Bruiser</sortname>
    <ancestry>Daask</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (gnoll)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>17</ac>
    <hp>150 (20d8+60)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+5</init>
    <str>20</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <save>Str +9, Con +7, Wis +5</save>
    <skill>Athletics +9, Intimidation +6, Perception +5</skill>
    <passive>15</passive>
    <languages>Common, Gnoll</languages>
    <cr>9</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Blood Frenzy</name>
      <text>The bruiser has Advantage on attack rolls against any creature that doesn't have all its Hit Points.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The bruiser makes three Pummel attacks and uses Glare.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Pummel</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d6+5) Bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+9|2d6+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Glare</name>
      <text>Wisdom Saving Throw: DC 14, one creature the bruiser can see within 30 feet.
Failure: The target has the Frightened condition until the start of the bruiser's next turn.</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Smackback</name>
      <text>Trigger: The bruiser takes damage from a creature within 5 feet.
Response: The bruiser makes one Pummel attack, targeting the triggering creature.</text>
    </reaction>
    <description>Daask:
Daask is a violent gang of muggers, extortionists, looters, cultists, and drug dealers supported by such monsters as harpies, medusas, minotaurs, ogres, and trolls. It seems like a simple criminal gang engaged in a battle for territory and power against the Boromar Clan and the forces of law and order — but the truth is more complicated. In fact, the members of Daask take their orders from Sora Katra, one of the three hags (the Daughters of Sora Kell) who rule the nation of Droaam. Daask's operations in Sharn are only a small part of a much larger scheme.

Goals of Daask:
The goals of Daask, like those of the Daughters of Sora Kell, are shrouded in mystery. As described in Eberron: Rising from the Last War, the reason for Daask's existence depends on the path you choose for the Daughters of Sora Kell — whether they seek peace and stability for their young nation of mistrusted monsters, desire to end humanity's dominance over Khorvaire and let monsters rule, or merely follow the visions of Sora Teraza wherever they lead. Regardless of Daask's larger purpose, however, one immediate goal remains: to eliminate the Boromar Clan, or at least break its hold on Sharn's criminal underworld. Its methods range from street violence — mugging, armed robbery, and even pillaging — to extortion and trade in drugs.

A Daask Arc:
The conflict between inquisitives and Daask might follow this broad outline.
	• Levels 1–4. The characters investigate crimes perpetrated by Daask against businesses they eventually discover are a­ffiliated with the Boromar Clan. The Sharn Watch might hire the characters to help bring a Daask gang to justice, but the inquisitives eventually learn that the Boromar Clan seeks to use the Watch and the characters to strike back at Daask.
	• Levels 5–10. What seems like a routine case of a wealthy noble disappearing into a drug den while looking for thrills leads the characters to dig into Daask's trade in dragon's blood, a mysterious and dangerous new drug. The investigation drives the characters into conflict with increasingly powerful monsters affi­liated with the gang.
	• Levels 11–16. Daask operatives kidnap a prominent figure in Sharn, but the freed "victim" turns out to be a doppelganger. The characters are hired to retrieve the real victim, who is undergoing a ritual that will eventually transform them into a hag.
	• Levels 17–20. While Daask stirs up riots in the Cogs and Malleon's Gate, the characters discover that the gang has also planted arcane explosives across the city. The characters must find the explosives before Sharn is thrown into utter chaos.

Daask Enforcers:
Daask's agents in Sharn include changelings, goblins, humans, and shifters recruited in the city, as well as monsters that have come to Sharn from Droaam: gnolls, harpies, medusas,
minotaurs, ogres, trolls, and an oni leader named Cavallah. Droaam's gnolls are untainted by the demonic influence of Yeenoghu; many such enforcers use the stat blocks presented here.

Daask Bruiser:
Intimidating and powerful, bruisers lead Daask operations when more violent and decisive shows of force are needed. These enforcers relish the brutality of their work.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Daask Raider [2024]</name>
    <sortname>Daask, Raider</sortname>
    <ancestry>Daask</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (gnoll)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15</ac>
    <hp>33 (6d8+6)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+1</init>
    <str>16</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>13</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>11</wis>
    <cha>8</cha>
    <save>Str +5</save>
    <skill>Athletics +5, Perception +2</skill>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages>Common, Gnoll</languages>
    <cr>1</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pack Tactics</name>
      <text>The raider has Advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the raider's allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally doesn't have the Incapacitated
condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Pummel</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d4+3) Bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+5|1d4+3</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Smackback</name>
      <text>Trigger: The raider takes damage from a creature within 5 feet.
Response: The raider makes one Pummel attack, targeting the triggering creature.</text>
    </reaction>
    <description>Daask

Daask is a violent gang of muggers, extortionists, looters, cultists, and drug dealers supported by such monsters as harpies, medusas, minotaurs, ogres, and trolls. It seems like a simple criminal gang engaged in a battle for territory and power against the Boromar Clan and the forces of law and order — but the truth is more complicated. In fact, the members of Daask take their orders from Sora Katra, one of the three hags (the Daughters of Sora Kell) who rule the nation of Droaam. Daask's operations in Sharn are only a small part of a much larger scheme.

Goals of Daask.

The goals of Daask, like those of the Daughters of Sora Kell, are shrouded in mystery. As described in Eberron: Rising from the Last War, the reason for Daask's existence depends on the path you choose for the Daughters of Sora Kell — whether they seek peace and stability for their young nation of mistrusted monsters, desire to end humanity's dominance over Khorvaire and let monsters rule, or merely follow the visions of Sora Teraza wherever they lead. Regardless of Daask's larger purpose, however, one immediate goal remains: to eliminate the Boromar Clan, or at least break its hold on Sharn's criminal underworld. Its methods range from street violence — mugging, armed robbery, and even pillaging — to extortion and trade in drugs.

A Daask Arc.

The conflict between inquisitives and Daask might follow this broad outline.
	• Levels 1–4. The characters investigate crimes perpetrated by Daask against businesses they eventually discover are a­ffiliated with the Boromar Clan. The Sharn Watch might hire the characters to help bring a Daask gang to justice, but the inquisitives eventually learn that the Boromar Clan seeks to use the Watch and the characters to strike back at Daask.
	• Levels 5–10. What seems like a routine case of a wealthy noble disappearing into a drug den while looking for thrills leads the characters to dig into Daask's trade in dragon's blood, a mysterious and dangerous new drug. The investigation drives the characters into conflict with increasingly powerful monsters affi­liated with the gang.
	• Levels 11–16. Daask operatives kidnap a prominent figure in Sharn, but the freed "victim" turns out to be a doppelganger. The characters are hired to retrieve the real victim, who is undergoing a ritual that will eventually transform them into a hag.
	• Levels 17–20. While Daask stirs up riots in the Cogs and Malleon's Gate, the characters discover that the gang has also planted arcane explosives across the city. The characters must find the explosives before Sharn is thrown into utter chaos.

Daask Enforcers.

Daask's agents in Sharn include changelings, goblins, humans, and shifters recruited in the city, as well as monsters that have come to Sharn from Droaam: gnolls, harpies, medusas,
minotaurs, ogres, trolls, and an oni leader named Cavallah. Droaam's gnolls are untainted by the demonic influence of Yeenoghu; many such enforcers use the stat blocks presented here.

Daask Raider.
Raiders use guerrilla tactics to ambush warehouses and beat down opponents. These skilled fistfighters work in tandem to claim goods and territory for Daask.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Dreaming Dark Infiltrator [2024]</name>
    <sortname>Dreaming Dark, Infiltrator</sortname>
    <ancestry>Dreaming Dark</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (chain shirt)</ac>
    <hp>104 (16d8+32)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+3</init>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>17</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>18</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>17</cha>
    <save>Int +7, Wis +6, Cha +6</save>
    <skill>Deception +6, Insight +6, Stealth +6</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, Quori; Telepathy 120 ft</languages>
    <cr>7</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>Psychic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Truesight 30 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Chain Shirt</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The infiltrator makes three Mind Blade attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Mind Blade</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 30 ft., one target. Hit: 14 (3d6+4) Psychic damage.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage|+7|3d6+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The infiltrator casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Intelligence as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 15):

	• 3/Day: Detect Thoughts
	• 1/Day: Synaptic Static</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Mind Curse (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>Wisdom Saving Throw: DC 15, one creature hit by the infiltrator's Mind Blade attack this turn.
Failure: The target takes 14 (4d6) Psychic damage and is cursed. While cursed in this way, it has Disadvantage on attack rolls against the infiltrator, and the infiltrator always knows the targets location while it and the infiltrator are on the same plane of existence. A cursed creature repeats the save whenever it finishes a Short or Long Rest, ending the effect on itself on a success.
Success: Half damage only.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||4d6</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>Detect Thoughts [2024], Synaptic Static [2024]</spells>
    <description>The Dreaming Dark:
The sinister and mysterious Dreaming Dark — a metaphysical force trying to prolong the current age of despair and violence — seeks to extend its reach toward Khorvaire. Over a century ago, the Dream Dark compromised House Deneith's enclave in Upper Tavick's Landing. Although the enclave seems normal to outsiders, and even to many in House Deneith, it is now a stronghold of shadows. Under the tutelage of the Dreaming Dark, the Sharn Deneith have become masters of intrigue and subtlety. They carefully conceal their psionic power from outsiders while using it to gather information from the wealthy citizens they ostensibly guard.
	While the enclave serves the Dreaming Dark, most of its members have no idea they are in league with the Inspired. Over a century of indoctrination, the Inspired dominator Tirashana has taught the Sharn Deneith to see themselves as superior because of their dragonmarks and raised above the other dragonmarked houses by their psionic abilities. Even members of the house who work directly with the Inspired believe that the Inspired consider them equal partners, but in fact the Inspired view them merely as useful pawns. Now quori spirits have possessed fifteen members of the house.
	In addition to the leaders of House Deneith in Sharn, the Dreaming Dark has agents strategically planted throughout the City of Towers. They include one member of the Sharn Council (Bestan ir'Tonn, who also has close ties to the Boromar Clan) and a leader in the Sharn Watch (Warden Maira ir'Talan of the Blackened Book). The Dreaming Dark also commands the allegiance of the Riedran ambassadors in Sharn.

Goals of the Dreaming Dark:
Building from the description in Eberron: Rising from the Last War, the Dream Dark has three objectives in the City of Towers:
	• To cause chaos and strife by undermining what little faith in law enforcement exists in Sharn — turning the forces of law and order against one another, fueling the feuds between criminal organizations, and spreading fear among the populace.
	• To promote their chosen champions, which in Sharn means the subverted and possessed agents of House Deneith.
	• To undermine the kalashtar throughout the city — especially in the Overlook district of Upper Dura and its Path of Light temple.

A Dreaming Dark Arc:
The Dream Dark poses a significant threat, which might not manifest fully until the characters can handle the danger. The conflict could play out according to this outline.
	• Levels 1–4. Early in their adventures, the inquisitives have vivid dreams that reveal key details about cases they're working on — easily interpreted as subconscious insights bringing overlooked information to light. (The discussion of the Dreaming Dark in Eberron: Rising from the Last War includes suggestions for incorporating dreams into your game.)
	• Levels 5–10. Investigating a series of grisly crimes, the characters are aided by a Sentinel Marshal of House Deneith. When captured, the criminal insists that recurring dreams led to the crimes. The Sentinel Marshal dismisses this claim. If the inquisitives investigate further, they find themselves drawn into a nightmare scenario involving a quori. In the course of that adventure, they glean clues that the Sentinel Marshal played a more sinister part in events than previously suspected.
	• Levels 11–16. The characters experience increasingly frequent nightmares, individually and as a group. Meanwhile, the Sentinel Marshals and other members of House Deneith interfere with their investigations.
	• Levels 17–20. The inquisitives uncover the corruption at the heart of the House Deneith enclave in Sharn, which reaches all the way to its lord, Sadran d'Deneith — a human man possessed by a powerful quori spirit. Their investigations lead to confrontations with Deneith leaders in the waking world, but eventually the inquisitives must fight the quori in the dream world of Dal Quor.

Dreaming Dark Agents:
Anyone can be seduced into the service of the Dream Dark, and a normal person possessed by a quori (see the quori stat blocks in Eberron: Rising from the Last War) uses their normal stat block. The two agents presented here are Inspired agents of the Dark who wield terrifying psionic power.

Dreaming Dark Infiltrator:
Dreaming Dark infiltrators are spies sent to gather intelligence. They plant psychic seeds in their minds of their foes that enhance the infiltrators' combat prowess against those enemies.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Dreaming Dark Mindkiller [2024]</name>
    <sortname>Dreaming Dark, Mindkiller</sortname>
    <ancestry>Dreaming Dark</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Evil</alignment>
    <ac>19</ac>
    <hp>180 (24d8+72)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+4</init>
    <str>15</str>
    <dex>19</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>21</int>
    <wis>18</wis>
    <cha>17</cha>
    <save>Dex +8, Int +9, Wis +8, Cha +7</save>
    <skill>Deception +7, Insight +8, Perception +8, Stealth +8</skill>
    <passive>18</passive>
    <languages>Common, Quori; Telepathy 120 ft</languages>
    <cr>11</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>Psychic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Frightened</conditionImmune>
    <senses>Truesight 30 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The mindkiller makes two Nightmare Whisper attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Nightmare Whisper</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +9, reach 5 ft. or range 30 ft. Hit: 27 (5d8+5) Psychic damage, and the target has the Frightened condition until the start of the
mindkiller's next turn. If the target is already Frightened, it instead takes an extra 10 (3d6) Psychic damage.</text>
      <attack>Nightmare Whisper (While Frightened)|+9|(5d8+5)+3d6</attack>
      <attack>Psychic Damage|+9|5d8+5</attack>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||3d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Primal Fear (1/Day)</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>Wisdom Saving Throw: DC 17, each creature in a 30-foot-radius Sphere centered on a point the mindkiller can see within 120 feet. 
Failure: 35 (10d6) Psychic damage, and the target has the Frightened condition until the start of the mindkiller's next turn. While Frightened in this way, the target can do only one of the following on each of its turns: move, take an action, or take a Bonus Action. 
Success: Half damage only.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||10d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Slayer's Puppet (1/Day) (Bonus Action)</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The mindkiller casts Dominate Person, requiring no spell components and using Intelligence as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 17).</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Dominate Person [2024]</spells>
    <description>The Dreaming Dark

The sinister and mysterious Dreaming Dark — a metaphysical force trying to prolong the current age of despair and violence — seeks to extend its reach toward Khorvaire. Over a century ago, the Dream Dark compromised House Deneith's enclave in Upper Tavick's Landing. Although the enclave seems normal to outsiders, and even to many in House Deneith, it is now a stronghold of shadows. Under the tutelage of the Dreaming Dark, the Sharn Deneith have become masters of intrigue and subtlety. They carefully conceal their psionic power from outsiders while using it to gather information from the wealthy citizens they ostensibly guard.

While the enclave serves the Dreaming Dark, most of its members have no idea they are in league with the Inspired. Over a century of indoctrination, the Inspired dominator Tirashana has taught the Sharn Deneith to see themselves as superior because of their dragonmarks and raised above the other dragonmarked houses by their psionic abilities. Even members of the house who work directly with the Inspired believe that the Inspired consider them equal partners, but in fact the Inspired view them merely as useful pawns. Now quori spirits have possessed fifteen members of the house.

In addition to the leaders of House Deneith in Sharn, the Dreaming Dark has agents strategically planted throughout the City of Towers. They include one member of the Sharn Council (Bestan ir'Tonn, who also has close ties to the Boromar Clan) and a leader in the Sharn Watch (Warden Maira ir'Talan of the Blackened Book). The Dreaming Dark also commands the allegiance of the Riedran ambassadors in Sharn.

Goals of the Dreaming Dark.

Building from the description in Eberron: Rising from the Last War, the Dream Dark has three objectives in the City of Towers:
	• To cause chaos and strife by undermining what little faith in law enforcement exists in Sharn — turning the forces of law and order against one another, fueling the feuds between criminal organizations, and spreading fear among the populace.
	• To promote their chosen champions, which in Sharn means the subverted and possessed agents of House Deneith.
	• To undermine the kalashtar throughout the city — especially in the Overlook district of Upper Dura and its Path of Light temple.

A Dreaming Dark Arc.

The Dream Dark poses a significant threat, which might not manifest fully until the characters can handle the danger. The conflict could play out according to this outline.
	• Levels 1–4. Early in their adventures, the inquisitives have vivid dreams that reveal key details about cases they're working on — easily interpreted as subconscious insights bringing overlooked information to light. (The discussion of the Dreaming Dark in Eberron: Rising from the Last War includes suggestions for incorporating dreams into your game.)
	• Levels 5–10. Investigating a series of grisly crimes, the characters are aided by a Sentinel Marshal of House Deneith. When captured, the criminal insists that recurring dreams led to the crimes. The Sentinel Marshal dismisses this claim. If the inquisitives investigate further, they find themselves drawn into a nightmare scenario involving a quori. In the course of that adventure, they glean clues that the Sentinel Marshal played a more sinister part in events than previously suspected.
	• Levels 11–16. The characters experience increasingly frequent nightmares, individually and as a group. Meanwhile, the Sentinel Marshals and other members of House Deneith interfere with their investigations.
	• Levels 17–20. The inquisitives uncover the corruption at the heart of the House Deneith enclave in Sharn, which reaches all the way to its lord, Sadran d'Deneith — a human man possessed by a powerful quori spirit. Their investigations lead to confrontations with Deneith leaders in the waking world, but eventually the inquisitives must fight the quori in the dream world of Dal Quor.

Dreaming Dark Agents.

Anyone can be seduced into the service of the Dream Dark, and a normal person possessed by a quori (see the quori stat blocks in Eberron: Rising from the Last War) uses their normal stat block. The two agents presented here are Inspired agents of the Dark who wield terrifying psionic power.

Dreaming Dark Mindkiller.
Mindkillers are the assassins of the Dreaming Dark, sent to terrify their foes before striking to kill. Mindkillers force foes to attack their own allies, causing physical and emotional devastation to grow the power of the Dreaming Dark.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <!-- House Tarkanen -->
  <monster>
    <name>Tarkanan Marauder [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (breastplate)</ac>
    <hp>247 (26d8+130)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+7</init>
    <str>15</str>
    <dex>17</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>16</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>13</cha>
    <save>Dex +7, Con +9, Wis +6</save>
    <skill>Deception +5, Perception +6, Stealth +7</skill>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>Common, Thieves' Cant</languages>
    <cr>11</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Breastplate, Shortsword</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Evasion</name>
      <text>If the marauder is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, the marauder instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the save and only half as much damage if it fails. It can't use this trait if it has the Incapacitated condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The marauder makes three Aberrant Strike attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Aberrant Strike</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +7, reach 5 ft. Hit: 13 (3d6+3) Piercing damage, plus 21 (6d6) Force damage if the marauder had Advantage on the attack roll.</text>
      <attack>Aberrant Strike|+7|(3d6+3)+(6d6)</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+7|3d6+3</attack>
      <attack>Force Damage||6d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The marauder casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Constitution as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 17):

	• At Will: Message
	• 1/Day: Disintegrate</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tear through Space (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The marauder teleports to a space it can see within 30 feet, appearing in a dazzling flash.
Constitution Saving Throw: DC 17, each creature in a 5-foot Emanation originating from the marauder when it appears.
Failure: The target has the Blinded condition until the end of the marauder's next turn.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Message [2024], Disintegrate [2024]</spells>
    <description>House Tarkanan

House Tarkanan is a criminal gang in Sharn, founded when Thora Tavin assembled the survivors of a suicide squad of Brelish spies who bore aberrant dragonmarks. She adopted the surname of Lord Halas Tarkanan, who used his aberrant dragonmark to wreak havoc in Sharn during the War of the Mark, and fashioned this group of thieves and assassins into a mockery of the dragonmarked houses. However, the gang lacks the recognition, power, and resources of the actual houses.

Goals of House Tarkanan.

House Tarkanan is a gang of thieves and assassins operating within the city of Sharn, but its name points to its founder's vision for building the gang into a larger movement. Most members have no higher aspirations than using their aberrant dragonmarks to profit from a criminal lifestyle. But the gang's leaders seek to amplify their dragonmarks' power to the worldshaking level of the aberrant champions of the War of the Mark, Halas Tarkanan and the Lady of the Plague. With such awesome power at their disposal, they plan to reawaken the ancient conflict over aberrant dragonmarks and topple the dragonmarked houses from their position of power.

Thora Tarkanan (still known about town under her original name, Thora Tavin), who founded the gang, recently stepped aside from its leadership, ceding power to a mysterious figure called the Son of Khyber. Little is known about him, but he bears the strongest aberrant mark seen in modern times along with the skills of a military commander. Some call him Halas Tarkanan born again, believing he is mustering an aberrant army to lead into battle against the dragonmarked houses. Thora remains the Son of Khyber's second-in-command and the public face of the gang.

A House Tarkanan Arc.

The conflict between adventurers and House Tarkanan might follow this broad outline.
	• Levels 1–4. A patron asks the characters to get involved in a criminal investigation into a rash of murders in Sharn because all the victims have dragonmarks. Both the Sharn Watch and one or more private inquisitives already squabble over access to evidence and witnesses — the characters' attempt to get involved merely heightens the tension. The perpetrators turn out to be members of House Tarkanan, whom the characters must bring to justice.
	• Levels 5–10. After the characters' success in dealing with the Tarkanan killers, the Watch comes to them for additional help. Petty thieves belonging to the gang have offered inside information into House Tarkanan's plans in exchange for leniency in their sentencing. These thieves don't share their leaders' delusions of grandeur or hatred of the dragonmarked houses. The information points to a gathering of aberrant heirs deep below Sharn.
	• Levels 11–16. After the characters disrupt House Tarkanan's schemes in the depths of Sharn, the gang sends powerful assassins with fearsome aberrant dragonmarks after the party.
	• Levels 17–20. The Son of Khyber leads a small army of aberrant-marked warriors and assassins to challenge the leadership of Sharn — and plots to conjure a Blob of Annihilation to level the city's skyscraping towers.

Aberrant Heirs.

House Tarkanan incorporates members with a wide variety of aberrant dragonmarks. Any Humanoid in the Monster Manual or another source could be a House Tarkanan agent with a mark that doesn't affect the creature's use in combat or that is re¬ected in the creature's existing abilities. For example, a Vampire Familiar might gain its unique abilities from an aberrant mark rather than from any connection to a vampire, and a Bandit Deceiver 's spellcasting could derive from such a mark. On the other hand, an ordinary Bandit or Tough might have an aberrant mark that allows the NPC to cast Disguise Self, Silent Image, or a similar spell with little impact on the NPC's combat abilities.

The two stat blocks presented here, along with the Tarkanan Assassin in Eberron: Rising from the Last War, illustrate members of House Tarkanan who wield the power of their aberrant marks in combat.

Tarkanan Marauder.
This powerful assassin relies on teleportation to catch targets unaware and deal out rapid death.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tarkanan Ruffian [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>13 (studded leather)</ac>
    <hp>32 (5d8+10)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <init>+1</init>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>11</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>13</cha>
    <save>Dex +3, Con +4</save>
    <skill>Intimidation +3, Perception +2</skill>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages>Common, Thieves' Cant</languages>
    <cr>1</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Spear, Studded Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aberrant Surge</name>
      <text>When the ru­ffian casts Witch Bolt, roll 1d8. On an even number, the ru­ffian gains a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to the number rolled. On an odd number, one
creature of the ruffi­an's choice within 30 feet of it takes Force damage equal to the number rolled; if no other creatures are in range, it takes the damage.</text>
      <attack>Temporary Hit Points||1d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Spear</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +4, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft. Hit: 6 (1d8+2) Piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+4|1d8+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The ruffi­an casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Constitution as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 12, +4 to hit with spell
attacks):

	• At Will: Thaumaturgy
	• 1/Day: Witch Bolt</text>
      <attack>Witch Bolt|+4|2d12</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>Thaumaturgy [2024], Witch Bolt [2024]</spells>
    <description>House Tarkanan:
House Tarkanan is a criminal gang in Sharn, founded when Thora Tavin assembled the survivors of a suicide squad of Brelish spies who bore aberrant dragonmarks. She adopted the surname of Lord Halas Tarkanan, who used his aberrant dragonmark to wreak havoc in Sharn during the War of the Mark, and fashioned this group of thieves and assassins into a mockery of the dragonmarked houses. However, the gang lacks the recognition, power, and resources of the actual houses.

Goals of House Tarkanan:
House Tarkanan is a gang of thieves and assassins operating within the city of Sharn, but its name points to its founder's vision for building the gang into a larger movement. Most members have no higher aspirations than using their aberrant dragonmarks to profit from a criminal lifestyle. But the gang's leaders seek to amplify their dragonmarks' power to the worldshaking level of the aberrant champions of the War of the Mark, Halas Tarkanan and the Lady of the Plague. With such awesome power at their disposal, they plan to reawaken the ancient conflict over aberrant dragonmarks and topple the dragonmarked houses from their position of power.
	Thora Tarkanan (still known about town under her original name, Thora Tavin), who founded the gang, recently stepped aside from its leadership, ceding power to a mysterious figure called the Son of Khyber. Little is known about him, but he bears the strongest aberrant mark seen in modern times along with the skills of a military commander. Some call him Halas Tarkanan born again, believing he is mustering an aberrant army to lead into battle against the dragonmarked houses. Thora remains the Son of Khyber's second-in-command and the public face of the gang.

A House Tarkanan Arc:
The conflict between adventurers and House Tarkanan might follow this broad outline.
	• Levels 1–4. A patron asks the characters to get involved in a criminal investigation into a rash of murders in Sharn because all the victims have dragonmarks. Both the Sharn Watch and one or more private inquisitives already squabble over access to evidence and witnesses — the characters' attempt to get involved merely heightens the tension. The perpetrators turn out to be members of House Tarkanan, whom the characters must bring to justice.
	• Levels 5–10. After the characters' success in dealing with the Tarkanan killers, the Watch comes to them for additional help. Petty thieves belonging to the gang have offered inside information into House Tarkanan's plans in exchange for leniency in their sentencing. These thieves don't share their leaders' delusions of grandeur or hatred of the dragonmarked houses. The information points to a gathering of aberrant heirs deep below Sharn.
	• Levels 11–16. After the characters disrupt House Tarkanan's schemes in the depths of Sharn, the gang sends powerful assassins with fearsome aberrant dragonmarks after the party.
	• Levels 17–20. The Son of Khyber leads a small army of aberrant-marked warriors and assassins to challenge the leadership of Sharn — and plots to conjure a Blob of Annihilation to level the city's skyscraping towers.

Aberrant Heirs:
House Tarkanan incorporates members with a wide variety of aberrant dragonmarks. Any Humanoid in the Monster Manual or another source could be a House Tarkanan agent with a mark that doesn't affect the creature's use in combat or that is re¬ected in the creature's existing abilities. For example, a Vampire Familiar might gain its unique abilities from an aberrant mark rather than from any connection to a vampire, and a Bandit Deceiver 's spellcasting could derive from such a mark. On the other hand, an ordinary Bandit or Tough might have an aberrant mark that allows the NPC to cast Disguise Self, Silent Image, or a similar spell with little impact on the NPC's combat abilities.
	The two stat blocks presented here, along with the Tarkanan Assassin in Eberron: Rising from the Last War, illustrate members of House Tarkanan who wield the power of their aberrant marks in combat.

Tarkanan Ruffi­an:
This rank-and-file gang member, recruited off the streets of Sharn, uses sinister lightning powers to supplement ordinary weaponry.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <!-- Morgrave Expedition Adventure -->
  <monster>
    <name>Emerald Claw Commander [2024]</name>
    <sortname>Emerald Claw, Commander</sortname>
    <ancestry>Emerald Claw</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Evil</alignment>
    <ac>20 (plate, shield)</ac>
    <hp>78 (12d8+24)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+2</init>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>11</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>15</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <save>Con +4, Wis +3</save>
    <skill>Athletics +6, Intimidation +4, Perception +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, Dwarvish</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Flail, Javelins (5), Plate Armor, Shield</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aura of Authority</name>
      <text>While in a 30-foot Emanation originating from the commander, the commander and its allies have Advantage on attack rolls and saving throws, provided the commander doesn't have the Incapacitated condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The commander makes two attacks, using Flail or Javelin in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Flail</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +6, reach 5 ft. Hit: 8 (1d8+4) Bludgeoning damage, plus 7 (2d6) Necrotic damage if the commander is Bloodied, and the target has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of the commander's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Flail|+6|(1d8+4)+(2d6)</attack>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+6|1d8+4</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Javelin</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +6, reach 5 ft. or range 30/120 ft. Hit: 7 (1d6+4) Piercing damage, plus 7 (2d6) Necrotic damage if the commander is Bloodied.</text>
      <attack>Javelin|+6|(1d6+4)+(2d6)</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+6|1d6+4</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Order of the Emerald Claw

Driven by fanatical evil and bolstered by legions of undead soldiers, the Order of the Emerald Claw is a villainous organization whose aims often pit its agents against expeditions from Morgrave University. The order's methods range from military raids using undead soldiers to subtle espionage and assassination.

Goals of the Emerald Claw.

In service of its undead leader, Lady Illmarrow, the Order of the Emerald Claw seeks powerful magic items, particularly those created with necromantic magic. Often its agents use these items simply to spread terror and destruction, but their efforts ultimately support Lady Illmarrow's goal of reactivating her dragonmark, the extinct Mark of Death.

An Emerald Claw Arc.

The conflict between adventurers and the Order of the Emerald Claw might follow this broad outline.
	• Levels 1–4. At low levels, the characters can clash with skeletons and zombies under the Emerald Claw's control. At the same time, they might build a relationship — professional or personal — with an Emerald Claw spy within the Morgrave University faculty, such as Dala Arand (see the "Cyre Tower" section later in this chapter). This spy could even serve as a patron for the characters' expeditions.
	• Levels 5–10. Emerald Claw agents use violence to keep the characters away from treasures the order has claimed. The adventurers might set out explicitly to prevent the Emerald Claw from acquiring powerful magic, or the two groups might be searching for the same sites and treasures. But the Claw agents seem to have inside information on the characters' activities and plans!
	• Levels 11–16. The spy at Morgrave University is uncovered and emerges as a powerful villain — perhaps a mighty necromancer or a vampire — who takes center stage through middle to high levels. Now the Emerald Claw primarily works to get the adventurers out of the way so they can't foil Lady Illmarrow's greater schemes.
	• Levels 17–20. The characters or the Emerald Claw agents acquire information about the Mark of Death, attracting Lady Illmarrow's attention. The would-be Queen of the Dead plans an elaborate ritual in the heart of Shae Mordai, the elven City of the Dead. The rite will destroy the islands of Aerenal and elevate Lady Illmarrow to divinity — unless the characters stop her first.

Emerald Claw Agents.

Agents of the Order of the Emerald Claw are soldiers whose obedience to the order and their superiors is absolute. They include the scouts, spies, and warriors, in addition to the stat blocks presented here, and they are often accompanied by Undead troops such as Skeletons, Zombies, and Karrnathi Undead Soldiers. Their leaders include Bone Knights.

Emerald Claw Commander.
Emerald Claw commanders lead large groups of soldiers, inspiring the fanatical devotion of Humanoids and Undead alike.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Emerald Claw Knight [2024]</name>
    <sortname>Emerald Claw, Knight</sortname>
    <ancestry>Emerald Claw</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Evil</alignment>
    <ac>18 (chain mail, shield)</ac>
    <hp>52 (8d8+16)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>17</str>
    <dex>11</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>13</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>13</cha>
    <save>Wis +2</save>
    <skill>Athletics +5, Perception +2</skill>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages>Common, Dwarvish</languages>
    <cr>2</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Flail, Javelins (5), Chain Mail, Shield</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The knight makes two attacks, using Flail or Javelin in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Flail</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +5, reach 5 ft. Hit: 7 (1d8+3) Bludgeoning damage, plus 4 (1d8) Necrotic damage if the knight is Bloodied, and the target has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of the knight's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Flail|+5|(1d8+3)+(1d8)</attack>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+5|1d8+3</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Javelin</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +5, reach 5 ft. or range 30/120 ft. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) Piercing damage, plus 4 (1d8) Necrotic damage if the knight is Bloodied.</text>
      <attack>Javelin|+5|(1d6+3)+(1d8)</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+5|1d6+3</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Order of the Emerald Claw:
Driven by fanatical evil and bolstered by legions of undead soldiers, the Order of the Emerald Claw is a villainous organization whose aims often pit its agents against expeditions from Morgrave University. The order's methods range from military raids using undead soldiers to subtle espionage and assassination.

Goals of the Emerald Claw:
In service of its undead leader, Lady Illmarrow, the Order of the Emerald Claw seeks powerful magic items, particularly those created with necromantic magic. Often its agents use these items simply to spread terror and destruction, but their efforts ultimately support Lady Illmarrow's goal of reactivating her dragonmark, the extinct Mark of Death.

An Emerald Claw Arc:
The conflict between adventurers and the Order of the Emerald Claw might follow this broad outline.
	• Levels 1–4. At low levels, the characters can clash with skeletons and zombies under the Emerald Claw's control. At the same time, they might build a relationship — professional or personal — with an Emerald Claw spy within the Morgrave University faculty, such as Dala Arand (see the "Cyre Tower" section later in this chapter). This spy could even serve as a patron for the characters' expeditions.
	• Levels 5–10. Emerald Claw agents use violence to keep the characters away from treasures the order has claimed. The adventurers might set out explicitly to prevent the Emerald Claw from acquiring powerful magic, or the two groups might be searching for the same sites and treasures. But the Claw agents seem to have inside information on the characters' activities and plans!
	• Levels 11–16. The spy at Morgrave University is uncovered and emerges as a powerful villain — perhaps a mighty necromancer or a vampire — who takes center stage through middle to high levels. Now the Emerald Claw primarily works to get the adventurers out of the way so they can't foil Lady Illmarrow's greater schemes.
	• Levels 17–20. The characters or the Emerald Claw agents acquire information about the Mark of Death, attracting Lady Illmarrow's attention. The would-be Queen of the Dead plans an elaborate ritual in the heart of Shae Mordai, the elven City of the Dead. The rite will destroy the islands of Aerenal and elevate Lady Illmarrow to divinity — unless the characters stop her first.

Emerald Claw Agents:
Agents of the Order of the Emerald Claw are soldiers whose obedience to the order and their superiors is absolute. They include the scouts, spies, and warriors, in addition to the stat blocks presented here, and they are often accompanied by Undead troops such as Skeletons, Zombies, and Karrnathi Undead Soldiers. Their leaders include Bone Knights.

Emerald Claw Knight:
Knights of the Emerald Claw command squads of Humanoid or Undead soldiers. As they draw nearer to death, the chill of the grave suffuses their weapon attacks.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Vulkoori Stingblade [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (elf)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14 (studded leather)</ac>
    <hp>27 (6d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+4</init>
    <str>11</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>11</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>12</cha>
    <save>Dex +4</save>
    <skill>Perception +3, Stealth +4</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, Elvish, Giant</languages>
    <cr>1/2</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>Poison</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 120 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Shortsword, Studded Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>Magic can't put the stingblade to sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Stingblade</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +4, reach 5 ft. Hit: 5 (1d6+2) Piercing damage plus 2 (1d4) Poison damage.</text>
      <attack>Stingblade|+4|(1d6+2)+(1d4)</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+4|1d6+2</attack>
      <attack>Poison Damage||1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Boomerang</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +4, reach 30/120 ft. Hit: 7 (2d4+2) Bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+4|2d4+2</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Drow of Xen'drik:
Within the cyclopean ruins of Xen'drik, drow are the self-proclaimed inheritors of the Age of Giants. The descendants of elves who were enslaved by giants, drow now dwell in the homes of their former masters, guarding the relics and holy sites that fate has entrusted to them. With a culture based on rebellion, magic, and combat prowess, drow are deadly enemies to any who would attempt to steal or debase the history of Xen'drik.
	Most drow of Xen'drik worship a fierce scorpion-god called Vulkoor. Some theologians of the Sovereign Host and the Dark Six believe Vulkoor to be an aspect of the Mockery (see Eberron: Rising from the Last War), but the Vulkoori drow show no partiality to the followers of the Mockery or any other god but their own. In imitation of their arachnid god, Vulkoori wear plates of scorpion chitin sewn to leather straps and sheaths. They tattoo their flesh using scorpion venom that leaves white scars on their skin.

Vulkoori Stingblade:
Vulkoori drow warriors coat their weapons with the same deadly scorpion venom they use to tattoo their skin. Thanks to their extensive use of poison, they are resistant to the scorpion venom's full effects.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Vulkoori Venom Priest [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (elf)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (studded leather)</ac>
    <hp>44 (8d8+8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>15</str>
    <dex>16</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>13</cha>
    <save>Con +3, Wis +5</save>
    <skill>Perception +5, Religion +2, Stealth +5</skill>
    <passive>15</passive>
    <languages>Common, Elvish, Giant</languages>
    <cr>2</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>Poison</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 120 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Holy Symbol, Quarterstaff, Studded Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>Magic can't put the priest to sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The priest casts one of the following spells, using Wisdom as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 13, +5 to hit with spell attacks):

	• At will: Dancing Lights, Ray of Sickness, Thaumaturgy
	• 1/day each: Cure Wounds, Hold Person, Protection from Poison</text>
      <attack>Ray of Sickness|+5|2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Venom Staff</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +4, reach 5 ft. Hit: 9 (2d6+2) Bludgeoning damage, and the target has the Poisoned condition until the end of the priest's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+4|2d6+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Intensify Poison (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>Each creature with the Poisoned condition within a 30-foot Emanation originating from the priest takes 3 (1d6) Poison damage.</text>
      <attack>Poison Damage||1d6</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>Dancing Lights [2024], Ray of Sickness [2024], Thaumaturgy [2024], Cure Wounds [2024], Hold Person [2024], Protection from Poison [2024]</spells>
    <description>Drow of Xen'drik:
Within the cyclopean ruins of Xen'drik, drow are the self-proclaimed inheritors of the Age of Giants. The descendants of elves who were enslaved by giants, drow now dwell in the homes of their former masters, guarding the relics and holy sites that fate has entrusted to them. With a culture based on rebellion, magic, and combat prowess, drow are deadly enemies to any who would attempt to steal or debase the history of Xen'drik.
	Most drow of Xen'drik worship a fierce scorpion-god called Vulkoor. Some theologians of the Sovereign Host and the Dark Six believe Vulkoor to be an aspect of the Mockery (see Eberron: Rising from the Last War), but the Vulkoori drow show no partiality to the followers of the Mockery or any other god but their own. In imitation of their arachnid god, Vulkoori wear plates of scorpion chitin sewn to leather straps and sheaths. They tattoo their flesh using scorpion venom that leaves white scars on their skin.

Vulkoori Venom Priest:
Vulkoori venom priests delight in inflicting suffering through poison. Their weaponry and magic are carefully crafted to evoke the presence of the scorpion-god and strike terror into their enemies' hearts.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Umbragen Shadow Walker [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (elf)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <hp>162 (25d8+50)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>19</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>13</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>20</cha>
    <save>Dex +8, Wis +6</save>
    <skill>Arcana +5, Perception +6, Stealth +8</skill>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>Common, Elvish, Undercommon</languages>
    <cr>9</cr>
    <vulnerable>Radiant</vulnerable>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 120 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
      <text>While in sunlight, the shadow walker has Disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>Magic can't put the shadow walker to sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The shadow walker makes three Gloom Burst attacks and uses Shadow Cowl.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Gloom Burst</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +9, reach 5 ft. or range 120 ft. Hit: 14 (2d8+5) Psychic damage.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage|+9|2d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shadow Cowl</name>
      <text>Wisdom Saving Throw: DC 17, one creature the shadow walker can see within 120 feet.
 Failure: 14 (4d6) Necrotic damage, and the target has the Blinded condition until the start of the shadow walker's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||4d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The shadow walker casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Charisma as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 17):

	• At will: Dancing Lights, Darkness, Minor Illusion</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Draining Teleport (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>While in Dim Light or Darkness, the shadow walker teleports up to 60 feet to a space it can see that is also in Dim Light or Darkness.
Constitution Saving Throw: DC 17, each creature in a 5-foot Emanation originating from the shadow walker at its destination space.
Failure: 9 (2d8) Necrotic damage</text>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>Dancing Lights [2024], Minor Illusion [2024], Darkness [2024]</spells>
    <description>Drow of Xen'drik

Within the cyclopean ruins of Xen'drik, drow are the self-proclaimed inheritors of the Age of Giants. The descendants of elves who were enslaved by giants, drow now dwell in the homes of their former masters, guarding the relics and holy sites that fate has entrusted to them. With a culture based on rebellion, magic, and combat prowess, drow are deadly enemies to any who would attempt to steal or debase the history of Xen'drik.

Most drow of Xen'drik worship a fierce scorpion-god called Vulkoor. Some theologians of the Sovereign Host and the Dark Six believe Vulkoor to be an aspect of the Mockery (see Eberron: Rising from the Last War), but the Vulkoori drow show no partiality to the followers of the Mockery or any other god but their own. In imitation of their arachnid god, Vulkoori wear plates of scorpion chitin sewn to leather straps and sheaths. They tattoo their flesh using scorpion venom that leaves white scars on their skin.

Umbragen Shadow Walker.
Umbragen drow are the descendants of drow who fled the giants and found refuge underground. For countless generations, they have lived in the lightless caverns of Khyber. There, they tapped into a mysterious magical shadow they called the Umbra. Though some have emerged to haunt the surface in the wake of the giant empire's fall, they retain a spiritual and physical connection to the darkness below. Umbragen shadow walkers weave shadow magic to confound foes.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <!-- Dragonmarked NPCs -->
  <monster>
    <name>Cannith Artificer [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (human)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>16 (chain mail)</ac>
    <hp>71 (11d8+22)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+1</init>
    <str>13</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>18</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>11</cha>
    <save>Con +4, Int +6</save>
    <skill>Arcana +6, Perception +4, Sleight of Hand +3</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Common plus two other languages</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Chain Mail, Mace, Tinker's Tools</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The artificer makes two attacks, using Battering Mace or Artillery Strike in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Battering Mace</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +6, reach 5 ft. Hit: 14 (3d6+4) Bludgeoning damage, and if the target is a Large or smaller creature, it has the Prone condition.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+6|3d6+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Artillery Strike</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +6, range 120 ft. Hit: 22 (4d8+4) Force damage.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage|+6|4d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The artificer casts one of the following spells, using its Tinker's Tools as an Arcane Focus and using Intelligence as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 14):

	• At Will: Mending, Burning Hands (level 3 version), Thunderwave (level 3 version)
	• 1/Day Each: Cure Wounds, Invisibility</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Mending [2024], Burning Hands [2024], Thunderwave [2024], Cure Wounds [2024], Invisibility [2024]</spells>
    <description>Dragonmarked artificers of House Cannith (typically human) often wield compact devices similar to eldritch cannons that can produce a variety of devastating effects. Both these cannons and the artificers' force-empowered maces function only in their creator's hands.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Ghallanda Troubleshooter [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>humanoid (halfling)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14 (leather)</ac>
    <hp>78 (12d6+36)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+3</init>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>16</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>13</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>17</cha>
    <save>Dex +5, Con +5, Wis +4, Cha +5</save>
    <skill>Insight +4, Perception +4, Stealth +5</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Common, Halfling</languages>
    <cr>3</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune>Frightened</conditionImmune>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Daggers (6), Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hustle</name>
      <text>The troubleshooter can move through the space of any creature that is of a larger size, but it can't stop there.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The troubleshooter makes two Poisoned Dagger attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Poisoned Dagger</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +5, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft. Hit: 5 (1d4+3) Piercing damage, and the target has the Poisoned condition until the start of the troubleshooter's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+5|1d4+3</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The troubleshooter casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Charisma as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 13):

	• 1/Day Each: Sleep, Unseen Servant</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Nimble Escape (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The troubleshooter takes the Disengage or Hide action.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Sleep [2024], Unseen Servant [2024]</spells>
    <description>The inns of House Ghallanda are meant to be places of safe refuge and quiet rest, so the house employs troubleshooters (mostly halflings) to protect the safety and serenity of its guests.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Jorasco Medic [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>humanoid (halfling)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>16 (breastplate)</ac>
    <hp>58 (9d6+27)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+4</init>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <save>Con +5, Wis +5</save>
    <skill>Insight +5, Medicine +5, Perception +5, Stealth +4</skill>
    <passive>15</passive>
    <languages>Common, Halfling</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Breastplate</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Lucky</name>
      <text>When the medic rolls a 1 on the d20 of a D20 Test, it can reroll the die, and it must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The medic makes two Radiant Burst attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Radiant Burst</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +5, reach 5 ft. or range 30 ft. Hit: 7 (2d6) Radiant damage, and the creature has the Blinded condition until the start of the medic's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Radiant Damage|+5|2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Mark of Healing (2/Day) (Bonus Action)</name>
      <recharge>2/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The medic casts Cure Wounds or Lesser Restoration, using Wisdom as the spellcasting ability.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Cure Wounds [2024], Lesser Restoration [2024]</spells>
    <description>Dragonmarked heirs of House Jorasco served alongside every nation's armies in the Last War, providing medical care and magical healing to the injured. Though the warring nations treated Jorasco medics as sacrosanct, these medics also learned to channel their healing power into dazzling light to help them reach the wounded and escape from the thick of combat when necessary.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p.81</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Kundarak Warden [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (dwarf)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14 (mage armor)</ac>
    <hp>82 (11d8+33)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+1</init>
    <str>15</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>17</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save>Con +6</save>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Common, Dwarvish</languages>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>The warden has Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The warden makes two Arcane Whip attacks. It can replace one attack with a use of Shackling Glyph if available.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Arcane Whip</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +6, reach 10 ft. Hit: 13 (3d6+3) Force damage, and if the target is a Medium or smaller creature, it has the Prone condition. If the target already has the Prone condition, the attack deals an extra 7 (2d6) Force damage.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage|+6|3d6+3</attack>
      <attack>Force Damage (While Prone)|+6|5d6+3</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shackling Glyph (Recharge 6)</name>
      <recharge>D6</recharge>
      <text>Strength Saving Throw: DC 14, one creature the warden can see within 60 feet.
Failure: The creature has the Grappled condition (escape DC 14). While Grappled, the creature has the Restrained condition.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The warden casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Intelligence as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 14):

	• At Will: Alarm, Arcane Lock, Mage Armor (included in AC)
	• 1/Day: Dispel Magic</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Protective Magic (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The warden casts Counterspell or Shield in response to the spell's trigger, using the same spellcasting ability as Spellcasting.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells>Alarm [2024], Arcane Lock [2024], Mage Armor [2024], Dispel Magic [2024], Counterspell [2024], Shield [2024]</spells>
    <description>Some dragonmarked heirs (mostly dwarves) of House Kundarak serve as personal guardians for the house's vaults and storehouses, and even its infamous prison, Dreadhold. Some also serve as agents of the mysterious Ghorad'din, a secretive group of assassins and spies little known beyond the members of the house. Kundarak wardens are adept at bypassing security measures as well as reinforcing them.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Lyrandar Scion [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (khoravar)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>13</ac>
    <hp>60 (11d8+11)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+3</init>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>16</dex>
    <con>13</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>18</cha>
    <save>Str +3, Dex +5</save>
    <skill>Acrobatics +5, Perception +4</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Common, Elvish</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>Lightning, Thunder</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Wand</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The scion makes two Thunderbolt attacks and uses Spellcasting.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Thunderbolt</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +6, reach 5 ft. or range 30 ft.
Hit: 11 (2d6+4) Lightning damage plus 9 (2d8) Thunder damage.
Critical Hit: The creature also has the Deafened condition for 1 minute.</text>
      <attack>Thunderbolt|+6|(2d6+4)+(2d8)</attack>
      <attack>Lightning Damage|+6|2d6+4</attack>
      <attack>Thunder Damage||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The scion casts one of the following spells, using Charisma as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 14):

	• At will: Elementalism, Gust of Wind, Thunderwave</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Jump (2/Day) (Bonus Action)</name>
      <recharge>2/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The scion casts Jump, requiring no spell components and using the same spellcasting ability as Spellcasting.</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Feather Fall (2/Day)</name>
      <recharge>2/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The scion casts Feather Fall in response to that spell's trigger, using the same spellcasting ability as Spellcasting.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells>Elementalism [2024], Feather Fall [2024], Jump [2024], Gust of Wind [2024], Thunderwave [2024]</spells>
    <description>The Khoravar dragonmarked scions of House Lyrandar include swashbuckling sky captains, seafaring adventurers, and sinister cultists of the Hurricane Harvest. The power of their dragonmarks manifests as easy control of wind, thunder, and lightning, which they wield as readily in combat as in navigating the sea and sky.

Members of the Hurricane Harvest believe that the Mark of Storm is not a gift of the Sovereign Host, as others in their house teach, but the sign of the Devourer. They maintain that the greatest ancestors of their house live on as krakens in the deep and guide the cult through visions to use their power for destruction and domination. They sometimes partner with kuo-toa, sahuagin, and other monsters of the deep.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Medani Inquisitive [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (khoravar)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14 (breastplate)</ac>
    <hp>45 (7d8+14)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+0</init>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>15</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <save>Con +4, Wis +5</save>
    <skill>Insight +5, Investigation +4</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, Elvish</languages>
    <cr>3</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Breastplate, Quarterstaff</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The inquisitive makes three Crooked Staff attacks. It can replace one attack with a use of Inquisitive Eye.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Crooked Staff</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +4, reach 5 ft. Hit: 6 (1d8+2) Bludgeoning damage. If the target is a Medium or smaller creature, it has the Prone condition. If the target already has the Prone condition, the attack deals an extra 7 (2d6) Radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Crooked Staff (While Prone)|+4|(1d8+2)+2d6</attack>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+4|1d8+2</attack>
      <attack>Radiant Damage||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Inquisitive Eye</name>
      <text>Wisdom Saving Throw: DC 13, one creature the inquisitive can see within 60 feet.
Failure: 10 (3d6) Psychic damage, and the target is marked. The inquisitive has Advantage on attack rolls against a target it has marked. While marked, the target can't become hidden from the inquisitive, and if it has the Invisible condition, it gains no benefit from that condition against the inquisitive. The mark disappears after 1 minute or when the inquisitive uses this action again.
Success: Half damage only.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||3d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The inquisitive casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Wisdom as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 13):

	• At Will: Guidance
	• 1/day each: Detect Thoughts, See Invisibility</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Spontaneous Barrier (Recharge 4–6)</name>
      <recharge>D4</recharge>
      <text>Trigger: The inquisitive or an ally it can see is hit with an attack roll.
Response: The inquisitive adds 2 to its or the ally's AC against that attack, possibly causing it to miss.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells>Guidance [2024], Detect Thoughts [2024], See Invisibility [2024]</spells>
    <description>The most prized inquisitives of House Medani, a house of mostly Khoravar, employ their dragonmarks and their keen intellects to anticipate threats from any quarter. Some are part of a secretive order called the Basilisk's Gaze, dedicated to hunting down fugitive war criminals who committed atrocities during the Last War.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Orien Enforcer [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (human)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>16 (studded leather)</ac>
    <hp>55 (10d8+10)</hp>
    <speed>35 ft.</speed>
    <init>+6</init>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>18</dex>
    <con>13</con>
    <int>16</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>11</cha>
    <save>Dex +6, Wis +4</save>
    <skill>Acrobatics +6, Perception +4</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Common plus two other languages</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Daggers (6), Studded Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The enforcer makes three Dagger attacks. It can replace one attack with a use of Lightning Cage if available.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Dagger</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +6, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft. Hit: 9 (2d4+4) Piercing damage plus 7 (2d6) Poison damage.</text>
      <attack>Dagger|+6|(2d4+4)+(2d6)</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+6|2d4+4</attack>
      <attack>Poison Damage||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Lightning Cage (Recharge 5-6)</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>Constitution Saving Throw: DC 13, each creature in a 20-foot-radius Sphere centered on a point the enforcer can see within 60 feet.
Failure: 13 (3d8) Lightning damage, and the creature can't take Reactions until the end of the enforcer's next turn.
Success: Half damage only.</text>
      <attack>Lightning Damage||3d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Misty Step (2/Day) (Bonus Action)</name>
      <recharge>2/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The enforcer casts Misty Step, using Intelligence as the spellcasting ability.</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Temporal Disruption (1/Day)</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>Trigger: The enforcer takes damage from a melee attack.
Response: The enforcer teleports up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space it can see. Each creature within 10 feet of the space the enforcer left must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw, or its Speed is halved until the start of the enforcer's next turn.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells>Misty Step [2024]</spells>
    <description>Whether riding on an Orien cart, guarding the lightning rail on a cross-continental journey, or using Orien Teleportation Circles to transport precious parcels in an instant, dragonmarked enforcers of House Orien (mostly humans) protect their house's interests and maintain its reputation for dependability.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Sentinel Marshal [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (human)</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>16 (studded leather)</ac>
    <hp>110 (20d8+20)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+10</init>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>19</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>11</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save>Dex +7, Con +4</save>
    <skill>Athletics +7, Insight +5, Perception +8</skill>
    <passive>18</passive>
    <languages>Common plus two other languages</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Longsword, Pistol, Studded Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The marshal makes three attacks, using Longsword or Pistol in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Longsword</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +7, reach 5 ft. Hit: 13 (2d8+4) Slashing damage, and the target has Disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes before the start of the marshal's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+7|2d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Pistol</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +7, range 30/90 ft. Hit: 15 (2d10+4) Piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+7|2d10+4</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Shield (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The marshal casts Shield in response to the spell's trigger, using Wisdom as the spellcasting ability.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells>Shield [2024]</spells>
    <description>The Sentinel Marshals of House Deneith, who are typically human, hold the honor of the house in their hands. The Treaty of Thronehold upheld their authority to pursue criminals across international borders, giving them the unique privilege and responsibility of upholding the law across Khorvaire.

Only the most trusted heirs of the house are honored with a position in the Sentinel Marshals, either after serving in the house's other guilds for several years (as bodyguards in the Defenders Guild and mercenary officers in the Blademarks Guild) or by special dispensation of House Deneith.

Sentinel Marshals are never authorized to break local or international laws, but neither are they accountable to the legal authorities of any nation. A rogue marshal can be punished only by the leadership of House Deneith, but some nations (such as Darguun and Droaam) ignore these conventions.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Shadow-Marked Agent [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (elf)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>17 (studded leather)</ac>
    <hp>132 (24d8+24)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+8</init>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>20</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>11</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>17</cha>
    <save>Dex +8, Wis +6</save>
    <skill>Perception +6, Performance +6, Sleight of Hand +8, Stealth +11</skill>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>Common, Elvish, Thieves' Cant</languages>
    <cr>7</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Studded Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The agent makes two Shadow Knife attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shadow Knife</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +8, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft. Hit: 10 (2d4+5) Piercing damage plus 14 (4d6) Necrotic damage, and the target's Speed is reduced by 10 feet until the end of its next turn.</text>
      <attack>Shadow Knife|+8|(2d4+5)+(4d6)</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+8|2d4+5</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||4d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>Spellcasting. The agent casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Charisma as the spellcasting ability (DC 14):

	• At will: Disguise Self, Minor Illusion
	• 1/day: Pass without Trace</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shadow Cloak (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The agent has the Invisible condition until the start of its next turn. This invisibility ends early immediately after the agent makes an attack roll.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Minor Illusion [2024], Disguise Self [2024], Pass without Trace [2024]</spells>
    <description>Agents of House Phiarlan and House Thuranni, who are primarily elves, combine stealth and espionage with mastery of the performing arts — and dragonmarked heirs augment those skills with shadow magic. This stat block can serve for an agent of either house.

Even though House Phiarlan agents don't typically work as entertainers or artists in addition to their espionage activities, they receive extensive training in those arts alongside other members of their house. House Thuranni agents, in contrast, are always both artists and spies.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Sivis Scribe [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>humanoid (gnome)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>15 (mage armor)</ac>
    <hp>56 (16d6)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+2</init>
    <str>11</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>16</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>11</cha>
    <save>Wis +3</save>
    <skill>Arcana +5, Sleight of Hand +4</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Common, Gnomish, plus three other languages</languages>
    <cr>3</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Words of Reason</name>
      <text>Allies in a 10-foot Emanation originating from the scribe have Advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Charmed or Frightened condition. This trait doesn't function if the scribe has the Incapacitated condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The scribe makes two Bursting Sigil attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bursting Sigil</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +5, reach 5 ft. or range 60 ft. Hit: 13 (3d6+3) Radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Radiant Damage|+5|3d6+3</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>1/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The scribe casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Intelligence as the spellcasting ability (DC 13):

	• At will: Comprehend Languages, Mage Armor (included in AC), Message
	• 1/Day: Sending</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Word of Stasis (Recharge 5–6) (Bonus Action)</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>Constitution Saving Throw: DC 13, each creature in a 20-foot-radius Sphere centered on a point the scribe can see within 60 feet.
Failure: The target has the Incapacitated condition until the start of the scribe's next turn. While the target is Incapacitated, its Speed is 0 and can't increase.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Message [2024], Comprehend Languages [2024], Mage Armor [2024], Sending [2024]</spells>
    <description>The dragonmarked heirs of House Sivis are typically accomplished gnome scholars of magic. In addition to the might that comes with their marks, they favor magical sigils and words of power.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tharashk Hunter [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (human, orc)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>16 (studded leather)</ac>
    <hp>97 (15d8+30)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <init>+4</init>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>19</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>11</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save>Dex +7, Con +5</save>
    <skill>Perception +6, Stealth +7, Survival +6</skill>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>Common, Orc, plus one other language</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Longbow, Shortsword, Studded Leather Armor</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The hunter makes three attacks, using Shortsword or Longbow in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shortsword</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +7, reach 5 ft. Hit: 11 (2d6+4) Piercing damage, and the target has Disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the end of its next turn.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+7|2d6+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Longbow</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +7, range 150/600 ft. Hit: 17 (3d8+4) Piercing damage, and the target's Speed is reduced by 10 feet until the end of its next turn.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+7|3d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Mark of Tharashk (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The hunter magically marks one creature it can see within 150 feet. The mark lasts for 1 hour, until the target dies, or until the hunter uses this Bonus Action again. While the target is marked in this way, the hunter has Advantage on attack rolls against the target, and the target gains no benefit from the Invisible condition against the hunter.</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
      <text>Trigger: The hunter is hit by an attack roll.
Response: The hunter halves the damage (round down) it takes from that attack.</text>
    </reaction>
    <description>House Tharashk's heirs include inquisitives, dragonshard prospectors, and bounty hunters. They are more at home in the trackless wilds than in crowded city streets, but they are quite capable of tracking and pursuing their prey in any environment.

Tharashk hunters, typically humans or orcs, often work alongside Druids of the Gatekeepers, and occasionally with Aberrant Cultists of the Dragon Below.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Vadalis Heir [2024]</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (human)</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14 (leather)</ac>
    <hp>52 (8d8+16)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>+3</init>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>16</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>13</cha>
    <save>Dex +5, Con +4, Wis +5</save>
    <skill>Animal Handling +7, Nature +4, Stealth +5</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, Sylvan</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium or Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gear</name>
      <text>Leather Armor, Scimitar</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pack Tactics</name>
      <text>The heir has Advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the heir's allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally doesn't have the Incapacitated condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The heir makes four attacks, using Scimitar or Lunar Wisp in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Scimitar</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +5, reach 5 ft. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) Slashing damage plus 3 (1d6) Poison damage.</text>
      <attack>Scimitar|+5|(1d6+3)+(1d6)</attack>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+5|1d6+3</attack>
      <attack>Poison Damage||1d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Lunar Wisp</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +5, range 60 ft. Hit: 9 (2d8) Radiant damage, and the target emits Dim Light in a 10-foot radius and can't benefit from the Invisible condition until the end of the heir's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Radiant Damage|+5|2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The heir casts one of the following spells, using Wisdom as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 13):

	• At will: Druidcraft, Light, Speak with Animals
	• 3/day each: Animal Friendship, Animal Messenger
	• 1/day: Ice Storm</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spur Beast (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The heir targets a Beast it can see within 30 feet. The target can take a Reaction to move up to half its Speed and make one melee attack.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Druidcraft [2024], Light [2024], Speak with Animals [2024], Animal Friendship [2024], Animal Messenger [2024], Ice Storm [2024]</spells>
    <description>Combining druidic magic with skill at handling natural and monstrous animals, the dragonmarked heirs of House Vadalis, most of whom are human, are more fearsome than their innocuous-seeming house suggests — especially when accompanied by a Giant Boar, Polar Bear, or Rhinoceros.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
</compendium>
