<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Aberrant [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. You bear an aberrant dragonmark. These rare marks appear on members of all species. Aberrant dragonmarks disturb the houses—you would be wise to avoid their attention.

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot: You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. For example, you could be a Halfling with the Mark of Healing but with no ties to House Jorasco. You're an anomaly; if House Jorasco became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house. To build this kind of character, choose a Dragonmark feat at level 4 or later.

Mark of Prophecy: You might bear a mark unrelated to your species. For example, you can choose to bear the Mark of Healing even if you're not a Halfling. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and a House might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Aberrant Fortitude. When you fail a Constitution saving throw, you can take a Reaction to roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the save, potentially turning the failure into a success. Once you've used this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Aberrant Magic. You know one cantrip of your choice from the Sorcerer spell list. Also, choose a level 1 spell from that spell list. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Short or Long Rest. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have. Constitution is your spellcasting ability for this spell.

Aberrant Surge. When you cast the level 1 spell from this feat, you can expend one of your Hit Point Dice and roll it. If you roll an even number, you gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to the number rolled. If you roll an odd number, one creature within 30 feet of you (not including you) takes Force damage equal to the number rolled. If no other creatures are in range, you take the damage.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Detection [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Human, not related to House Medani): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Medani became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Human): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Medani might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Deductive Intuition. When you make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Insight) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Magical Detection. You always have the Detect Magic and Detect Poison and Disease spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the See Invisibility spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Detection Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Detection Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Detect Evil and Good, Identify
2 | Detect Thoughts, Find Traps
3 | Clairvoyance, Nondetection
4 | Arcane Eye, Divination
5 | Legend Lore

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Finding [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Orc, not related to House Tharashk): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Tharashk became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Orc): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Tharashk might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Hunter's Intuition. When you make a Wisdom (Perception or Survival) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Finder's Magic. You always have the Hunter's Mark spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Locate Object spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Finding Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Finding Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Faerie Fire, Longstrider
2 | Locate Animals or Plants, Mind Spike
3 | Clairvoyance, Speak with Plants
4 | Divination, Locate Creature
5 | Commune with Nature

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Handling [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Human, not related to House Vadalis): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Vadalis became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Human): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Vadalis might not claim you.
You gain the following benefits.

Wild Intuition. When you make an Intelligence (Nature) or Wisdom (Animal Handling) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Primal Connection. You always have the Animal Friendship and Speak with Animals spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Monstrous Connections. When you reach character level 3, you can target a Monstrosity when you cast Animal Friendship or Speak with Animals if the creature's Intelligence score is 3 or lower.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Handling Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Handling Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Command, Find Familiar
2 | Beast Sense, Calm Emotions
3 | Beacon of Hope, Conjure Animals
4 | Aura of Life, Dominate Beast
5 | Awaken

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Healing [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Halfling, not related to House Jorasco): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Jorasco became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Halfling): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Jorasco might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Medical Intuition. When you make a Wisdom (Medicine) check or an ability check using a Herbalism Kit, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Healing Touch. You always have the Cure Wounds spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Lesser Restoration spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Healing Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Healing Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | False Life, Healing Word
2 | Arcane Vigor, Prayer of Healing
3 | Aura of Vitality, Mass Healing Word
4 | Aura of Life, Aura of Purity
5 | Greater Restoration

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Hospitality [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Halfling, not related to House Ghallanda): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Ghallanda became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Halfling): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Ghallanda might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Ever Hospitable. When you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check or an ability check using Brewer's Supplies or Cook's Utensils, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Innkeeper's Magic. You always have the Purify Food and Drink and Unseen Servant spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Calm Emotions spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Hospitality Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Hospitality Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Goodberry, Sleep
2 | Aid, Enhance Ability
3 | Create Food and Water, Leomund's Tiny Hut
4 | Aura of Purity, Mordenkainen's Private Sanctum
5 | Hallow

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Making [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Human, not related to House Cannith): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Cannith became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Human): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Cannith might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Artisan's Intuition. When you make an Intelligence (Arcana) check or an ability check using Artisan's Tools, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Spellsmith. You know the Mending cantrip. You also always have the Magic Weapon spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Making Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Making Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Identify, Tenser's Floating Disk
2 | Continual Flame, Spiritual Weapon
3 | Conjure Barrage, Elemental Weapon
4 | Fabricate, Stone Shape
5 | Creation

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Passage [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Human, not related to House Orien): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Orien became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Human): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Orien might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Courier's Speed. Your Speed increases by 5 feet.

Intuitive Motion. When you make a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Magical Passage. You always have the Misty Step spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Passage Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Passage Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Expeditious Retreat, Jump
2 | Find Steed, Pass without Trace
3 | Blink, Phantom Steed
4 | Dimension Door, Freedom of Movement
5 | Teleportation Circle

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Scribing [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Gnome, not related to House Sivis): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Sivis became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Gnome): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Sivis might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Gifted Scribe. When you make an Intelligence (History) check or an ability check using Calligrapher's Supplies, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Scribe's Insight. You know the Message cantrip. You also always have the Comprehend Languages spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).
	When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Magic Mouth spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Scribing Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.he Mark: If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic feature, the spells on the Mark of Scribing Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Scribing Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Command, Illusory Script
2 | Animal Messenger, Silence
3 | Sending, Tongues
4 | Arcane Eye, Confusion
5 | Dream

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Sentinel [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Human, not related to House Deneith): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Deneith became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Human): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Deneith might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Sentinel's Intuition. When you make a Wisdom (Insight or Perception) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Guardian's Shield. You always have the Shield spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

Vigilant Guardian. When a creature you can see within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to swap places with that creature, and you are hit by the attack instead. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus and regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Sentinel Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Sentinel Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Compelled Duel, Shield of Faith
2 | Warding Bond, Zone of Truth
3 | Counterspell, Protection from Energy
4 | Death Ward, Guardian of Faith
5 | Bigby's Hand

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Shadow [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Elf, not related to House Phiarlan): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Phiarlan became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Elf): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Phiarlan might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Cunning Intuition. When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) or Charisma (Performance) check, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Shape Shadows. You know the Minor Illusion cantrip. You also always have the Invisibility spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Shadow Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Shadow Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Disguise Self, Silent Image
2 | Darkness, Pass without Trace
3 | Clairvoyance, Major Image
4 | Greater Invisibility, Hallucinatory Terrain
5 | Mislead

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Storm [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Khoravar, not related to House Lyrandar): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Lyrandar became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Khoravar): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Lyrandar might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Windwright's Intuition. When you make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check or an ability check using Navigator's Tools, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Storm's Boon. You have Resistance to Lightning damage.

Storm Magic. You know the Thunderclap cantrip. When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Gust of Wind spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast it using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Storm Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Storm Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Feather Fall, Fog Cloud
2 | Levitate, Shatter
3 | Sleet Storm, Wind Wall
4 | Conjure Minor Elemental, Control Water
5 | Conjure Elemental

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Mark of Warding [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Eberron Campaign, Can't Have Another Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>&gt;Dragonmarks are mysterious and magical symbols that appear on the skin of some people across Khorvaire. The twelve established dragonmarks are tied to specific family lines, and the scions of those families work hard at consolidating the power of the marks in order to maximize the profit and influence they gain from them. The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services. 

Marks of Mystery: Centuries of manipulation and consolidation have caused the established dragonmarks to manifest primarily in members of certain races and family lines. However, exceptions have always existed, and they've grown increasingly common in recent years.

Distant Offshoot (Dwarf, not related to House Kundarak): You are a distant offshoot of a dragonmarked family line, sharing the species that most commonly manifests the mark but unencumbered by ties to its house. You're an anomaly; if House Kundarak became aware of you, it would try to bring you and your family line into the house.

Mark of Prophecy (Not Dwarf): You might bear a Mark unrelated to the Race normally associated with the Mark. Your dragonmark has nothing to do with the house's family line. It might be a direct mark of the Draconic Prophecy, or it could be an Aberrant Mark that happens to duplicate an established one. You'll probably never meet an NPC in the world like you, and House Kundarak might not claim you.

You gain the following benefits.

Warder's Intuition. When you make an Intelligence (Investigation) check or an ability check using Thieves' Tools, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Wards and Seals. You always have the Alarm and Mage Armor spells prepared. You can cast each spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this feat).

When you reach character level 3, you also always have the Arcane Lock spell prepared and can cast it the same way.

Spells of the Mark. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Warding Spells table are added to that feature's spell list.

Mark of Warding Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1 | Armor of Agathys, Sanctuary
2 | Knock, Nystul's Magic Aura
3 | Glyph of Warding, Magic Circle
4 | Leomund's Secret Chest, Mordenkainen's Faithful Hound
5 | Antilife Shell

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Aberrant Mark [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Aberrant Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Fortitude. When you use the Aberrant Fortitude benefit of your Aberrant Dragonmark feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4. You also now regain your use of Aberrant Fortitude whenever you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Mark of Inspiration. When you cast a cantrip, you can roll one or two of your unexpended Hit Point Dice. You gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to the number rolled plus your Constitution modifier, and one creature of your choice within 30 feet of you (not including you) takes Force damage equal to the number rolled. Those dice are then expended.

You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Detection [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Detection Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Deductive Intuition benefit of your Mark of Detection feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Shared Detection. When you use the Magical Detection benefit of your Mark of Detection feat to cast See Invisibility without a spell slot, you can choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself. That creature also gains the benefits of the spell for its duration.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Finding [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Finding Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Hunter's Intuition benefit of your Mark of Finding feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Improved Finding. When you use the Finder's Magic benefit of your Mark of Finding to cast Hunter's Mark without a spell slot, the range of the spell is doubled, and you can modify the spell so that the target can't benefit from the Invisible condition for the duration.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Handling [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Handling Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Wild Intuition benefit of your Mark of Handling feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Improved Handling. While you are mounted, immediately after you hit a target within 5 feet of your mount with a melee attack roll, your mount can take a Reaction to move up to its Speed or take the Attack action to make one attack only (your choice).

Subdue Animal. As a Magic action, you exert command over one Beast or Monstrosity you can see within 30 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC 8 plus your Wisdom modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or have the Frightened condition until the start of your next turn. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Healing [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Healing Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Medical Intuition benefit of your Mark of Healing feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Improved Healing. You can now use the Healing Touch benefit of your Mark of Healing feat to cast Cure Wounds without using a spell slot a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Additionally, when you cast Cure Wounds and roll dice to determine the number of Hit Points restored, you can treat any 1 or 2 on a roll as a 3.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Hospitality [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Hospitality Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Ever Hospitable benefit of your Mark of Hospitality feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Inspired Hospitality. When you cast Purify Food and Drink, you can modify the spell so that instead of its normal effect, each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you is refreshed. Each affected creature's Exhaustion level is reduced by 1, and the creature gains Temporary Hit Points equal to your Proficiency Bonus plus your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma modifier (choose when you select this feat). Once you modify the spell with this benefit, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Making [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Making Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Artisan's Intuition benefit of your Mark of Making feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Improved Making. When you use the Spellsmith benefit of your Mark of Making feat to cast Magic Weapon without a spell slot, you cast the spell as its level 3 version.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Passage [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Passage Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.



You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Intuitive Motion benefit of your Mark of Passage feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Inspired Passage. When you use the Magical Passage benefit of your Mark of Passage feat to cast Misty Step without a spell slot, you can also choose up to two willing creatures you can see within 30 feet of yourself before you teleport. Each target can then take a Reaction to also teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space it can see.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Scribing [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Scribing Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Gifted Scribe benefit of your Mark of Scribing feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Inspired Scribing. When you cast Comprehend Languages, you can modify the spell to encompass up to three willing creatures you can see within 30 feet of yourself. Each chosen creature also gains the benefits of the spell for the duration. In addition, for the duration of the spell, you and the chosen creatures can communicate telepathically with each other while within 1 mile of each other. Once you modify the spell with this benefit, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Sentinel [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Sentinel Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Sentinel's Intuition benefit of your Mark of Sentinel feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Improved Sentinel. When you use the Vigilant Guardian benefit of your Mark of Sentinel feat, you can also make one attack with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike as part of that same Reaction.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Shadow [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Shadow Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Cunning Intuition benefit of your Mark of Shadow feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Improved Shadow. When you use the Shape Shadows benefit of your Mark of Shadow feat to cast Invisibility without a spell slot, you cast the spell as its level 3 version.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Storm [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Storm Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Windwright's Intuition benefit of your Mark of Storm feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Improved Storm. When you use the Storm Magic benefit of your Mark of Storm feat to cast Gust of Wind without a spell slot, you also gain a Fly Speed of 60 feet for the duration of the spell.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Greater Mark of Warding [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Mark of Warding Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Most dragonmarks are small—no more than the size of the bearer's palm—and grant limited magical power. And even these minor marks are rather rare. But rarer and more powerful marks appear on some individuals, both within and outside the dragonmarked houses. Greater dragonmarks manifest only on people who already possess an ordinary mark. When a greater dragonmark manifests, it grows from an ordinary mark and expands outward to two or three times the original mark's size.
	The dragonmarked houses view greater marks as more significant than ordinary marks in every way—more important to the livelihood of the house, more essential to keep under the house's control, and potentially more significant in terms of fulfilling the Draconic Prophecy that some believe is written in the marks.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Improved Intuition. When you use the Warder's Intuition benefit of your Mark of Warding feat, you can roll 1d6 instead of 1d4.

Improved Warding. When a creature makes an attack roll against you or a creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself, you can take a Reaction to impose Disadvantage on that roll. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonmark, Potent [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Any Dragonmark Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase the spellcasting ability score used by your Dragonmark feat by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Dragonmark Preparation. You always have the spells on your Spells of the Mark list (if any) prepared.

Dragonmark Spellcasting. You have one extra spell slot to cast the spells granted by your Dragonmark feat. The spell slot's level is half your level (round up), to a maximum of level 5. You regain the expended slot when you finish a Short or Long Rest. You can use this spell slot to cast only a spell you have prepared because of your Dragonmark feat or the Dragonmark Preparation benefit of this feat.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Boon of Siberys [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 19+, Eberron Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>The Boon of Siberys can reflect either a Siberys mark or a powerful Aberrant Mark. While the people of Khorvaire have a limited understanding of dragonmarks, Siberys dragonmarks remain a complete mystery to them. The magic of these powerful marks clearly relates—visually and thematically—to the other marks in one's house. But a dragonmarked heir may spend years perfecting and mastering the powers of a mark without ever manifesting a Siberys mark. Meanwhile, an unmarked scion of a dragonmarked house might suddenly display one against all expectations.
	Siberys marks are mighty, unpredictable, and rare, and the dragonmarked houses keep a careful eye on anyone who manifests one. If its power can serve the house, fine—but an heir of Siberys who doesn't conceal the dragonmark's ability or remain firmly aligned with the dragonmarked house is likely to become the target of assassins.

You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 30.

Aberrant Magic. Choose a level 8 or lower spell from the Sorcerer spell list or a spell from the Siberys Dragonmark Spells table (the table includes dragonmark suggestions if you'd like to associate a spell with one of the marks). You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot or spell components, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Short or Long Rest. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you gain this feat).

Siberys Dragonmark Spells:
Spell | Suggested Dragonmark
Animal Shapes | Handling
Control Weather | Storm
Demiplane | Making
Heroes' Feast | Hospitality
Maze | Warding
Mind Blank | Sentinel
Plane Shift | Passage
Project Image | Shadow
Regenerate | Healing
Symbol | Scribing
Teleport | Finding
True Seeing | Detection

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</text>
  </feat>
</compendium>
