<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Fairy (UA)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Feywild is home to many fantastic peoples, including fairies. Fairies are a wee folk, but not nearly as much so as their pixie and sprite friends.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana 77 - Folk of the Feywild</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>When determining your character's ability scores, increase one of those scores by 2 and a different score by 1, or increase three different scores by 1
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Fairies have a life span of about a century.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Fairies can be of any alignment but tend to lean more towards chaotic because of their playful trickster nature.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>You are Small.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>You are a Fey
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Characteristics</name>
      <text>The Feywild is home to many fantastic peoples, including fairies. Fairies are a wee folk, but not nearly as much so as their pixie and sprite friends.

Infused with the magic of the Feywild, fairies share a few commonalities with one another but can differ widely in appearance, behavior, and attitude. Many fairies have a special physical characteristic that sets them apart from other creatures of their kind. For your fairy, roll on the Fey Characteristic table or choose an option from it. The Feywild is a wild place, so come up with your own characteristic if none of these fit your character.

d8 — Characteristic
1 — You have small wings like those of an insect.
2 — You have shimmering, multicolored skin.
3 — You have exceptionally large ears.
4 — A glittering mist constantly surrounds you.
5 — You have a small spectral horn on your forehead, like a little unicorn horn.
6 — Your hands never look dirty.
7 — You smell like fresh brownies.
8 — A noticeable, harmless chill surrounds you
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fairy Flight</name>
      <text>You have a flying speed equal to your walking speed and can hover. This flight is magical and does not require the use of your wings (if you have them).
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fairy Magic</name>
      <text>You know the Druidcraft and Faerie Fire spells. You can cast Faerie Fire without expending a spell slot, and you must finish a long rest before you can cast it this way again. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have. Your spellcasting ability for these spells is your choice of Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Passage</name>
      <text>You can squeeze through a space as narrow as 1 inch wide.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Language</name>
      <text>The first fairies spoke Elvish, Goblin, or Sylvan, and encounters with human visitors prompted many of them to learn Common as well. You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for the character.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
