<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Lizardfolk (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Nature</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Born from the union of the Material Plane and the Elemental Plane of Earth, Lizardfolk are hardy, stoic beings shaped by their elemental heritage. These reptilian people are pragmatic survivors, viewing the world through a lens of practicality rather than emotion. Their connection to stone and soil is deeply ingrained, allowing them to instinctively manipulate earth magic to shape their surroundings.
	Lizardfolk often dwell in coastal marshes, rocky riverbeds, and dense jungles, where their natural resilience and elemental attunement give them an advantage. While they rarely seek conflict, their calm detachment can make them seem cold or unfeeling to outsiders.
	Though Lizardfolk are not inherently hostile, they are fiercely territorial and will defend their homes with ruthless efficiency.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Elemental</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small or Medium (2-3 feet or 4-6 feet)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft., Swim 15 ft., Burrow 15 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Nature</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Unarmed strikes made with your fanged maw deal 1d6 Piercing damage instead of the normal Bludgeoning damage. This is a Strength-based attack, and you are proficient with it. If you score a critical hit with this attack, you gain temporary hit points equal to the damage dealt.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Natural Armor</name>
      <text>Your scales provide ample protection. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC equals 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Geomancy</name>
      <text>Your affinity with the Elemental Plane of Earth grants you certain magical gifts:

	• You know the Elementalism cantrip, which you can cast at will.

	• At 5th level, you learn Spike Growth. You always have these spells prepared.

You can cast each of them once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast a spell using this trait, you choose Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma as your spellcasting ability (choose the ability when you create your Lizardfolk).</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
