<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Bounty Hunter (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Investigation, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You've been carving a living by cutting down monsters in exchange for coin. Whether bandits and criminals or horrific beings who prowl in the dark of night, you are well-trained in studying and tracking down your quarry, as well as finding ways to outwit and neutralize it. Your trade is a rare one to find in Zamanora and, as few would dare undertake it, it is much in demand. There are usually plenty of parties interested in employing your services, often with contradictory intentions for your mark, aiming to either convince you on how to better deal with it, or to outbid one another on your pay. Common folk, however, tend to be wary of your profession; for if a mere wayfarer can spell trouble for their humble abodes, the arrival of an armed mercenary with unknown intentions presents a serious cause for concern.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Monster Slayer</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Courageous. Once per day, upon failing a saving throw against an effect that would cause you to become Frightened, you can choose to roll again and keep the better result.

Know Thy Enemy. By collecting three pieces of information regarding a creature, you can choose to designate it as your Quarry for the next 7 days. These pieces of information can be any three amongst the following: its name, its creature type, an accurate description of its appearance, a location it frequents, a routine habit that it has, a piece of evidence of its presence (such as a track or body part). While a creature is designated as your Quarry, you have Advantage on any Search and Study Actions you take in relation to it, and add your Proficiency Bonus to your damage rolls against it. You can have a number of active Quarries up to your Proficiency Bonus at a time.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Gaming Set</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.

Gaming sets:
Set | Cost | Weight
Dice set | 1 sp | -
Dragonchess set | 1 gp | 1/2 lb
Playing card set | 5 sp | -
Three-Dragon Ante set | 1 gp | -</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Dungeoneer's Pack, 1 Gaming Set (same as above), 3 Hunting Traps, 1 Shovel, 21 GP or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Hedge Mage (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You were taken in by a witch, either by choice or circumstance. Under the witch's tutelage, you were exposed to the raw magic of the land, experiencing the subtle art of communing with the natural and the spiritual world from a very young age. Your mentor may have been a benevolent healer of the community, or maybe a hermit that chose to devote to their art and its mysteries in solitude. Perhaps, they were even feared, for it is known that folks will dread that which they cannot understand. Regardless of their social standing, your days were filled with gathering herbs, assisting in rituals, and learning more of the Hidden World. Whether you now chose to grow into the mantle of the witch yourself, or if you have ended your apprenticeship prematurely, the knowledge you gained has prepared you for a life beyond your mentor's humble abode, and the lessons that were imparted upon you are invaluable.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 30 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Intelligence, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Witchcraft </name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Forager. You have Advantage on D20 Tests made for foraging and identifying herbs and mushrooms.

Poppet Mage. You gain the Poppet Mage feature, associated with the same Artisan's Tool as above, allowing you to practice Poppet Magic (see Chapter III: Poppet Magic).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Artisan's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.

Artisan's tools:
Tools | Cost | Weight
Alchemist's supplies | 50 gp | 8 lb.
Brewer's supplies | 20 gp | 9 lb.
Calligrapher's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Carpenter's tools | 8 gp | 6 lb.
Cartographer's tools | 15 gp | 6 lb.
Cobbler's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Cook's utensils | 1 gp | 8 lb.
Glassblower's tools | 30 gp | 5 lb.
Jeweler's tools | 25 gp | 2 lb.
Leatherworker's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Mason's tools | 10 gp | 8 lb.
Painter's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Potter's tools | 10 gp | 3 lb.
Smith's tools | 20 gp | 8 lb.
Tinker's tools | 50 gp | 10 lb.
Weaver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.
Woodcarver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Herbalism Kit (same as above), 1 Backpack, 10 Candles, 1 Set of Traveler's Clothes, 5 days of Rations, 3 Vials, 15 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Kupalen'ka (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are a child conceived during the Kupala Night; the annual celebration of the summer solstice, a revelry of fertility and harvest. The collectively felt emotions of joy and elation that permeated this magical night have seeped into you, gifting you with natural charms that make others quick to endear you. Throughout your life, you've been treated as a precious child, and were led to believe that nothing sort of a blessed future lies ahead of you; a wonderful portent, yet one that could turn rather cumbersome. Due to the burden of expectation that has been laid upon your shoulders, you've grown adept in sensing what others desire from you.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 30 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Constitution, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Natural Grace </name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Alluring Presence. People are impressed by your innate charm. Every Humanoid creature that is Indifferent towards you and does not yet know you is treated as Friendly for the Influence Actions you take, until you fail a relevant ability check.

Keen Intuition. When trying to determine a creature's state of mind through Insight, you can take the Study Action as a Bonus Action instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Musical Instrument</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.

Musical instruments:
Instrument | Cost | Weight
Bagpipes | 30 gp | 6 lb.
Drum | 6 gp | 3 lb.
Dulcimer | 25 gp | 10 lb.
Flute | 2 gp | 1 lb.
Lute | 35 gp | 2 lb.
Lyre | 30 gp | 2 lb.
Horn | 3 gp | 2 lb.
Pan flute | 12 gp | 2 lb.
Shawm | 2 gp | 1 lb.
Viol | 30 gp | 1 lb.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Entertainer's Pack, Musical Instrument (same as above), 1 Perfume, 5 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Lorekeeper (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>History, Performance</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You were apprenticed to a Wise One, a practiced Speaker, or another sagacious figure, for the purpose of carrying their mantle as a custodian of local folklore, after they have departed from this world. Your education in the ways and traditions of your kin ranged from participating in ritualistic ceremonies to assuming unique tasks for your community, such as the sacred duty of grave tending, or the memorization of the laws and genealogical trees of your peoples. Since such knowledge endures the test of time by being passed down orally from one generation to the next, individuals who possess it are viewed as living troves of it, often sought out by others for their wisdom and counsel. Eventually, you will be expected to assume the role of your predecessor, becoming a spiritual leader for your community; a responsibility you must prepare yourself for, as well as decide whether it is one you are willing to undertake altogether.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 31 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Constitution, Intelligence, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Speaker of Ceremonies </name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Glossolalist. You learn two more languages of your choice. In addition, you can learn other languages or Idioms in half the time it usually takes.

Pass on Knowledge. During a Long Rest, you may choose one willing creature that can understand you and impart it with your knowledge. Choose one skill in which you are proficient. The target creature gains proficiency in that skill until it completes its next Long Rest.

Upholding Tradition. You learn three Ceremonies of your choice. These do not count against the maximum number of Ceremonies you know.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Musical Instrument</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.

Musical instruments:
Instrument | Cost | Weight
Bagpipes | 30 gp | 6 lb.
Drum | 6 gp | 3 lb.
Dulcimer | 25 gp | 10 lb.
Flute | 2 gp | 1 lb.
Lute | 35 gp | 2 lb.
Lyre | 30 gp | 2 lb.
Horn | 3 gp | 2 lb.
Pan flute | 12 gp | 2 lb.
Shawm | 2 gp | 1 lb.
Viol | 30 gp | 1 lb.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Musical Instrument (same as above), Scholar's Pack, 5 days of Rations, Chest, Lock, 10 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Remembrancer (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>History, Investigation</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Scarcely anything is known of the Old World, a time where the predecessors of the Zamanori led a life completely different than that of their descendants. Tales speak of a mighty civilization and its eventual downfall, yet they mostly contradict one another when they regale its traits; as well as what ultimately brought it to ruin. You are amongst those who grew up with tales such as these, inspired to shed light into the obfuscated chapters of your kin's history. You have thus devoted your life to delving into places forlorn, chasing fable after fable in hopes of unraveling any shred of truth that may lie within them, unearthing lore that has been lost to the ages, and remnants of a world that once was. Only time will tell if your quest will lead you to grand discoveries beyond any expectation, or disturbing truths of a past most sorrowful, that are best left forgotten.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 32 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Crypt Delver </name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Scavenger. You have Advantage on Search Actions taken to spot traps, secret doors, and concealed items.

Collector of Oddities. You have Advantage on Study Actions taken to accurately estimate an item's worth, as well as discern any magical properties it might feature. In addition, according to the occasion and the Storyteller's discretion, you may attempt the latter using History instead of Arcana, as you normally would.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Cartographer's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Cartographer's Tools, Scholar's Pack, 5 days of Rations, Chest, Lock, 10 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Veilborn (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana, Deception, Nature, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You were born at a time and place where the Veil of the Hidden World was at its thinnest, or abandoned there as an infant. The energies of the spiritual realm, roaming wildly around you, infused your being. Ever since childhood, you showed signs of divergent behaviour, spooking and unnerving your peers, causing you to be treated with caution even by those responsible for your upbringing. Alternatively, you might have been raised by spirits; Rusalki bathed your hair or Poputniki taught you to hunt for wild mushrooms, educating you in the ways of their elusive domain long before you came into contact with denizens of civilized society. Regardless, you could never truly attain a sense of belonging, as you still struggle to find your place between these two worlds.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 32 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Touch of the Veil </name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Harrowkin. When a Harrow causes your Veilmark Score to increase after you had chosen to Resist its effects, deduct your Proficiency Bonus from this increment (minimum 1). If you had chosen to Embrace the Harrow's effects instead, you may add your Proficiency Bonus to this increment.

Spiritual Manifestation. Your exposure to the influence of the Hidden World and its beings has shaped you. Your Veilmark Score increases to 25, if not already higher.

Speaking in Tongues. You can understand and speak Sylvan.

Unnatural Stamina. Whenever you finish a Long rest, you regain one additional spent Hit Die, for each Veilmark threshold you have crossed.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Artisan's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.

Artisan's tools:
Tools | Cost | Weight
Alchemist's supplies | 50 gp | 8 lb.
Brewer's supplies | 20 gp | 9 lb.
Calligrapher's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Carpenter's tools | 8 gp | 6 lb.
Cartographer's tools | 15 gp | 6 lb.
Cobbler's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Cook's utensils | 1 gp | 8 lb.
Glassblower's tools | 30 gp | 5 lb.
Jeweler's tools | 25 gp | 2 lb.
Leatherworker's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Mason's tools | 10 gp | 8 lb.
Painter's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Potter's tools | 10 gp | 3 lb.
Smith's tools | 20 gp | 8 lb.
Tinker's tools | 50 gp | 10 lb.
Weaver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.
Woodcarver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Artisan's Tools (same as above), 1 Backpack, 1 Bedroll, 10 Candles, 1 Dagger, 5 days of Rations, Rope, 10 Torches, 10 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Woebringer (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Deception, Stealth, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>A falsehood that you spoke, such as witnessing a monster or treasure that you never actually saw, led others on a fool's errand. Alternatively, you may have spoken the truth but, ultimately, no one would believe you. The consequences of this action made you a pariah amongst your peers. Ever since, your kinsfolk treated you with disdain, branding you as a bearer of illnews and omen of bad luck. With most of the things that would go wrong during their everyday lives being unreasonably accredited to you, you've learned to keep your head down and act discreetly around them, as well as to fend for yourself. Whether you've ended up harboring bitterness towards them, an imperative need to redeem yourself in their eyes, or even both, this choice rests entirely with you.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 33 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Constitution, Intelligence</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Willful </name>
      <text>You're no stranger to hardship, and are determined to press on despite any failures and shortcomings. Whenever you roll a 1 on a D20 Test, you gain Heroic Inspiration. Heroic Inspiration gained in this way cannot be used to reroll the D20 Test that yielded it or be given to another, and vanishes if it has not been spent until your next Long Rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Artisan's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.

Artisan's tools:
Tools | Cost | Weight
Alchemist's supplies | 50 gp | 8 lb.
Brewer's supplies | 20 gp | 9 lb.
Calligrapher's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Carpenter's tools | 8 gp | 6 lb.
Cartographer's tools | 15 gp | 6 lb.
Cobbler's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Cook's utensils | 1 gp | 8 lb.
Glassblower's tools | 30 gp | 5 lb.
Jeweler's tools | 25 gp | 2 lb.
Leatherworker's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Mason's tools | 10 gp | 8 lb.
Painter's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Potter's tools | 10 gp | 3 lb.
Smith's tools | 20 gp | 8 lb.
Tinker's tools | 50 gp | 10 lb.
Weaver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.
Woodcarver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Artisan's Tools (same as above), 1 Explorer's Pack, 1 2 Daggers, Ink, Ink Pen, 5 pieces of Parchment, 8 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Epic Origin: The Crone's Progeny (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana, Nature</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Crone's Progeny
Of all the tales whispered in Zamanora, none cause more dread than those of Baba Yaga, the Bone Mother, the First Witch, the Crone with Countless Names. At her mere mention, villagers spit to ward off ill luck or call upon the gods to drive her shadow away. To most, she is the eternal hag, capricious and cruel, whose name graces every tale of misfortune. Yet of all her terrors, one tale is stranger, softer, and far more human: the tale of her only child.

Made, not Born:
It is said that Yaga is as ancient as Zamanora itself, possessing abilities that cannot ever be fully comprehended. Yet at that peak of magical prowess, she stood utterly alone. Her gifts and burdens unshared, she would witness isolation eat away at her soul, her lingering humanity. A witch, especially the greatest Witch of all, must have a coven. Lacking equals then, she devised another way to fulfil that hope: she would fashion a child. Thus she turned not to womb but cauldron, bringing to bear the secrets of creation that she beheld at the world's first dawn. So was conceived the pinnacle of alchemy, the Progeny; a living, breathing homunculus graced with the capacity for thought and emotion, able to grow and dream, love and hate, like any other person. Endowed with potential but free of control, this being was created to evolve into the Crone's match in power and cunning, but also as a tether to her own mortal nature. Alas, no growth can be achieved without experience. So the child must be sent into the world, to live among its kind.
	No mark betrays the Progeny's nature and they grow like any other, a person among the people. Only, fate seems to subtly bend around them. The strange clings to them, knowledge and challenge always drifts their way. Even so, danger seems to avert its gaze, and when calamity strikes some hidden hand intercedes; that of Baba Yaga herself. Unseen but never absent, she yearns for her creation's experience to broaden, for it to grow into a worthy member of her Coven. At the same time, she also fusses over its safety, never daring to reveal herself, lest her daunting presence harm the Progeny's acceptance by their peers. So she cares from afar, always tampering with the experiment, rarely pausing to wonder what unbidden emotions might be guiding her actions.

The Progeny's Dilemma:
Baba Yaga's Progeny will eventually face a haunting crossroads, a moment of terrible clarity when they discover the truth of their origin. Faced with this haunting reality, the Progeny might rebel against Yaga, rejecting their creator and the unspoken expectation placed upon them. They may seek a life in opposition to her legacy, treating her as the Crone, monster of legend, even attempting to hunt her down. However, one might approach such a revelation not as a puppet that can finally see its strings, but as a child finding connection to a parent. They might do as the First Witch hopes, returning to the embrace of their Mother to become her Coven. Perhaps such a child, tempered by the touch of community that its mother never felt, could change the Witch's frigid perspective. The acceptance of her creation by the society that threw her out, or even a simple act of love, reciprocated to an attentive parent, may stoke the flame of Baba Yaga's withered humanity. Or perhaps such miracles only occur in fairy tales.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 36 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Constitution, Wisdom, Intelligence</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: The Crone's Own</name>
      <text>Epic Origin Feats are reserved solely for Epic Origins. You gain the following benefits.

Homunculus. When you walk within 15 feet of an area where a spell was cast within the last 24 hours, you can sense its school of magic. If multiple spells were cast, you sense the school of magic of the most powerful spell.

Forbidden Cradle. Your exposure to the ancient magics of the Crone has altered your being. Your Veilmark Score increases by 25.

Conduit of the Arcane. As a Reaction to a creature casting a spell that deals damage or restores Hit Points within 60 feet of you that you can see, you can partially absorb its magic. When you do so, reduce its dice rolled by a number of dice equal to your Proficiency Bonus. Then, you roll these dice instead and gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to the amount rolled. You may use this feat a number of times per day equal to half your Proficiency Bonus.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Alchemist's Supplies</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Explorer's Pack, 1 Alchemist's Supplies, 1 Dagger, 5 Candles, 1 set of Traveler's Clothes, 8 GP or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Epic Origin: The Drangue (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Athletics, Acrobatics</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Drangue:
In every age, when storms blacken the skies and the earth trembles as the Kulshedra stirs, tales of the Drangue are told anew. The Drangue is a legendary warrior whose strength defies mortal measure, bound by a cosmic destiny to battle the fabled Kulshedra. Each age knows but one such child, born when the monstrous, three-headed balaur appears, whose awakening will threaten the very existence of the realm.

Birthmarked:
Ever since their birth, a Drangue is marked by destiny. Such a mark also manifests physically, granting them traits that distinguishes them from their biological species. Hidden beneath their arms lie small feathers that grow back even if plucked, while in the rarest of occasions, a caul covers their heads at birth, like a hood. Finally, the skin of their chest emits a faint glow, giving rise to the claim that they do not possess a normal heart but one made of gold, crowned by a jewel. From an early age, they possess strength that defies mortal limitations, which only grows after they reach maturity. This extraordinary prowess usually lands them positions of manual labor; tending the fields in the absence of an ox, cutting down trees, or even diverting rivers.

Destiny of Battle:
Regardless of the blessing the birth of a Drangue may bring to the denizens of a settlement, it is also a grim reminder for a great upcoming calamity; the Kulshedra. When this dormant evil is close to stirring into action, the stars themselves summon the birth of a Drangue, one of the only beings capable enough to stand against its destructive powers. As the years pass, visions and dreams of the three-headed beast haunt a Drangue's waking hours, leaving no doubt in their mind of their destiny. When their purpose becomes clear, it is up to them to prepare for the final confrontation with the Kulshedra. Some may attempt to reject their destiny, hiding away behind the veil of a different life. Throughout history, however, they too will eventually answer the call, inexorably drawn towards the inevitable confrontation, until finally these two primordial forces clash in battle, ending only when one of them falls.
	Besides relying on their own capabilities, a Drangue has almost never been able to take down the Daughter of Storms alone. However, their very presence becomes a beacon for all those who wish to banish the darkness of the Kulshedra, and many powerful figures would gather beneath the Drangue's stead. One of the most notable such allies are the Svyatogor's Banner, a group of warriors whose life-long purpose is to prepare for the coming of the Kulshedra, and ride into battle alongside the Drangue so that the chosen warrior may land the final blow.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 38 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Dexterity, Constitution</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Dragonslayer</name>
      <text>Epic Origin Feats are reserved solely for Epic Origins. You gain the following benefits.

Apex Predator. Whenever you deal damage to a Dragon with an attack or spell, you can add your Proficiency Bonus to one damage roll.

Colossal Build. You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can lift, push or drag.

Winged. As a Bonus Action you can unfurl or hide your wings. You have a Fly Speed equal to your Speed while your wings are unfurled. You can't use this Flying Speed if you are wearing Medium or Heavy Armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Artisan's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.

Artisan's tools:
Tools | Cost | Weight
Alchemist's supplies | 50 gp | 8 lb.
Brewer's supplies | 20 gp | 9 lb.
Calligrapher's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Carpenter's tools | 8 gp | 6 lb.
Cartographer's tools | 15 gp | 6 lb.
Cobbler's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Cook's utensils | 1 gp | 8 lb.
Glassblower's tools | 30 gp | 5 lb.
Jeweler's tools | 25 gp | 2 lb.
Leatherworker's tools | 5 gp | 5 lb.
Mason's tools | 10 gp | 8 lb.
Painter's supplies | 10 gp | 5 lb.
Potter's tools | 10 gp | 3 lb.
Smith's tools | 20 gp | 8 lb.
Tinker's tools | 50 gp | 10 lb.
Weaver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.
Woodcarver's tools | 1 gp | 5 lb.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Backpack, Bedroll, 10 days of Rations, Rope, 10 Torches, Waterskin, 1 Artisan's Tools set (same as above), 1 Shovel, 1 Pole, 14 GP or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Epic Origin: The Elden Soul (HB) [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Elden Soul:
The sudden and mysterious collapse of the Old World spawned a unique type of story within Zamanora: tales of a hero who would one day arise to return the land to its rightful glory. Travelling over mountains and through time, this fable has taken many forms along the way. In the most prevalent version, the hero lies petrified in a secret place, waiting in frozen time for a moment of fate to bring them back to life. When that fateful instance occurs, the Elden Soul will return, to uncover the lost history of the Old World, vanquish great evils, and usher in an age of renewal for the realm, or choose to bury the past forever.

Legendary Origins:
The appearance of an Elden Soul is not a birth so much as a working of great magic. Indeed, the hero has already been born aeons ago, when the Old World still existed. By mysterious forces of chance or preservation, the legends say they were placed in stasis, turned to marble, or lulled into a wakeless sleep, to await the moment when the time is ripe for their return. That moment too must be heralded by a magical force, as the hero can only be woken by the call of the Gamayun, or the touch of destiny's golden thread. In that moment, they will know their charge and their pedigree, and must choose to follow or reject it.
	When an Elden Soul awakens, their memories of the Old World, as well as their skills are hazy and dulled. The magic that set them adrift loosens their grip on the past, preventing their mind from breaking under the contrast between old and new realities. They know where they came from, but all else appears as visions under fog. Gradually, new faces and experiences will spark forgotten memories, restoring the image of a world gone by and whatever emotions those recollections carry.

The Fate of Heroes:
Once awoken, an Elden Soul is drawn to multiple directions at once. The new world they find themselves in may initially overwhelm them, but soon their task becomes apparent: they must find what happened to the Old World. An ancient being that once dwelled in its elden cities might know this truth. Beings such as the dreaded lich Koschei, the Deathless, or the lord of the Gallery of Pain are bound to hold precious information regarding the passing of that age. Throughout this journey, they must become a hero anew, leading a life of adventure and fable. To that end, they are compelled to chase rumors of ancient artifacts, seek steadfast allies, face powerful foes, and consult wise sages. All the while their inner compass leads them to cross the path of those who have need, in an inexorable dance of service and reward. To the individual Elden Soul, this guiding light may lead to a blessed life of righteous toil, or it may seem a cruel leash by which they are drawn from one struggle to the next. This is all in preparation for the moment they learn the truth about the Old World; and once they do, they will have to choose if it must be resurrected, or its veracity forgotten.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Constitution, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Inner Compass</name>
      <text>Epic Origin Feats are reserved solely for Epic Origins. You gain the following benefits.

Adventure Sense. You have Advantage on D20 Tests made to collect information about creatures, locations or items of legendary importance.

An Age in Marble. You can call on the magic that kept your soul intact for aeons to withstand the journey. When you take damage, you can use your Reaction to reduce the damage taken by a number of d8s equal to your Proficiency Bonus. You can use this benefit once before you finish a Long Rest.

Hero's Soul. Whenever you encounter a new character, or location, or have a novel experience linked to the Old World, such as a ruin, artifact, or ancient Dragon, roll a d20. On a 10 or above, you gain Heroic Inspiration as you recall a piece of information about your past life, or a bit of lore about the Old World. The Storyteller decides what the recollection is.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Gaming Set</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category. Gaming sets: Set | Cost | Weight Dice set | 1 sp | - Dragonchess set | 1 gp | 1/2 lb Playing card set | 5 sp | - Three-Dragon Ante set | 1 gp | -</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Spear, Shortsword, Gaming Set (same as above), Healer's Kit, Fine Clothes, 18 GP or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
