<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Warlock [2024]</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Veilmark Information (Zamanora)</name>
        <text>It is said that trespassing upon the spirit world leaves a tangible brand on one's body and soul. Mortals should never peer beyond the Veil, lest the spirits take notice and mark them forevermore. Let a marked person into your home and you invite certain calamity. The lands of Zamanora are riddled with such fiction and cautionary tales that only work to paint those who are inquisitive in a bad light. Yet they are right about one thing; someone who interacts with the Hidden World too often is bound to be "marked".

As characters engage in encounters with curses, spirits, and other supernatural phenomena, they accrue Veilmark. This attribute reflects their growing connection to the spirit realm and the transformative effects of these experiences on their physical and spiritual selves. Veilmarked is the term used by the Zamanori to describe individuals who have thus changed, and denotes characters who have accrued enough Veilmark to cross a threshold. If playing in a different setting, you may use the broader term Aura to describe the system.
	The influence of Veilmark on a character is determined by their Veilmark Score. The more a character interacts with curses, spirits, and other supernatural phenomena, delving into the mysteries of the Hidden World, the more their Veilmark Score increases. A character's Veilmark Score is effectively a pool of innate power they may tap into in order to produce certain effects that aid them when interacting with spiritual entities. However, at the same time, the higher one's Veilmark Score is, the more otherworldly they feel when interacting with their peers, making them wary and distrustful of their presence.
	Characters start out with a Veilmark Score of 0, which may increase up to a maximum of 100 throughout a campaign. Certain features, such as the Veilborn Origin (see Chapter II: Origins), or the Veilscarred Barbarian's Dark Bargain and Willow's Embrace (see Chapter II: Subclasses), signify that a character has already been extensively exposed to the Hidden World and influence that character's starting Veilmark Score according to their description.

Gaining Veilmark:
An increase of Veilmark results in noticeable physical changes, signifying the character's deepening connection with the spirit realm. Every time a character's Veilmark modifier increases, roll on the table below or choose one of the physical alterations listed to manifest on them.
	Your Veilmark Score may increase every time you experience an event that severely impacts your psyche by challenging what you priorly thought was real. Interacting with a being you believed to be a mere folktale, falling victim to a vicious curse, or drinking water from a bewitched spring can all increase your Veilmark Score. Such an experience, along with the implications caused upon oneself due to it, is known as a Harrow.
	A Harrow may affect a single or multiple characters at once, and at different levels of Severity (see Harrows table), based on roleplay and the narrative course of the story. For example, when a stranger who asks to share in the warmth of the party's campfire is later revealed to be a malign spirit, every character present may be subjected to a Harrow of Considerable level; yet for a character who recognizes the spirit as that of a deceased relative of theirs, the same Harrow may qualify as Intense. At the same time, another character who has already dabbled in occult practices to a point of communing with the spirits of the dead may treat this as a Harrow of Inconsequential level. The Severity of a Harrow on a character's psyche, as well as which character is subject to the risk of gaining Veilmark due to it and which isn't, is determined by the Storyteller, according to their interpretation of the player characters' backgrounds, stories, personalities, and any circumstantial factors that apply to each occasion.
	When the Storyteller declares a Harrow, each character that is subject to it must choose whether they wish to Resist or Embrace it. This choice represents their disposition towards the supernatural world, and their openness towards its truths and mysteries.

Reisting Veilmark:
A character who chooses to Resist a Harrow makes a Wisdom saving throw against a DC determined by its Severity. On a success, the experience leaves them unaffected, and nothing happens. On a failure, they must roll the corresponding Veilmark Die. Their Veilmark Score becomes increased by an amount equal to the result. A Hero that succeeds on their Action without Consequences resists the Harrow completely, taking no increase to their Veilmark Score. Otherwise, the Hero rolls the corresponding amount of Veilmark dice. A Success with Consequences means that the Hero's Veilmark increases by an amount equal to half of their result. A roll that only results in Consequences means that the Hero's Veilmark score is increased by the total amount rolled. You may also employ special means, such as the Veil Charm item (see Chapter IV: Fabled Relics), in order to better your chances in resisting any unwanted increases in your Veilmark Score.

Embracing Veilmark:
A character who chooses to Embrace a Harrow forgoes making any attempts at resisting its effects and does not roll the corresponding Veilmark Die. That character's Veilmark Score automatically increases by the maximum amount possible.

Veilmark:
d6 | Veilmark Die | DC | Status Tier
1 | 1d6 | 10 | harrowing-1
2 | 2d6 | 15 | harrowing-2
3 | 3d6 | 20 | harrowing-3
4 | 4d6 | 25 | harrowing-4
5 | 5d6 | 30 | harrowing-5

Veilmark Thresholds:
Whenever a Harrow causes your Veilmark Score to increase beyond the thresholds of 25, 50, 75 and 99 for the first time, you gain a Veilmark Transformation. For every Veilmark Transformation that you have, you gain a cumulative -2 penalty to any Influence Actions you take against other non-Veilmarked Humanoids and Beasts, unless you are trying to intimidate them.

Veilmark Thresholds Table:
Threshold | Title
25 | Shadowlit
50 | Equinoctial
75 | Moonstruck
99 | Spiritwalker

Transformations &amp; Powers:
Veilmark transformations are a physical manifestation of the Hidden World's effects on your body. Such a transformation is a consequence of your innate understanding of the supernatural and ability to harness the powers that lie within, but ultimately comes at a cost. The first time you cross each of those Veilmark Thresholds, you gain a Veilmark Transformation and two new Veilmark Abilities from the tables below. For every Veilmark Transformation you have, you gain a cumulative -2 penalty to any Influence Actions you take against other non-Veilmarked Humanoids and Beasts, unless you are trying to intimidate them.

When you gain a new Veilmark Transformation, roll on the table below to determine its nature. If the result is a Transformation you have already undergone, roll again until you get a new one. Once you gain a Veilmark Transformation, it remains with you permanently, even if your Veilmark Score later decreases below that threshold.

Veilmark Transformations Table:
d10 | Transformation
1 | One of your eyes changes color. At night, when the Veil grows thin, you glimpse visions from the other side. This distraction grants you Disadvantage on Initiative rolls during nighttime hours.
2 | A streak of silver appears on your hair. Silvered weapons deal an extra Damage Die to you.
3 | Your skin's complexion becomes a tone paler. Whenever you take Fire damage you take an additional 1d4 Fire damage.
4 | Veins throughout your body become visibly dark beneath your skin. While you are Bloodied and can see an enemy, you can't willingly move away from them.
5 | Your shadow changes to resemble that of a different being. The Attitude of Beasts towards you worsens by one stage.
6 | A strange marking brands your skin like a scar. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Curses.
7 | A strange marking brands your skin like a scar. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Curses.
8 | A Zagovory symbol appears on your tongue. Whenever you fail an Influence Action, it is treated as attempted Intimidation regardless of your intentions.
9 | You appear sickly and weak. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Diseases.
10 | You no longer cast a reflection. You are excluded from beneficial effects caused by spells that target multiple creatures.

Every time you cross a Veilmark threshold, you unlock two new abilities, as detailed in the Veilmark Abilities table. You may use the abilities gained from each threshold a combined total of two times per day. For example, you may use one ability twice, or each ability once. Unlike Transformations, Veilmark Abilities do not last indefinitely. If your Veilmark Score falls below the Threshold that granted you these abilities (see Losing Veilmark), they become dormant and cannot be used until your Veilmark Score rises above the corresponding Threshold again.

Veilmark Threshold Abilities:

Shadowlit:

Detect Spirit. You cast the spell Spirit Sense, without expending a spell slot.

Incorporeal Reach. As a Bonus Action, your attacks harm the very essence of spirits for the next minute. For the duration, once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 Force damage to a target you hit with an attack or spell.

Equinoctial:

Exorcism. As an Action, you touch a creature and end one of the following effects currently afflicting it: Frightened, Charmed, or a Possession.

Pierce the Veil. As part of a successful Study Action made against a creature of the Spirit subtype, you discern either of the following: its Immunities, Resistances or Vulnerabilities.

Moonstruck:

Soul Harvest. As a Reaction to a creature dying within 30 feet of you, you can infuse yourself with a fragment of its departing essence. As a result, you may choose to either regain a number of expended spell slots as a 4th-level Wizard using the Arcane Recovery feature, or gain 25 Temporary Hit Points.

Spiritual Kinship. When you fail a saving throw against a spell or magical effect caused by a creature of the Spirit subtype, you succeed instead.

Spiritwalker:

Ethereal Echo. As an Action, you create an ethereal duplicate of yourself that lasts for 1 minute. This spectral reflection appears in your space and mimics your movements precisely, with an almost imperceptible delay. The echo has half your current Hit Points. When you make an attack that deals damage to a single target, your echo repeats the attack but only deals half damage (rounded down). The echo takes the same damage as you do when you are damaged. It cannot regain Hit Points and vanishes if it reaches 0 Hit Points, you become Incapacitated, or when the duration ends.

Tether Soul. By spending an hour in meditation, you bind your soul to a clearly defined point that you can see in your environment; for example, the hollow of an oak tree, or a statue made of stone. If you die before your next Long Rest, you gain the effects of the Reincarnate spell, but your new species is Haunt (see Chapter II: Species), while your new body forms in the bound point based on the materials it consists of. If you successfully return to life in this way, your Veilmark Score is reduced to 0 and you lose any Veilmark Transformations you have.

Losing Veilmark:
Once you have been exposed to the challenging truths of the Hidden World, it is very difficult, if indeed possible at all, to forget them. However, there are ways to reduce its impact on your being. The diminishing of one's Veilmark represents a retreat from the otherworldly, a return to the mundane, and a fixated anchoring to the Real. Below are the ways you may employ to reduce your Veilmark Score.

Downtime Activity:
You may choose to detach yourself from the supernatural by indulging in mundane activities for extended periods. For every month or Sojourn you spend this way, your Veilmark Score decreases by 5. Examples of such activities include:

	• Engaging with a community in manual labor, such as aiding in the building of a home.

	• Exploring and cultivating deep emotional bonds with others through steady everyday life.

	• Spending time alone to reflect upon yourself, or pursue artistic creations.

Recreation:
Other than spending time in peace and tranquility, you may also pursue more radical methods to reduce your Veilmark Score. These include consuming a God Flesh mushroom (see Chapter IV: Zamanoran Mushrooms), meditating within the Gemstone Caverns, or bathing in the waters of a lake within the Three Nines Forest. While such methods are the swiftest and most potent ways to achieve the intended result, they may carry certain hazards and must be undertaken with caution.

Potent Arcana:
Employing powerful magic, such as an archmage's spell of wishing, or returning to life through use of a Tether Soul (see Veilmark Abilities above) can reduce your Veilmark Score to 0, as well as remove any Veilmark Transformations you have. Once you surpass a Veilmark Threshold and gain a Veilmark Transformation, it remains with you permanently, even if your Veilmark Score later decreases below that threshold. Only Potent Arcana may remove a Veilmark Transformation. These transformations continue to affect both your body and soul, even if you disguise yourself through the means of illusory magic or a shape-changing ability. However, if your score increases again past a threshold you've previously crossed, you won't gain additional transformations for that same threshold. During a campaign in which you want to make the Veilmark system less punishing, you may rule that the effects of Greater Restoration also remove the effects of a Veilmark Transformation from a character. Conversely, reducing your Veilmark below each Threshold means that you lose access to the corresponding Abilities, as detailed above.

Roleplaying Veilmark:
As your Veilmark increases, consider how these changes affect your character's personality and demeanor. Do you welcome them as a mark of growth, or do you view them as aberrations upon your appearance? Consider how your personality might change to reflect them. You might become more aloof, skittish, or stoic. You may pick up a repetitive habit or mannerism. Perhaps the weight of the spirit world will deeply affect your psyche, gradually changing you into an altogether different person.

Social Implications:
In small communities such as the villages of Zamanora, these physical changes can lead to fear, reverence, or superstition. Characters bearing those marks are considered branded by the spirits, influencing their interactions with NPCs.

Fear and Distrust:
In most organized communities, the appearance of a Veilmarked stranger is met with apprehension, the locals fearing the character and associating their marks with bad omens or curses. Otherworldly features in their appearance might put the common folk ill at ease, but beyond that, their mere presence is unsettling for reasons that cannot be interpreted directly, as they carry the stigma of the Hidden World. A character with more than a couple of Veilmark transformations is usually treated as a Spook by common folk who first encounter them. Superstitious folk may be wary of such characters and treat them with extreme caution, to the point of turning them into a pariah amongst their societies or even chasing them away.

Reverence and Respect:
In the dwellings of spirits, or places where their presence is strongly felt, denizens might see the marks as a sign of a blessed or powerful individual, offering assistance or seeking their aid. In such cases, according to the Storyteller's discretion, the penalties to Influence Actions normally associated with Veilmark Transformations may become bonuses instead.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 120 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Transformation">1d10</roll>
        <roll description="Fire Damage">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Force Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: The Murrain Maiden (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: The Murrain Maiden (HB)</name>
        <text>Legend has it that the visage of the goddess Kogha often appears to Zamanori when they are about to perish from a degenerative illness, or the fumes of a poisonous mushroom. In their time of need, she offers them a choice: perish, or become her advocate. Those who submit receive her pestilent grace, along with the ability to infect and envenom living beings. These plague-bearers often form covenants outside of civilized lands, preferring the embrace of swamps where their patron's creations thrive.
	Kogha's creed is not one of wanton destruction. Her devout believe that disease is but a trial; one that determines which souls are bound for the domain of Belegorn, her father, and which still belong to the world of the living. They see this as a necessary process of selection, like separating the wheat from the chaff, allowing the strong to survive and the weak to pass on.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 105 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Intoxication (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</name>
        <text>You relish in the blight wrought by your patron. Whenever you deal Poison damage to a creature within 10 feet of you, or whenever you start your turn within 5 feet of a creature that has the Poisoned condition, you can use your Reaction to become toxified for the next minute. While you are toxified, you gain the following benefits:

Fumes of the Rot. You gain 1d8 Temporary Hit Points at the start of your turn.

Semi-Lucid. You are immune to the Charmed and Frightened conditions.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 106 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Temporary Hit Points">1d8</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Murrain Maiden Spells (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Warlock level specified in the Murrain Maiden Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Murrain Maiden Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
3 | Detect Poison and Disease, Hold Person, Ray of Enfeeblement, Ray of Sickness
5 | Animate Dead, Speak with Dead
7 | Blight, Patchwork Restoration*
9 | Cloudkill, Insect Plague

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 106 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Noxious Flower (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</name>
        <text>You can sprout a venomous rose, which emanates a fog of nauseating fumes that devastates your enemies. As a Magic Action, you create a 10-foot radius Sphere of toxic vapors centered on a point within 30 feet of you. The Sphere also spreads around corners. When a creature enters the effect's area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the creature has the Poisoned condition and remains so until it ends its turn outside the affected area. During each of your turns, you can use your Bonus Action to move the cloud up to 15 feet. It lasts for 1 minute or until a strong wind (such as one created by Gust of Wind) disperses it.
	In addition, your spells and abilities ignore Resistance to Poison damage against creatures within the area of your Noxious Flower.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses of this ability when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 106 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Noxious Flower</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Murrain Maiden (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Mudwalk (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</name>
        <text>You can evoke your patron's putrid form with each step that you tread. At the end of each of your turns and while you are standing on soft ground, you may choose to turn the area within a 5-foot radius around you into a swamp for the next minute. The area becomes Difficult Terrain for all creatures other than you. As a Bonus Action while standing over a swamp area created by you, you can teleport to any swamp square created by you. You can teleport in this way a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses of this ability when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 107 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Mudwalk</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Murrain Maiden (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Mudwalk</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Murrain Maiden (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Blightbringer (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</name>
        <text>You can bring forth pestilence and disease. As a Magic Action, all creatures of your choice within the area of your Noxious Flower must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 6d8 Poison damage and have the Poisoned condition for the next minute. Also, choose one ability when you use this feature. While Poisoned, a creature target has Disadvantage on saving throws made with the chosen ability. At the end of each of its turns, an affected creature repeats its save, ending the effects on itself on a success.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by expending a level 5 spell slot or higher (no action required).

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 107 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Blightbringer</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Murrain Maiden (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Mudwalk</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Murrain Maiden (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: The Old Crone (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: The Old Crone (HB)</name>
        <text>Whether out of desperation or of the Crone's purpose, you have been bound to the ageless witch Baba Yaga. Perhaps she aided you when you needed her most, or spared you when you transgressed against her. Despite the true reason, you stirred the old magic and the Crone demanded a pact. Other beings may serve as your patron as well; beings that have transcended mortal bounds and wield ancient magics that once shaped the world. Regardless of the true nature of your patronage, yours is a journey of reticence, following the signs of the Crone to realize her design; an intricate tapestry spanning the whole of Zamanora.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 109 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Old Crone Spells (The Old Crone (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Warlock level specified in the Old Crone Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Old Crone Spells:
Warlock level | Spells
3 | Detect Thoughts, Hex, Identify, Mirror Image
5 | Bestow Curse, Tiny Hut
7 | Black Tentacles, Polymorph
9 | Modify Memory, Teleportation Circle

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 109 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Secrets of the Earth (The Old Crone (HB))</name>
        <text>The Crone has imparted you with a fraction of her alchemical knowledge. You gain proficiency with the Alchemist's Supplies if you don't already have it. You know the recipes of 3 common Potions or Alchemical Brews (see Chapter IV: Fabled Relics) and can craft a number of brews up to your Proficiency Bonus by gathering herbs and various other ingredients as part of a Long Rest.
	Creating a Potion or Alchemical Brew requires you to have Alchemist's Supplies on your person, and due to the borrowed nature of your powers, any brew you create with this feature lasts until it is consumed or until the end of your next Long Rest.
	Whenever you gain a new feature in this subclass, you also learn the recipes of 3 Potions or Alchemical Brews of your choice of one step higher rarity (up to Rare). If you successfully cast the Identify spell on a brew for which you don't know the recipe for and that is of a rarity that you can craft, you can add it to your known recipes.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 109 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Izbushka (The Old Crone (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action you can target the area of a Tiny Hut spell that you cast, turning it into an Izbushka with the following benefits.

Chicken Legs. The Izbushka grows a pair of giant legs beneath it that resemble those of a Beast of your choice, and gains a walking Speed of 30 feet. You can mentally control its movements (no action required).

Cozy Hut. Both the outside and the inside of the Tiny Hut's Emanation changes to resemble that of an actual wooden hut with a design of your choice, but it cannot exceed the physical parameters of the Emanation. The Izbushka is also susceptible to damage. It has an AC of 15 and Hit Points equal to 5 times your Warlock level. If the Izbushka is reduced to 0 Hit Points or if you die, the spell dissipates and all creatures and objects within fall to the ground.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 109 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: The Crone's Design (The Old Crone (HB))</name>
        <text>Having proven your worth to the Crone, she has entrusted you with a fraction of her power. You then gain the following benefits.

Timeless Being. You can no longer die from old age. However, you still visibly age normally.

Evil Eye. You can cast the Bane spell at a level equal to your Pact Magic slot level without expending a spell slot. Additionally, when you cast it this way, the spell affects only one target, and does not require any verbal, somatic or material components. Finally, as a Reaction to rolling Initiative, you can cast the Bane spell.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 110 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Herbarium (The Old Crone (HB))</name>
        <text>The Old Crone has granted you the ability to cultivate and preserve the souls of the departed. You gain a mystical herbarium that can contain a number of souls equal to your Warlock level. You can summon or dismiss the herbarium as a Magic Action. You can also use the herbarium as a spellcasting focus.
	As a Magic Action, you can touch the body of a creature that has died within the last minute and harvest its soul, adding it to your herbarium. The soul appears as a spectral impression pressed between the pages, similar to a dried flower. If you attempt to harvest a soul when your herbarium is full, you must choose an existing soul to release. You can also release a specific soul as a Magic Action.
	When you cast a spell that is not a cantrip, you can, as a Reaction, empower it by expending any number of souls from your herbarium. Consult the Herbarium Effects table below to determine the effects of a spell empowered in this way, based on the number of souls expended.

Herbarium Effects:
Number of Souls | Effect
2 | You gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your Warlock level
7 | The target has Disadvantage on its saving throw
13 | You gain the effects of an Eldritch Invocation that you meet the prerequisites for, which last until you finish a Long Rest

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 110 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: The Underlord (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: The Underlord (HB)</name>
        <text>Warlocks of the Underlord rarely enter into a pact of their own accord. Instead, they are chosen by Belegorn, high ruler of Gloomlight and the underworld. In his infinite wisdom, the Treefather anoints mortal souls as emissaries of his will, charged with reserving balance in the living world and shepherding those who would defy death back into his domain. This task also coincides with containing Belegorn's daughter, Kogha—the Murrain Maiden whose minions, cursed with unlife, undermine the Treefather's domain.
	Some of those chosen naturally drifted into the underworld as souls, only to be sent back reshaped by his hand. Others descended into Gloomlight deep enough to hear his reverberating voice and were remade by its truth. As stern and unyielding as the peaks of the Mountain Sculptor himself, they now walk the land as agents of balance, striking down oath-breakers and the profane who would disturb the natural order—for good or ill. Forever tied to the earth, they feel the soft hum of Belegorn's will echoing through the endless caverns of the Gloomlight beneath Zamanora.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 111 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Underlord Spells (The Underlord (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Warlock level specified in the Underlord Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Underlord Spells:
Warlock level | Spells
3 | Thunderwave, Shield, Silence, Warding Bond
5 | Glyph of Warding, Meld into Stone
7 | Resilient Sphere, Stoneskin
9 | Legend Lore, Wall of Stone

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 112 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Indomitable Mountain (The Underlord (HB))</name>
        <text>Whenever you connect to the earth on a deeper level, you gain heightened senses and endurance. While you maintain Concentration on a spell, you gain Tremorsense with a range of 30 feet and Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage that you take is reduced by an amount equal to your Proficiency Bonus.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 112 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: One with the Earth (The Underlord (HB))</name>
        <text>Your kinship with the earth and its metals grows. You gain proficiency with Medium armor and shields made of metal. In addition, your first attack against an enemy during each of your turns has Advantage, as long as you are both standing on solid ground.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 112 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Awaken the Titan (The Underlord (HB))</name>
        <text>You can awaken a small fragment of your patron's powers. As a Magic Action, you can imbue yourself with the power of the ageless mountains for 1 minute. The effect ends early if you gain the Incapacitated condition. While this effect is active, you gain the following benefits:

Echoing Strike. Your attacks send out powerful shockwaves. Each time you hit a target, it and every creature in a 15-foot Cone behind it, must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, a creature takes 3d6 Bludgeoning damage and is knocked Prone. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and isn't knocked Prone.

Might of the Mountain. You gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your spellcasting ability modifier at the start of each of your turns.

Skin of Bedrock. Indomitable Mountain reduces all damage except Psychic damage.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 112 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Awaken the Titan</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>The Underlord (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Kingdom of Belegorn (The Underlord (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain the ability to permanently imprison a creature deep within the earth. You can cast the Force Cage spell once, without expending a spell slot. A trapped creature must make a Wisdom saving throw at the end of every turn it remains within the cage. If the target fails three of these saves, it falls under the effects of the Imprisonment spell (burial option).
	You can use this feature once, regaining its usage after 7 days. You can regain its usage early if you willingly free a creature previously trapped by Imprisonment in this way.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 112 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Kingdom of Belegorn</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Underlord (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Thoughts [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hex [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Identify [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mirror Image [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bestow Curse [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tiny Hut [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Black Tentacles [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Polymorph [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Modify Memory [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Teleportation Circle [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Old Crone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Thunderwave [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shield [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Silence [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Warding Bond [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Glyph of Warding [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Meld Into Stone [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Resilient Sphere [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Stoneskin [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Legend Lore [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Stone [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Underlord (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Poison and Disease [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Person [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ray of Enfeeblement [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ray of Sickness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Animate Dead [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Speak with Dead [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blight [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Patchwork Restoration (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cloudkill [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Insect Plague [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (The Murrain Maiden (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
