<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Druid [2024]</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Veilmark Information (Zamanora)</name>
        <text>It is said that trespassing upon the spirit world leaves a tangible brand on one's body and soul. Mortals should never peer beyond the Veil, lest the spirits take notice and mark them forevermore. Let a marked person into your home and you invite certain calamity. The lands of Zamanora are riddled with such fiction and cautionary tales that only work to paint those who are inquisitive in a bad light. Yet they are right about one thing; someone who interacts with the Hidden World too often is bound to be "marked".

As characters engage in encounters with curses, spirits, and other supernatural phenomena, they accrue Veilmark. This attribute reflects their growing connection to the spirit realm and the transformative effects of these experiences on their physical and spiritual selves. Veilmarked is the term used by the Zamanori to describe individuals who have thus changed, and denotes characters who have accrued enough Veilmark to cross a threshold. If playing in a different setting, you may use the broader term Aura to describe the system.
	The influence of Veilmark on a character is determined by their Veilmark Score. The more a character interacts with curses, spirits, and other supernatural phenomena, delving into the mysteries of the Hidden World, the more their Veilmark Score increases. A character's Veilmark Score is effectively a pool of innate power they may tap into in order to produce certain effects that aid them when interacting with spiritual entities. However, at the same time, the higher one's Veilmark Score is, the more otherworldly they feel when interacting with their peers, making them wary and distrustful of their presence.
	Characters start out with a Veilmark Score of 0, which may increase up to a maximum of 100 throughout a campaign. Certain features, such as the Veilborn Origin (see Chapter II: Origins), or the Veilscarred Barbarian's Dark Bargain and Willow's Embrace (see Chapter II: Subclasses), signify that a character has already been extensively exposed to the Hidden World and influence that character's starting Veilmark Score according to their description.

Gaining Veilmark:
An increase of Veilmark results in noticeable physical changes, signifying the character's deepening connection with the spirit realm. Every time a character's Veilmark modifier increases, roll on the table below or choose one of the physical alterations listed to manifest on them.
	Your Veilmark Score may increase every time you experience an event that severely impacts your psyche by challenging what you priorly thought was real. Interacting with a being you believed to be a mere folktale, falling victim to a vicious curse, or drinking water from a bewitched spring can all increase your Veilmark Score. Such an experience, along with the implications caused upon oneself due to it, is known as a Harrow.
	A Harrow may affect a single or multiple characters at once, and at different levels of Severity (see Harrows table), based on roleplay and the narrative course of the story. For example, when a stranger who asks to share in the warmth of the party's campfire is later revealed to be a malign spirit, every character present may be subjected to a Harrow of Considerable level; yet for a character who recognizes the spirit as that of a deceased relative of theirs, the same Harrow may qualify as Intense. At the same time, another character who has already dabbled in occult practices to a point of communing with the spirits of the dead may treat this as a Harrow of Inconsequential level. The Severity of a Harrow on a character's psyche, as well as which character is subject to the risk of gaining Veilmark due to it and which isn't, is determined by the Storyteller, according to their interpretation of the player characters' backgrounds, stories, personalities, and any circumstantial factors that apply to each occasion.
	When the Storyteller declares a Harrow, each character that is subject to it must choose whether they wish to Resist or Embrace it. This choice represents their disposition towards the supernatural world, and their openness towards its truths and mysteries.

Reisting Veilmark:
A character who chooses to Resist a Harrow makes a Wisdom saving throw against a DC determined by its Severity. On a success, the experience leaves them unaffected, and nothing happens. On a failure, they must roll the corresponding Veilmark Die. Their Veilmark Score becomes increased by an amount equal to the result. A Hero that succeeds on their Action without Consequences resists the Harrow completely, taking no increase to their Veilmark Score. Otherwise, the Hero rolls the corresponding amount of Veilmark dice. A Success with Consequences means that the Hero's Veilmark increases by an amount equal to half of their result. A roll that only results in Consequences means that the Hero's Veilmark score is increased by the total amount rolled. You may also employ special means, such as the Veil Charm item (see Chapter IV: Fabled Relics), in order to better your chances in resisting any unwanted increases in your Veilmark Score.

Embracing Veilmark:
A character who chooses to Embrace a Harrow forgoes making any attempts at resisting its effects and does not roll the corresponding Veilmark Die. That character's Veilmark Score automatically increases by the maximum amount possible.

Veilmark:
d6 | Veilmark Die | DC | Status Tier
1 | 1d6 | 10 | harrowing-1
2 | 2d6 | 15 | harrowing-2
3 | 3d6 | 20 | harrowing-3
4 | 4d6 | 25 | harrowing-4
5 | 5d6 | 30 | harrowing-5

Veilmark Thresholds:
Whenever a Harrow causes your Veilmark Score to increase beyond the thresholds of 25, 50, 75 and 99 for the first time, you gain a Veilmark Transformation. For every Veilmark Transformation that you have, you gain a cumulative -2 penalty to any Influence Actions you take against other non-Veilmarked Humanoids and Beasts, unless you are trying to intimidate them.

Veilmark Thresholds Table:
Threshold | Title
25 | Shadowlit
50 | Equinoctial
75 | Moonstruck
99 | Spiritwalker

Transformations &amp; Powers:
Veilmark transformations are a physical manifestation of the Hidden World's effects on your body. Such a transformation is a consequence of your innate understanding of the supernatural and ability to harness the powers that lie within, but ultimately comes at a cost. The first time you cross each of those Veilmark Thresholds, you gain a Veilmark Transformation and two new Veilmark Abilities from the tables below. For every Veilmark Transformation you have, you gain a cumulative -2 penalty to any Influence Actions you take against other non-Veilmarked Humanoids and Beasts, unless you are trying to intimidate them.

When you gain a new Veilmark Transformation, roll on the table below to determine its nature. If the result is a Transformation you have already undergone, roll again until you get a new one. Once you gain a Veilmark Transformation, it remains with you permanently, even if your Veilmark Score later decreases below that threshold.

Veilmark Transformations Table:
d10 | Transformation
1 | One of your eyes changes color. At night, when the Veil grows thin, you glimpse visions from the other side. This distraction grants you Disadvantage on Initiative rolls during nighttime hours.
2 | A streak of silver appears on your hair. Silvered weapons deal an extra Damage Die to you.
3 | Your skin's complexion becomes a tone paler. Whenever you take Fire damage you take an additional 1d4 Fire damage.
4 | Veins throughout your body become visibly dark beneath your skin. While you are Bloodied and can see an enemy, you can't willingly move away from them.
5 | Your shadow changes to resemble that of a different being. The Attitude of Beasts towards you worsens by one stage.
6 | A strange marking brands your skin like a scar. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Curses.
7 | A strange marking brands your skin like a scar. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Curses.
8 | A Zagovory symbol appears on your tongue. Whenever you fail an Influence Action, it is treated as attempted Intimidation regardless of your intentions.
9 | You appear sickly and weak. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Diseases.
10 | You no longer cast a reflection. You are excluded from beneficial effects caused by spells that target multiple creatures.

Every time you cross a Veilmark threshold, you unlock two new abilities, as detailed in the Veilmark Abilities table. You may use the abilities gained from each threshold a combined total of two times per day. For example, you may use one ability twice, or each ability once. Unlike Transformations, Veilmark Abilities do not last indefinitely. If your Veilmark Score falls below the Threshold that granted you these abilities (see Losing Veilmark), they become dormant and cannot be used until your Veilmark Score rises above the corresponding Threshold again.

Veilmark Threshold Abilities:

Shadowlit:

Detect Spirit. You cast the spell Spirit Sense, without expending a spell slot.

Incorporeal Reach. As a Bonus Action, your attacks harm the very essence of spirits for the next minute. For the duration, once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 Force damage to a target you hit with an attack or spell.

Equinoctial:

Exorcism. As an Action, you touch a creature and end one of the following effects currently afflicting it: Frightened, Charmed, or a Possession.

Pierce the Veil. As part of a successful Study Action made against a creature of the Spirit subtype, you discern either of the following: its Immunities, Resistances or Vulnerabilities.

Moonstruck:

Soul Harvest. As a Reaction to a creature dying within 30 feet of you, you can infuse yourself with a fragment of its departing essence. As a result, you may choose to either regain a number of expended spell slots as a 4th-level Wizard using the Arcane Recovery feature, or gain 25 Temporary Hit Points.

Spiritual Kinship. When you fail a saving throw against a spell or magical effect caused by a creature of the Spirit subtype, you succeed instead.

Spiritwalker:

Ethereal Echo. As an Action, you create an ethereal duplicate of yourself that lasts for 1 minute. This spectral reflection appears in your space and mimics your movements precisely, with an almost imperceptible delay. The echo has half your current Hit Points. When you make an attack that deals damage to a single target, your echo repeats the attack but only deals half damage (rounded down). The echo takes the same damage as you do when you are damaged. It cannot regain Hit Points and vanishes if it reaches 0 Hit Points, you become Incapacitated, or when the duration ends.

Tether Soul. By spending an hour in meditation, you bind your soul to a clearly defined point that you can see in your environment; for example, the hollow of an oak tree, or a statue made of stone. If you die before your next Long Rest, you gain the effects of the Reincarnate spell, but your new species is Haunt (see Chapter II: Species), while your new body forms in the bound point based on the materials it consists of. If you successfully return to life in this way, your Veilmark Score is reduced to 0 and you lose any Veilmark Transformations you have.

Losing Veilmark:
Once you have been exposed to the challenging truths of the Hidden World, it is very difficult, if indeed possible at all, to forget them. However, there are ways to reduce its impact on your being. The diminishing of one's Veilmark represents a retreat from the otherworldly, a return to the mundane, and a fixated anchoring to the Real. Below are the ways you may employ to reduce your Veilmark Score.

Downtime Activity:
You may choose to detach yourself from the supernatural by indulging in mundane activities for extended periods. For every month or Sojourn you spend this way, your Veilmark Score decreases by 5. Examples of such activities include:

	• Engaging with a community in manual labor, such as aiding in the building of a home.

	• Exploring and cultivating deep emotional bonds with others through steady everyday life.

	• Spending time alone to reflect upon yourself, or pursue artistic creations.

Recreation:
Other than spending time in peace and tranquility, you may also pursue more radical methods to reduce your Veilmark Score. These include consuming a God Flesh mushroom (see Chapter IV: Zamanoran Mushrooms), meditating within the Gemstone Caverns, or bathing in the waters of a lake within the Three Nines Forest. While such methods are the swiftest and most potent ways to achieve the intended result, they may carry certain hazards and must be undertaken with caution.

Potent Arcana:
Employing powerful magic, such as an archmage's spell of wishing, or returning to life through use of a Tether Soul (see Veilmark Abilities above) can reduce your Veilmark Score to 0, as well as remove any Veilmark Transformations you have. Once you surpass a Veilmark Threshold and gain a Veilmark Transformation, it remains with you permanently, even if your Veilmark Score later decreases below that threshold. Only Potent Arcana may remove a Veilmark Transformation. These transformations continue to affect both your body and soul, even if you disguise yourself through the means of illusory magic or a shape-changing ability. However, if your score increases again past a threshold you've previously crossed, you won't gain additional transformations for that same threshold. During a campaign in which you want to make the Veilmark system less punishing, you may rule that the effects of Greater Restoration also remove the effects of a Veilmark Transformation from a character. Conversely, reducing your Veilmark below each Threshold means that you lose access to the corresponding Abilities, as detailed above.

Roleplaying Veilmark:
As your Veilmark increases, consider how these changes affect your character's personality and demeanor. Do you welcome them as a mark of growth, or do you view them as aberrations upon your appearance? Consider how your personality might change to reflect them. You might become more aloof, skittish, or stoic. You may pick up a repetitive habit or mannerism. Perhaps the weight of the spirit world will deeply affect your psyche, gradually changing you into an altogether different person.

Social Implications:
In small communities such as the villages of Zamanora, these physical changes can lead to fear, reverence, or superstition. Characters bearing those marks are considered branded by the spirits, influencing their interactions with NPCs.

Fear and Distrust:
In most organized communities, the appearance of a Veilmarked stranger is met with apprehension, the locals fearing the character and associating their marks with bad omens or curses. Otherworldly features in their appearance might put the common folk ill at ease, but beyond that, their mere presence is unsettling for reasons that cannot be interpreted directly, as they carry the stigma of the Hidden World. A character with more than a couple of Veilmark transformations is usually treated as a Spook by common folk who first encounter them. Superstitious folk may be wary of such characters and treat them with extreme caution, to the point of turning them into a pariah amongst their societies or even chasing them away.

Reverence and Respect:
In the dwellings of spirits, or places where their presence is strongly felt, denizens might see the marks as a sign of a blessed or powerful individual, offering assistance or seeking their aid. In such cases, according to the Storyteller's discretion, the penalties to Influence Actions normally associated with Veilmark Transformations may become bonuses instead.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 120 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Transformation">1d10</roll>
        <roll description="Fire Damage">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Force Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Druid Subclass: Circle of the Berendei (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Druid Subclass: Circle of the Berendei (HB)</name>
        <text>While the curse of shapeshifting is feared across the realm as the ultimate act of divine punishment, the Druids of the sacred Circle of the Berendei embrace it willingly as a blessing. Capable of assuming the forms of ferocious werebears, the Berendei employ the gifts of Belegorn to the service of their god. They zealously act to maintain balance between the Real and the Hidden World, combat accursed lycanthropes and shepherd the souls of the departed onto Nav, bearing the primal powers of death while warding the cycle of life. The Zamanori view the Berendei as benevolent symbols of great reverence, believing them to speak with the voice of the Treefather himself, as they bestow righteous justice upon the wicked and the profane, while alleviating the pain of the wrongly afflicted.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 72 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Circle of the Berendei Spells (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Druid level specified in the Circle of the Berendei Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Circle of the Berendei Spells:
Druid Level | Prepared Spells
3 | Ancestral Guidance*, Augury, Guidance, Inflict Wounds, Protection from Evil and Good
5 | Bestow Curse, Remove Curse
7 | Banishment, Spirit Sense*
9 | Dispel Evil and Good, Reincarnate

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 73 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hybrid Form (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</name>
        <text>You embrace the primal gifts of Belegorn. As a Bonus Action you can expend a use of your Wild Shape feature to take on a hybrid form of a werebear. Each time you do so, instead of following the transformation rules of Wild Shape, you gain the following benefit:

Berendei Magic. You can cast spells normally while benefiting from this feature.

Bestial Senses. You gain Advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.

Enhanced Fortitude. You gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to twice your Druid level plus your Wisdom modifier.

Natural Weapons. You gain the hybrid form's natural weapons.

Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: Proficiency Bonus + Strength modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d10 + Strength modifier Piercing damage.

Claw. Melee Weapon Attack: Proficiency Bonus + Strength modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d8 + Strength modifier Slashing damage.

Ursine Physique. Your Strength score changes to 19, your Dexterity score changes to 10 and your Constitution score changes to 17. In addition, you can use any equipment your hybrid form would normally allow, such as weapons or appropriate armor.

You can remain in this hybrid form indefinitely, or revert back to your true form by using a Bonus Action. If you die, you also revert back to your true form. You can speak and cast spells while in your hybrid form.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 73 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d10+%1</roll>
        <roll description="Slashing Damage">1d8+%1</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Ursine Pilgrim (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</name>
        <text>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack Action on your turn while in your hybrid form (but only once using your Bite for your extra attack). When you attack a Bloodied creature, your natural weapons can score a Critical Hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20. Additionally, each of your natural weapon attacks can deal its normal damage type or Necrotic damage. You make this choice each time you hit with those attacks.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 73 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Grimclaw (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</name>
        <text>The potency of your power over the cycle of life and death grows. While in your hybrid form, you gain natural armor, increasing your AC by a number equal to the maximum number of your Wild Shape uses. Additionally, your natural weapon attacks deal bonus Necrotic damage equal to your Wisdom modifier.
	Finally, when you score a Critical Hit while in your hybrid form, the target also suffers the effects of the Bestow Curse spell. If this occurs while you are concentrating on another spell, you must choose which spell you wish to maintain Concentration on.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 74 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Roots of the Sacred Tree (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</name>
        <text>The wrath of the gods incarnates through your very form. As a true gatekeeper of the Underworld, the spirits of the realm brace you when you are about to fall. Upon being reduced to 0 Hit Points but not killed outright, you cast the Spirit Guardians spell (at Level 5, Necrotic damage) without expending a spell slot. You do not need to be conscious or concentrate to maintain this effect. Whenever a creature takes damage from this effect, you regain a number of Hit Points equal to half of the Necrotic damage dealt. This effect ends if you die.
	Once you have used this feature once, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 74 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Roots of the Sacred Tree</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Berendei (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Druid Subclass: Circle of the Long Night (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Druid Subclass: Circle of the Long Night (HB)</name>
        <text>Druids of the Circle of the Long Night embody the harshness of winter and the fears that dwell within its unending black nights. They embrace the stillness and dormancy it brings to the world; a necessary struggle before allowing for rebirth and growth in the spring. A time when only the wise and the strong survive, necessary for the cycles of death and rebirth, growth and decay.
	Druids of this circle understand that the cold and scarcity are no less important than the fear the night brings, as powerful harbingers of change. They become living horrors that showcase the most savage and relentless side of nature or use fear as a means to ignite transformation in others, helping them emerge stronger and more enlightened. To those ends they become the mare in nightmare, the beast of ill omen, the horror that lurks just beyond sight.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 75 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Circle of the Long Night Spells (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Druid level specified in the Circle of the Long Night Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Circle of the Long Night Spells:
Druid Level | Prepared Spells
3 | Dissonant Whispers, Elementalism, Find Steed (Fiend), Ice Knife, Mirror Image
5 | Fear, Sleet Storm
7 | Ice Storm, Phantasmal Killer
9 | Deepening Gloom*, Dream

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 76 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hoarfrost (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</name>
        <text>Your presence brings the touch of cold with you. As a Bonus Action, you can activate your Hoarfrost for 1 minute. While this aura is active, creatures of your choice within a 15-foot Emanation that surrounds you take Cold damage equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1) at the start of each of their turns. Creatures in Dim Light or Darkness within the Emanation take additional Psychic damage equal to the Cold damage and have Disadvantage on saving throws made to avoid or end the Frightened condition.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 76 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Hoarfrost</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Long Night (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <counter>
        <name>Hoarfrost</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Long Night (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Shape of Nightmares (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</name>
        <text>You can use your Wild Shape to assume the form of creatures that embody the deepest fears of your enemies. When you use your Wild Shape, you can choose to assume the form of a creature that a target within 60 feet of you fears most (at the Storyteller's discretion) for 10 minutes, or until you choose to end it (no action required). Your physical shape does not alter, as this feature only affects the way that the target perceives you. For the duration of the effect, you can use a Bonus Action to change its target. Creatures with Truesight ignore this feature's effects.
	While you are in this form, you gain the following benefits against the target creature:

Frigid Fear. The first time it sees you in this form, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition. A Frightened creature takes the Dash Action and moves away from you by the safest route on each of its turns unless there is nowhere to move. If the creature ends its turn in a space where it doesn't have line of sight to you, the creature makes a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the effect ends on that creature.

Inescapable Horrors. While the creature is not Frightened of you but can see you, you can use a Bonus Action to force it to repeat its initial Wisdom save.

Of Weak Mind. The first time on a turn you damage a creature that is Frightened of you, it takes an extra 2d10 Psychic damage.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 76 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Psychic Damage">2d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Hoarfrost</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Long Night (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Desolation's Grasp (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</name>
        <text>The frigid magic within you, awakens feelings of isolation and its chilling grasp deepens. Whenever you deal Cold damage to a creature, it is no longer considered a willing target for other creatures' spells and effects until the start of your next turn. Additionally, creatures that start their turn within Hoarfrost have their Speed halved and lose any immunities to the Frightened condition until the start of their next turn.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 76 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Hoarfrost</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Long Night (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Cold Night's Embrace (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</name>
        <text>Call upon the dark grasp of winter to snuff the light in an area. As a Magic Action, you can submerge an area with a 120-foot radius Emanation centered on you into shadow. The shadows last for 10 minutes or until you dismiss them as a Bonus Action. While this shadow persists, all color is drained away, leaving everything in shades of black and white. You and creatures of your choice treat this area as Dim Light, while enemies perceive the area as Darkness. If Hoarfrost is active while you are within this area, its effects extend to the entire radius of this Emanation.
	You can use this feature once, regaining its usage after finishing a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 77 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Scion of Morana (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</name>
        <text>Like the beast of prophecy devouring the sun, your magic can plunge the world into darkness. You can cast the Control Weather spell without expending a spell slot and without needing to maintain Concentration. When casting this spell and changing the weather conditions in this way, you can also change the lighting within the affected area by one step for the duration.
	You can use this feature once, regaining its usage after 7 days.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 77 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Cold Night's Embrace</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Long Night (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Hoarfrost</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Long Night (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Druid Subclass: Circle of the Oakenheart (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Druid Subclass: Circle of the Oakenheart (HB)</name>
        <text>Druids of the Circle of the Oakenheart embody the harsh reality of the deep woods. They are the will of the wild in its most unyielding and merciless form. To them, the natural world and the mortal one are two separate realms: the first ancient and deliberate, shaped into balance through eons of growth, the second fleeting and restless, forever in flux. They believe the wild does not mingle with civilization, and though some crossing is inevitable, there are some places that brook no trespass.
	Often solitary onlookers, these Druids rarely intervene in social affairs unless the forest itself is imperiled. To the Zamanori, they exist in cautionary tales, warning against braving the unknown weald; for a single transgression may be the difference between an Oakenheart leading a wayfarer safely through the woods, or drowning them in unforgiving soil.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 78 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Circle Spells (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Druid level specified in the Circle of the Oakenheart Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared. In addition, you can cast the spells from this feature while you're in a Wild Shape form.

Circle of the Oakenheart Spells:
Druid Level | Prepared Spells
3 | Barkskin, Ensnaring Strike, Shillelagh
5 | Speak with Plants
7 | Woodland Awakening*
9 | Tree Stride

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 78 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Wrath of the Wildwood (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</name>
        <text>You draw upon the primal powers of nature to enhance your forms. When you use Wild Shape, you can expend a spell slot to empower your new form, granting you the benefits below.

Creature Type. You can choose to transform into a Plant form that you have learned instead.

Challenge Rating. The maximum Challenge Rating for the form equals the level of the spell slot you expended.

Thirsting Roots. Whenever another creature within 10 feet of you becomes Bloodied or drops to 0 Hit Points, you regain Hit Points equal to your Druid level.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 79 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Breaking Boughs (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</name>
        <text>As your attunement to the grim woods of Zamanora increases, so does your strength. While in a Wild Shape form, your melee attacks may target one additional creature within your reach that is adjacent to the original target. You compare the same attack roll against each targeted creature's AC.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 79 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: One with the Land (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</name>
        <text>You have learned to become a conduit for the power of the earth. While you are in Wild Shape form, you can use a Bonus Action to root yourself into the ground, gaining the following benefits:

Immovable. Your Speed becomes 0. You can't be knocked Prone or be forcibly moved.

Rootsnare. You create a 10-foot Emanation of grasping thorns and roots. This area is Difficult Terrain. Any creature of your choice that starts its turn there or enters it for the first time during its turn takes Piercing damage equal to your Wisdom modifier.

Unbreaking. Your Armor Class becomes 20, unless already higher.

Your rooted state lasts for 1 minute or until you choose to uproot yourself (Bonus Action). You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses of this ability when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 79 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>One with the Land</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Oakenheart (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: The Deep Dark Woods (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain the ability to banish a creature into the darkest corners of the deepwood. As a Magic Action, you can force a creature within your reach to make a Charisma saving throw, suffering the effects of the Maze spell on a failure. While a creature is inside your maze it also suffers the effects of your Rootsnare feature. To navigate the labyrinthine woods and escape, a creature must succeed on an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC (instead of 20).
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 79 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Ancestral Guidance (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Augury [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Guidance [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Inflict Wounds [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Protection from Evil and Good [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bestow Curse [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Remove Curse [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Banishment [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spirit Sense (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Evil and Good [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Reincarnate [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Berendei (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dissonant Whispers [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Elementalism [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Find Steed (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ice Knife [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mirror Image [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fear [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sleet Storm [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ice Storm [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Killer [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Deepening Gloom (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dream [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Long Night (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Barkskin [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ensnaring Strike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shillelagh [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Speak with Plants [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Woodland Awakening (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tree Stride [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of the Oakenheart (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
