<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric [2024]</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Veilmark Information (Zamanora)</name>
        <text>It is said that trespassing upon the spirit world leaves a tangible brand on one's body and soul. Mortals should never peer beyond the Veil, lest the spirits take notice and mark them forevermore. Let a marked person into your home and you invite certain calamity. The lands of Zamanora are riddled with such fiction and cautionary tales that only work to paint those who are inquisitive in a bad light. Yet they are right about one thing; someone who interacts with the Hidden World too often is bound to be "marked".

As characters engage in encounters with curses, spirits, and other supernatural phenomena, they accrue Veilmark. This attribute reflects their growing connection to the spirit realm and the transformative effects of these experiences on their physical and spiritual selves. Veilmarked is the term used by the Zamanori to describe individuals who have thus changed, and denotes characters who have accrued enough Veilmark to cross a threshold. If playing in a different setting, you may use the broader term Aura to describe the system.
	The influence of Veilmark on a character is determined by their Veilmark Score. The more a character interacts with curses, spirits, and other supernatural phenomena, delving into the mysteries of the Hidden World, the more their Veilmark Score increases. A character's Veilmark Score is effectively a pool of innate power they may tap into in order to produce certain effects that aid them when interacting with spiritual entities. However, at the same time, the higher one's Veilmark Score is, the more otherworldly they feel when interacting with their peers, making them wary and distrustful of their presence.
	Characters start out with a Veilmark Score of 0, which may increase up to a maximum of 100 throughout a campaign. Certain features, such as the Veilborn Origin (see Chapter II: Origins), or the Veilscarred Barbarian's Dark Bargain and Willow's Embrace (see Chapter II: Subclasses), signify that a character has already been extensively exposed to the Hidden World and influence that character's starting Veilmark Score according to their description.

Gaining Veilmark:
An increase of Veilmark results in noticeable physical changes, signifying the character's deepening connection with the spirit realm. Every time a character's Veilmark modifier increases, roll on the table below or choose one of the physical alterations listed to manifest on them.
	Your Veilmark Score may increase every time you experience an event that severely impacts your psyche by challenging what you priorly thought was real. Interacting with a being you believed to be a mere folktale, falling victim to a vicious curse, or drinking water from a bewitched spring can all increase your Veilmark Score. Such an experience, along with the implications caused upon oneself due to it, is known as a Harrow.
	A Harrow may affect a single or multiple characters at once, and at different levels of Severity (see Harrows table), based on roleplay and the narrative course of the story. For example, when a stranger who asks to share in the warmth of the party's campfire is later revealed to be a malign spirit, every character present may be subjected to a Harrow of Considerable level; yet for a character who recognizes the spirit as that of a deceased relative of theirs, the same Harrow may qualify as Intense. At the same time, another character who has already dabbled in occult practices to a point of communing with the spirits of the dead may treat this as a Harrow of Inconsequential level. The Severity of a Harrow on a character's psyche, as well as which character is subject to the risk of gaining Veilmark due to it and which isn't, is determined by the Storyteller, according to their interpretation of the player characters' backgrounds, stories, personalities, and any circumstantial factors that apply to each occasion.
	When the Storyteller declares a Harrow, each character that is subject to it must choose whether they wish to Resist or Embrace it. This choice represents their disposition towards the supernatural world, and their openness towards its truths and mysteries.

Reisting Veilmark:
A character who chooses to Resist a Harrow makes a Wisdom saving throw against a DC determined by its Severity. On a success, the experience leaves them unaffected, and nothing happens. On a failure, they must roll the corresponding Veilmark Die. Their Veilmark Score becomes increased by an amount equal to the result. A Hero that succeeds on their Action without Consequences resists the Harrow completely, taking no increase to their Veilmark Score. Otherwise, the Hero rolls the corresponding amount of Veilmark dice. A Success with Consequences means that the Hero's Veilmark increases by an amount equal to half of their result. A roll that only results in Consequences means that the Hero's Veilmark score is increased by the total amount rolled. You may also employ special means, such as the Veil Charm item (see Chapter IV: Fabled Relics), in order to better your chances in resisting any unwanted increases in your Veilmark Score.

Embracing Veilmark:
A character who chooses to Embrace a Harrow forgoes making any attempts at resisting its effects and does not roll the corresponding Veilmark Die. That character's Veilmark Score automatically increases by the maximum amount possible.

Veilmark:
d6 | Veilmark Die | DC | Status Tier
1 | 1d6 | 10 | harrowing-1
2 | 2d6 | 15 | harrowing-2
3 | 3d6 | 20 | harrowing-3
4 | 4d6 | 25 | harrowing-4
5 | 5d6 | 30 | harrowing-5

Veilmark Thresholds:
Whenever a Harrow causes your Veilmark Score to increase beyond the thresholds of 25, 50, 75 and 99 for the first time, you gain a Veilmark Transformation. For every Veilmark Transformation that you have, you gain a cumulative -2 penalty to any Influence Actions you take against other non-Veilmarked Humanoids and Beasts, unless you are trying to intimidate them.

Veilmark Thresholds Table:
Threshold | Title
25 | Shadowlit
50 | Equinoctial
75 | Moonstruck
99 | Spiritwalker

Transformations &amp; Powers:
Veilmark transformations are a physical manifestation of the Hidden World's effects on your body. Such a transformation is a consequence of your innate understanding of the supernatural and ability to harness the powers that lie within, but ultimately comes at a cost. The first time you cross each of those Veilmark Thresholds, you gain a Veilmark Transformation and two new Veilmark Abilities from the tables below. For every Veilmark Transformation you have, you gain a cumulative -2 penalty to any Influence Actions you take against other non-Veilmarked Humanoids and Beasts, unless you are trying to intimidate them.

When you gain a new Veilmark Transformation, roll on the table below to determine its nature. If the result is a Transformation you have already undergone, roll again until you get a new one. Once you gain a Veilmark Transformation, it remains with you permanently, even if your Veilmark Score later decreases below that threshold.

Veilmark Transformations Table:
d10 | Transformation
1 | One of your eyes changes color. At night, when the Veil grows thin, you glimpse visions from the other side. This distraction grants you Disadvantage on Initiative rolls during nighttime hours.
2 | A streak of silver appears on your hair. Silvered weapons deal an extra Damage Die to you.
3 | Your skin's complexion becomes a tone paler. Whenever you take Fire damage you take an additional 1d4 Fire damage.
4 | Veins throughout your body become visibly dark beneath your skin. While you are Bloodied and can see an enemy, you can't willingly move away from them.
5 | Your shadow changes to resemble that of a different being. The Attitude of Beasts towards you worsens by one stage.
6 | A strange marking brands your skin like a scar. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Curses.
7 | A strange marking brands your skin like a scar. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Curses.
8 | A Zagovory symbol appears on your tongue. Whenever you fail an Influence Action, it is treated as attempted Intimidation regardless of your intentions.
9 | You appear sickly and weak. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Diseases.
10 | You no longer cast a reflection. You are excluded from beneficial effects caused by spells that target multiple creatures.

Every time you cross a Veilmark threshold, you unlock two new abilities, as detailed in the Veilmark Abilities table. You may use the abilities gained from each threshold a combined total of two times per day. For example, you may use one ability twice, or each ability once. Unlike Transformations, Veilmark Abilities do not last indefinitely. If your Veilmark Score falls below the Threshold that granted you these abilities (see Losing Veilmark), they become dormant and cannot be used until your Veilmark Score rises above the corresponding Threshold again.

Veilmark Threshold Abilities:

Shadowlit:

Detect Spirit. You cast the spell Spirit Sense, without expending a spell slot.

Incorporeal Reach. As a Bonus Action, your attacks harm the very essence of spirits for the next minute. For the duration, once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 Force damage to a target you hit with an attack or spell.

Equinoctial:

Exorcism. As an Action, you touch a creature and end one of the following effects currently afflicting it: Frightened, Charmed, or a Possession.

Pierce the Veil. As part of a successful Study Action made against a creature of the Spirit subtype, you discern either of the following: its Immunities, Resistances or Vulnerabilities.

Moonstruck:

Soul Harvest. As a Reaction to a creature dying within 30 feet of you, you can infuse yourself with a fragment of its departing essence. As a result, you may choose to either regain a number of expended spell slots as a 4th-level Wizard using the Arcane Recovery feature, or gain 25 Temporary Hit Points.

Spiritual Kinship. When you fail a saving throw against a spell or magical effect caused by a creature of the Spirit subtype, you succeed instead.

Spiritwalker:

Ethereal Echo. As an Action, you create an ethereal duplicate of yourself that lasts for 1 minute. This spectral reflection appears in your space and mimics your movements precisely, with an almost imperceptible delay. The echo has half your current Hit Points. When you make an attack that deals damage to a single target, your echo repeats the attack but only deals half damage (rounded down). The echo takes the same damage as you do when you are damaged. It cannot regain Hit Points and vanishes if it reaches 0 Hit Points, you become Incapacitated, or when the duration ends.

Tether Soul. By spending an hour in meditation, you bind your soul to a clearly defined point that you can see in your environment; for example, the hollow of an oak tree, or a statue made of stone. If you die before your next Long Rest, you gain the effects of the Reincarnate spell, but your new species is Haunt (see Chapter II: Species), while your new body forms in the bound point based on the materials it consists of. If you successfully return to life in this way, your Veilmark Score is reduced to 0 and you lose any Veilmark Transformations you have.

Losing Veilmark:
Once you have been exposed to the challenging truths of the Hidden World, it is very difficult, if indeed possible at all, to forget them. However, there are ways to reduce its impact on your being. The diminishing of one's Veilmark represents a retreat from the otherworldly, a return to the mundane, and a fixated anchoring to the Real. Below are the ways you may employ to reduce your Veilmark Score.

Downtime Activity:
You may choose to detach yourself from the supernatural by indulging in mundane activities for extended periods. For every month or Sojourn you spend this way, your Veilmark Score decreases by 5. Examples of such activities include:

	• Engaging with a community in manual labor, such as aiding in the building of a home.

	• Exploring and cultivating deep emotional bonds with others through steady everyday life.

	• Spending time alone to reflect upon yourself, or pursue artistic creations.

Recreation:
Other than spending time in peace and tranquility, you may also pursue more radical methods to reduce your Veilmark Score. These include consuming a God Flesh mushroom (see Chapter IV: Zamanoran Mushrooms), meditating within the Gemstone Caverns, or bathing in the waters of a lake within the Three Nines Forest. While such methods are the swiftest and most potent ways to achieve the intended result, they may carry certain hazards and must be undertaken with caution.

Potent Arcana:
Employing powerful magic, such as an archmage's spell of wishing, or returning to life through use of a Tether Soul (see Veilmark Abilities above) can reduce your Veilmark Score to 0, as well as remove any Veilmark Transformations you have. Once you surpass a Veilmark Threshold and gain a Veilmark Transformation, it remains with you permanently, even if your Veilmark Score later decreases below that threshold. Only Potent Arcana may remove a Veilmark Transformation. These transformations continue to affect both your body and soul, even if you disguise yourself through the means of illusory magic or a shape-changing ability. However, if your score increases again past a threshold you've previously crossed, you won't gain additional transformations for that same threshold. During a campaign in which you want to make the Veilmark system less punishing, you may rule that the effects of Greater Restoration also remove the effects of a Veilmark Transformation from a character. Conversely, reducing your Veilmark below each Threshold means that you lose access to the corresponding Abilities, as detailed above.

Roleplaying Veilmark:
As your Veilmark increases, consider how these changes affect your character's personality and demeanor. Do you welcome them as a mark of growth, or do you view them as aberrations upon your appearance? Consider how your personality might change to reflect them. You might become more aloof, skittish, or stoic. You may pick up a repetitive habit or mannerism. Perhaps the weight of the spirit world will deeply affect your psyche, gradually changing you into an altogether different person.

Social Implications:
In small communities such as the villages of Zamanora, these physical changes can lead to fear, reverence, or superstition. Characters bearing those marks are considered branded by the spirits, influencing their interactions with NPCs.

Fear and Distrust:
In most organized communities, the appearance of a Veilmarked stranger is met with apprehension, the locals fearing the character and associating their marks with bad omens or curses. Otherworldly features in their appearance might put the common folk ill at ease, but beyond that, their mere presence is unsettling for reasons that cannot be interpreted directly, as they carry the stigma of the Hidden World. A character with more than a couple of Veilmark transformations is usually treated as a Spook by common folk who first encounter them. Superstitious folk may be wary of such characters and treat them with extreme caution, to the point of turning them into a pariah amongst their societies or even chasing them away.

Reverence and Respect:
In the dwellings of spirits, or places where their presence is strongly felt, denizens might see the marks as a sign of a blessed or powerful individual, offering assistance or seeking their aid. In such cases, according to the Storyteller's discretion, the penalties to Influence Actions normally associated with Veilmark Transformations may become bonuses instead.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 120 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Transformation">1d10</roll>
        <roll description="Fire Damage">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Force Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Hearth Domain (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Hearth Domain (HB)</name>
        <text>Fostered around the warmth of the hearth, community is the heart of a thriving society. It is a place where virtues like compassion, cooperation, and resilience are seeded and cultivated. The gods of this domain inspire the nurturing of communal bonds and protection of the vulnerable, often likening the capacity for growth they offer to the hearth's firelight. Clerics of the Hearth bless new homes, mediate conflicts, and reinforce mutual support, acting as stewards of unity. They see every act of kindness and shared meal as strengthening the community as a whole. Their magic heals and protects, embodying the enduring power of unity.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hearth Domain Spells (Hearth Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the Hearth Domain Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Hearth Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
3 | Alarm, Aid, Calm Emotions, Sanctuary
5 | Beacon of Hope, Bestow Grace*
7 | Guardian of Faith, Private Sanctum
9 | Hallow, Telepathic Bond

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Embrace and Exile (Hearth Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your magic embodies the warmth of your community or the coldness towards those who reject or harm it. When you cast a spell using a spell slot that targets a willing creature, that creature also regains 1d6 Hit Points. If you cast a spell using a spell slot that targets an unwilling or Hostile creature, and they are hit by the spell attack or fail their saving throw, you may deal 1d6 Psychic damage to them.
        This die increases to a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Heal" level="3">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="Psychic Damage" level="3">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="Psychic Damage" level="5">1d8</roll>
        <roll description="Psychic Damage" level="10">1d10</roll>
        <roll description="Psychic Damage" level="15">1d12</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hearth's Spark (Hearth Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you present your Holy Symbol and expend a use of your Channel Divinity to bolster the resolve and spirit of your community. Choose a number of creatures within 30 feet of yourself, up to a maximum of your Wisdom modifier (minimum of one creature). Each creature gains Temporary Hit Points equal to 2d6 plus your Cleric level. While these Temporary Hit Points last, a creature can take the Help Action as a Bonus Action.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Temporary Hit Points">2d6+%7</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: United We Stand (Hearth Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Even in dire circumstances, you inspire unity among your allies. As a Reaction, when you and one or more allies within 30 feet are required to make a saving throw, you can allow your allies to use your saving throw result in place of their own against the effect.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>United We Stand</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Hearth Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Kindred's Hearth (Hearth Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>You can infuse an area with the radiant energy of unity and warmth shared around the hearth, creating a sanctum of protection. As a Magic Action, you can create a stationary Sphere with a 30-foot radius centered on you that lasts for 1 hour. Whenever an ally starts their turn in the area, they gain Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d6 plus your Wisdom modifier. In addition, they gain a bonus to all D20 Tests equal to the roll on the d6, until the start of their next turn.
	You can use this feature once per day.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Kindred's Hearth</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Hearth Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Journey Domain (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Journey Domain (HB)</name>
        <text>Not all those who wander are lost, they say; and such is the case for the pious pilgrims who pledge their faith to the deities of wind and travel. Living a life where every step is a prayer, every newfound experience a testament to divinity itself, these devoted wayfarers constantly seek to discover whatever lies just beyond the edge of the horizon. Clerics of the Journey grace those who venture far from home, daring to tread into the unknown whether by choice, or necessity. Companionship is sacred to them, and they view migrants, caravaneers, explorers, as well as all those who answer the call of the uncharted, as their flock. Carried forward by hallowed winds, beyond borders and conceptual boundaries, their magic keeps their fellowship from harm, until it has arrived at its intended destination.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 69 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Journey Domain Spells (Journey Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the Journey Domain Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Journey Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
3 | Expeditious Retreat, Gust of Wind, Long Strider, Pass Without Trace
5 | Fly, Wind Wall
7 | Freedom of Movement, Outward Gale*
9 | Passwall, Tree Stride

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 70 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Worldly Traveler (Journey Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency with the Navigator's Tools and a Vehicle type of your choice. You also gain proficiency in the Animal Handling or Survival skill and one language of your choice. As your travels take you to faraway lands, your knowledge of the world and its people grows. You gain proficiency with an additional language of your choice at 8th and at 14th level that is spoken in places you have visited in the past.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 70 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Wanderer's Repose (Journey Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you etch your Holy Symbol upon any solid surface, such as a tree's bark, the face of a rock, or on the ground, and expend a use of your Channel Divinity to provide a place of respite for you and your allies. The area within 20 feet of the etched symbol is protected from the effects of extreme heat and extreme cold for the next 24 hours. In addition, upon finishing a Short or Long rest within the area, a creature gains the following benefits:

Short Rest. The creature gains an amount of Temporary Hit Points equal to your level plus your Wisdom modifier.

Long Rest. The creature gains the Temporary Hit Points granted by taking a Short Rest while in the area, regains all its spent Hit Dice, and reduces its Exhaustion by an additional level.

When you use this feature to imbue a Holy Symbol with magic, you can innately sense the direction to it for the next 24 hours, or until you imbue a new one.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 70 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Tailwind (Journey Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your spells breathe favorable winds towards your allies. When you cast a spell using a spell slot that targets willing creatures, each affected creature's movement does not provoke Opportunity Attacks and it is unaffected by Difficult Terrain until the end of its next turn.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 70 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Vardoval's Passage (Journey Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Divine boons are conferred to your fellow travelers by your mere presence, carrying them forward over swift winds and hiding them from the gaze of assailants. While you are conscious, you and each friendly creature within 30 feet of you gain the following benefits, based on the time of day:

Dawn until Dusk. Your travel pace is doubled and you do not have Disadvantage on checks imposed when traveling at a Fast pace. Additionally, you add your Wisdom modifier to your Initiative rolls.

Dusk until Dawn. You do not have Disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks while traveling at Normal travel pace and any attempts to track you have Disadvantage. Additionally, you add your Wisdom modifier to your Dexterity (Stealth) checks.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 70 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Legacy of the Wayfarer (Journey Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Every voyage is wondrous in its own way, precisely because it must eventually end. Once per day, you can cast the Word of Recall spell without expending a spell slot, using the location most recently affected by your Wanderer's Repose feature as the spell's designated sanctuary. Moreover, while a willing creature is under the effects of a spell cast by you, it has the benefits of your Tailwind feature for the spell's duration.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 71 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Aid [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Alarm [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Beacon of Hope [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bestow Grace (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Calm Emotions [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Guardian of Faith [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallow [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Private Sanctum [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sanctuary [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Telepathic Bond [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Hearth Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Expeditious Retreat [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Gust of Wind [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Long Strider [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Pass without Trace [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fly [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wind Wall [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Freedom of Movement [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Outward Gale (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Passwall [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tree Stride [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Journey Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
