<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora]</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Veilmark Information (Zamanora)</name>
        <text>It is said that trespassing upon the spirit world leaves a tangible brand on one's body and soul. Mortals should never peer beyond the Veil, lest the spirits take notice and mark them forevermore. Let a marked person into your home and you invite certain calamity. The lands of Zamanora are riddled with such fiction and cautionary tales that only work to paint those who are inquisitive in a bad light. Yet they are right about one thing; someone who interacts with the Hidden World too often is bound to be "marked". As characters engage in encounters with curses, spirits, and other supernatural phenomena, they accrue Veilmark. This attribute reflects their growing connection to the spirit realm and the transformative effects of these experiences on their physical and spiritual selves. Veilmarked is the term used by the Zamanori to describe individuals who have thus changed, and denotes characters who have accrued enough Veilmark to cross a threshold. If playing in a different setting, you may use the broader term Aura to describe the system.

The influence of Veilmark on a character is determined by their Veilmark Score. The more a character interacts with curses, spirits, and other supernatural phenomena, delving into the mysteries of the Hidden World, the more their Veilmark Score increases. A character's Veilmark Score is effectively a pool of innate power they may tap into in order to produce certain effects that aid them when interacting with spiritual entities. However, at the same time, the higher one's Veilmark Score is, the more otherworldly they feel when interacting with their peers, making them wary and distrustful of their presence. Characters start out with a Veilmark Score of 0, which may increase up to a maximum of 100 throughout a campaign. Certain features, such as the Veilborn Origin (see Chapter II: Origins), or the Veilscarred Barbarian's Dark Bargain and Willow's Embrace (see Chapter II: Subclasses), signify that a character has already been extensively exposed to the Hidden World and influence that character's starting Veilmark Score according to their description.

Gaining Veilmark
An increase of Veilmark results in noticeable physical changes, signifying the character's deepening connection with the spirit realm. Every time a character's Veilmark modifier increases, roll on the table below or choose one of the physical alterations listed to manifest on them. Your Veilmark Score may increase every time you experience an event that severely impacts your psyche by challenging what you priorly thought was real. Interacting with a being you believed to be a mere folktale, falling victim to a vicious curse, or drinking water from a bewitched spring can all increase your Veilmark Score. Such an experience, along with the implications caused upon oneself due to it, is known as a Harrow. A Harrow may affect a single or multiple characters at once, and at different levels of Severity (see Harrows table), based on roleplay and the narrative course of the story. For example, when a stranger who asks to share in the warmth of the party's campfire is later revealed to be a malign spirit, every character present may be subjected to a Harrow of Considerable level; yet for a character who recognizes the spirit as that of a deceased relative of theirs, the same Harrow may qualify as Intense. At the same time, another character who has already dabbled in occult practices to a point of communing with the spirits of the dead may treat this as a Harrow of Inconsequential level. The Severity of a Harrow on a character's psyche, as well as which character is subject to the risk of gaining Veilmark due to it and which isn't, is determined by the Storyteller, according to their interpretation of the player characters' backgrounds, stories, personalities, and any circumstantial factors that apply to each occasion.

When the Storyteller declares a Harrow, each character that is subject to it must choose whether they wish to Resist or Embrace it. This choice represents their disposition towards the supernatural world, and their openness towards its truths and mysteries.

Reisting Veilmark
A character who chooses to Resist a Harrow makes a Wisdom saving throw against a DC determined by its Severity. On a success, the experience leaves them unaffected, and nothing happens. On a failure, they must roll the corresponding Veilmark Die. Their Veilmark Score becomes increased by an amount equal to the result. A Hero that succeeds on their Action without Consequences resists the Harrow completely, taking no increase to their Veilmark Score. Otherwise, the Hero rolls the corresponding amount of Veilmark dice. A Success with Consequences means that the Hero's Veilmark increases by an amount equal to half of their result. A roll that only results in Consequences means that the Hero's Veilmark score is increased by the total amount rolled. You may also employ special means, such as the Veil Charm item (see Chapter IV: Fabled Relics), in order to better your chances in resisting any unwanted increases in your Veilmark Score.

Embracing Veilmark
A character who chooses to Embrace a Harrow forgoes making any attempts at resisting its effects and does not roll the corresponding Veilmark Die. That character's Veilmark Score automatically increases by the maximum amount possible.

d6 | Veilmark Die | DC | Status Tier
1 | 1d6 |	10 | harrowing-1
2 | 2d6 | 15 | harrowing-2
3 | 3d6 | 20 | harrowing-3
4 | 4d6 | 25 | harrowing-4
5 | 5d6 | 30 | harrowing-5

Veilmark Thresholds
Whenever a Harrow causes your Veilmark Score to increase beyond the thresholds of 25, 50, 75 and 99 for the first time, you gain a Veilmark Transformation. For every Veilmark Transformation that you have, you gain a cumulative -2 penalty to any Influence Actions you take against other non-Veilmarked Humanoids and Beasts, unless you are trying to intimidate them.

Veilmark Thresholds Table:
Threshold | Title
25 | Shadowlit
50 | Equinoctial
75 | Moonstruck
99 | Spiritwalker

Transformations &amp; Powers:
Veilmark transformations are a physical manifestation of the Hidden World's effects on your body. Such a transformation is a consequence of your innate understanding of the supernatural and ability to harness the powers that lie within, but ultimately comes at a cost. The first time you cross each of those Veilmark Thresholds, you gain a Veilmark Transformation and two new Veilmark Abilities from the tables below. For every Veilmark Transformation you have, you gain a cumulative -2 penalty to any Influence Actions you take against other non-Veilmarked Humanoids and Beasts, unless you are trying to intimidate them.

When you gain a new Veilmark Transformation, roll on the table below to determine its nature. If the result is a Transformation you have already undergone, roll again until you get a new one. Once you gain a Veilmark Transformation, it remains with you permanently, even if your Veilmark Score later decreases below that threshold.

Veilmark Transformations Table:
d10 | Transformation
1 | One of your eyes changes color. At night, when the Veil grows thin, you glimpse visions from the other side. This distraction grants you Disadvantage on Initiative rolls during nighttime hours.
2 | A streak of silver appears on your hair. Silvered weapons deal an extra Damage Die to you.
3 | Your skin's complexion becomes a tone paler. Whenever you take Fire damage you take an additional 1d4 Fire damage.
4 | Veins throughout your body become visibly dark beneath your skin. While you are Bloodied and can see an enemy, you can't willingly move away from them.
5 | Your shadow changes to resemble that of a different being. The Attitude of Beasts towards you worsens by one stage.
6 | A strange marking brands your skin like a scar. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Curses.
7 | A strange marking brands your skin like a scar. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Curses.
8 | A Zagovory symbol appears on your tongue. Whenever you fail an Influence Action, it is treated as attempted Intimidation regardless of your intentions.
9 | You appear sickly and weak. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made to resist the effects of Diseases.
10 | You no longer cast a reflection. You are excluded from beneficial effects caused by spells that target multiple creatures.

Every time you cross a Veilmark threshold, you unlock two new abilities, as detailed in the Veilmark Abilities table. You may use the abilities gained from each threshold a combined total of two times per day. For example, you may use one ability twice, or each ability once. Unlike Transformations, Veilmark Abilities do not last indefinitely. If your Veilmark Score falls below the Threshold that granted you these abilities (see Losing Veilmark), they become dormant and cannot be used until your Veilmark Score rises above the corresponding Threshold again.

Veilmark Threshold Abilities:

Shadowlit
Detect Spirit.
You cast the spell Spirit Sense, without expending a spell slot.
Incorporeal Reach.
As a Bonus Action, your attacks harm the very essence of spirits for the next minute. For the duration, once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 Force damage to a target you hit with an attack or spell.

Equinoctial
Exorcism.
As an Action, you touch a creature and end one of the following effects currently afflicting it: Frightened, Charmed, or a Possession.
Pierce the Veil.
As part of a successful Study Action made against a creature of the Spirit subtype, you discern either of the following: its Immunities, Resistances or Vulnerabilities.

Moonstruck
Soul Harvest.
As a Reaction to a creature dying within 30 feet of you, you can infuse yourself with a fragment of its departing essence. As a result, you may choose to either regain a number of expended spell slots as a 4th-level Wizard using the Arcane Recovery feature, or gain 25 Temporary Hit Points.
Spiritual Kinship.
When you fail a saving throw against a spell or magical effect caused by a creature of the Spirit subtype, you succeed instead.

Spiritwalker
Ethereal Echo.
As an Action, you create an ethereal duplicate of yourself that lasts for 1 minute. This spectral reflection appears in your space and mimics your movements precisely, with an almost imperceptible delay. The echo has half your current Hit Points. When you make an attack that deals damage to a single target, your echo repeats the attack but only deals half damage (rounded down). The echo takes the same damage as you do when you are damaged. It cannot regain Hit Points and vanishes if it reaches 0 Hit Points, you become Incapacitated, or when the duration ends.
Tether Soul.
By spending an hour in meditation, you bind your soul to a clearly defined point that you can see in your environment; for example, the hollow of an oak tree, or a statue made of stone. If you die before your next Long Rest, you gain the effects of the Reincarnate spell, but your new species is Haunt (see Chapter II: Species), while your new body forms in the bound point based on the materials it consists of. If you successfully return to life in this way, your Veilmark Score is reduced to 0 and you lose any Veilmark Transformations you have.

Losing Veilmark
Once you have been exposed to the challenging truths of the Hidden World, it is very difficult, if indeed possible at all, to forget them. However, there are ways to reduce its impact on your being. The diminishing of one's Veilmark represents a retreat from the otherworldly, a return to the mundane, and a fixated anchoring to the Real. Below are the ways you may employ to reduce your Veilmark Score.

Downtime Activity
You may choose to detach yourself from the supernatural by indulging in mundane activities for extended periods. For every month or Sojourn you spend this way, your Veilmark Score decreases by 5. Examples of such activities include:

	• Engaging with a community in manual labor, such as aiding in the building of a home.
	• Exploring and cultivating deep emotional bonds with others through steady everyday life.
	• Spending time alone to reflect upon yourself, or pursue artistic creations.

Recreation
Other than spending time in peace and tranquility, you may also pursue more radical methods to reduce your Veilmark Score. These include consuming a God Flesh mushroom (see Chapter IV: Zamanoran Mushrooms), meditating within the Gemstone Caverns, or bathing in the waters of a lake within the Three Nines Forest. While such methods are the swiftest and most potent ways to achieve the intended result, they may carry certain hazards and must be undertaken with caution.

Potent Arcana
Employing powerful magic, such as an archmage's spell of wishing, or returning to life through use of a Tether Soul (see Veilmark Abilities above) can reduce your Veilmark Score to 0, as well as remove any Veilmark Transformations you have. Once you surpass a Veilmark Threshold and gain a Veilmark Transformation, it remains with you permanently, even if your Veilmark Score later decreases below that threshold. Only Potent Arcana may remove a Veilmark Transformation. These transformations continue to affect both your body and soul, even if you disguise yourself through the means of illusory magic or a shape-changing ability. However, if your score increases again past a threshold you've previously crossed, you won't gain additional transformations for that same threshold. During a campaign in which you want to make the Veilmark system less punishing, you may rule that the effects of Greater Restoration also remove the effects of a Veilmark Transformation from a character. Conversely, reducing your Veilmark below each Threshold means that you lose access to the corresponding Abilities, as detailed above.

Roleplaying Veilmark
As your Veilmark increases, consider how these changes affect your character's personality and demeanor. Do you welcome them as a mark of growth, or do you view them as aberrations upon your appearance? Consider how your personality might change to reflect them. You might become more aloof, skittish, or stoic. You may pick up a repetitive habit or mannerism. Perhaps the weight of the spirit world will deeply affect your psyche, gradually changing you into an altogether different person.

Social Implications
In small communities such as the villages of Zamanora, these physical changes can lead to fear, reverence, or superstition. Characters bearing those marks are considered branded by the spirits, influencing their interactions with NPCs.

Fear and Distrust
In most organized communities, the appearance of a Veilmarked stranger is met with apprehension, the locals fearing the character and associating their marks with bad omens or curses. Otherworldly features in their appearance might put the common folk ill at ease, but beyond that, their mere presence is unsettling for reasons that cannot be interpreted directly, as they carry the stigma of the Hidden World. A character with more than a couple of Veilmark transformations is usually treated as a Spook by common folk who first encounter them. Superstitious folk may be wary of such characters and treat them with extreme caution, to the point of turning them into a pariah amongst their societies or even chasing them away.

Reverence and Respect
In the dwellings of spirits, or places where their presence is strongly felt, denizens might see the marks as a sign of a blessed or powerful individual, offering assistance or seeking their aid. In such cases, according to the Storyteller's discretion, the penalties to Influence Actions normally associated with Veilmark Transformations may become bonuses instead.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Firebird (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Firebird (HB)</name>
        <text>Paladins following the Oath of the Firebird are bound to a calling greater than valor or vengeance. Inspired by the mythic Zhar-Ptitsa, they are the guiding light before dawn and the blaze that stirs a broken soul back to its feet. Many who swear this oath have glimpsed the abyss, experiencing a moment of despair so profound it should have broken them. Yet at their lowest point, an act of kindness, whether through divine will or mortal hand, brought them back igniting their spark of hope ablaze. Now they carry that light with them, illuminating a world dimmed by despair. They see goodness not as a rarity, but a smoldering flame within every soul, waiting to be nurtured by kindness.

Tenets of the Firebird:
The tenets of the Oath of the Firebird prompt the Paladin to become a spark of light amidst the darkest night, encouraging their peers to stand tall in the face of insurmountable odds and bringing out the best in them.

Stand Beside, not Above. Look down on no one, unless to extend a helping hand.

Kindle the Spark. Endeavor to bring out the best in others.

Nurture All Light. Let your judgment be tempered with empathy, and your acts guide instead of rebuke.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 87 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oath of the Firebird Spells (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your oath ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Paladin level specified in the Oath of the Firebird Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Oath of the Firebird Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3rd | Burning Hands, Searing Smite
5th | Aid, Suncloak*
9th | Beacon of Hope, Fireball
13th | Fire Shield (warm version), Wall of Fire
17th | Flame Strike, Greater Restoration

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 88 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hope for the Hopeless (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you can expend one use of your Channel Divinity to gain Heroic Inspiration. While you have this Heroic Inspiration, you can spend a Bonus Action to grant Heroic Inspiration to one ally within 30 feet who can see or hear you.
	Heroic Inspiration gained in this way is lost unless used within the next minute.
	You can activate this feature as a Reaction instead, if you or an ally you can see or hear within 30 feet of you becomes Bloodied.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 88 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Aura of Blazing Vigor (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</name>
        <text>Your flames kindle the spirits of those crestfallen, urging them to stand tall in the face of adversity. Whenever you deal Fire or Radiant damage, roll 1d8 for each enemy that was dealt this type of damage. You and each ally within your Aura of Protection regain a number of Hit Points equal to the amount rolled plus your Charisma modifier.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 88 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Undaunted Light (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</name>
        <text>Those inspired by you shall come to discover they hold more potential than they knew. If a creature is subjected to damage that would reduce it to 0 Hit Points, or an effect that would kill it instantly without dealing damage, while it has Heroic Inspiration granted by you, the creature drops to 1 Hit Point instead. A creature can benefit from this effect once before it finishes a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 88 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 20: Knight of the Breaking Dawn (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you don a mantle of golden flames, removing the Frightened condition from all allies who can see you and are within 30 feet of you. You gain the benefits below for 10 minutes or until you end them (no action required).

Freedom Flight. You sprout fiery wings on your back, have a Fly Speed of 60 feet, and can hover, shedding bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for 30 feet beyond.

Rise from the Ashes. After you have dealt a total of at least 50 Fire damage, Radiant damage, or any combination of both while this feature is active, you can cast the Heal spell once before the feature's duration is over without expending a spell slot. When you cast Heal this way, all creatures of your choice within 30 feet of the target that can see the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, they are Blinded until the end of their next turn.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by expending a level 5 spell slot (no action required).

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 88 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Knight of the Breaking Dawn</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oath of the Firebird (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Skycaller (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Skycaller (HB)</name>
        <text>Also known as Arunites, the devout warriors who undertake the sacred Oath of the Skycaller are individuals most venerated amongst their peers. Adorned with the holy Wreath of Thunderbolts, they advocate Arun's divine creed across the realm. Bearing the power to command tempests, these sacred paragons wield it with valor to combat mortalkind's most vicious adversaries, or ease their fury to preserve the less-fortunate from their passing. Despite their supernal gifts, however, an Arunite's journey is not a mere quest for fame or glory, but rather a pilgrimage of self-discovery. For, to be worthy of this oath, one must always be mindful of the power they have been given, seeking the wisdom to know when to employ it, and how to be worthy of it.

Tenets of the Skycaller:
The tenets of the Oath of the Skycaller revolve around being a symbol of courage and valiance to one's kinsfolk, as well as one that strikes fear into the wretched hearts of its otherworldly foes. Rather than straightforward commandments, the principles they epitomize are philosophical at their core, aiming to direct the Paladin towards a path of humility and self-actualization.

Show no Fear. Brave is not the heart that knows no fear, but the one that overcomes it.

Seek the Fiercest Foe. A true warrior's value is measured by that of their enemies'.

Walk With Honor. Vanity is a weakness. To bear the mantle of power with integrity, is to outstretch it and shelter the bedeviled from woe.

Lightning from a Clear Sky. Never draw steel in folly. Advocate for peace; be remorseless in times of war.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 90 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oath of the Skycaller Spells (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your oath ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Paladin level specified in the Oath of the Skycaller Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Oath of the Skycaller Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3 | Protection from Evil and Good, Thunderwave
5 | Begraced Armaments*, Shatter
9 | Fly, Lightning Bolt
13 | Conjure Minor Elementals (air), Freedom of Movement
17 | Conjure Elemental (air), Destructive Wave

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 92 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Thunderstrike (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can expend one use of your Channel Divinity to magically imbue one weapon you are holding with tempestuous energy. For the next minute, you have Advantage on attack rolls made using this weapon if the target is wearing armor made of metal. On a hit, you deal bonus Lightning damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum bonus of +1) and the target can't take Reactions until the start of its next turn. While your weapon is imbued in this way, you can choose to deal Lightning or Thunder instead of Radiant damage when you cast the Divine Smite spell.
	You can end this effect on your turn as a Bonus Action. If you are no longer holding or carrying this weapon, or if you fall Unconscious, this effect ends.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 92 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Aura of the Living Tempest (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</name>
        <text>Your presence shelters your allies from the wrath of storms and channels their power. You and your allies have Resistance to Lightning and Thunder damage while in your Aura of Protection.
	In addition, by using a Bonus Action, you can draw power from your Lay on Hands pool and expend 10 points to send electrical currents jolting through your body, granting you lightning reflexes for a short burst. When you do so, you can also conduct this effect to allies within your Aura of Protection by expending an additional 10 points for each ally. Each affected creature gains the benefits of the Haste spell until the start of your next turn. When this effect ends, affected creatures do not suffer the usual Incapacitated condition or Speed reduction.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 92 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Storm Surge (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</name>
        <text>During any part of your movement, you can briefly turn into a clap of thunder and teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Each creature within 10 feet of the point you arrive at must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes Thunder damage equal to 1d8 plus your Charisma modifier, it is pushed 10 feet away from you and is Deafened until the start of its next turn. On a success, it takes half as much damage, and it isn't pushed or Deafened. The thunder can be heard from up to 300 feet away.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses of this ability when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 93 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Storm Surge</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oath of the Skycaller (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Storm Surge</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oath of the Skycaller (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 20: Eye of the Storm (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</name>
        <text>You become one with the tempestuous might of the raging storms. Using your Action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 hour, you gain the following benefits:

Bringer of Storms. As part of undergoing this transformation, the weather in a 5-mile radius quickly deteriorates and then bursts into a thunderstorm. For the duration, you can as a Magic Action cast the Call Lightning spell at 5th level without expending a spell slot or maintaining Concentration. When cast in this way, you can call down lightning as a Bonus Action at any point that you can see within the thunderstorm's radius.

The Storm Lord's Blessing. You are immune to Lightning and Thunder damage.

Wings of Arun. You gain a Fly Speed of 60 feet.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 93 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Eye of the Storm</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oath of the Skycaller (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Burning Hands [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Searing Smite [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aid [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Suncloak (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Beacon of Hope [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fireball [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fire Shield [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Fire [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Flame Strike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Restoration [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Firebird (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Protection from Evil and Good [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Thunderwave [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Begraced Armaments (HB) [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shatter [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fly [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Lightning Bolt [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Conjure Minor Elementals [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Freedom of Movement [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Conjure Elemental [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Destructive Wave [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] [Zamandora] (Oath of the Skycaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
