<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Crypt Delver (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Scavenger. You have Advantage on Search Actions taken to spot traps, secret doors, and concealed items.

Collector of Oddities. You have Advantage on Study Actions taken to accurately estimate an item's worth, as well as discern any magical properties it might feature. In addition, according to the occasion and the Storyteller's discretion, you may attempt the latter using History instead of Arcana, as you normally would.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 34 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Monster Slayer (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Courageous. Once per day, upon failing a saving throw against an effect that would cause you to become Frightened, you can choose to roll again and keep the better result.

Know Thy Enemy. By collecting three pieces of information regarding a creature, you can choose to designate it as your Quarry for the next 7 days. These pieces of information can be any three amongst the following: its name, its creature type, an accurate description of its appearance, a location it frequents, a routine habit that it has, a piece of evidence of its presence (such as a track or body part). While a creature is designated as your Quarry, you have Advantage on any Search and Study Actions you take in relation to it, and add your Proficiency Bonus to your damage rolls against it. You can have a number of active Quarries up to your Proficiency Bonus at a time.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 34 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Natural Grace (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Alluring Presence. People are impressed by your innate charm. Every Humanoid creature that is Indifferent towards you and does not yet know you is treated as Friendly for the Influence Actions you take, until you fail a relevant ability check.

Keen Intuition. When trying to determine a creature's state of mind through Insight, you can take the Study Action as a Bonus Action instead.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 34 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Speaker of Ceremonies (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Glossolalist. You learn two more languages of your choice. In addition, you can learn other languages or Idioms in half the time it usually takes.

Pass on Knowledge. During a Long Rest, you may choose one willing creature that can understand you and impart it with your knowledge. Choose one skill in which you are proficient. The target creature gains proficiency in that skill until it completes its next Long Rest.

Upholding Tradition. You learn three Ceremonies of your choice. These do not count against the maximum number of Ceremonies you know.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 34 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Touch of the Veil (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Harrowkin. When a Harrow causes your Veilmark Score to increase after you had chosen to Resist its effects, deduct your Proficiency Bonus from this increment (minimum 1). If you had chosen to Embrace the Harrow's effects instead, you may add your Proficiency Bonus to this increment.

Spiritual Manifestation. Your exposure to the influence of the Hidden World and its beings has shaped you. Your Veilmark Score increases to 25, if not already higher.

Speaking in Tongues. You can understand and speak Sylvan.

Unnatural Stamina. Whenever you finish a Long rest, you regain one additional spent Hit Die, for each Veilmark threshold you have crossed.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 35 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Willful (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>You're no stranger to hardship, and are determined to press on despite any failures and shortcomings. Whenever you roll a 1 on a D20 Test, you gain Heroic Inspiration. Heroic Inspiration gained in this way cannot be used to reroll the D20 Test that yielded it or be given to another, and vanishes if it has not been spent until your next Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 35 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Witchcraft (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Forager. You have Advantage on D20 Tests made for foraging and identifying herbs and mushrooms.

Poppet Mage. You gain the Poppet Mage feature, associated with the same Artisan's Tool as above, allowing you to practice Poppet Magic (see Chapter III: Poppet Magic).

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 35 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Epic Origin: Dragonslayer (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>Epic Origin Feats are reserved solely for Epic Origins. You gain the following benefits.

Apex Predator. Whenever you deal damage to a Dragon with an attack or spell, you can add your Proficiency Bonus to one damage roll.

Colossal Build. You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can lift, push or drag.

Winged. As a Bonus Action you can unfurl or hide your wings. You have a Fly Speed equal to your Speed while your wings are unfurled. You can't use this Flying Speed if you are wearing Medium or Heavy Armor.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 38 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Epic Origin: The Crone's Own (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>Epic Origin Feats are reserved solely for Epic Origins. You gain the following benefits.

Homunculus. When you walk within 15 feet of an area where a spell was cast within the last 24 hours, you can sense its school of magic. If multiple spells were cast, you sense the school of magic of the most powerful spell.

Forbidden Cradle. Your exposure to the ancient magics of the Crone has altered your being. Your Veilmark Score increases by 25.

Conduit of the Arcane. As a Reaction to a creature casting a spell that deals damage or restores Hit Points within 60 feet of you that you can see, you can partially absorb its magic. When you do so, reduce its dice rolled by a number of dice equal to your Proficiency Bonus. Then, you roll these dice instead and gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to the amount rolled. You may use this feat a number of times per day equal to half your Proficiency Bonus.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 37 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Epic Origin: Inner Compass (HB) [2024]</name>
    <text>Epic Origin Feats are reserved solely for Epic Origins. You gain the following benefits.

Adventure Sense. You have Advantage on D20 Tests made to collect information about creatures, locations or items of legendary importance.

An Age in Marble. You can call on the magic that kept your soul intact for aeons to withstand the journey. When you take damage, you can use your Reaction to reduce the damage taken by a number of d8s equal to your Proficiency Bonus. You can use this benefit once before you finish a Long Rest.

Hero's Soul. Whenever you encounter a new character, or location, or have a novel experience linked to the Old World, such as a ruin, artifact, or ancient Dragon, roll a d20. On a 10 or above, you gain Heroic Inspiration as you recall a piece of information about your past life, or a bit of lore about the Old World. The Storyteller decides what the recollection is.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 41 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
</compendium>
