<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <item>
    <name>Apple of Youth [2024]</name>
    <detail>legendary</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This divine boon of nature is normally kept in a secret garden, away from the prying eyes of mortals, bestowed only upon a select few who have performed a great service to the gods. Upon consuming this apple, you no longer age or suffer the effects of old age. Additionally, any detrimental condition or curse currently afflicting you, immediately ends.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 192 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Blue Balaur Stone [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Legend has it that the saliva of a mythical Balaur condensates into precious gemstones that bestow incredible magical properties. Few are those who can boast having witnessed such a wondrous creation, and even fewer are those to have possessed it. Yet none can truly tell why these magnificent gems feature different colors and properties. Some speculate that they vary according to the age of the Balaur that produced them or what it had recently feasted upon. Others trust a legend, which dictates that they gain their color depending on the phase of the moon, when its light first shone upon them.
	A skilled artisan can attach such a gemstone to a weapon, armor, shield, or other item, in order to enhance its properties. Only a single Balaur gemstone can be attached to a piece of equipment.

A blue Balaur gemstone strengthens and wards from harm.

Weapon. The weapon ignores Resistance to Bludgeoning, Slashing and Piercing damage.

Armor or Shield. Any damage dealt to you is reduced by 2. After reducing 10 points of damage in this way, the stone's magic becomes inert until the next dawn.

Other. Once before every new dawn, upon failing a saving throw, you may choose to roll it again. You must use the new roll.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 192 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Green Balaur Stone [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Legend has it that the saliva of a mythical Balaur condensates into precious gemstones that bestow incredible magical properties. Few are those who can boast having witnessed such a wondrous creation, and even fewer are those to have possessed it. Yet none can truly tell why these magnificent gems feature different colors and properties. Some speculate that they vary according to the age of the Balaur that produced them or what it had recently feasted upon. Others trust a legend, which dictates that they gain their color depending on the phase of the moon, when its light first shone upon them.
	A skilled artisan can attach such a gemstone to a weapon, armor, shield, or other item, in order to enhance its properties. Only a single Balaur gemstone can be attached to a piece of equipment.

A green Balaur gemstone strengthens and wards from harm.

Weapon. Unless the weapon is Heavy, it becomes Light. Otherwise, the weapon loses the Heavy property.

Armor or Shield. You gain Advantage on Initiative rolls.

Other. Your Speed increases by 5 feet.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 192 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Red Balaur Stone [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Legend has it that the saliva of a mythical Balaur condensates into precious gemstones that bestow incredible magical properties. Few are those who can boast having witnessed such a wondrous creation, and even fewer are those to have possessed it. Yet none can truly tell why these magnificent gems feature different colors and properties. Some speculate that they vary according to the age of the Balaur that produced them or what it had recently feasted upon. Others trust a legend, which dictates that they gain their color depending on the phase of the moon, when its light first shone upon them.
	A skilled artisan can attach such a gemstone to a weapon, armor, shield, or other item, in order to enhance its properties. Only a single Balaur gemstone can be attached to a piece of equipment.

A red Balaur gemstone strengthens and wards from harm.

Weapon. Each time you deal damage to a creature using this weapon, you regain 1 Hit Point.

Armor or Shield. You gain +1 bonus to your saving throws while you are Bloodied.

Other. Your maximum Hit Points increase by 5 while wearing this item.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 192 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>White Balaur Stone [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Legend has it that the saliva of a mythical Balaur condensates into precious gemstones that bestow incredible magical properties. Few are those who can boast having witnessed such a wondrous creation, and even fewer are those to have possessed it. Yet none can truly tell why these magnificent gems feature different colors and properties. Some speculate that they vary according to the age of the Balaur that produced them or what it had recently feasted upon. Others trust a legend, which dictates that they gain their color depending on the phase of the moon, when its light first shone upon them.
	A skilled artisan can attach such a gemstone to a weapon, armor, shield, or other item, in order to enhance its properties. Only a single Balaur gemstone can be attached to a piece of equipment.

A white Balaur gemstone strengthens and wards from harm.

Weapon. The wielder becomes proficient with this weapon.

Armor or Shield. The wearer becomes proficient with this armor or shield.

Other. If the item requires attunement, attuning to it does not count against your total attuned magic items.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 193 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bowl of Divine Offering [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This ornate bowl can be used to commit offerings to the gods, imploring their favor and acting as a conduit between mortalkind and the divine. Once before every new dawn, you can fill this bowl with water, honey or blood to cast the Augury spell. When casting Augury in this way, depending on the omen yielded by the spell and the substance that was used to fill the bowl, the gods bestow a corresponding boon or curse, as presented in the following table:

Bowl of Divine Offering:
Omen | Water | Honey | Blood
Weal | The water turns into a dose of Holy Water | Consuming a portion of honey causes the effects of Bless for 24 hours (the bowl contains 3 portions) | The creature who offered its blood gains the effects of False Life (at Level 5)
Woe | The water turns into a dose of Poison, Basic | Consuming a portion of honey causes the effects of Bane for 24 hours (the bowl contains 3 portions) | The creature who offered its blood is afflicted by a Level 5 curse or lower for 24 hours, determined at random amongst the effects of Bestow Curse (see Chapter III: Folklore Magic)
Weal and Woe | The effect is unknown; upon using the water, roll a d20. On 1 to 10, it has the effects of Weal. On 11 to 20, it has the effects of Woe | The effect is unknown; upon consuming a portion of honey, roll a d20. On 1 to 10, it has the effects of Weal. On 11 to 20, it has the effects of Woe | The creature who offered its blood gains the effects of False Life (at Level 5). When the Temporary Hit Points granted by the spell are lost, it suffers the effects of Woe

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 193 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Buckler of Annealing [2024]</name>
    <detail>shield, common</detail>
    <type>S</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <ac>2</ac>
    <text>This shield has 4 charges and regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn.
	While holding it, as a Reaction to a melee weapon attack that misses you by a result of 1 or 2 lower than your AC, you can spend 1 charge to cast Heat Metal (save DC 14) at the attacker's wielded weapon. Alternatively, you can spend 1 charge as part of a Shove action to cast Heat Metal at the target's worn armor or shield. When casting Heat Metal in this way, its effects last until the start of your next turn and do not require you to maintain Concentration.
	Creatures made of manufactured metal are eligible targets for this shield's properties, while weapons, armors and shields not made of such, ignore its effects.

Utilize Action to Don or Doff.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 194 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook p. 144</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Duskbane [2024]</name>
    <detail>dagger, rare</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <property>F,L,T</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>20/60</range>
    <text>You gain a +1 on attack and damage rolls made using this silvered magic weapon.

On a hit, the dagger deals an extra 2d4 Radiant damage to shape-shifted creatures (as a result of the Polymorph spell, for example). Additionally, when a shape-shifted creature is dealt damage by this dagger, it reverts to its true form and can't shape-shift until it regains a number of Hit Points equal to the damage dealt by this dagger.

Nick (Mastery): When you make the extra attack of the Light property, you can make it as part of the Attack action in· stead of as a Bonus Action. You can make this extra attack only once per turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Proficiency: simple, dagger
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 194 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Grim Harvester [2024]</name>
    <detail>sickle, rare</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <value>1</value>
    <property>F,L</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. This weapon has the Finesse property. On a hit, the sickle deals an extra 1d6 Necrotic damage.
	In addition, by using a Bonus Action, you can awaken the sinister energies that dwell within this weapon for 1 minute. For the duration, wounds inflicted by this weapon harvest the essence of the target's soul, reducing its Hit Point maximum by an amount equal to the damage dealt. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a Long Rest. The target dies if this property reduces its Hit Point maximum to 0.
	Once this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dusk.

Nick (Mastery): When you make the extra attack of the Light property, you can make it as part of the Attack action in· stead of as a Bonus Action. You can make this extra attack only once per turn.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Proficiency: simple, sickle
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 194 (Homebrew),
		Player's Handbook (2024) p. 215</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gusle of Fables [2024]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement by a bard)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Tale has it that this magic gusle has been crafted by spirits of the land, lacquered with water at the hands of the Rusalki and imbued with the Dushavoy's mystical breath. Its wood has been carved out of a Tree Weird's left hand, while its string, weaved by the hair of a Vodnik's beard. It is believed that, in the hands of a true artist, this instrument is capable of performing melodies that resonate with the very core of Creation. A creature that attempts to play the instrument without being attuned to it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (save DC 15) or take 2d4 Psychic damage.
	While attuned to this gusle, you can speak Sylvan. In addition, you gain the following benefits:

Spiritual Allure. While playing this gusle, you can magically sense the presence, general location and alignment of each creature with the Spirit subtype within 3 miles of you. Upon focusing on one such presence and playing the gusle for at least 10 minutes while maintaining Concentration, you can make a Charisma (Performance) check. The spirit that corresponds to the presence that you are focusing on must make a Wisdom saving throw (save DC equal to the result of your check). On a failed save, the spirit is compelled to come to your location, even if it has Immunity to the Charmed condition. On a success, the spirit is not compelled but may still choose to investigate the source of the supernatural melody, according to the Storyteller's discretion.

World Waker. During your turn while playing this gusle, you can choose to wake all slumbering creatures within 120 feet of you, even if they have been put to sleep by the magic of Koschei, the Deathless.

Chorus of Creation. When casting a spell that has a verbal component and requires a spell attack or forces creatures to make a saving throw while playing this gusle, you can tap into the essence of Creation, composing a convergence of power. The spell twists into a Power Word. Rather than relying on a saving throw or a spell attack roll to determine the effectiveness of this spell, the target is instead affected by it if its current Hit Points are 100 or lower. You may use this property once before the next dawn, or regain its use by expending your Heroic Inspiration.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 195 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Psychic Damage">2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Hearthbread [2024]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This loaf of bread appears ordinary at first glance but emits a comforting warmth and a faint, inviting aroma. It is wrapped in a simple, checkered cloth that always feels fresh and clean. A loaf of Hearthbread counts as 5 rations, each portion offering sustenance to a creature for an entire day. By breaking the bread and sharing it with at least one other creature, you can gain either of the following benefits.

Sweetest Taste. When shared as part of a Short Rest, Hit Dice rolled to restore Hit Points are rolled twice, keeping the highest result. In addition, creatures which partake gain Advantage on saving throws made to avoid or end the Frightened condition for the next hour.

Warmest Feeling. When shared around the fire before a Long Rest, it evokes warmth, warding the party from the harshest effects of cold environments for the duration of their rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 196 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Khronika: Volkhovnik [2024]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This ancient book is the quintessential guide to interpreting omens of every nature. While attuned to it, you gain the following benefits:

Book of Omens. You know all spells that belong to the Divination school of magic and can cast them normally by expending the appropriate spell slots.

Dispel Hex. As a Magic Action, you can cast the Remove Curse spell on a creature that is touching the book. If the curse affecting the creature is of Level 3 or lower, the curse ends and you can't use this feature again until the next dawn. If the curse is of Level 4 or higher, the curse still ends but you can't use this feature again until a number of days equal to the level of the curse have passed.

Sealed Dreams. During a Long Rest, you are under the effects of the Mind Blank spell.

Spellcasting Focus. You can use this book as a Spellcasting Focus for your spells. When you cast a Level 1 Divination spell while doing so, you don't expend a spell slot.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 196 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Kindred Fang [2024]</name>
    <detail>shortsword, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>M,F,L</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. This weapon deals Slashing or Necrotic damage (your choice), every time you use it to make an attack.

When you attune to this weapon, you must reduce your maximum number of Hit Dice by 1. The expended vitality swirls around the hilt and forms a shorsword's blade. The blade of this weapon elongates further as it feasts on the blood of your foes. While attuned to this sword, each time you hit a creature with it, its weapon damage die increases by 1 category; for example, a d6 becomes a d8, a d8 becomes a d10, up to a d12. While at an upgraded die category, you may use a Bonus Action to gain the following effects until the end of your turn:

Bloodthirst (d8). You may siphon the blood drawn by this blade to replenish your wounds. When you hit a creature with this weapon, you regain a number of Hit Points equal to the Necrotic damage dealt.

Spread Necrosis (d10). The blood of the blade slithers through the wounds of your enemies to corrupt them. When you hit a creature with this weapon, it cannot regain Hit Points until the end of its next turn.

A Thousand Cuts (d12). The blood of the blade bursts into thin lethal rivulets. When you hit a creature with this weapon, if the result of the attack roll is higher than the Armor Class of any other creatures of your choice within 15 feet of you, those creatures also take damage equal to the damage dealt to the original target.
	At the end of a turn in which you activate any of these effects, the weapon's damage die resets to a d6.

Vex (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon and deal damage to the creature, you have Advantage on your next attack roll against that creature before the end of your next turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Proficiency: martial, shortsword
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 197 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
    <roll description="A Thousand Cuts">1d12</roll>
    <roll description="Bloodthirst">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Spread Necrosis">1d10</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Loyal Pitchfork [2024]</name>
    <detail>spear, uncommon</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>T,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d8</dmg2>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <text>This seemingly unremarkable pitchfork is bolstered by the courage of mettlesome folk who pick it up to protect their homestead from wanton destruction, turning into a powerful tool in their hands. The first time you deal damage using this pitchfork during each of your turns to a creature whose maximum number of Hit Dice is higher than your own, you deal an extra 1d6 Piercing damage (1d8 if you are wielding the pitchfork with both hands).

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: simple, spear
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 197 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="If">1d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Mantle of the bear [2024]</name>
    <detail>hide armor, cursed, very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>MA</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>12</weight>
    <ac>12</ac>
    <text>You have a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor.

Legend has it that the gods often punish mortals for their misbehaviors by turning them into turnskin bears. While wearing this armor, you gain a +1 bonus to your Armor Class. Once every new dawn while attuned to this armor, you can take a Magic Action to change your shape into that of a Werebear. By doing so, you assume the statistics of a Werebear (as presented in the creature's stat block), except that you do not have the Handaxe attack option and that you cannot use the Shape-Shift Bonus Action to turn into a bear. If you use the Shape-Shift Bonus Action to revert to your original form, you cannot turn back into a werebear until the next dawn. This transformation otherwise works as per the Druid's Wild Shape feature.

Curse. Once you don this cursed armor, you can't doff it unless you are targeted by a Remove Curse spell or similar magic. Alternatively, if you try to remove or end your attunement to this armor, its claws dig violently into your skin, as its fur becomes suffused with your body. Make a DC 18 Strength saving throw. On a success, you remove the armor and your attunement with it ends. On a failed save, your shape turns into that of a Brown Bear. Your game statistics become replaced by those of the bear, except your Intelligence score which remains the same, and any equipment you are wearing or carrying merges into this new form. This effect lasts indefinitely, and can only be reverted through the effects of spells such as Remove Curse (at Level 6 or higher) or a Wish.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 198 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Mantle of the wolf [2024]</name>
    <detail>spaulders, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This mantle has been crafted using the fur of a gray direwolf. While attuned to it, you have Advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of your allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally doesn't have the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 198 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Morana's Sacred Spear [2024]</name>
    <detail>spear, very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>T,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d8</dmg2>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>20/60</range>
    <text>You can only attune to this spear during the coldest months, or at a time of great personal mourning. While attuned, you gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made using it, and Advantage on saving throws made to avoid or end the Frightened condition. On a hit, the spear deals a bonus 2d8 Necrotic damage and you regain a number of Hit Points equal to half the amount of Necrotic damage dealt in this way.
	In addition, when making a ranged weapon attack to throw this spear and hitting a creature of size Large or larger with it, the creature is run through by it, while dark magics begin to siphon its vitality. A creature impaled by this spear takes 4d8 Necrotic damage at the start of each of its turns, while you regain a number of Hit Points equal to half the amount of Necrotic damage taken by the creature. This effect lasts until the impaled creature uses an Action to remove the spear from itself.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: simple, spear
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 199 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage">2d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage">4d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Pendant of Little Miracles [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This pendant is empowered by the small every-day miracles that occur in life. While attuned to this pendant, whenever you witness a little miracle (like a flower growing from within the cracks of a boulder, rainfall during the dry season or rolling the same number twice on a check with Advantage or Disadvantage) the pendant gains 1 charge out of a maximum of 3 charges. You are notified of which event counts as such by your Storyteller.
	When you roll a 1 on the d20 on a D20 Test you can expend 3 charges to release the miraculous magic of the pendant and succeed on your roll instead.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 199 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="On">1d20</roll>
    <roll description="Test">1D20</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Plume of the Firebird [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This plucked feather still glimmers with warm sunlight; a promise of luck and prosperity for its owner. The feather emits Bright Light in a 10-foot radius, and Dim Light in another 10 feet. While carrying it, you gain Advantage on saving throws made against effects made to avoid or end the Poisoned condition or a disease.
	Additionally, while holding the feather, you can use an Action to simultaneously cast the Beacon of Hope spell and the Freedom of Movement spell without expending a spell slot or maintaining Concentration. These effects last for the next minute, affecting every creature within the area of the bright light emitted by the feather. Once this property has been used once, the feather turns into solid gold, therefore losing its magic.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 199 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Quiver of the Yonder Breath [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Arrows kept in this quiver are imbued with a breath of magical wind at every new dawn. The quiver can hold up to 20 arrows at a time. When an arrow enchanted by this quiver hits a creature, the creature is pushed 5 feet away from you. If the same creature is hit by a second enchanted arrow during the same turn, it is pushed for another 5 feet and must succeed on a Strength saving throw to avoid falling Prone. The DC of this saving throw is equal to the damage dealt by your ranged attack.
	Alternatively, you can shoot an enchanted arrow at an unoccupied space within your weapon's range. When doing so, each creature adjacent to that square is pushed 5 feet away from it.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 200 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ring of Draconic Ancestry [2024]</name>
    <detail>cursed, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>The creation of this ring predates the birth of most beings that live in the lands of Zamanora. Its exquisite craftsmanship is unparalleled, while the lemniscate curves of its shape resemble the symbol of infinity.
	Within the ring dwells the ageless spirit of a Balaur. The first time you touch it, you must succeed on a DC 20 Charisma saving throw, or be compelled to wear it. While wearing it, you can telepathically communicate with the spirit through conveying simple feelings, while your consciousness begins to eerily blend with its own. When attuned to it, you gain the following benefits:

	• You can understand and speak Draconic.

	• You gain blindsight out to a range of 60 feet.

	• Your Intelligence, Wisdom and Charisma scores are replaced with those of the balaur (unless already higher), according to its corresponding monster statistics.

Curse. Once you wear this ring, you can't remove it unless you are targeted by a Remove Curse spell or similar magic. The Balaur's spirit has been imprisoned inside the ring for eons as per the spell Imprisonment (minimus containment option) and is secretly scheming an escape from its eternal confinement. Each time you fail a Death Saving Throw, you must also make a DC 20 Charisma saving throw, as the spirit suddenly wrestles you over the control of your body. On a success, you manage to withstand its attempts. On a failed save, the balaur's spirit possesses your body, while your own spirit becomes trapped inside the ring in place of its own. Once that happens, your possessed body regains 1 Hit Point. Its statistics are otherwise those of the Balaur, as if it has used the Shape Change trait to polymorph into you.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 200 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Roadwarden's Cane [2024]</name>
    <detail>staff, very rare (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>ST</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <property>V</property>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>This staff has trodden countless miles alongside seasoned wayfarers, illuminating their way through the darkest of paths. Moreover, those who gaze into its lantern's light can peer into the wielder's past experiences. This staff has 10 charges and can be used as a spellcasting focus for your spells.

Casting a Spell. While holding this staff, you can expend its charges to cast the following spells, using your spell save DC: Druidcraft (0 charges), Comprehend Languages (1 charge), Haste (3 charges), Aura of Life (4 charges).

Guiding Flame. You can use a Magic Action and speak the staff's command word to light up its lantern. While lit, the lantern emits Bright Light in a 30-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 30 feet. It requires no fuel, and remains lit until you use another Magic Action to extinguish it. This light can pierce through magical darkness. You and friendly creatures within the lantern's light have Advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks made to navigate, track, or avoid becoming lost.

Spark of Revelation. While another creature that you are aware of is looking directly at the lantern's light, you can use an Action to convey the memory of an event to that creature, as if it had experienced it itself. The event must have transpired within the confines of the lantern's light, after the most recent time that you lit it. The conveyed memory can last no longer than one minute. The creature's observation of your memory ends prematurely if it is disturbed. Once this property has been used, it cannot be used again until the next dawn.

Regaining Charges. The staff regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll 1d20. On a 1, the staff crumbles into dust and is destroyed, leaving behind nothing but the lantern which is thereon a mundane item.

An Arcane Focus takes one of the forms in the Arcane Focuses table and is bejeweled or carved to channel arcane magic. A Sorcerer, Warlock, or Wizard can use such an item as a Spellcasting Focus.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: simple, staff, quarterstaff
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 201 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d6+4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Rusalka's Bane [2024]</name>
    <detail>handaxe, rare</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>L,T</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <range>20/60</range>
    <text>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. On a hit, when thrown at a creature or object, the weapon bursts with glitterdust. Each creature in a 20-foot Sphere centered at the weapon's target must succeed on a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw or suffer the effects of the Faerie Fire spell for the next minute. Hit or miss, the weapon returns swirling back to the thrower's hand.

Vex (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon and deal damage to the creature,[ you have Advantage on your next attack roll against that creature before the end of your next turn.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Proficiency: simple, handaxe
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 201 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Sacrificial Kindjal [2024]</name>
    <detail>dagger, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <property>F,L,T</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>20/60</range>
    <text>By spilling your own blood, you petition the spirits to bestow boons or hexes upon those around you. While attuned to this dagger and wielding it, you can use a Bonus Action to deal 1d4 Necrotic damage to yourself while focusing your intent towards a creature that you can see for the next minute. Each time you take damage in this way, your Hit Point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken until you finish a Long Rest.
	If the creature targeted by this effect is an ally, whenever it deals damage for the duration, it deals extra Necrotic damage equal to the damage you took from the dagger. Conversely, if the creature is an enemy, any damage it takes for the duration is increased by the same amount.
	When performing Blessed be the Hunters (see Chapter III: Ceremonies) as a Speaker, you may use this dagger as the material component for the Ceremony. Doing so allows you to impart the benefit granted by the dagger's properties to all the Ceremony's participants, on top of the effects normally yielded by it.

Nick (Mastery): When you make the extra attack of the Light property, you can make it as part of the Attack action in· stead of as a Bonus Action. You can make this extra attack only once per turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Proficiency: simple, dagger
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 202 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Seven-League Boots [2024]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>These shabby leather boots feature the magical properties of both Boots of Speed and Boots of Striding and springing. In addition, while attuned to these boots, you can take a Magic Action to take a 7-league step. The step functions as Teleportation with a 21-mile range, except you must have an uninterrupted path to your intended destination, though this path doesn't have to follow a straight line. Harmful environments between you and your destination cause you no harm.
	If your path is blocked, your travel ends just short of the obstacle blocking you. If you try to step too far, you appear in the closest available space to your destination without going beyond 21 miles of where you started.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 202 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Sharp Tree Feller [2024]</name>
    <detail>handaxe, rare</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>L,T</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <range>20/60</range>
    <text>This mundane-looking handaxe appears old and raggedy, yet remains curiously sharp. When dealing damage to Plant creatures or creatures that treat forests as their natural habitat using this handaxe, you add your Strength modifier twice instead of once to the damage dealt.

Vex (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon and deal damage to the creature, you have Advantage on your next attack roll against that creature before the end of your next turn.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Proficiency: simple, handaxe
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 202 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Stormbringer's Boots [2024]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This pair of boots has been masterfully crafted using the skin of a nose-horned viper, and then enchanted with Evocation magics that cause them to constantly crackle with electricity. While attuned to this boots, you gain the following benefits:

Crackling Conduit. You have Resistance to Lightning damage.

Lightning Discharge. By taking a Magic Action, you can turn into a flash of light and teleport in a straight line to an unoccupied space within 100 feet that you can see. Each creature in the line is affected by the Lightning Bolt spell.

Once this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn, or until you take at least 10 points of Lightning damage in a single instance, as the electrical currents recharge the boots' magic.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 203 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Survival Guide [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This tome, bound in rich brown leather, is a comprehensive guide to surviving and thriving in mystical forests. Written by Živko Bilkober, its pages are filled with detailed illustrations, maps, and handwritten notes from various adventurers and scholars. While the knowledge hidden in the tome is too intricately written to remember in detail, referencing it can grant multiple benefits.

Forest Guide. By reading the book for at least 1 hour, you gain Advantage on Study and Wisdom (Survival) checks related to forest terrain, such as the foraging and identification of Zamanoran mushrooms, as well as creatures of the Beast, Fey and Plant types. This effect lasts until you complete a Long Rest.

Exploration Tips. While referencing the book (as if you were maintaining Concentrating on a spell) and using materials found in the forest, you and up to five creatures can move through the wilderness leaving behind no tracks or other traces and ignoring Difficult Terrain.

Language of the Woods. While referencing the book (as if you were maintaining Concentrating on a spell) during your communication with a Fey creature, you can understand and speak Sylvan in a limited manner. Additionally, you gain Advantage on a single Influence check made against it.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 203 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Tankard of Reflection [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This finely crafted metal tankard has a highly polished surface that reflects the drinker perfectly.
	During a Long Rest, by spending part of your time drinking alcohol using this goblet and selfreflecting, you gain Heroic Inspiration. If you do so for five consecutive rests, you also have Disadvantage on Initiative checks until your next Long Rest, the constant second guessing taking its toll.
	Additionally during a Long Rest, by drinking yourself to a stupor, you can contemplate your future Actions. You cast the Augury spell, mulling over the results of an Action you plan to take the next day. For the first four hours after your Long Rest, you have the Poisoned condition from the hangover.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 204 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Targe of the Midsummer [2024]</name>
    <detail>shield, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>S</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <ac>2</ac>
    <text>While holding this shield, you have a +1 bonus to Armor Class, in addition to the Shield's normal bonus to AC. While attuned to it, you can always orient yourself by innately knowing the direction of the sun.
	Moreover, you can use a Bonus Action on your turn to make a melee attack against a target within reach, using the bull horns that protrude from the shield's front. On a hit, this attack deals Piercing damage equal to 1d4 plus your Strength modifier, and you can speak the Shield's command word, causing its hay effigy to burst aflame. Doing so causes the target to catch fire; until someone takes an Action to douse the fire, the target takes 1d4 Fire damage at the start of each of its turns. The effigy is then destroyed.
	You can create a new effigy by weaving a bundle of dry plant matter (such as hay, twigs, wheat, kindling, etc.) together by making a successful DC 10 Nature or Religion check over a course of 10 minutes, and then place it upon the Shield.

Utilize Action to Don or Doff.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 204 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d4+%1</roll>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>The Blade Hidden in the Mists [2024]</name>
    <detail>longsword, uncommon (requires attunement by a bogatyr fighter)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>Throughout the centuries, this legendary longsword has known many names; Kladenets, Samosek or, most commonly, the Hidden Blade. The sword is thought as lost, obscured by perpetual mists that refuse to reveal it, until a foretold time that the worthy hands of a brave Bogatyr (see Chapter II: Subclasses) shall reach out to seize it. Then, the mists will spread for the hero's passing, allowing them to gain a fabled weapon most worthy of a legend.
	You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While attuned to this weapon and wielding or carrying it, you gain Resistance to Bludgeoning, Slashing and Piercing damage.
	In addition, once before every new dawn, you can take a Magic Action to cast the Globe of Invulnerability spell without maintaining Concentration. The Emanation is centered on you and moves with you.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, longsword
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 205 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +3</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>The Epitaph [2024]</name>
    <detail>greatsword, uncommon (requires attunement by a charector with a str score of 18+)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <property>M,H,2H</property>
    <dmg1>3d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>B</dmgType>
    <text>This greatsword's blade resembles a headstone, the very sight of which sends shivers down your spine. It feels as if it was mounted on the hilt as a warning, a rebuke to those who would deny the eternal peace of the afterlife: refuse the inevitable call of the grave, and your own headstone shall come hunting for you.
	You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Even though it has the shape of a greatsword, the weapon damage dealt by it on a hit is 3d6 (instead of 2d6) and its damage type is Bludgeoning.

Unwieldy. This enormous greatsword is wildly unbalanced and almost entirely made of stone, which makes it difficult to wield with deftness and precision. When making an attack using this weapon, your attack targets all creatures within its reach. Additionally, you cannot use this weapon to make Opportunity Attacks.

Sepulchre's Smite. When you hit an Undead with this weapon, it takes an extra 2d6 Radiant damage. On a Critical Hit, the Undead also becomes Stunned until the end of its next turn

Requiem for the Deathless. As a Magic Action, you can plunge this weapon into the earth and speak its command word. When doing so, each Undead creature in a 30-foot radius centered at the weapon must make a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or suffer the effects of the Cleric's Channel Divinity feature (Turn Undead option). When an Undead of CR 1 or lower fails its saving throw against this effect, the creature is instantly destroyed. While the weapon remains plunged in this way, this effect is automatically repeated at the end of each of your subsequent turns. To pull the weapon from the earth, you must spend another Action.

Litany of Remembrance. When an Undead is destroyed or has its soul released onto the afterlife within 30 feet of this weapon, you can choose to have the name it had in life magically appear upon the blade besides the inscription that adorns it. The inscription then begins to glimmer, revealing a prayer for the dead. When that happens, the weapon gains a number of charges equal to the Undead creature's maximum amount of Hit Dice. While the inscription is glimmering, you can use a Bonus Action on your turn to utter a litany of remembrance for the departed, spending one or more of its available charges and gaining 1 Temporary Hit Point for each charge spent in this way. When the weapon's charges are depleted, the creature's name vanishes and the inscription ceases to glimmer. Only one creature's name can be upon the blade at a time, and a new one cannot appear until the charges granted by the previous have been depleted.

Graze (Mastery): If your attack roll with this weapon misses a creature, you can deal damage to that creature equal to the ability modifier you used to make the attack roll. This damage is the same type dealt by the weapon, and the damage can be increased only by increasing the ability modifier.

Heavy: You have Disadvantage on attack rolls with a Heavy weapon if it's a Melee weapon and your Strength score isn't at least 13 or if it's a Ranged weapon and  your Dexterity score isn't at least 13.

Two-Handed: A Two-Handed weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Proficiency: martial, greatsword
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 206 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +3</modifier>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Vasilisa's Skull Lantern [2024]</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>The infamous lantern bestowed upon Vasilisa by the crone Baba Yaga still emanates with an eerie, otherwordly lightthat purges those who have greatl ywronged its bearer.
	This lantern has 20 charges and can be used as a spellcasting focus for your spells. While you hold it, you gain a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls and your spell save DC. It casts bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. By using a Magic Action to speak its command word, you can reduce the light to dim light in a 5-foot radius.

Casting a Spell. You can expend the lantern's charges to cast the following spells with a spell save DC of 20: Chill Touch (0 charges), Eyebite (6 charges), Fear (3 charges), Find the Path (6 charges), Scorching Ray (Level 4, 4 charges), Spirit Guardians (evil option, 3 charges).
	Upon casting either of the above spells through the lantern, it immediately begins to cast bright light (if it isn't already).

Witchfire. Whenever you deal Fire or Necrotic damage through a spell cast by the lantern to a creature that is within the lantern's Bright Light, you can expend 1 additional charge to cause that creature to also catch on witchfire; a creature on witchfire takes 1d4 Fire and 1d4 Necrotic damage at the start of each of its turns. Each creature on witchfire must make a Charisma saving throw (save DC 20) at the start of each of its subsequent turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.

Unveiling Light. By using a Magic Action and spending 1 charge while the lantern casts bright light, Illusion spells of 3rd level of lower are suppressed in the light's radius. Addionally, creatures in the area are seen for what they truly are, as if perceived by the True Seeing spell. In order to maintain this effect, you must spend a Bonus Action and 1 additional charge on each of your subsequent turns.

Regaining Charges. The lantern regains 2d6 + 2 expended charges daily at dusk. If you expend the last charge, roll 1d20. On a 20, the lantern regains 2d8 + 2 charges. On a 1, the lantern immediately vanishes and magically returns to Baba Yaga's possession, while you fall under the effects of Curse of Hopeless Wandering (see Chapter III: Curses) as if cast by her at 9th level.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 208 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Witchfire">(1d4)+(1d4)</roll>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">1d4</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage">1d4</roll>
    <roll description="Recharge">2d6+2</roll>
    <roll description="Recharge">2d8+2</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Veil charm [2024]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>While this charm is in your possession, you have Advantage on saving throws made to resist effects that would increase your Veilmark Score (see Chapter II: Veilmark). In addition, you may choose to make these saving throws using Charisma or Intelligence, rather than Wisdom as you normally would.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 208 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of the Beekeeper [2024]</name>
    <detail>arcane or druidic focus, uncommon (requires attunement by a bard, cleric, or druid)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>In witchcraft, the use of honey symbolizes abundance, healing, and nourishment. While attuned to this wand, when you roll a 1 or 2 on the amount of Hit Points regained after casting a spell that allows a creature to regain Hit Points, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.
	In addition, you can use a Bonus Action to call forth a Swarm of Insects (bees) to emerge from the hive at the head of the wand and appear in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. The swarm is Friendly to you and your allies, and it acts immediately after you on your Initiative count. You can take a Bonus Action to command swarm on how to move and what Action it takes on its next turn, such as attacking an enemy. In the absence of such orders, the swarm acts in a fashion appropriate to its nature.
	If the swarm of insects is reduced to 0 Hit Points, you cannot use this property again until the next dawn.

Arcane Focus: An arcane focus is a special item designed to channel the power of arcane spells. A sorcerer, warlock, or wizard can use such an item as a spellcasting focus.

Druidic Focus: A druid can use this object as a spellcasting focus.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 209 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of Draconic Insight [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Like the legendary Balaur who act as the lorekeepers of the world, this wand becomes more powerful as its wielder attains newfound knowledge. This wand has 6 charges, regaining 1d4 + 1 charges daily at dawn. Each time you succeed on a Study check made to determine the lore and traits of a creature, the wand regains 1 charge.

Cast Spell. While attuned to this wand, you can spend a number of its available charges in order to cast the following spells with a spell save DC of 14: Burning Hands (1 charge), Scorching Ray (2 charges).

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 209 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of the Murrain Maiden [2024]</name>
    <detail>cursed, very rare (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>This wand has been blessed by the lady of plagues, conferring pestilence and decay to any form of life it is pointed at. While you hold it, you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls and the saving throw DCs of your spells.

Contamination. While attuned to this wand, you can cast Poison Spray out to a range of 30 feet as a Magic Action. A creature that fails its save against this spell also gains the Poisoned condition until the end of your next turn. In addition, once every new dusk, you can cast Contagion out to a range of 30 feet. Both spells use your spell save DC and spellcasting ability.

Relish in Agony. While attuned to this wand, at the start of each of your turns, you gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to your spellcasting ability modifier for each creature that has the Poisoned condition or carries a disease within 30 feet of you.

Curse. The gifts of the Murrain Maiden come at a cost, as the voracious power that surges through the wand seeks to consume its Bearer as well. Upon ending your attunement to it, you suffer the effects of the Contagion spell (save DC 16). This spell's effects can end prematurely by attuning to the wand once again.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 210 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of the Mycologist [2024]</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Encountering a potent and rare mushroom in the wilds is viewed as a symbol of good luck, recreation, transformation, and even enlightenment. This wand has 3 charges, represented by the magical mushrooms that sprout from it. While holding it, you can take a Magic Action to expend 1 of its charges and consume a mushroom growing from the wand. Upon doing so, you benefit from one of the following properties chosen at random. Each property lasts for the duration of 1 hour and does not require you to maintain Concentration in order to benefit from its effect.

Wand of the Mycologist:
d6 | Mushroom Property
1 | Alter Self
2 | Enhance Ability
3 | Enlarge/Reduce
4 | Expeditious Retreat
5 | Longstrider
6 | Spider Climb

The wand regains 1d3 charges daily at dawn, as it sprouts an equal number of new mushrooms. For each additional mushroom you consume while the effects of another are still ongoing, there is a cumulative 25 percent chance of falling under the effects of the Confusion spell (save DC 15), on top of the benefits yielded by the mushroom.
	By becoming attuned to this wand, you grow aware of the benefits granted by the magical mushrooms it sprouts prior to their consumption, and you may choose which mushroom to benefit from based on your preference. Every time the wand regains a new charge, roll 1d6 to determine the property that corresponds to it.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 210 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Mushroom">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of the Winter mare [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>As cold winds howl and the leaves are stripped from the trees, the annual sense of terror before the coming of the cold months grips the hearts of everyone. This wand has 6 charges, regaining 1d4 + 1 charges daily at dusk.
	While attuned to this wand, each time you cast a spell that deals Cold damage, you can use the wand's available charges as Sorcery Points in order to enhance your spell with a Metamagic option from the following list: Distant Spell, Heightened Spell, Quickened Spell, Twinned Spell.
	In addition, when you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die after casting such a spell, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.

Cast Spell. You can spend the wand's charges in order to cast the Dream spell (5 charges, monstrous messenger only).

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 211 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4+1</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Witch's Hand Sweeper [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>The broom has 3 charges. It regains all expended charges daily at dusk. The broom can be wielded as a one-handed improvised weapon, and can be used to sweep at a creature, object or magical effect within 5 feet of you.
	When sweeping at a creature, make a melee spell attack against it. On a hit, the creature takes no damage, but you may expend 1 of the broom's charges to cast the Dispel Magic spell to it. When sweeping an object or magical effect, your attack automatically hits.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 211 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Yaga's Cauldron [2024]</name>
    <detail>legendary</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Baba Yaga's vile magics have seeped into this squat, copper cauldron. As part of casting a spell, throwing its material components into this magic cauldron while it boils for at least 10 minutes with any liquid substance enhances its magic. If it has a duration of 1 minute or longer, the spell's duration becomes 24 hours instead, and it can target any willing creature within the same plane of existence, regardless of range. If that spell is Bestow Curse and the target creature is in the same plane of existence and familiar to you, it can be targeted by the spell regardless of range.
	All the spell's components are destroyed in the process. When casting a spell that targets a creature, you may substitute the spell's original components with an important heirloom or body part (such as a drop of blood, lock of hair, bit of nail, and the like) that belongs to that creature. In order to yield the cauldron's benefits to a spell that doesn't require material components at all, you must still use one of the aforementioned items.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 211 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Zhor, Vestige of the Old world [2024]</name>
    <detail>longsword, artifact (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>This blade, the only one of its kind ever made, was created with an express purpose: the slaying of Dragons. In ages past, it is said the goddess Yorveth would despair at the havoc the Dragons wrought upon the land, the ruin they visited to mortal settlements. Feeling the need for a limit to be placed between the worlds of Dragons and mortals, the Giving Goddess embarked upon an unprecedented act of tipping the scales. She gathered the bones of a slain balaur, and brought them to her own hearth in the core of the earth. There, the goddess put forth all her craft and inspiration, all her will to restore the land to equilibrium.
	And from those flames, that ever until then and ever since, have only borne tools of making and repairing, emerged for a single time a vessel of death. Zhor, the Blade Between, to mark the edge dividing dragonkin from mortalkind. Her purpose exhausted, Yorveth bestowed this blade upon a mortal champion, charging them to uphold the balance, and returned to her sacred hearth.
	Even though it was forged as an instrument of war, Yorveth made it so that the blade's very existence would keep the peace, serving as a warning to all of dragonkind, discouraging even the most elder of wyrms from delving too close to mortal settlements in fear of the blade's emergence. Yet the eons pass like flowing creeks, and a purpose once clear has now been lost to lethe. No one knows where the blade now lies forlorn, yet one thing is for certain: an Artifact of such might shall be given a new purpose by the hands that pick it up anew, and the heart that stirs them into motion. Will it remain a symbol of hope for the hopeless, in the hands of a warden for all of mortalkind? Or will it turn into a symbol of vengeance, even war against the Old World and its most venerated custodians; the Dragons?
	This weapon has 12 charges You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While attuned to it, you gain Resistance to Fire damage. The Longsword can hold up to 12 charges.
	By using a Bonus Action to speak its command word, the weapon becomes coated with a molten layer of magma. For the duration, it gains the following properties:

Firebrand. The weapon sheds Bright Light in a 10-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 10 feet. In addition, it deals an extra 2d6 Fire damage on a successful hit, igniting flammable objects and setting its target on fire. A target on fire burns for 1d6 Fire damage at the start of each of its turns, until someone uses an Action to douse the fire.

Sundering Blaze. When you hit a creature wearing armor or wielding a shield made of manufactured metal using this weapon, you can spend 2 charges to cause it to melt. The item takes a −1 penalty to the AC it offers. Armor is destroyed if the penalty reduces its Armor Class to 10. A shield is destroyed if its bonus is reduced to 0. The penalty can be removed by casting the Mending spell. Magic items ignore this property's effects.

Bane of Dragonkind. When you damage a Dragon using this weapon, the Dragon's Hit Point maximum is reduced by a number equal to half the amount of damage taken. This effect is permanent, and can only be reversed through the effects of a Wish spell. Dragons that become aware of this weapon, supernaturally sense the effects of this property and often act to avoid a direct conflict with its wielder, as even if they emerge victorious from it, the wounds they might sustain may forever cripple them.

Casting a Spell. You can expend the weapon's charges to cast the following spells with a spell save DC of 18: Burning Hands (1 charge), Fireball (3 charges), Fire Shield (4 charges, warm shield variant), Wall of Fire (4 charges).
	The weapon's flames are doused when you spend a Bonus Action to speak itscommand word, or when its last charge has been depleted.

Regaining Charges. The weapon regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn. The weapon can also regain charges by absorbing extensive heat and roaming embers from the environment in either of the following ways:

	• On a hit against a creature that has Immunity to Fire damage, the weapon regains 1 charge.

	• While wielding the weapon, you can use your Reaction when another creature casts a spell that deals Fire damage and targets only you. When you do so, the weapon absorbs the magic of the spell, canceling its effect and gaining a number of charges equal to the absorbed spell's level.

	• By using a Magic Action to point the weapon towards an open source of flame within 60 feet of you that fits within a 10-foot cube, you can cause it to be instantaneously extinguished. The weapon then gains 1 charge for each 5 feet of flame extinguished in this way.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Versatile: A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, longsword
Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 212 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +3</modifier>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">2d6</roll>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Recharge">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle of Revealing [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This sacred candle wards an area from evil, while constituting an opening between the visible and the invisible.
	This candle's magic is activated when the candle is lit, which requires a Magic Action. After burning for 1 hour, the candle is destroyed. You can snuff it out early for use at a later time. Deduct the time it burned in increments of 1 minute from its total burn time.
	While lit, the candle sheds Dim Light in a 30-foot radius. Creatures and objects that have the Invisible condition and are within that light, are revealed as if they were visible. In addition, Fey, Fiend and Undead creatures can't willingly move through the light produced by this candle by nonmagical means unless they first succeed on a DC 14 Charisma saving throw. If the creature tries to use teleportation or interplanar travel to do so, it must first succeed on a Charisma saving throw against the same DC. On a success, the creature becomes immune to the effects of this candle for the next 24 hours.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 214 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle of Spectral Anamnesis [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This candle's emanating fragrance carries your voice over to the world of the dead, where it echoes, compelling its denizens to your call.
	This candle's magic is activated when the candle is lit, which requires a Magic Action. After burning for 1 hour, the candle is destroyed. You can snuff it out early for use at a later time. Deduct the time it burned in increments of 1 minute from its total burn time.
	While lit, the candle sheds Dim Light in a 30-foot radius. Upon lighting this candle, you can attempt to summon the soul of a deceased creature which you know by name or title. The soul can willingly respond to your call or resist it by making a Charisma saving throw (save DC 14). Depending on how familiar the creature was to you in life and the Storyteller's discretion, it may gain Advantage or Disadvantage on this saving throw.
	On a successful save, the soul ignores your call and the candle's total burn time is reduced by 10 minutes. On a failed save, it appears before you at an unoccupied space within the light of the candle. You can then converse with the soul normally. The soul may remain in the world of the living for as long as the candle burns.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 215 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle of Vicious Torment [2024]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This candle's wax has been infused with the enchanted blood of living creatures. It has no wick, yet when it melts, it appears to liquify unnervingly fast.
	When the hair of a target creature is inserted into the top and ignited, the hair will burn like a regular candle wick. This candle's magic is activated when the candle is lit, which requires a Magic Action. After burning for 1 hour, the candle is destroyed. You can snuff it out early for use at a later time. Deduct the time it burned in increments of 1 minute from its total burn time.
	For every minute that the candle burns, the target creature to whom the hair belongs to has its Hit Point total reduced by 1, as a wound it has suffered in the past magically reopens and bleeds. If its Hit Point maximum is reduced to 0 in this way, the creature dies. The creature's Hit Point total can be reverted to normal through the effects of spells such as Greater Restoration or a Wish.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 215 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Arcane Replenishment [2024]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>When you drink this potion, the next time you expend a level 6 spell slot or lower before the end of your turn, you immediately replenish it.
	The liquid inside this vial looks like the night sky, its stars glittering with the tiniest ray of sunlight.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 217 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Arun's Voice [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>When you drink this potion, your voice turns booming and thunderous, while your intent becomes supernaturally difficult to resist. This effect lasts for the next minute. For the duration, you gain Advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) and Charisma (Persuasion) checks. In addition, whenever you succeed on such a D20 Test against a creature, you can force it to follow a one-word command of yours, as if it was under the effects of the Command spell.
	Shaking this vial causes the dark liquid within to produce sparks, and a rumbling noise emanates from it.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 217 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Elemental Attunement [2024]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This potion attunes itself to a substantial source of elemental energy when it comes within 5-feet of it (for example, a campfire) or is exposed to its general vicinity (for example, a raging storm) for at least 1 hour. TheseSources of energy can relate to either Acid, Cold, Fire or Lightning.
	The color of its contents signifies which element it is currently attuned to. When you drink this potion, you are imbued with the essence of the aforementioned element, gaining Immunity to its corresponding damage type for the next hour.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 217 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Enhanced Pheromones [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Drinking this potion causes your hair and skin to excrete special pheromones that attract Beasts for the next minute. For the duration, Beasts know your exact location if you are within 60 feet of them and they treat you as Indifferent unless attacked or provoked first. Additionally, you gain Advantage on Influence checks made against them.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 218 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Liquid Courage [2024]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>When you drink this potion, your senses become dampened. For the next minute, you gain Advantage on saving throws you make to end or avoid the Frightened condition, and Disadvantage on Study checks.
	The stinging taste of this potion pleasantly burns your throat and tongue with alcohol.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 218 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Rejuvenation [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>When you drink this potion, your body's regenerative mechanisms are enhanced until the end of your next turn. For the duration, you regain the maximum number of Hit Points possible from any healing effect.
	At first glance, this liquid looks like any ordinary healing potion; except that it has amber bubbles floating within.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 218 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Serenity [2024]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>When you drink this potion, you gain Advantage on saving throws you make to end or avoid the Charmed conditions for the next minute. In addition, if you are Poisoned when drinking this potion, make a Constitution saving throw against the initial DC of the effect that afflicted you with the Poisoned condition. On a success, you are no longer Poisoned.
	This potion has the mellow taste of a chamomile.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 219 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Temsul's Embrace [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This heavy flask of blackened glass bears the faint imprint of a skull whose hollow eyes seem to follow the drinker. When drunk, your skin shrivels, growing leathery and tough. You gain 20 Temporary Hit Points for 1 minute. While you have these Temporary Hit Points, you are Immune to Necrotic damage and the Poisoned condition. Additionally, unintelligent Undead treat you as one of their own. For the duration, you are treated as if under the effects of Sanctuary against Undead creatures of Intelligence 6 or lower.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 219 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Windy Escape [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>When you drink this potion, favorable winds follow you as you feel lighter. For the next minute, your movement does not provoke Opportunity Attacks and you have Advantage on your Acrobatics (Dexterity) checks when trying to escape from a grapple. Additionally, you can take the Dash Action as a Bonus Action.
	This translucent liquid has a sharp taste that invokes zest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 219 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Elixir of the Blooming Thorn [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>The effects of this elixir last for 8 hours. This elixir contains a thorny sapling within it. When you drink this elixir's contents, the sapling immediately starts growing within you. After one minute it blossoms, as thorns and vines grow from your skin and cover it. You gain the effects of the Barkskin spell for the next 8 hours.
	Additionally, during that time, you may use a Bonus Action once to exhale a cloud of deadly poison. When you do so, creatures in a 20-foot Cone must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC 13). On a failure, a creature takes 4d6 Poison damage and has the Poisoned condition for the next minute. On a success a creature takes half as much damage.
ource Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 220 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Poison Damage">4d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Elixir of Morana's Embrace [2024]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>A minute after drinking this elixir, the icy cold breath of the Long Night begins to run through your veins. For the next 8 hours, you gain the following benefits:

	• Resistance to Cold damage.
	• Immunity to the Frightened condition.
	• Creatures that become Frightened of you are Stunned instead.
	• Once before the duration of the effect is over, you can cast the Cone of Cold spell (save DC 15). For the duration, if you cause another creature to become Frightened of you, you regain use of this property.

The contents of this vial immediately begin to evaporate in a freezing mist when it is unstoppered.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 221 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Elixir of the Nightprowler [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Consuming this dark gloomy liquid seems to bring the world into sharper focus. A minute after drinking this elixir, you gain the predatory awareness of nocturnal beasts for the next 8 hours.
	For the duration, you gain Darkvision out to a range of 60 feet (if you already have Darkvision, its range increases by 60 feet). In addition, you gain Advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight, hearing or smell.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 221 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Elixir of Springtide [2024]</name>
    <detail>very rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>A minute after drinking this elixir, you regain 8d4 Hit Points. Additionally, if you die within 8 hours after consumption, you return to life with 1 Hit Point at the end of the elixir's duration. This elixir can't return to life a creature that has died of old age, nor can it restore any missing body parts. Junipers and raspberries float within this liquid, giving it a vibrant appearance. It is extremely sweet to the tongue and goes down easier than water.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 222 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Heal">8d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Elixir of Stillness [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Upon drinking this light brown liquid you immediately become aware of your breath rising from your stomach, your heartbeat slowing. A minute after drinking this elixir, you attain a state of internal tranquility that can be conferred to others by your mere touch. This effect lasts for the next 8 hours. For the duration, you gain Immunity to the Frightened condition. In addition, you may forgo making an attack to instead touch a creature within your reach and subject it to the effects of the Calm Emotions spell (save DC 14). Finally, when a creature hits you with an attack, it then treats you as if you were under the effects of Sanctuary (save DC 14) until the end of its turn.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 222 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Elixir of Swiftness [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>A minute after drinking this elixir, your reflexes become almost supernatural. For the next 8 hours, you can take the Dodge Action as a Reaction when a Weapon Attack is made against you, that you are aware of. For the duration, you also have Advantage on Dexterity saving throws. The swirling dark liquid within this elixir tastes foul and rotten.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 222 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Elixir of Viper's Vexing [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>A minute after drinking this elixir and for the next 8 hours, you gain Immunity to Poison damage, to the Poisoned condition and to contracting diseases. At the end of the duration, if you avoided any Poison damage or the Poisoned condition while under the elixir's effects, you must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or become Poisoned until you finish a Long Rest.
	Dark sediment gathers at the bottom of the milky-colored liquid in this vial.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 223 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil of the Anointed Hunter [2024]</name>
    <detail>rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>For the next 8 hours after applying the oil, you are under the effects of the Protection from Evil and Good spell. For the duration, if you kill a Humanoid, you immediately lose the effects of this oil and suffer the effects of Bane for the remainder of the effect. Applying this oil to the shoulders and forehead of a Humanoid causes barely perceptible patterns to appear on the skin.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 223 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil of Coagulation [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>For the next 8 hours after applying the oil, you can use a Bonus Action to expend a Hit Die, roll it and regain an amount of Hit Points equal to the result plus your Constitution modifier.
	The crimson-tinted liquid is ever swirling even if its vial is undisturbed, while thick bubbles grow and shrink within.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 224 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil of Magic Resistance [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>After applying the oil, your skin begins glimmering with an abjuring aura. For the next 8 hours, you gain Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.
	The interior of this vial seems to sparkle with tiny wisps of azure light.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 224 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil of Mortal Likeness [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>For the next 24 hours after applying the oil, the effigy animates under your command as if you had cast the Animate Objects spell at it. You are not required to maintain Concentration for this effect. When the duration is over, the effigy falls inanimate again.
	The clear liquid in this vial seems to ever-so-slightly ignore gravity to move under its own power.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 224 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Emberspark [2024]</name>
    <detail>powder, uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>Glowing embers scatter in a 10-foot-radius Sphere centered on the point of impact. For every 5 feet a creature moves within the area, it takes 1d4 Fire damage as the embers explode beneath its feet. The embers fizzle out at the end of your next turn.
	Colorful flames seem to flicker over the red dust within the flask.

Powder: A powder is not consumed or applied, but rather packed in a flask, usually equipped with a fuse. The contents of a powder flask spread upon impact, affecting a small area around it. In order to use them, you must forego one of your attacks and throw the powder up to a range of 20 feet.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 225 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Powder of the Red Death [2024]</name>
    <detail>powder, very rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>All creatures within a 30-foot radius from the point of impact must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (save DC 17) or have the Poisoned condition for the next minute. While Poisoned in this way, a creature immediately begins suffocating. At the end of each of its turns, an affected creature repeats the save at Disadvantage, ending the effects on itself on a success.
	This crimson powder smells of lavender and burning wood.

Powder: A powder is not consumed or applied, but rather packed in a flask, usually equipped with a fuse. The contents of a powder flask spread upon impact, affecting a small area around it. In order to use them, you must forego one of your attacks and throw the powder up to a range of 20 feet.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 225 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Restoring Spores [2024]</name>
    <detail>powder, rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>All creatures within a 10-foot-radius Sphere centered on the point of impact regain 1d8 Hit Points. The dust lingers in the air for 1 minute unless a strong wind dissipates it. When a creature starts its turn within the area of the lingering dust, it regains 1d4 Hit Points.
	This concoction includes a blend of herbs with a thin gray dust.

Powder: A powder is not consumed or applied, but rather packed in a flask, usually equipped with a fuse. The contents of a powder flask spread upon impact, affecting a small area around it. In order to use them, you must forego one of your attacks and throw the powder up to a range of 20 feet.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 225 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Heal">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Heal">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Shimmerdust [2024]</name>
    <detail>powder, uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>All creatures within a 15-foot-radius Sphere centered on the point of impact must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (save DC 13) or be Blinded until the end of their next turn.
	This golden powder bursts into a blinding light once it is released from its flask.

Powder: A powder is not consumed or applied, but rather packed in a flask, usually equipped with a fuse. The contents of a powder flask spread upon impact, affecting a small area around it. In order to use them, you must forego one of your attacks and throw the powder up to a range of 20 feet.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 226 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Stinging Powder [2024]</name>
    <detail>powder, common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>All creatures within a 10-foot-radius Sphere centered on the point of impact must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (save DC 12) or be covered with this powder. The powder is so itchy and distracting that an affected creature can take either an Action or a Bonus Action on its turns, not both, until it uses an Action to wipe the dust off of it.
	Specks of this powder seem to dance within their own flask.

Powder: A powder is not consumed or applied, but rather packed in a flask, usually equipped with a fuse. The contents of a powder flask spread upon impact, affecting a small area around it. In order to use them, you must forego one of your attacks and throw the powder up to a range of 20 feet.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 226 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Belted Conk [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You gain Tremorsense out to a range of 60 feet for the next 8 hours.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 228 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Blackstem Truffle [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You gain the effects of the False Life spell at a spell level equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1), but whenever you fail a D20 Test, you gain the Poisoned condition for the next minute, as you are struck with lightheadedness. These effects last until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 228 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Death Cap [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>If you have less than 60 Hit Points, you are immediately reduced to 0 Hit Points, fall Unconscious and start making Death Saving Throws. If you have 60 Hit Points or more, you are reduced to 0 Hit Points and fall Unconscious but Stable instead, regaining consciousness in 1d4 days. During this time, you cannot regain consciousness by any means short of the effects of the spells Greater Restoration, Lesser Restoration or similar magic.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 229 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Days">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Foxfire [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>Your skin glows with a greenish hue, shedding dim light in a 5-foot radius around you. In addition, you have the Blinded condition while directly exposed to Bright Light. These effects last until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 229 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Fury Cap [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You gain Advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks and saving throws made to avoid or end the Frightened condition against you, until you finish a Long Rest. For the duration, the first time you are dealt damage by another creature, you gain the effects of the Barbarian's Rage feature.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 229 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gigglespore [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You gain Advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks and saving throws made to avoid or end the Frightened condition against you, until you finish a Long Rest. For the duration, the first time you are dealt damage by another creature, you gain the effects of the Barbarian's Rage feature.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 229 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>God Flesh [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You fall under the effects of the Hallucinatory Terrain spell (save DC 12 plus your Wisdom modifier) for the next 8 hours, as described by the Storyteller. For the duration, whenever you succeed on a Study check made to disbelieve or discern the Illusion, you also take Psychic damage equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1). If you have not taken any Psychic damage by the time the effect's duration due, you gain Heroic Ιnspiration.
	When you gain Heroic Inspiration in this way, you can choose to expend it and reduce your Veilmark Score. You must select three memories of great personal significance and assign each a number from 1 to 3. Then, roll a d10. On a result of 1 to 3, you permanently forget the corresponding numbered memory, as you struggle to remove your Veilmark experiences from your mind. On a result of 4 to 10, your memories remain intact. Regardless of the outcome, when the 8-hour trance concludes, your Veilmark Score is halved.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 230 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Memories">1d10</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Haze Lichen [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You experience the disorienting sense of seeing things double until you finish a Long Rest. For the duration, you have Disadvantage on Study checks and attack rolls.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 230 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Musty Puffball [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You become Poisoned for the next minute. Once throughout the effect's duration, you can take a Magic Action to exhale nauseating gas, as per the Stinking Cloud spell (save DC 16). When the duration ends, you spend your Action retching and reeling, as you expel the poison from your body.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 230 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Pale Pilgrim [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You gain Truesight out to a range of 60 feet for the next 8 hours.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 231 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Prickly Goadcap [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You fall under the effects of the Slow spell for the next minute, without getting to make a save to end the effects prematurely. Should not be confused with the Prickly Spurcap.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 231 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Prickly Spurcap [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You gain the effects of the Haste spell for the next minute. When this effect ends, you do not suffer the usual Incapacitated condition or Speed reduction. Should not be confused with the Prickly Goadcap.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 231 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Roamer's Folly [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You have the Poisoned condition and gain two levels of Exhaustion until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 231 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Scuffle Bell [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You fall under the effects of the Confusion spell for the next minute, without getting to make a save to end the effects prematurely.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 231 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Soldier Beech [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>Whenever you spend a Hit Dice for the purpose of regaining Hit Points, you forgo rolling it and instead regain the maximum result. Additionally, you ignore the negative effects of travelling at a Fast Pace and require no food or drink to sustain yourself for the day. These effects last until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 232 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Trickster Toadstool [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You grow especially gullible for the next 8 hours. For the duration, you gain Disadvantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks, and every time a creature succeeds on an Influence check against you, you become Charmed by it as per the effects of the Charm Person spell.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 232 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Violet Parasol [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>Eating this mushroom or inhaling its spores causes you to fall Unconscious and into a deep, wakeless slumber for the next 8 hours. Being aware of this mushroom's properties prior to falling under its effects allows you to benefit from them by casting the Dream spell (save DC 14) once throughout the duration of your slumber.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 232 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Voracious Maw [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>As soon as you have eaten this mushroom, it begins to slowly spread from the inside out, ultimately taking over your body. Every time you finish a Long Rest, you gain a level of Exhaustion that cannot be removed in any way. If you die from Exhaustion caused in this way, you rise as a fungi-infested nezhit 2d6 minutes after your death. Spells like Greater Restoration, Lesser Restoration or similar magic, end this condition on yourself and therefore allow you to remove any accumulated levels of Exhaustion through normal means.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 232 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Minutes">2d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Witch's Gambit [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>Roll a d100. On a 1-50, your Intelligence score changes to 24. On a 51-100, your Intelligence score changes to 1. Both of these effects last for 1 hour.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 233 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll>1d100</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Witty Morsel [2024]</name>
    <detail>zamanoran mushrooms</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You gain telepathic communication with every other creature that is currently under the effects of the same type of mushroom within a mile's radius. This effect lasts until you finish a Long rest. For the duration, every time you make a D20 Test, the Storyteller can choose to whisper false telepathic messages to your mind, such as a flattery of your success or a mockery of your failure, without specifying which creature communicated them to you.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 233 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
</compendium>
