<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of the Ashen Tongue (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature's words to twist and bend in meaning, failing to ally with its intentions. When attempting to make a Deception, Intimidation or Persuasion check, the creature must roll a d20. On a result of 1 to 10, it is forced to use another skill from amongst the three (chosen by the Storyteller) in place of its initial choice.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 179 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Disarmament (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>6</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature to be no longer capable of bearing arms. While the creature is holding a weapon, it takes 1d8 Psychic damage at the end of each of its turns. Whenever the creature takes damage in this way, it must succeed on a Concentration check or drop the weapon if it can. In addition, the creature has Disadvantage on attack rolls made using a manufactured weapon.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 179 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Psychic Damage">1d8</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Fleeting Seasons (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>8</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature to age rapidly. For every day that passes, the creature ages an entire year. This aging occurs gradually, with visible changes manifesting each day. If the creature's age exceeds the normal limits for its species, it dies shortly after. Lifting this Curse reverses the aging it caused while it was in effect.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 180 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Forewarning (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>6</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature to meet its end in a way specified by you. The creature becomes vulnerable to a certain type of damage of your choice. Creatures that already have permanent Resistance or Immunity to the chosen damage type ignore this Curse's effects. Effects that grant temporary Resistance or Immunity (such as those of spells or the properties of magic items) suppress the curse's effects for their duration.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 180 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Hopeless Wandering (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature to constantly drift into lands unfamiliar. On a failed save, it can no longer discern the way to any location it has already visited in the past, and any ability checks made for the purpose of doing so fail automatically.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 180 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Hunger (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature to no longer satisfy its hunger through conventional food. It must consume raw flesh in order to meet its daily needs. When the creature completes a Long Rest without consuming raw flesh, it loses one of its maximum Hit Dice (minimum of 0) until the Curse is removed.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 181 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Kinslaying (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature's violent hands to err tragically. Whenever it misses with an attack and an ally is within its range or reach, the ally becomes the new target of that attack.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 181 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Lethe (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature's mind to be slowly swallowed by oblivion. Whenever it fails an Intelligence check for the purpose of recalling information on a subject, it forgets all knowledge that it has on that particular subject. Removing this Curse or having its effects otherwise end causes the target to regain any knowledge it has lost in this way.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 181 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Miscreation (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>6</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature's creations to bring misfortune to those who wield them. Choose a type of Artisan's Tools. As soon as the creature finishes the crafting process of an item using the chosen tools, work with your Storyteller to determine a curse property and bestow it upon the item, which therefore becomes a cursed magic item. The potency of the curse property must be appropriate to the item's rarity.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 181 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Torpor (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>9</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature to a tormenting wakefulness, denying it the respite of slumber. It no longer gains the benefits of a Long Rest upon finishing a Long Rest.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 182 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Trepidation (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You touch a creature, which must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the duration. You curse a creature to experience a constant sense of fearfulness and apprehension. The creature has Disadvantage on saving throws made against becoming Frightened. In addition, whenever the creature becomes Frightened, it is also Stunned until the end of its next turn.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 182 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Uprooting (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You curse a creature to a state of never ending, restless agitation. It can no longer stay in the same location for more than 24 hours. Upon finishing a Long Rest in the same location twice in a row, it automatically suffers one point of Exhaustion.

Components. The spell requires a body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like that belongs to the creature. The component is consumed in the casting process. At the Storyteller's discretion, if the creature has wronged you greatly in the past, you may use your seething hatred towards it as the spell's sole component.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 182 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Vampirism (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>9</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You curse a Humanoid with restless death. The target's heart becomes frail and vulnerable. The next time the target drops to 0 Hit Points it dies outright, without rolling Death Saving Throws. If the target's body is not buried and bestowed proper funeral rites until the next dawn, it rises as an Umpyr.

Neonate. On the first night, the creature rises with a ravenous hunger. Its eyes darken, its reflection grows faint, and its blackened heart begins to beat anew. The creature's alignment shifts one step towards evil, as its morals grow insignificant when compared to the hunger. Its Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution scores each become 14, unless already higher. In addition, it gains one of the Vampire Weaknesses described in the Vampire statblock, at random.
	Henceforth, the cursed creature needs to consume some part of a living Humanoid, such as the blood, liver, or soul, in order to survive. If it refuses to feed, it suffers one level of Exhaustion at dawn, which lasts until it feeds or dies.

Fledgling. After the creature feeds for the first time, the Curse strengthens. Its alignment shifts one step towards evil, as its hunger becomes an all-encompassing torture, leaving room for little else. Its Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution scores each become 16, unless already higher, and it gains one additional Vampire Weakness. In addition, the cursed creature becomes resistant to Necrotic damage and gains Darkvision out to 120ft.
	The cursed creature's type becomes Undead (Umpyr). It doesn't need to eat, drink, breathe, or sleep, and magic can't put it to sleep. It can finish a Long Rest in 4 hours if it spends those hours in an inactive, motionless state, during which it retains consciousness.

Umpyr. The second night the cursed creature feeds, its Curse latches on forever. Its Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution scores each become 18, unless already higher, and it gains the final two Vampire Weaknesses. The creature also gains the Vampire's Speeds, Traits, and Actions. It is proficient with the form's natural attacks, such as its bite or grave strike, which deal damage as shown in its statistics.
	From now on, in order to complete a Long Rest, the cursed creature must be lying on soil from the place where it first rose; otherwise it does not gain the benefits of resting. Only a Wish or its specific lifting conditions can undo the Curse at this point.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 184 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Curse of Therianthropy (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 Hour</time>
    <range>same place of existence as caster</range>
    <components>V, S, M</components>
    <duration>Indefinitely, Caster dies, or lifting condition is met</duration>
    <text>You curse a Humanoid that has committed inhuman acts to assume a form befitting their heinous deeds. Over the next 7 days, the target transforms into a werekin befitting their circumstances (from the options in the Monster Manual). Therianthropic transformations typically reflect the nature of the target's actions. For example, ruthless anger may be punished with a Werewolf form, gluttony with that of a Wereboar, and avarice with the form of the Wererat.

The Mark. After the cursed creature finishes its first Long Rest, it starts growing visible alterations to its physical form, such as patches of fur, claws, or fangs. It also begins to develop increased aggression and mood swings. These grant the target Disadvantage on Charisma (Persuasion) and Charisma (Deception) checks against Humanoids.

The Hunger. By the third day, the cursed creature feels an unrelenting craving for raw flesh. At the end of each Long Rest, it must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or gain one level of Exhaustion unless it has consumed raw meat during the day.

The Beast Without. When the moon rises on the night of the 7th day, the target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against the Curse's spell save DC. On a success, the beast is contained until the next full moon, until the target is bloodied, or until it kills a Humanoid, whereupon the target repeats its saving throw. On a failure, the target succumbs to the Curse, assuming the hybrid form of its therianthropic variant. It loses control of itself until the next dawn, while the beast tries to sate its needs. The target can repeat the saving throw each subsequent night, suppressing the Curse on a success, as described above. If the moon is full, this saving throw is made with Disadvantage.

Mortal No More. Once the creature has failed five saving throws in this way (not necessarily consecutively), it loses itself to the Curse entirely. Its type changes to Monstrosity (Lycanthrope), and its mind regresses to that of an agitated beast, the creature's Intelligence, Wisdom and Charisma scores replaced by those of the therianthrope's animal form. The creature remains in the hybrid form indefinitely, losing the ability to turn back. Only a Wish or its specific lifting conditions can undo the Curse at this point.

Bestial Form. A creature cursed with therianthropy, that has succeeded on a saving throw made to suppress or control its transformation at least once, can willingly assume the bestial or hybrid form of its variant, as described in the monster's Shape-Shift trait. When it does so, it gains the following traits:

	• The creature's Strength, Dexterity and Constitution scores are replaced by those of the therianthrope, unless these scores are already higher.

	• The creature gains the therianthrope's speeds, traits, and the Actions of its beast or hybrid form.

	• The character is proficient with the form's natural attacks, such as its bite or claws, which deal damage as shown in its statistics.

	• A therianthrope can't speak while in animal form.

When the creature reduces a Humanoid to 0 Hit Points while in these forms, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or suffer the effects of succumbing to the Curse, as described above.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 186 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>
