<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Arun's Mercy (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>8</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <text>This is an Origin level Ceremony when affecting a couple of fields, Adventure for the area around a settlement, and Greatness for an entire region or nation.
	The Speaker and the participants must remain outside for the duration of this Ceremony. They sprinkle an offering of water or dirt onto a child wearing a gown of flowers, then beseech the Sky-god to bless them with fair weather.

Practitioners: Weatherworkers, farmers, devotees of Arun, Skycallers

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 158 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Blessed Be the Hunters (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>EN</school>
    <time>10 minutes</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a ceremonial dagger)</components>
    <duration>24 hours</duration>
    <text>This spell anoints hunters, blessing their endeavor for a successful pursuit. Upon completion of the casting of the spell, the Speaker designates a number of hunters as participants and declares a Quarry for them. For the duration, the hunters have Advantage on Wisdom checks made in relevance to the Quarry. Additionally, each anointed hunter can choose to gain one of the following benefits once throughout the effect's duration, expending the power of the anointment:

	• A hunter can use a Bonus Action to deal an extra 1d6 weapon damage on their next successful attack.

	• As a Reaction to an attack it can see, the hunter gains a 1d6 bonus to its AC until the start of its next turn.

	• When the hunter is reduced to 0 Hit Points, it drops to 1 Hit Point instead.

Participants: The Speaker, and at least 2 hunters

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 159 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Weapon Damage">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="AC Bonus">1d6</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Fanuris Pie (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>D</school>
    <time>1 hour</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (ingredients for a pie worth at least 10 cp which the spell consumes)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <text>As part of the casting of this spell, the Speaker must prepare a meal and share it with the participants. The spell is cast after the food has been consumed, at which time the Speaker may describe or name an object that is familiar to them and that they have held within the past month. After 2d4 hours, if the object is within 1 mile of the Speaker, signs will appear upon the Speaker's path leading to the described object.

Participants: The Speaker, and at least 2 creatures who consume the pie.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 161 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Hours">2d4</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Funeral Rites (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>10 minutes</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S, M (honeyed wine, two copper pieces)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <text>As part of the rites of burying a deceased creature, the Speaker places two copper pieces upon the eyes of the creature and then pours honeyed wine into its freshly dug grave. The participants speak words of parting, warding the creature's corpse against ill fate. The creature cannot rise as a Spirit or become an Undead on its own. If another creature attempts to raise the corpse as an Undead, it must succeed on a D20 Test using its spellcasting modifier against the DC of this Ceremony. On a failed check, the creature cannot make another attempt for the next 7 days.

Participants: The Speaker, and at least 2 creatures familiar to the deceased person.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 162 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="D20 Test">d20</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Hexer's Unmasking (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>D</school>
    <time>10 minutes</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (pieces of parchment, ink, a pendant worth at least 25 gp)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <text>This spell allows you to detect who has cast a harmful spell against you or your allies. The Speaker swings the pendant above the names of suspects written on pieces of parchment. If one of these creatures has cast a spell against the Speaker or the participants within the last 24 hours, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or the pendant stops abruptly above its name, revealing their involvement.

Participants: The Speaker, a creature that writes the names and a creature that chants.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 164 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Kupala Night (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>D</school>
    <time>1 hour</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (at least 1 gallon of water, a bonfire, wreaths of flowers)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <text>This spell allows you to alleviate yourself from ailments that afflict you. During the casting of the spell, the participants bathe their bodies with water and prepare a bonfire of at least Large size. At dusk, the Speaker sets it ablaze and crowns each of the participants with a wreath of flowers, who proceed to dance or chant around the fire until their skin is dry. Each participant suffering from the effects of a curse or disease must then make a D20 Test using the Ceremony's spellcasting modifier against the affliction's DC. If multiple such effects afflict a participant at the same time, they must make separate D20 Tests for each of them. Each successful D20 Test ends the corresponding effect on the participant who makes it. On a failure, a participant cannot benefit from this Ceremony's effects until the next year.

Participants: The Speaker, and at least 2 creatures who partake in the dance.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 166 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="D20 Test">d20</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: People's Tribunal (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>EN</school>
    <time>10 minutes</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
    <text>This spell prevents a defendant from lying to the court. Upon completion of the casting of the spell, the Speaker designates a 15-foot radius sphere centered on a point within range. The Speaker must also designate a target within range. Until the spell ends, as long as both the Speaker and the target stand within the area of the spell, neither of them can speak a deliberate lie. They can be evasive in their speaking as long as they remain within the boundaries of the truth. If either creature attempts to lie while within the circle, they must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the witnesses instinctively know that the creature tried to lie. Finally, before the spell ends and while both the Speaker and the target stand within the area of the spell, the Speaker may pass a verdict upon the target. A magical command is then placed on the creature, forcing it to carry out a sentence or refrain from some action as described by the Speaker. The magical command has no effect if it is directly harmful to the target.

Participants: The Speaker, the accused creature, and at least 1 witness.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 167 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Sacrificial Lamb (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>10 minutes</time>
    <range>500 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a living creature that is sacrificed as part of the spell)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <text>This spell banishes plights from the land in exchange for the life of a creature. To enact it, the sacrifice must be accompanied and witnessed by a creature that is friendly to it, while the sacrificial altar is prepared by a different creature. The spell is completed with the sacrifice's death. Upon completion of the casting of the spell, the Speaker may attempt to end an ongoing magical effect or Curse they are aware of, affecting a creature or an area within range, as per the spell Dispel Magic or Remove Curse. If the magical effect or Curse affecting the target is of 4th level or higher, the Speaker must make a D20 Test using the Ceremony's spellcasting modifier against a DC of 10 + the spell or Curse's level. If the sacrificed creature is a Humanoid or can understand and speak at least one language, the Speaker gains Advantage on the D20 Test.

Participants: The Speaker, and at least two creatures who prepare the sacrifice and the altar.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 169 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="D20 Test">d20</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Song of Sorrow (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>10 minutes</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, M (a black candle and a piece of fabric)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <text>This spell is used during dark times, when a great calamity has befallen a community in order to find lost hope once more. During the casting of the spell, both the participants and the speaker remain still. Upon the completion of the casting of the spell, all participants including the Speaker gain Heroic Inspiration. As long as they hold on to that Heroic Inspiration, they also have Advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Frightened condition.

Participants: The Speaker, and at least 2 people who were harmed by the disaster.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 171 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Spirit Warding (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>A</school>
    <time>1 hour</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (bestial or fur costumes, a handful of harvested seeds)</components>
    <duration>24 hours</duration>
    <text>The Ceremony's central part consists of the paroxysmal circular dance performed. By dressing up in fur costumes and dancing while throwing seeds in circles, the Speaker and participants of this ritual can abjure spirits from a large area. For the duration of the Ceremony, each creature within a 1-mile radius centered on the Speaker that has the Spirit subtype must make a Wisdom saving throw or be turned from the area. A turned creature has the Frightened and Incapacitated conditions for 1 minute. For that duration, it tries to move as far from the Speaker as it can on its turns. This effect ends early on the creature if it takes any damage, if the Speaker has the Incapacitated condition, or if the Speaker dies. Additionally, the effect ends early if the creature moves outside the area of the Ceremony, but it becomes turned again if it moves within the affected area.

Participants: The Speaker, and at least two additional dancers.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 172 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ceremony: Vows of Union (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>A</school>
    <time>10 minutes</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a number of decorated wreaths equal to the targets, oil, water)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <text>This spell allows the strengthening of vows of devotion. The Speaker touches willing adult Humanoids and performs a unification Ceremony. Upon completion of the casting of the spell, whenever each target uses the Help Action to aid one of the targets they are united with, it also adds its Proficiency Bonus to the result of the roll. Additionally, while one of the targets is making Death Saving Throws in the presence of a creature it is united with, it makes its Death Saving Throws with Advantage, regaining 1 Hit Point on three successes.

Participants: The Speaker, and the creatures joined in union.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 174 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>
