<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Caliban (HB) [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Zamanori find comfort in separating the Real from the Hidden, giving names to spirits, painting its laws in cautionary tales shared around the hearthfire, and generally setting boundaries in the belief that distance means safety. But the reality could not be further from the truth. These two worlds overlap and mingle in quiet, unseen ways. Spirits visit the world of mortals in mortal guises as spooks, others develop kinship with fascinating individuals, and some even opt to live amongst them. At the same time, those who often peer behind the Veil and interact with its denizens are forever scarred by that contact (see Chapter II: Veilmark). The result of the Hidden's touch finding its way into lineage takes the form of a Caliban, a child who belongs to both worlds and to neither.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 46 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Child of the Veil</name>
      <text>Many tales that surround the Caliban tell of babes stolen in the night and replaced with
"witch-children" or infants found in the woods, left behind by spiteful spirits. The truth is rarely so fantastical. Most Caliban are the offspring of people scarred by Veilmark, often Wise Ones, spellcasters, witches, or seekers who peer too far into forbidden truths. Others are born from unions of spirit and mortal, inheriting some of their characteristics, telltale behaviors, and other traits both wondrous and unsettling.
	At first, Caliban appear as any other child, until a sharp-eyed neighbor or weary parent notices that something feels off. A shadow that moves half a beat too late, a reflection which blinks when they do not; these small echoes of a Veilmark grow more apparent with age, until the truth is undeniable. The Zamanori often treat such children with caution, for to live beside the Hidden is to invite calamity. Some communities shun them outright, while others might revere them as blessings from the spirits or even holy emissaries of the unseen.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Shapeless Sojourn</name>
      <text>Caliban spend their early years in the form inherited from their parents, growing up much like any other child. For a time, they may believe themselves ordinary, until the day they learn the truth. Their soul is not attached to one specific shape; instead it is malleable and can flow into new forms according to their wishes. As terrifying as it is liberating, the discovery of their shapeshifting abilities marks a turning point in every Caliban's life.
	With it comes freedom and the burden of choice. They usually embark on long journeys, slipping unnoticed through unfamiliar towns, evading the suspicious and trying on countless lives in search of one that fits. Eventually, most Caliban choose a specific "normal" form and stick with it, once they feel the need for permanency in their lives. For some, this is the form they came into the world in, before they discovered their innate talents, if they still remember it by the time they finish their journey. Others choose one that better reflects who they have become at the end of their journey.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Between Two Worlds</name>
      <text>Because of their affinity to it, the Hidden whispers to Caliban in ways mortals cannot perceive. They feel the weight of cursed ground beneath their feet, hear voices carried on winds that should be silent, and sense the pressure of an unseen presence. To spirits, they carry the scent of one of their own, though not fully. Half kin, half stranger, they are at once intriguing and unsettling. While some spirits might find this fractured essence wrong, others are drawn closer, curious to see what they are or even eager to interact with a mortal who shares kinship with them.
	This liminal nature makes Caliban natural mediators between the mortals and spirits, able to parley, placate, or even hunt what others cannot. Yet this gift can also be a burden, for they belong wholly to neither side. Never left unbothered for long by either party, many Caliban adopt the life of the wayfarer. They wander, seeking places where they may belong, always torn between the safety of settling and the fear of being discovered.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid (Spirit)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (4-7 feet tall) or Small (2-4 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Shapeshifter</name>
      <text>As a Magic Action, you shapeshift, altering your appearance. You decide what you look like, including your height, weight, facial features, sound of your voice, hair length, coloration, and other distinguishing characteristics. You can make yourself appear as a member of another species, though none of your statistics change. You can't appear as a creature of a different size, and your basic shape stays the same; if you're bipedal, you can't use this trait to become quadrupedal, for instance. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this transformation. You stay in the new form until you use a Magic Action to revert to another form or until you die.
	No matter the form you take, your innate Veilmark echo afflicts it as well. A shadow that is larger than your frame, eyes that glimmer in the candlelight, and similar details grant Advantage to Study Actions made to discern your identity or see through your deception.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Sojourner's Expertise</name>
      <text>Throughout your journeys, you've spent significant amounts of time in multiple roles and guises, granting you glimpses of countless skills. When you make a D20 Test using a skill you are not proficient in, you can add your Proficiency Bonus to the roll. You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Otherworldly. You have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Charmed and Frightened conditions, when imposed by a creature of the Spirit subtype.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Veilmarked</name>
      <text>Due to your attunement with the spirit world, you start with a Veilmark Score of 25 (if you are using the Veilmark optional ruleset). If not using the Veilmark ruleset, you instead gain access to the Detect Spirit and Incorporeal Reach abilities, each usable once, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Detect Spirit. You cast the spell Spirit Sense, without expending a spell slot.

Incorporeal Reach. As a Bonus Action, your attacks harm the very essence of spirits for the next minute. For the duration, once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 Force damage to a target you hit with an attack or spell.</text>
      <roll description="Force Damage">1d6</roll>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Chort (HB) [2024]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <resist>fire</resist>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Though far from the mightiest creatures in Zamanora, few beings have sown as much chaos in mortal lives as the mischievous Chorts have. Known for their cunning and cruelty, these creatures emerge to the surface from the dark depths of the subterranean Gloomlight in search of quarry or for the sheer delight of mischief. A pack of Chorts is called a bogey, a name which these Fiends vehemently live up to.
	Due to their reputation for ruthless trickery, the sighting of a Chort is widely regarded as an ill omen. While most village dwellers would pick up arms against a bogey of Chorts, a single Chort is rarely treated as a threat to the well-being of a community, and it is oftentimes bribed with food or mundane objects so that it does not cause any trouble. Solitary Chorts are mostly harmless, resorting to the theft of small animals—like rabbits, hens, and young goats—which they later present to their bogey as trophies. Rarely, however, during nights when the veil is thin, Chorts often indulge in darker activities: such as snatching children, putting granaries to the torch, or butchering a community's livestock. These activities are usually perpetrated by the more zealous bogeys with great numbers, as most Chorts are content with sticking to pranking and petty crime.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 48 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Fiendish Heritage</name>
      <text>Chorts commit their vile acts for their own rapture, as well as to appease Warthog, their demonic progenitor; an unforgiving entity most Chorts worship and fear to an equal extent. Warthog's word to his offspring is encapsulated in a simple edict:

Dread nothing more than you dread my own wrath. Fear my name as you should, and you shall hold fear for nothing else.

It is this notion that spurs chortkind into action and emancipates it from fear of its seemingly more formidable adversaries. Warthog is depicted as a gigantic twin-headed boar with eight legs that sweats black blood and gorges itself on the souls of the Chort that failed to please him, as well as those of the unfortunate creatures that have been claimed by them. While not viewed as a true deity by most, the very belief of Chorts has raised Warthog into a status of demi-godhood. At the same time, scholarly arcanists and researchers speculate that he could in truth be a brooding Archfiend that reigns supreme over the sunless and abysmal bowels of the uncharted Gloomlight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Callous Pranksters</name>
      <text>For most Chorts, pleasing Warthog is viewed as a question of survival rather than choice. They seek to prove themselves in the eyes of their god and die in fearlessness so that he, in turn, does not feast upon their souls after death and torment them for all eternity. To that end, they also strive to conscribe the souls of mortals, in order to appease their voracious master with less tasty, yet satisfactory delicacies.
	The way Chorts usually achieve that is through tricking other creatures into pledging their souls for a proposed recompense, without realizing the stakes of the bargain. This usually begins with the Chort tormenting an individual by pulling cruel pranks against them and harassing their daily life, eventually leading to direct threats and extortion for an end to these baleful activities. Whether this transaction truly involves something metaphysical or it is purely a notion that Chorts believe in, is a question that none may provide an honest answer to.
	This long tradition of trickery has made the identity of a prankster the Chort's most defining mark. Yet not every Chort is driven by zealotry or malice. Some prank simply out of habit, others treat it as a kind of cultural inheritance or a way to gain something, yet all pursue it with zest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Searching for a Purpose</name>
      <text>Chorts that fail to contribute to the pack and their chief, or are viewed as weak by their peers, are often banished from the bogey. These outcasts are then left to fend for themselves, facing the dangers of Zamanora outside the safety of a larger group. Some obsess over finding ways to demonstrate their mettle and be allowed to return to the fold. Goaded by desperation, these are usually the most vicious kind of Chort one may encounter. Others strive to carve a path of their own, making unlikely allies along the way while picking up new skills, deviating further and further from the stereotype of their kin.
	Though at first glance, a Chort is bound to be treated with caution and distrust, there have been multiple cases of Chorts shedding their malicious ways and integrating into other Zamanori societies. These exceptions to the rule include Chorts who have earned tentative trust to settle in villages, or make their living as roamers, becoming peddlers and even adventurers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fiend</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Small. (2-3 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Burrow</name>
      <text>You have a Burrow Speed of 15 feet. To use this Speed, you can't be wearing Medium or Heavy armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 60 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fiendish Heritage</name>
      <text>You have Resistance to Fire damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Insatiable</name>
      <text>You need double the normal amount of rations to gain enough nourishment for the day.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Uncanny Prankster</name>
      <text>When you take the Attack Action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks to attempt a Mischief against a creature within your reach. Make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check contested by the target's Passive Perception score. On a failure, the target can use their Reaction to make an opportunity attack against you. On a success, you perform a Mischief from the Mischief table. You may use this trait a number of times up to your Proficiency Bonus before you finish a Long Rest.

Mischief:
Mischief | Effect
Pilfer | You take a small, unattended item from the target that they aren't actively holding or that isn't securely fastened to their person. The item must weigh no more than 1 pound.
Sabotage | You entangle the target with a piece of thread or similar material. If the target moves 5 feet or more before the end of its next turn without using an Action to remove the entanglement, it falls Prone.
Tampering | You temporarily unbalance a weapon the target is holding. Until the end of the target's next turn, it has Disadvantage on attack rolls made with that weapon.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Haunt (HB) [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Haunts are entities that lack a body of their own. Such entities live within corporeal forms they create themselves, which they tend to call "Vessels". An uncommon occurrence around Zamanora, most people will nevertheless encounter several throughout their lifetime; some, not even that. While they may, in cases, be incorporated into a community, they seldom stay in the same place for long. The origin of these entities is a matter of some debate. Some claim they are souls, lingering in the Real even after the death of their mortal self. Others think that they manifest through the belief of common folk; a village's remembrance of a renowned, reclusive hunter, a grandmother's cautionary tale of a predatory spook, brought into reality through the dwellers' imagination.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 51 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Manifesting</name>
      <text>In their true form, Haunts are bodiless entities. When a Haunt first manifests it does so within a mundane object which acts as its temporary Vessel. This can be anything from a doll, to a scarecrow, to an empty suit of armor, or even, in more unfortunate situations, less convenient objects like a sword, a boot, or a spoon. Some scholars even claim that numerous sentient items are in fact the Vessels of unlucky Haunts, who remained incapable of escaping that first receptacle. In most cases, however, a Haunt will eventually abandon their first Vessel for a more convenient form; most usually one of its own design.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Seeking Identity</name>
      <text>At the moment of its manifestation, a Haunt may already possess some memories—either real or fabricated—or suffer from complete amnesia. This state of uncertainty is a cause of severe confusion for Haunts, as they awaken with no way of innately knowing where they come from and why they came to be. Even worse, they cannot determine if those memories, or lack thereof, are the remnant of a previous life on the Real, or the figment of someone's imagination. Many Haunts thus dedicate their lifetime to researching their own past, trying to trace their existence to something tangible. In Zamanora, where history is kept in oral tales, and only rarely written down, this is a thankless, grueling task. Most Haunts eventually abandon their search, unable to discover the true essence of their past.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Artists &amp; Craftsmen</name>
      <text>This lack of a concrete sense of their past selves, joined with the practical need of crafting and maintaining a Vessel, sees many Haunts gravitate towards artisanal exploits, especially those related to craftsmanship. Through their Vessels, Haunts not only ensure their continued existence, but also express the identity they have created for themselves. The necessity of maintaining a sturdy, durable Vessel molds Haunts into excellent craftsmen, capable of creating all sorts of wondrous things. After all, without a shell, a naked Haunt will drift away into nothingness within days, and no stories mention such an entity ever returning to the world.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Remarkable Haunts</name>
      <text>On rare occasions, a Haunt's willpower may expand to overwhelming heights. These Haunts are typically ancient, having persisted for hundreds or thousands of years, amassing power all the while. In even more exceptional cases, a newly formed Haunt may coalesce already possessing such force, a frightening prospect for a creature with such fragmented memories. Haunts like these cannot be contained within a normal Vessel. Instead, their consciousness expands, spreading to inhabit an entire building, a copse of trees, even a whole village. As their essence spreads thin, such Haunts are in a constant state of struggle, balancing between the perils of expanding to the point of dissipation or imploding under the weight of their own presence. Places occupied by these entities are particularly dangerous, as the Haunt will try to eject or eradicate any creature that threatens that fine balance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Remarkable Haunts</name>
      <text>On rare occasions, a Haunt's willpower may expand to overwhelming heights. These Haunts are typically ancient, having persisted for hundreds or thousands of years, amassing power all the while. In even more exceptional cases, a newly formed Haunt may coalesce already possessing such force, a frightening prospect for a creature with such fragmented memories. Haunts like these cannot be contained within a normal Vessel. Instead, their consciousness expands, spreading to inhabit an entire building, a copse of trees, even a whole village. As their essence spreads thin, such Haunts are in a constant state of struggle, balancing between the perils of expanding to the point of dissipation or imploding under the weight of their own presence. Places occupied by these entities are particularly dangerous, as the Haunt will try to eject or eradicate any creature that threatens that fine balance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid (Spirit)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (4-7 feet tall) or Small (2-4 feet tall), depending on your Vessel</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>25-35</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Bottled Soul</name>
      <text>Your Vessel was created to be resilient and durable, represented by the following benefits:

	• You have Advantage on saving throws against being Poisoned, and you have Resistance to Poison damage.
	• You don't need to eat, drink, or breathe.
	• You are immune to disease.
	• You don't need to sleep, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Bodiless Entity</name>
      <text>As a Haunt, you have a corporeal form for as long as you inhabit a Vessel. You can exit your Vessel at any time as a Magic Action, but you must spend 1 minute to inhabit a Vessel again. When you exit your Vessel, you appear in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of it. The Storyteller rolls 2d12 and adds your character level to the result. This roll is hidden and the result represents how many hours you have until you must inhabit a new Vessel. If you do not enter a new Vessel within that time, you fade out of existence, unable to sustain your form. Any inanimate object can function as a Vessel, but unless bipedal in shape, it limits your abilities accordingly. Your base AC without a Vessel is 5, you have 1 Hit Point and any amount of damage will cause your ultimate death. While in this form, your creature type is Fey (spirit), you gain incorporeal movement, but you cannot use any features other than your Haunt traits.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Emergency Abandon</name>
      <text>Before you roll a Death Saving Throw you can choose to exit your Vessel instead and gain the effects of your Bodiless Entity trait. When you choose to abandon your Vessel in this way, your old Vessel is immediately destroyed. Each time you attempt to inhabit a mundane object rather than a Vessel of your own creation, you must make a Death Saving Throw. On a failure, you do not inhabit the object.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Ethereal Awareness</name>
      <text>As a being that has a loose grasp on reality, you have the ability to perceive ethereal creatures and objects. As a Magic Action, you can see into the Ethereal Plane up to a range of 30 feet for 10 minutes. During that time, you may attempt to interact with something on the Ethereal Plane. When you do so, roll a d20. On a 1-9 you fail to interact with it and you can't try to interact with it again for the next 24 hours. On a 10-20, you can interact with it as if you were both on the same plane of existence for the next minute. Once you use this trait, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Vessel Crafting</name>
      <text>To create a Vessel, you must spend the time shown on the Haunt Vessels table, working without interruption for up to 8 hours per day. You must also pay the specified cost to purchase supplies. Additionally, due to their intricate nature, Vessels cannot be outfitted with armor. Instead, your AC is calculated solely based on your Vessel's AC from the Haunt Vessels table below. You can still add your Dexterity modifier to it and use shields.
	Sometimes in its adventures, a Haunt may stumble upon exotic materials of exceptional rarity that would be perfect for a Vessel. Such materials may be anything from ironwood, to true ice or the scales of a Balaur.

Haunt Vessels Table:
Prime Material | Speed | Base AC | Time | Cost
Cloth | 35 ft. | 10 | 1 day | 2 gp
Clay, Wood | 30 ft. | 11 | 2 days | 10 gp
Stone | 25 ft. | 14 | 4 days | 40 gp
Iron | 30 ft. | 14 | 10 days | 100 gp

Haunt Vessels Table (Exotic):
Prime Material | Speed | Base AC | Time | Cost
Mithral | 35 ft. | 15 | 75 days | 80,000 gp
Dragonscale | 25 ft. | 17 | 90 days | 120,000 gp
Adamantine | 30 ft. | 18 | 120 days | 180,000 gp</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Vila (HB) [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Performance</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>All spirits belong to a sphere, a central concept around which their essence revolves. For Vilas, that sphere is the land of Zamanora itself; the places where life first flourished, where green leaves unfurl, rivers race bright and untamed, glades lie sun-kissed, and dew glimmers like crystal. That is a Vila. A spirit of life in its most primal form, bound and shaped by the wild heart of Zamanora. Old tales tie their origin to the nourishing goddess Namyra, and from that bond flow their ties to the waters of the land, their affinity for magical healing and their telltale streaming hair.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 54 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>They of the Land</name>
      <text>Physiologically, Vilas are Elementals, yet they look deceptively like members of the mortal races, with peculiarly long hair, that stirs and flows as if alive, even when no wind touches it. They are lithe and graceful, with alterations depending on where they dwell. Much like Humanoids, they form communities and socialize with each other, seemingly for no other reason than the joy of creating bonds. It is commonly believed that this peculiarity is due to Namyra's influence, as Vilas are considered the goddess' favored spirits. This belief is enhanced by their innate ability to use restorative magic, calling upon the healing properties of water and plants to close wounds and restore illness.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>The Forever Dance</name>
      <text>True to their goddess and their charge, these spirits display a fondness for music and art. Unlike most spirits, they usually appear in groupings of five or more which the Zamanori call "choruses" for their love of dance and song. They will happily invite passers-by to join them, but one must be careful, for these spirits can dance endlessly, far beyond the limits of mortal exhaustion. Those who betray their kindness witness an entirely different side of these spirits, for the same flowing hair that crowns them with beauty can tighten like a noose, and a chorus of Vilas will strangle the offender without hesitation or remorse.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Wandering Healers</name>
      <text>Vilas are met with mixed receptions by Zamanori communities. Some welcome them for their knowledge of medicinal plants and healing abilities, while others view them with apprehension and fear due to their spiritual nature. Whatever their reception however, Vilas who venture into settlements soon discover an inherent difficulty. Being spirits of the wilderness, they are overcome with unease in the confines of a village, even more so under the roof of a building. The studied shapes and right angles of constructed dwellings vex them, making them unable to settle in such places. For that reason, a Vila never stays among mortals for long. Even in the rare cases where love for a person or community may keep them in a village for years, they eventually succumb to the call of the wilderness, turning to the horizon like the water that drives them.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Elemental (Spirit)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (4-7 feet tall) or Small (2-4 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Flowing Hair</name>
      <text>You can use your hair to grasp things. It has a reach of 5 feet, and can lift a number of pounds equal to twice your Strength score. You can use it to perform simple tasks such as the following: lift, drop, hold, push, or pull an object or a creature; open or close a door or a container. You can also use your hair to grapple someone, without requiring any free hands. Your hair can't wield weapons or shields or do anything that requires manual precision, such as using tools or magic items or performing the somatic components of a spell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fluvial Spellcasting</name>
      <text>Your very nature grants you access to the arcane. Depending on your level, you know the spells described in the Vila Spellcasting table. You can cast each of these spells that are not cantrips once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast them in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. You can't cast these spells if your hair is tied, or if you are using it to grapple a creature or hold onto an object. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait (choose the ability when you select this species).

Vila Spellcasting:
Level | Spells Known
1 | Thorn Whip
2 | Cure Wounds
3 | Lesser Restoration</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Harmonic Soul</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Performance skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Humanoid Visage</name>
      <text>You appear as a Humanoid to creatures that have a Veilmark score lower than 25, or have a Passive Perception of 13 or lower.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Spiritual Nature</name>
      <text>As a spirit, you are sensitive to matters of the Hidden World. You have Advantage on Wisdom and Intelligence checks related to such matters.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
