<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <spell>
    <name>Ancestral Guidance (HB)</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>D</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
    <classes>School: Divination, Bard [2024], Cleric [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>When you cast this spell, you open your mind to the vast experiences of your ancestors and call upon their wisdom to aid you in your current endeavors. Choose a character background. For the duration, you gain Advantage on ability checks made in relevance to skills, tools, gaming sets or musical instruments that an ancestor of yours was proficient at, as dictated by your background of choice. In addition, you can understand and speak the languages they knew in life.
	At the Storyteller's discretion, the ancestral being that guides you may also be capable of providing you with specific information it is privy to, based on what it has learned about the world during its life. For example, by choosing the Acolyte background, the ancestor who aids you in your Wisdom (Insight) and Intelligence (Religion) checks might have been an adventuring dungeon dweller who also knows that a Skeleton has Vulnerability to Bludgeoning damage.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch - Core Book v0.9 p. 131 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Begraced Armaments (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>EN</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a holy symbol of Arun)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Enchantment, Cleric [2024], Paladin [2024]</classes>
    <text>You grace the weapons of your allies with Arun's blessing. Choose any number of creatures within 30 feet of you that you can see and are holding a weapon to bless it. When a chosen creature deals damage with a blessed weapon, it deals extra Lightning damage equal to your spellcasting ability modifier. Additionally, for the duration, each creature affected by this spell cannot be disarmed unless it has the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 131 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bestow Grace (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>EN</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Enchantment, Bard [2024], Cleric [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You touch a willing creature and imbue it with grace for the duration of the spell. When you cast this spell, choose the nature of the grace from the following options.

	• Choose one ability score. The target has Advantage on ability checks and saving throws made with that ability score.

	• The target has Advantage on the first attack it makes during each of its turns.

	• The target makes a Wisdom check at the start of each of its turns. The DC for this check equals its Wisdom score. If it succeeds, it gains an additional Action for that turn. This Action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object Action.

	• The target deals an extra 1d8 Radiant damage with its attacks and spells.

A Dispel Magic spell can end this effect. At the Storyteller's discretion, you may choose an alternative grace effect, but it should be no more powerful than those described above. The Storyteller has final say on such a grace's effect.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the duration is Concentration, up to 10 minutes. If you use a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the duration is 8 hours. If you use a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the duration is 24 hours. If you use a 9th level spell slot, the spell lasts until it is dispelled. Using a spell slot of 5th level or higher grants a duration that doesn't require you to maintain Concentration.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 131 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">1d8</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Conspiracy of Ravens (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a bloodied raven feather)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Conjuration, Bard [2024], Druid [2024], Ranger [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You target a creature within range and summon a Swarm of Ravens to appear in the same space as itself. The swarm disappears if it is reduced to 0 Hit Points or when the spell ends.
	The swarm shares your Initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys your commands (no action required by you). If you don't issue any, it takes the Dodge Action and uses its movement to avoid danger. While another creature is in the swarm's space and the swarm has half its Hit Points or more, that creature is Blinded.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you summon an additional swarm of ravens at a target's space for each 2 slot levels above 2nd.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 132 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Darkplume Shot (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <time>Bonus Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>1 round</duration>
    <classes>School: Conjuration, Ranger [2024]</classes>
    <text>You cause your projectile to turn into a harrowing raven while mid-flight towards its mark. The next time you make a Ranged weapon attack against a target while this spell is active, your attack ignores any benefit of Cover the target has, as long as there is a clear path towards it. In addition to its normal effects, this attack can be made against any target you are aware of and is within your weapon's range, even if it has Total Cover from you. On a hit, this attack deals an extra 1d8 Necrotic damage. Hit or miss, this spell ends after the attack is resolved.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: The damage increases by 1d8 for each spell slot level above 1 (to a maximum of 6d8).

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 132 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="1">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="2">2d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="3">3d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="4">4d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="5">5d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="6">6d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="7">7d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="8">8d8</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="9">9d8</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Daybreak (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>8</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a solar rock worth at least 500+ GP)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Evocation, Bard [2024], Cleric [2024], Druid [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You summon the light of dawn to shine down upon your allies and enemies alike. You must be outdoors to cast this spell. Until the spell ends, a 500-foot radius Emanation centered at you is bathed in Bright Light. The light is sunlight. While directly exposed to the Bright Light, each creature that enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there is affected in the following ways:

	• Each Undead takes 2d10 Radiant damage
	• Each creature that is not an Undead regains 2d10 Hit Points.

This spell also causes any magic items within the area that regain their charges or used properties at dawn to immediately do so.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 132 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d10</roll>
    <roll description="Heal">2d10</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Deepening Gloom (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a Gloomlight stone)</components>
    <duration>24 hours</duration>
    <classes>School: Evocation, Druid [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Warlock [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You enhance the density of the shadows in a 30-foot Emanation centered on you so that light cannot penetrate them. When you cast this spell in an area with Dim Light or Darkness, you turn it into magical Darkness. Each nonmagical source of illumination in the area is extinguished. If any of this spell's area overlaps with an area of light created by a spell of 5th level or lower, the spell that created the light is dispelled. In addition, while in the affected area, you gain Blindsight up to the confines of the magical Darkness.
	Each time a creature ends its turn within the area affected by this spell, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the creature becomes immune to this spell's effects for 24 hours. On a failed save, it becomes Frightened. While a creature is Frightened in this way, it also has Disadvantage on its saving throws and it is no longer considered a willing target for other creatures' spells and effects. If a Frightened creature ends its turn outside the area of this spell, it can repeat its saving throw to end the effect on itself. Creatures that can see through magical Darkness ignore this spell's effects.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 133 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>False Visage (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>I</school>
    <time>Reaction, which you take in response to taking damage from a creature that you can see within 60 feet of yourself</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>V</components>
    <duration>1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Illusion, Bard [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Warlock [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>In the eyes of the chosen creature, your appearance shifts to resemble that of a Humanoid that is or was beloved to it, and the creature takes an amount of Psychic damage equal to half the damage it dealt to you with its attack. Until the spell ends, when the creature targets you with an attack roll or a damaging spell, it must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or either choose a new target or lose the attack or spell. This spell doesn't protect you from areas of effect.
	If you make an attack roll, cast a spell, or deal damage against the creature, it can repeat its saving throw, ending the effects on a success.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 133 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Frostwave (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>School: Evocation, Druid [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Warlock [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You release a burst of icy energy in all directions. Each creature in a 15-foot Emanation originating from you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 4d8 Cold damage and is frozen in place, becoming Restrained. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and isn't Restrained. A trapped creature can take an Action to make a Strength (Athletics) check against your spell save DC to break free.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: The damage increases by 1d8 for each spell slot level above 3.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 133 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Cold Damage" level="3">4d8</roll>
    <roll description="Cold Damage" level="4">5d8</roll>
    <roll description="Cold Damage" level="5">6d8</roll>
    <roll description="Cold Damage" level="6">7d8</roll>
    <roll description="Cold Damage" level="7">8d8</roll>
    <roll description="Cold Damage" level="8">9d8</roll>
    <roll description="Cold Damage" level="9">10d8</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hearthfire Warmth (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a small piece of coal)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Evocation, Bard [2024], Cleric [2024], Druid [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You call upon the comforting warmth of a hearthfire, shedding a soothing heat that heals and protects. You create a 20-foot radius Sphere of pleasant heat centered on you. The area is bathed in Bright Light, dispelling any magical Darkness, and extends another 20 feet with Dim Light. When the spell is cast, each creature of your choice within the area regains Hit Points equal to 2d8 plus your spellcasting ability modifier. Additionally, for the duration, each target gains Resistance to Cold damage and has Immunity to the Frightened condition.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: The healing increases by 1d8 for each spell slot level above 3.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 134 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Heal" level="3">2d8+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Heal" level="4">3d8+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Heal" level="5">4d8+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Heal" level="6">5d8+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Heal" level="7">6d8+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Heal" level="8">7d8+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Heal" level="9">8d8+SPELL</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mantle of Dreams (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>EN</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a sprig of lavender and a drop of perfume)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
    <classes>School: Enchantment, Bard [2024], Druid [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>When you cast this spell, the pores of your skin begin to emanate a soporific fragrance that causes living creatures of your choice in a 20-foot Emanation centered on you to fall into slumber. Each creature that enters the area affected by the spell for the first time during its turn or starts its turn there must make a Constitution saving throw. On a success, whenever the creature makes a D20 Test until the start of your next turn, it must roll a d4 and subtract the number rolled from the result, as it becomes weary from drowsiness. On a failed save, the creature falls asleep and is Unconscious until the spell ends, the sleeper takes damage, or someone uses an Action to shake or slap the sleeper awake.
	Undead and creatures immune to being Charmed aren't affected by this spell.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: The range increases by 5 feet for each spell slot level above 3. Using a spell slot level of 5 or higher grants a duration that doesn't require you to maintain Concentration.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 134 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Moonveil (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>I</school>
    <time>Reaction, which you take in response to seeing a creature within range being targeted by an attack</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a vial of water which once held the reflection of the moon)</components>
    <duration>1 round</duration>
    <classes>School: Illusion, Druid [2024], Paladin [2024], Ranger [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You imbue yourself or a willing creature with the moon's blessing. Until the start of your next turn, a veil of moonlight envelops the creature, and it gains the Invisible condition before the triggering attack is resolved, giving Disadvantage on the attack. While a creature is Invisible through this spell's effects, its attacks deal an extra 1d10 Radiant damage.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 134 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">1d10</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Outward Gale (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Evocation, Druid [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>Upon casting this spell, fierce winds begin to swirl and howl violently around you. The winds spiral in a 30-foot radius, 60-foot high Cylinder centered at you. Whenever the Cylinder enters a creature's space and whenever a creature enters the Cylinder or ends its turn there, the creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 4d8 Bludgeoning damage and is forcefully moved in a straight Line until it is outside the area, where it falls Prone. If this movement is obstructed by a solid object (such as a wall), the creature and the object take 4d8 Bludgeoning damage and it becomes Stunned until the end of its next turn instead.
	For the duration, the area is under the effects of a strong wind and counts as Difficult Terrain.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 134 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage">4d8</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Patchwork Restoration (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <time>10 minutes</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a silver needle and silken thread worth 10+ GP)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>School: Transmutation, Cleric [2024], Druid [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>This spell allows you to reattach severed limbs and appendages or graft foreign flesh onto your body. During casting, you must hold the severed part against the corresponding stump or target area. At the spell's completion, the attachment is secured with silken thread. If you graft a limb or organ from a different species, you may choose one trait from the donor species. Upon completion of the spell, one of your species' traits is replaced by the chosen trait.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 135 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Pas Seul (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>EN</school>
    <time>Reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack roll</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Enchantment, Bard [2024]</classes>
    <text>Your movements begin to blend into a lively dance, swaying, spinning and rollicking around. Make a Charisma (Performance) check and replace your AC with the result. If the result of your check is higher than that of the attack, the attack misses you. For the duration of the spell, you can repeat this effect on each incoming attack and gain Advantage on Dexterity saving throws. You must spend your Bonus Action on each of your subsequent turns in order to maintain this effect.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 136 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Peddler's Bargain (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>S</components>
    <duration>10 minutes, or until discharged</duration>
    <classes>School: Transmutation, Bard [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You touch up to three coins and turn them into deadly projectiles that can be flicked with lethal velocity against your foes. For the duration, you can flick one transmuted coin as a ranged spell attack with a range of 30 feet as part of the casting of this spell. You can make a single attack using a transmuted coin as part of casting this spell. On subsequent turns, you can flick a transmuted coin by using a Bonus Action. Only you can make attacks using the coins, though other creatures can safely handle them without discharging the spell. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your hurled coins of each type by taking a minute to search the battlefield.
	Different coins create different effects when used to make attacks, as presented below:

Copper. On a hit, the coin deals 1d6 Piercing damage plus your spellcasting ability modifier.

Silver. On a hit, the coin deals 1d8 Piercing damage plus your spellcasting ability modifier ignoring Resistance to Piercing damage.

Gold. On a hit, the coin deals 1d10 Piercing damage plus your spellcasting ability modifier ignoring Resistance and Immunity to Piercing damage.

Platinum. On a hit, the coin deals 1d12 Piercing damage plus your spellcasting ability modifier ignoring Resistance and Immunity to Piercing damage and can score a Critical Hit on a roll of 15-20.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: You can enchant one more coin for each spell slot level above 1.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 136 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d6+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d8+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d10+SPELL</roll>
    <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d12+SPELL</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Reveal the Trail (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>D</school>
    <time>Action or Ritual</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a handful of moss)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
    <classes>School: Divination, Druid [2024], Ranger [2024]</classes>
    <text>By touching another creature or the corpse of one that has died within the last 24 hours, you magically retrace the steps it took before arriving at its current location. For the duration, arcane marks that are visible only to you indicate the direction it came from and the route it took. For example, if the creature has been walking, the marks appear like glowing tracks, while if it has been flying, its trail resembles a faint magical aura.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 136 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Roaming Embers (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>120 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (an open source of flame)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>School: Evocation, Cleric [2024], Druid [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>Choose a number of openSources of flame of size Medium or smaller up to your spellcasting ability modifier that you can see within the spell's range and hurl them towards the target. Make a ranged spell attack for each flame hurled in this way that has a direct line of sight to the target, originating from itsSource. On a hit, a flame hurled in this way deals Fire damage according to the size of the source according to the Roaming Embers source table below, and the source is then extinguished.

Roaming Embers Table:
Size | Fire Damage
Tiny | 1d8
Small | 1d10
Medium | 1d12

Open flames such as a Tiny candle, a Small torch or a Medium campfire count for a singleSource. For the purposes of this spell, flames that cover larger areas such as a Huge bonfire or the effects created by the Wall of Fire spell provide a potential source of size Medium for each 5-foot square they occupy.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 137 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shield Wall (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>A</school>
    <time>Reaction, which you take when you or an ally within 5 feet of you are hit by an attack roll or targeted by the Magic Missile spell</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>1 round</duration>
    <classes>School: Abjuration, Bard [2024], Cleric [2024], Paladin [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>An invisible barrier of force protects you and each ally within 5 feet of you. Until the start of your next turn, you and each affected ally have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from Magic Missile.
	When you cast this spell, its effects are passed over to each ally in range that is within 5 feet of an ally affected by it.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 137 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spirit Sense (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>D</school>
    <time>Action or Ritual</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>School: Divination, Cleric [2024], Druid [2024], Ranger [2024]</classes>
    <text>Upon casting this spell, you grow magically aware of the presence and alignment of each creature that has the Spirit subtype within 1,000 feet of you, as well as the direction and general distance to their locations.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 137 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Summon Oh's Companion (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <time>1 minute</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (juniper berries and milk)</components>
    <duration>8 hours</duration>
    <classes>School: Conjuration, Bard [2024], Cleric [2024], Druid [2024], Ranger [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You summon a friendly Spirit in order to aid you depending on your situation and your location.

Within a Building. You summon a Domovik. The Spirit guards you while you rest and tries to ward off any hostile creatures that try to enter the building, or telepathically warns you if it fails to do so. Upon casting this spell, there is a 25 percent chance you summon a Kikimora instead, which offers the same services but is grumpy about it.

While Exploring Outdoors. You summon a Poputnik with 5 berries in its pockets infused with the magic of the Goodberry spell. The Spirit can share knowledge about the surrounding area and, as long as it is nearby, it grants you Advantage on any Wisdom (Survival) and Intelligence (Nature) checks you attempt by using the Help Action.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 137 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Suncloak (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a piece of soft cloth, a needle)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Evocation, Druid [2024], Paladin [2024], Ranger [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You touch a willing creature and imbue it with the sun's blaze. Until the spell ends, a radiant mantle appears upon the creature's back, shedding Bright Light in a 30-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 30 feet. For the duration, the affected creature's Melee weapon attacks deal an extra 1d6 Fire damage and 1d6 Radiant damage. On a Critical Hit, the creature can also choose to deal the extra Fire and Radiant damage dealt by this spell to every creature of its choice within the area of the Bright Light produced by it.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 138 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Fire Damage">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">1d6</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Yorveth's Beacon (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <time>Action or Ritual</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>1 hour</duration>
    <classes>School: Transmutation, Bard [2024], Cleric [2024], Druid [2024], Paladin [2024], Ranger [2024]</classes>
    <text>You summon a beacon of fire that occupies a 10-foot Cube and burns at a point you can see within range, emitting a pillar of thick black smoke in the sky. You must be outdoors to cast this spell.
	Upon casting the spell, you can choose to relay a short message of 25 words or fewer to a number of creatures up to your spellcasting ability modifier. Each designated creature that can see the pillar of smoke becomes magically aware of your message. The creatures can also be designated in a vague way, for example "warriors of Svyatogor's Banner" or "people of Kadivka". Every other creature must succeed on an Intelligence (Arcana) check against your spell save DC, in order to decipher it.
	Additionally, creatures allied to you that become aware of the beacon's message are stirred into motion by a magical sense of urgency. For the duration, each such affected creature's movement is unaffected by Difficult Terrain and their Speed and travel pace is doubled as long as they are moving in response to your message.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 138 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Warding Cornerstone (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>A</school>
    <time>Action or Ritual</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a wooden talisman of Yorveth)</components>
    <duration>24 hours</duration>
    <classes>School: Abjuration, Cleric [2024], Paladin [2024]</classes>
    <text>You touch a building and bless it with abjurant magics that ward it from trespassers. The building must not be larger than a 60-foot Cube. When casting this spell, you also designate a creature that you can see or are familiar with as the building's householder. For the duration, the spell affects creatures in the following ways:

	• A creature that tries to enter the building must first succeed on a Charisma saving throw, unless the householder grants it permission to enter. Creatures of the Elemental, Fey, Fiend or Undead type also take 1d8 Psychic damage on a failed save.

	• Creatures inside the building cannot be Charmed, Frightened or possessed by creatures outside the building.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: The size of the building you can affect increases by 20 feet for each spell slot level above 1.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 138 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Psychic Damage">1d8</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Woodland Awakening (HB) [2024]</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <time>Action</time>
    <range>90 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a handful of sunflower petals)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Transmutation, Druid [2024], Ranger [2024]</classes>
    <text>This spell causes the flora in your vicinity to stir into awakening and fight alongside you. Choose up to four nonmagical plants within range that are not larger than Huge. Trees count as two plants. Each Tiny, Small, or Medium plant targeted this way turns into an Awakened Shrub. Each Large or Huge plant turns into an Awakened Tree. Each awakened creature comes under your control until the spell ends or until reduced to 0 Hit Points.
	As a Bonus Action, you can mentally command any Plant you have awakened with this spell (if you control multiple creatures, you can command any or all of them at the same time, issuing the same command to each one). You decide what action it will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you can issue a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor. If you issue no commands, it only defends itself against hostile creatures.
	Once given an order, it continues to follow it until its task is complete. Once the duration is over, they return to their initial positions, bury their roots back into the soil and become inanimate again, unless they have already been killed.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can awaken an additional nonmagical plant for each spell level above 4th.

Source:	Zamanora: Ballad of the Witch p. 139 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>
