<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Wizard [2024]</name>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: Bladesinger (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: Bladesinger (UA)</name>
        <text>Wield Sword and Sorcery in Elegant Tandem

Bladesingers master a tradition of wizardry that incorporates swordplay and dance. In combat, a Bladesinger uses a series of intricate, elegant maneuvers that fend off harm and allow the Bladesinger to channel magic into devastating attacks and a cunning defense. Many who have observed a Bladesinger at work remember the display as one of the more beautiful experiences in their life, a glorious dance accompanied by a singing blade.

Bladesinging is strongly associated with the ancient elven societies that first mastered the art and coined the term. Even today, most Bladesingers still hail from old elven realms, such as Cormanthyr, or from non-elven societies that share land and history with elves, such as the Silver Marches. Wherever they hail from, Bladesingers are known for taking their talents all across the Realms in order to help common people and perform heroic deeds. Few communities greet the arrival of a Bladesinger as anything but a good omen.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Bladesong (Bladesinger (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you invoke an elven magic called the Bladesong, provided you aren't wearing armor or using a Shield.

The Bladesong lasts for 1 minute and ends early if you have the Incapacitated condition, if you don armor or a Shield, or if you use two hands to make an attack with a weapon. You can dismiss the Bladesong at any time (no action required).

While the Bladesong is active, you gain the following benefits. You can invoke the Bladesong a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Agility. You gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1), and your Speed increases by 10 feet.

Bladework. Whenever you attack with a weapon with which you have proficiency, you can use your Intelligence modifier for the attack and damage rolls instead of using Strength or Dexterity.

Focus. When you make a Constitution saving throw to maintain Concentration, you can add your Intelligence modifier to the total.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Training In War And Song (Bladesinger (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency with all Melee Martial weapons that don't have the Two-Handed or Heavy property. You can use a Melee weapon with which you have proficiency as a Spellcasting Focus for your Wizard spells.

You also gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Acrobatics, Athletics, Performance, or Persuasion.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Extra Attack (Bladesinger (UA))</name>
        <text>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn. Moreover, you can cast one of your Wizard cantrips that has a casting time of an action in place of one of those attacks.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Song Of Defense (Bladesinger (UA))</name>
        <text>When you take damage while your Bladesong is active, you can take a Reaction to expend one spell slot and reduce the damage taken by an amount equal to five times the spell slot's level.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Song Of Victory (Bladesinger (UA))</name>
        <text>After you cast a spell that has a casting time of an action, you can make one attack with a weapon as a Bonus Action.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <class>
    <name>Artificer [2024]</name>
    <hd>8</hd>
    <proficiency>Intelligence, Constitution, Arcana, History, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>
    <armor>light armor, medium armor, shields</armor>
    <weapons>simple weapons</weapons>
    <tools>thieves' tools, tinker's tools</tools>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Becoming A Artificer As A Level 1 Character</name>
        <text>As a 1st-level Artificer, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Core Artificer Traits</text>
        <text>Primary Ability: Intelligence</text>
        <text>Hit Point Die: D8 per Artificer level</text>
        <text>Saving Throw Proficiencies: Constitution and Intelligence</text>
        <text>Skill Proficiencies: Choose 2: Arcana, History, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, or Sleight of Hand</text>
        <text>Weapon Proficiencies: Simple weapons</text>
        <text>Tool Proficiencies: Thieves' Tools, Tinker's Tools, and one type of Artisan's Tools of your choice</text>
        <text>Armor Training: Light and Medium armor and Shields</text>
        <text>Starting Equipment: Choose A or B: (A) Studded Leather Armor, Dagger, Thieves' Tools, Tinker's Tools, Dungeoneer's Pack, and 16 GP; or (B) 150 GP</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 1</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Becoming A Artificer As A Multiclass Character</name>
        <text>Core Artificer Traits</text>
        <text>Hit Point Die: D8 per Artificer level</text>
        <text>Tool Proficiencies: Tinker's Tools</text>
        <text>Skill Proficiencies: Choose 1: Arcana, History, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, or Sleight of Hand</text>
        <text>Armor Training: Light and Medium armor and Shields</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 1</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 1: Magical Tinkering</name>
        <text>As a Magic action while holding Tinker's Tools, you can create one item in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of yourself, choosing the item from the following list:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Ball Bearings</text>
        <text>Basket</text>
        <text>Bedroll</text>
        <text>Bell</text>
        <text>Blanket</text>
        <text>Block and Tackle</text>
        <text>Bucket</text>
        <text>Caltrops</text>
        <text>Candle</text>
        <text>Crowbar</text>
        <text>Flask</text>
        <text>Jug</text>
        <text>Lamp</text>
        <text>Net</text>
        <text>Oil</text>
        <text>Paper</text>
        <text>Parchment</text>
        <text>Pole</text>
        <text>Pouch</text>
        <text>Rope</text>
        <text>Sack</text>
        <text>Shovel</text>
        <text>String</text>
        <text>Tinderbox</text>
        <text>Torch</text>
        <text>Vial</text>
        <text/>
        <text>	See the rules for the item in the Player's Handbook. The item vanishes after 1 hour.</text>
        <text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 1: Spellcasting</name>
        <text>You have learned how to channel magical energy through objects. See the Player's Handbook for the rules on spellcasting. The information below details how you use those rules with Artificer spells, which appear in the Artificer spell list later in the class's description.</text>
        <text>	Tools Required. You produce your Artificer spells through tools. You can use Thieves' Tools, Tinker's Tools, or another kind of Artisan's Tools with which you have proficiency as a Spellcasting Focus, and you must have one of those focuses in hand when you cast an Artificer spell (meaning the spell has an “M” component when you cast it).</text>
        <text>	Cantrips. You know two Artificer cantrips of your choice. Acid Splash and Prestidigitation are recommended.</text>
        <text>	Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace one of your cantrips from this feature with another Artificer cantrip of your choice.</text>
        <text>	When you reach Artificer levels 10 and 14, you learn another Artificer cantrip of your choice, as shown in the Cantrips column of the Artificer Features table.</text>
        <text>	Spell Slots. The Artificer Features table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your level 1+ spells. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text>	Prepared Spells of Level 1+. You prepare the list of level 1+ spells that are available for you to cast with this feature. To start, choose two level 1 Artificer spells. Cure Wounds and Grease are recommended.</text>
        <text>	The number of spells on your list increases as you gain Artificer levels, as shown in the Prepared Spells column of the Artificer Features table. Whenever that number increases, choose additional Artificer spells until the number of spells on your list matches the number on the table. The chosen spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For example, if you're a level 5 Artificer, your list of prepared spells can include six Artificer spells of levels 1 and 2 in any combination.</text>
        <text>	If another Artificer feature gives you spells that you always have prepared, those don't count against the number of spells you can prepare with this feature, but those spells otherwise count as Artificer spells for you.</text>
        <text>	Changing Your Prepared Spells. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can change your list of prepared spells, replacing any of the spells there with other Artificer spells for which you have spell slots.</text>
        <text>	Spellcasting Ability. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your Artificer spells.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Level | Spells Prepared</text>
        <text>1 | 2</text>
        <text>2 | 3</text>
        <text>3 | 4</text>
        <text>4 | 5</text>
        <text>5 | 6</text>
        <text>7 | 7</text>
        <text>9 | 9</text>
        <text>11 | 10</text>
        <text>13 | 11</text>
        <text>15 | 12</text>
        <text>17 | 14</text>
        <text>19 | 15</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <slots>2, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <slots>2, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <slots>2, 3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4">
      <slots>2, 3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <slots>2, 4, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <slots>2, 4, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <slots>2, 4, 3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <slots>2, 4, 3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <slots>2, 4, 3, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <slots>3, 4, 3, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <slots>3, 4, 3, 3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12">
      <slots>3, 4, 3, 3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16">
      <slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 2: Replicate Magic Item</name>
        <text>You have learned arcane plans that you use to make magic items.</text>
        <text>	Plans Known. When you gain this feature, choose four plans to learn from the Magic Item Plans (Artificer Level 2+) table (see the Dungeon Master's Guide for the items' descriptions). Bag of Holding, Cap of Water Breathing, Sending Stones, and Wand of the War Mage +1 are recommended. Whenever you gain an Artificer level, you can replace one of the plans you know with a new plan for which you qualify.</text>
        <text>	You learn another plan of your choice when you reach certain Artificer levels, as shown in the Plans Known column of the Artificer Features table (5 at 6th level, 6 at 10th level, 7 at 14th level, 8 at 18th level).</text>
        <text>	Creating an Item. When you finish a Long Rest, you can create one or two different magic items if you have Tinker's Tools in hand. Each item is based on one of the plans you know for this feature.</text>
        <text>	If a created item requires Attunement, you can attune yourself to it the instant you create it. If you decide to attune to the item later, you must do so using the normal process for Attunement.</text>
        <text>	When you reach certain Artificer levels specified in the Magic Items column of the Artificer Features table, the number of magic items you can create at the end of a Long Rest increases. Each item you create must be based on a different plan you know.</text>
        <text>	If you try to exceed your maximum number of magic items for this feature, the oldest item vanishes, and then the new item appears.</text>
        <text>	Duration. A magic item created by this feature functions exactly like the normal magic item, except its magic isn't permanent. When you die, the magic item vanishes after 1d4 of days.</text>
        <text>	If an item that you created with this feature is a container, such as a Bag of Holding, and it vanishes, its contents harmlessly appear in and around its space.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Magic Item Plans (Artificer Level 2+)</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Magic Item Plan | Attunement</text>
        <text>Alchemy Jug | No</text>
        <text>Bag of Holding | No</text>
        <text>Cap of Water Breathing | No</text>
        <text>Common magic item that isn't a Potion, a Scroll, or cursed (you can learn this option multiple times and must select a different item each time; each item selected counts as a different plan) | Varies</text>
        <text>Goggles of Night | No</text>
        <text>Rope of Climbing | No</text>
        <text>Sending Stones | No</text>
        <text>Shield +1 | No</text>
        <text>Wand of Magic Detection | No</text>
        <text>Wand of Secrets | No</text>
        <text>Wand of the War Mage +1 | Yes</text>
        <text>Weapon +1 | No</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 3</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 3: Artificer Subclass</name>
        <text>You gain an Artificer subclass of your choice. The Alchemist, Armorer, Artillerist, and Battle Smith subclasses are detailed after this class's description. A subclass is a specialization that grants you features at certain Artificer levels. For the rest of your career, you gain each of your subclass's features that are of your Artificer level or lower.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 3: Right Tool For The Job</name>
        <text>The list of items you can create with Magical Tinkering now includes Artisan's Tools, which are described in the Player's Handbook.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 4: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify. You gain this feature again at Artificer levels 8, 12, and 16.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 6: Magic Item Tinker</name>
        <text>Your Replicate Magic Item feature improves as follows:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Drain Magic Item. As a Bonus Action, you can touch a magic item within 5 feet of yourself that you created with Replicate Magic Item and cause the item to vanish, converting its magical energy into a spell slot. The slot is level 1 if the item is Common or level 2 if the item is Uncommon or Rare. Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest. Any spell slot you create with this feature vanishes when you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text>Expanded Replication. When you learn a plan for your Replicate Magic Item feature, you can now also choose from the Magic Item Plans (Artificer Level 6+) table.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Magic Item Plans (Artificer Level 6+)</text>
        <text/>
        <tetx>Magic Item Plan | Attunement</tetx>
        <tetx>Armor +1 | No</tetx>
        <tetx>Boots of Elvenkind | No</tetx>
        <tetx>Cloak of Elvenkind | Yes</tetx>
        <tetx>Cloak of the Manta Ray | No</tetx>
        <tetx>Eyes of Charming | Yes</tetx>
        <tetx>Gloves of Thievery | No</tetx>
        <tetx>Lantern of Revealing | No</tetx>
        <tetx>Pipes of Haunting | No</tetx>
        <tetx>Uncommon Armor, Wand, or Weapon that isn't cursed (you can learn this option multiple times and must select a different item each time; each item selected counts as a different plan) | Varies</tetx>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 7: Flash Of Genius</name>
        <text>When you or a creature you can see within 30 feet of you fails an ability check or a saving throw, you can take a Reaction to add a bonus to the roll, potentially causing it to succeed. The bonus equals your Intelligence modifier.</text>
        <text>	You can take this Reaction a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 8: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify. You gain this feature again at Artificer levels 8, 12, and 16.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 10: Magic Item Adept</name>
        <text>You've achieved a profound understanding of how to use and make magic items, granting you the following benefits:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Additional Attunement. You can attune to up to four magic items at once rather than three.</text>
        <text>Expanded Replication. When you learn a plan for your Replicate Magic Item feature, you can now also choose from the Magic Item Plans (Artificer Level 10+) table.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Magic Item Plans (Artificer Level 10+)</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Magic Item Plan | Attunement</text>
        <text>Uncommon Ring or Wondrous Item that isn't cursed (you can learn this option multiple times and must select a different item each time; each item selected counts as a different plan) | Varies</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 11: Spell-Storing Item</name>
        <text>Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can touch one Simple or Martial weapon or one item that you can use as a Spellcasting Focus, and you store a spell in it, choosing a level 1, 2, or 3 Artificer spell that has a casting time of an action (you needn't have the spell prepared).</text>
        <text>	While holding the object, a creature can take an action to produce the spell's effect from it, using your spellcasting ability modifier. If the spell requires Concentration, the creature must concentrate. The spell stays in the object until it's been used a number of times equal to twice your Intelligence modifier (minimum of twice) or until you use this feature again to store a spell in an object.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 12: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify. You gain this feature again at Artificer levels 8, 12, and 16.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 14: Magic Item Savant</name>
        <text>Your skill with magic items deepens, granting you the following benefits:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Additional Attunement. You can attune to up to five magic items at once rather than three.</text>
        <text>Expanded Replication. When you learn a plan for your Replicate Magic Item feature, you can now also choose from the Magic Item Plans (Artificer Level 14+) table. You can have no more than three Rare items created by Replicate Magic Item at a time.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Magic Item Plans (Artificer Level 14+)</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Magic Item Plan | Attunement</text>
        <text>Rare Armor, Ring, Wand, Weapon, or Wondrous Item that isn't cursed (you can learn this option multiple times and must select a different item each time; each item selected counts as a different plan) | Varies</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 16: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify. You gain this feature again at Artificer levels 8, 12, and 16.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 18: Magic Item Master</name>
        <text>You can now attune to up to six magic items at once rather than three.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 19: Epic Boon</name>
        <text>You gain an Epic Boon feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify. Boon of Energy Resistance is recommended.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 20: Soul Of Artifice</name>
        <text>You have developed a mystical connection to your magic items, which you can draw on for aid. You gain the following benefits:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Cheat Death. If you're reduced to 0 Hit Points but not killed outright, you can disintegrate one Uncommon or Rare magic item created by your Replicate Magic Item feature, changing your Hit Points to 20 instead of 0.</text>
        <text>Magical Guidance. While you have Attunement to at least one magic item, you can add 1d6 to any ability check you make. You decide to add the die after rolling the d20, and you can use this benefit only once per turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artificer Subclass: Alchemist (UA)</name>
        <text>Craft Magic Elixirs and Potions</text>
        <text>An Alchemist is an expert at combining reagents to produce magical effects. Alchemists use their creations to give life and to leech it away.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 6</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Tool Proficiency (Alchemist (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency with Alchemist's Supplies. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of Artisan's Tools of your choice.</text>
        <text>	In addition, when you brew a potion using the crafting rules in the Dungeon Master's Guide, the amount of time required to craft it is halved.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Alchemist Spells (Alchemist (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach an Artificer level specified in the Alchemist Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Artificer Level — Spells</text>
        <text>3 — Healing Word, Ray of Sickness</text>
        <text>5 — Flaming Sphere, Melf's Acid Arrow</text>
        <text>9 — Gaseous Form, Mass Healing Word</text>
        <text>13 — Death Ward, Vitriolic Sphere</text>
        <text>17 — Cloudkill, Raise Dead</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Experimental Elixir (Alchemist (UA))</name>
        <text>Whenever you finish a Long Rest while holding Alchemist's Supplies, you can use that tool to magically produce two elixirs. For each elixir, roll on the Experimental Elixir table for the elixir's effect, which is triggered when someone drinks the elixir. The elixir appears in a vial, and the vial vanishes when the elixir is drunk or poured out. If any elixir remains when you finish a Long Rest, the elixir and its vial vanish.</text>
        <text>	Drinking an Elixir. As a Bonus Action, a creature can drink the elixir or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of itself.</text>
        <text>	Creating Additional Elixirs. As a Magic action while holding Alchemist's Supplies, you can expend one spell slot to create another elixir. When you do so, you choose its effect from the Experimental Elixir table rather than rolling.</text>
        <text>	When you reach certain Artificer levels, you can make an additional elixir at the end of each Long Rest: a total of three at level 5, four at level 9, and 5 at level 15.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>D6 | Effect</text>
        <text>1 | Healing. The drinker regains a number of Hit Points equal to 2d8 plus your Intelligence modifier.</text>
        <text>2 | Swiftness. The drinker's Speed increases by 10 feet for 1 hour.</text>
        <text>3 | Resilience. The drinker gains a +1 bonus to AC for 10 minutes.</text>
        <text>4 | Boldness. The drinker can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to every attack roll and saving throw they make for the next minute.</text>
        <text>5 | Flight. The drinker gains a Fly Speed of 10 feet for 10 minutes.</text>
        <text>6 | You determine the elixir's effect by choosing one of the other rows in this table.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 5: Alchemical Savant (Alchemist (UA))</name>
        <text>Whenever you cast a spell using your Alchemist's Supplies as the Spellcasting Focus, you gain a bonus to one roll of the spell. That roll must restore Hit Points or be a damage roll that deals Acid, Fire, Necrotic, or Poison damage. The bonus equals your Intelligence modifier (minimum bonus of +1).</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Restorative Reagents (Alchemist (UA))</name>
        <text>You can incorporate restorative reagents into some of your works, granting the following benefits:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Fortify. Whenever a creature drinks an elixir you created with the Experimental Elixir feature, the creature gains Temporary Hit Points equal to your Intelligence modifier plus your Artificer level.</text>
        <text>Restore. You can cast Lesser Restoration without expending a spell slot and without preparing the spell, provided you use Alchemist's Supplies as the Spellcasting Focus. You can do so a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Chemical Mastery (Alchemist (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Alchemical Eruption. When you cast an Artificer spell that deals Acid, Fire, Necrotic, or Poison damage to a target, you can also deal 2d8 Force damage to that target. You can use this benefit only once on each of your turns.</text>
        <text>Chemical Resistance. You gain Resistance to Acid damage and Poison damage.</text>
        <text>Conjured Cauldron. You can cast Tasha's Bubbling Cauldron without expending a spell slot, without preparing the spell, and without Material components, provided you use Alchemist's Supplies as the Spellcasting Focus. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artificer Subclass: Armorer (UA)</name>
        <text>Craft Magic Armor to Enhance Your Abilities</text>
        <text>An Artificer who specializes as an Armorer modifies armor to function almost like a second skin. The armor is enhanced to hone the Artificer's magic, unleash potent attacks, and generate a formidable defense.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Tools Of The Trade (Armorer (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain training with Heavy armor. You also gain proficiency with Smith's Tools. If you already have this tool proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of Artisan's Tools of your choice.</text>
        <text>	In addition, when you craft nonmagical or magic armor, the amount of time required to craft it is halved.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Armorer Spells (Armorer (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach an Artificer level specified in the Armorer Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Artificer Level — Spells</text>
        <text>3 — Magic Missile, Thunderwave</text>
        <text>5 — Mirror Image, Shatter</text>
        <text>9 — Hypnotic Pattern, Lightning Bolt</text>
        <text>13 — Fire Shield, Greater Invisibility</text>
        <text>17 — Passwall, Wall of Force</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Arcane Armor (Armorer (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Magic action while you have Smith's Tools in hand, you can turn a suit of armor you are wearing into Arcane Armor. The armor continues to be Arcane Armor until you don another suit of armor or you die.</text>
        <text>	You gain the following benefits while wearing your Arcane Armor:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>No Strength Requirement. If the armor normally has a Strength requirement, the Arcane Armor lacks this requirement for you.</text>
        <text>Quick Don and Doff. You can don or doff the armor as a Utilize action.</text>
        <text>Second Skin. The armor attaches to you and can't be removed against your will. It also expands to cover your entire body, although you can retract or deploy the helmet as a Bonus Action. The armor replaces missing limbs, functioning identically to a limb it replaces.</text>
        <text>Spellcasting Focus. You can use the Arcane Armor as a Spellcasting Focus for your Artificer spells.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Armor Model (Armorer (UA))</name>
        <text>You can customize your Arcane Armor. When you do so, choose one of the following armor models: Dreadnaught, Guardian, or Infiltrator. The model you choose gives you special benefits while you wear it.</text>
        <text>	Each model includes a special weapon. When you attack with that weapon, you can add your Intelligence modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity modifier, to the attack and damage rolls.</text>
        <text>	You can change the armor's model whenever you finish a Short or Long Rest if you have Smith's Tools in hand.</text>
        <text>	Dreadnaught. You design your armor to become a towering juggernaut in battle. It has the following features:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Armor Flail. An iron ball on a chain appears on one of your armor's gauntlets and has the following traits:</text>
        <text>Weapon Category: Simple Melee</text>
        <text>Damage on a Hit: 1d10 Bludgeoning plus the ability modifier used for the attack roll</text>
        <text>Properties: Reach</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Giant Stature. As a Bonus Action, you transform and enlarge your armor for 1 minute. For the duration, your reach increases by 5 feet, and if you are smaller than Large, you become Large, along with anything you are wearing. If there isn't enough room for you to increase your size, your size doesn't change. You can use this Bonus Action a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Wrecking Ball. If you hit a creature that is at least one size smaller than you with the flail, you can push the creature up to 10 feet straight away from yourself or pull the creature up to 10 feet toward yourself.</text>
        <text>	Guardian. You design your armor to be in the front line of conflict. It has the following features:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Thunder Gauntlets. Each of the armor's gauntlets has the following traits:</text>
        <text>Weapon Category: Simple Melee</text>
        <text>Damage on a Hit: 1d8 Thunder plus the ability modifier used for the attack roll</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Distracting Pulse. A creature hit by the gauntlet has Disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you until the start of your next turn.</text>
        <text>Defensive Field. While you are Bloodied, you can take a Bonus Action to gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your Artificer level. You lose these Temporary Hit Points if you doff the armor.</text>
        <text>	Infiltrator. You customize your armor for subtle undertakings. It has the following features:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Lightning Launcher. A gemlike node appears on one of the armor's gauntlets or on the armor's chest (your choice). It has the following traits:</text>
        <text>Weapon Category: Simple Ranged</text>
        <text>Damage on a Hit: 1d6 Lightning plus the ability modifier used for the attack roll</text>
        <text>Properties: Thrown (Range 90/300 feet)</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Lightning Jolt. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your Lightning Launcher, you can deal an extra 1d6 Lightning damage to that target.</text>
        <text>Powered Steps. Your Speed increases by 5 feet.</text>
        <text>Dampening Field. You have Advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. If the armor normally imposes Disadvantage on such checks, the Advantage and Disadvantage cancel each other, as normal.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 5: Extra Attack (Armorer (UA))</name>
        <text>You can attack twice instead of once whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Armor Replication (Armorer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn an additional plan for your Replicate Magic Item feature, and it must be in the Armor category. If you replace that plan, you must replace it with another Armor plan.</text>
        <text>	In addition, you can create an additional item with that feature, and the item must also be in the Armor category.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Perfected Armor (Armorer (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Arcane Armor gains additional benefits based on its model, as detailed below.</text>
        <text>	Dreadnaught. The damage die of your Armor Flail increases to 2d6 Bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <text>	In addition, when you use your Giant Stature, your reach increases by 10 feet, your size can increase to Large or Huge (your choice), and you gain a Fly Speed equal to your Speed.</text>
        <text>	Guardian. The damage die of your Thunder Gauntlets increases to 1d10 Thunder damage.</text>
        <text>	In addition, when a Huge or smaller creature you can see ends its turn within 30 feet of you, you can take a Reaction to magically force that creature to make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, you pull the creature up to 25 feet directly to an unoccupied space. If you pull the target to a space within 5 feet of yourself, you can make a melee weapon attack against it as part of this Reaction.</text>
        <text>	You can take this Reaction a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text>	Infiltrator. The damage die of your Lightning Launcher increases to 2d6. Any creature that takes Lightning damage from your Lightning Launcher glimmers with magical light until the start of your next turn. The glimmering creature sheds Dim Light in a 5-foot radius, and it has Disadvantage on attack rolls against you, as the light jolts it if it attacks you.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artificer Subclass: Artillerist (UA)</name>
        <text>Wield Destructive Power from Afar</text>
        <text>An Artillerist specializes in using magic to hurl energy, projectiles, and explosions on a battlefield.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 10</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Tool Proficiency (Artillerist (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency with Woodcarver's Tools. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of Artisan's Tools of your choice.</text>
        <text>	In addition, when you craft a magic Wand, the amount of time required to craft it is halved.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 10</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Artillerist Spells (Artillerist (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach an Artificer level specified in the Artillerist Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Artificer Level — Spells</text>
        <text>3 — Shield, Thunderwave</text>
        <text>5 — Scorching Ray, Shatter</text>
        <text>9 — Fireball, Wind Wall</text>
        <text>13 — Ice Storm, Wall of Fire</text>
        <text>17 — Cone of Cold, Wall of Force</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 10</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Eldritch Cannon (Artillerist (UA))</name>
        <text>Using Woodcarver's Tools or Smith's Tools, you can take a Magic action to create a Small or Tiny Eldritch Cannon in an unoccupied space on a horizontal surface within 5 feet of yourself. The cannon's game statistics appear below. You determine its appearance, which includes your choice of legs or wheels. It disappears if it is reduced to 0 Hit Points or after 1 hour. You can dismiss it early as a Magic action.</text>
        <text>	Once you create a cannon, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest or expend a spell slot to create one. You can have only one cannon at a time and can't create one while your cannon is present.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 10</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 5: Arcane Firearm (Artillerist (UA))</name>
        <text>When you finish a Long Rest, you can use Woodcarver's Tools to carve special sigils into a Rod, Staff, or Wand and thereby turn it into your arcane firearm. The sigils disappear from the object if you later carve them on a different item. The sigils otherwise last indefinitely.</text>
        <text>	You can use your arcane firearm as a Spellcasting Focus for your Artificer spells. When you cast an Artificer spell through the firearm, roll 1d8, and you gain a bonus to one of the spell's damage rolls equal to the number rolled.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 10</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Explosive Cannon (Artillerist (UA))</name>
        <text>Every Eldritch Cannon you create is now more destructive. You gain the following benefits:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Detonate. When your cannon is reduced to 0 Hit Points, you can take a Reaction to command the cannon to detonate if you are within 60 feet of it. Doing so destroys the cannon and forces each creature within 20 feet of it to make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 3d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <text>Firepower. The cannon's damage rolls increase by 1d8.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Fortified Position (Artillerist (UA))</name>
        <text>You're a master at forming well-defended emplacements using your Eldritch Cannon. You gain the following benefits:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Double Firepower. You can now have two cannons at the same time. You can create two with the same Magic action (but not with the same spell slot), and you can activate both of them with the same Bonus Action, ordering them to use the same activation option or different ones. You can't create a third cannon while you have two.</text>
        <text>Shimmering Field Projection. You and your allies have Half Cover while within 10 feet of your Eldritch Cannon.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artificer Subclass: Battle Smith (UA)</name>
        <text>Command a Construct Guardian</text>
        <text>A Battle Smith is a combination of protector and medic, an expert at defending others and repairing both materiel and personnel. To aid in their work, Battle Smiths are accompanied by a Steel Defender, a protective companion of their own creation.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Tool Proficiency (Battle Smith (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency with Smith's Tools. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of Artisan's Tools of your choice.</text>
        <text>	In addition, when you craft an ordinary or magic weapon, the amount of time required to craft it is halved.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Battle Smith Spells (Battle Smith (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach an Artificer level specified in the Battle Smith Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Artificer Level — Spells</text>
        <text>3 — Heroism, Shield</text>
        <text>5 — Shining Smite, Warding Bond</text>
        <text>9 — Aura of Vitality, Conjure Barrage</text>
        <text>13 — Aura of Purity, Fire Shield</text>
        <text>17 — Banishing Smite, Mass CureWounds</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Battle Ready (Battle Smith (UA))</name>
        <text>Your combat training and your experiments with magic have paid off in two ways:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Arcane Empowerment. When you attack with a magic weapon, you can use your Intelligence modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity modifier, for the attack and damage rolls.</text>
        <text>Weapon Knowledge. You gain proficiency with Martial weapons.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Steel Defender (Battle Smith (UA))</name>
        <text>Your tinkering has borne you a companion, a Steel Defender (see the stat block). You determine the defender's appearance and whether it has two legs or four; your choices don't affect the defender's game statistics.</text>
        <text>	The Steel Defender is Friendly to you and your allies and obeys you. It vanishes if you die.</text>
        <text>	The Defender in Combat. In combat, the defender acts during your turn. It can move and take its Reaction on its own, but the only action it takes is the Dodge action unless you take a Bonus Action to command it to take an action. If you have the Incapacitated condition, the defender acts on its own and isn't limited to the Dodge action.</text>
        <text>	Restoring or Replacing the Defender. If the defender has died within the last hour, you can take a Magic action to touch it and expend a spell slot. The defender returns to life after 1 minute with all its Hit Points restored.</text>
        <text>	Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can create a new Steel Defender if you have Smith's Tools in hand. If you already have a defender from this feature, the first one vanishes.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 5: Extra Attack (Battle Smith (UA))</name>
        <text>You can attack twice instead of once whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 12</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Arcane Jolt (Battle Smith (UA))</name>
        <text>When either you hit a target with an attack roll using a magic weapon or your Steel Defender hits a target, you can channel magical energy through the strike to create one of the following effects:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Destructive Energy. The target takes an extra 2d6 Force damage.</text>
        <text>Restorative Energy. Choose one creature or object you can see within 30 feet of the target. Healing energy flows into the chosen recipient, restoring 2d6 Hit Points to it.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>	You can use this energy a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), but you can do so no more than once a turn. You regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 12</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Improved Defender (Battle Smith (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Arcane Jolt and Steel Defender have become more powerful, granting these benefits:</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Improved Jolt. The extra damage and healing of your Arcane Jolt both increase to 4d6.</text>
        <text>Fortified Defender. Your Steel Defender gains a +2 bonus to Armor Class.</text>
        <text>Improved Deflection. Whenever your Steel Defender uses its Deflect Attack, the attacker takes Force damage equal to 1d4 plus your Intelligence modifier.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: 2024 Artificer p. 12</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
