<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Sorcerer [2024]</name>
    <!-- Sorcerer Subclass: Spellfire Sorcery (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerer Subclass: Spellfire Sorcery (UA)</name>
        <text>Radiate Raw Magic Potential

Your innate power stems from the source of magic itself: the Weave. This connection manifests as a rare ability known as spellfire, and you surge with radiant bursts of this raw magic. Your talent with spellfire allows you to heal allies, sear enemies, and absorb powerful spells.

Wielders of spellfire tend to be adventurous souls with penchants for wandering. Many travel between cosmopolitan settlements, such as those along the Sword Coast, and wield their magic in service of the common good. Others prioritize the realization of their own strange powers by roaming equally strange lands, from the magic-blasted wastes of the Anauroch Desert to the god-touched wilds of the Old Empires. Wherever they go in the Realms, spellfire Sorcerers are often courted by factions with interests in the arcane arts, such as the Harpers and the Cult of the Dragon.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Spellfire Burst (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>When you spend at least 1 Sorcery Point as part of the Magic action or a Bonus Action on your turn, you can unleash one of the following magical effects of your choice. You can do so only once per turn.

Bolstering Flames. You or one creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself gains Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d4 plus your Charisma modifier.

Radiant Fire. One creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take 1d6 Fire or Radiant damage (your choice).

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Spellfire Spells (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Sorcerer level specified in the Spellfire Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Spellfire Spell List:
Level | Spells
3 | Cure Wounds, Guiding Bolt, Lesser Restoration, Scorching Ray
5 | Aura of Vitality, Dispel Magic
7 | Fire Shield, Wall of Fire
9 | Greater Restoration, Flame Strike

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Absorb Spells (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>You always have Counterspell prepared.

Additionally, whenever a target fails the saving throw against a Counterspell you cast, you regain 1d4 Sorcery Points.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Honed Spellfire (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Spellfire Burst improves. You add your Sorcerer level to the Temporary Hit Points gained from Bolstering Flames, and the 1d6 of Radiant Fire increases to 3d6.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Crown Of Spellfire (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you gain the following benefits for 1 minute. Once you use this Bonus Action, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest unless you spend 7 Sorcery Points (no action required) to restore your use of it.

Burning Life Force. Once per turn when you are hit by an attack roll, you can expend a number of Hit Dice, up to a maximum equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Roll the expended dice and reduce the amount of damage from that attack equal to the total rolled plus your Sorcerer level.

Flight. You gain a Fly Speed of 60 feet and can hover.

Spell Avoidance. When you're subjected to a spell or magical effect that allows you to make a saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw and only half damage if you fail. You can't use this benefit if you have the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Cure Wounds [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Guiding Bolt [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Lesser Restoration [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Scorching Ray [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Vitality [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Magic [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fire Shield [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Fire [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Restoration [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Flame Strike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Spellfire Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
