<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Skeleton [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <vulnerable>bludgeoning</vulnerable>
    <resist>poison</resist>
    <proficiency>History</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Few undead possess true sapience, and intelligent skeletons are among the rarest of their kind. Some originate from the necropolis of Evernight in the Shadowfell, a city of the dead where ancient magics sustain them. However, most are the discarded remnants of powerful spellcasters—animated to serve, only to be abandoned when their usefulness wanes. Despite their unnatural existence, some skeletons retain a flicker of free will, forging their own paths in a world that often fears them.
	Devoid of flesh and incapable of speech, skeletons rely on the residual necromantic energy that sustains them. Their brittle bones make them fragile in battle, but their undead nature grants them unnatural resilience and a lingering connection to the magic that first reanimated them.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Undead</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small or Medium</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiency</name>
      <text>History</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Languages</name>
      <text>Any (see Limited Telepathy)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Vulnerability</name>
      <text>Bludgeoning (see Brittle Bones)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Resistances</name>
      <text>Poison</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Blindsight</name>
      <text>90 ft. (blind beyond this range).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Brittle Bones</name>
      <text>Your skeletal form makes you vulnerable to crushing blows. You have vulnerability to bludgeoning damage unless you are wearing heavy armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Limited Telepathy</name>
      <text>You cannot speak, but you can communicate telepathically with creatures within 90 feet. This communication is one-way; you can send thoughts, but you cannot receive them telepathically.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Residual Necromancy</name>
      <text>The magic that binds your soul to your bones grants you a lingering connection to necrotic forces. When you create your skeleton, choose one cantrip from the following list:

	• Chill Touch
	• Poison Spray
	• Toll the Dead.

You always have this cantrip prepared. When casting a spell using this trait, choose Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma as your spellcasting ability (this choice is made when you create your skeleton).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Spark of Life</name>
      <text>Though undead, the magic that reanimated you carries a flicker of vitality. You regain hit points from spells, potions, and resting as though you were a living creature.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
