<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Fighter [2024]</name>
    <!-- Fighter Subclass: Arcane Archer (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighter Subclass: Arcane Archer (UA)</name>
        <text>Deploy Magical Effects through Enchanted Ammunition

An Arcane Archer studies a unique elven method of archery that weaves magic into attacks to produce supernatural effects. The first Arcane Archers stood watch over their communities and used magic-infused arrows to defeat monsters and invaders. Over the centuries, other species have learned this method of blending magical aptitude with archery. These archers have broadened this method's application to ranged weapons of many kinds and to aspects of adventuring life outside of combat.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Arcane Archer Lore (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn magical theory and secrets of nature, granting you the following benefits.

Cantrip. You know either the Druidcraft or Prestidigitation cantrip. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.

Skills. You gain proficiency in the Arcana and Nature skills. If you already have one of these proficiencies, you instead gain proficiency in a different skill of your choice (or with two other skills if you have both).

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Arcane Shot (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn to unleash special magical effects with some of your shots.

Arcane Shot Options. You learn two Arcane Shot options of your choice from the "Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options" spell list.
	You learn an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice when you reach Fighter levels 7, 10, 15, and 18. Each time you learn a new Arcane Shot option, you can also replace one option you know with a different one.

Using Arcane Shot. Once per turn when you make a ranged attack using a weapon with the Ammunition property, you can apply one of your Arcane Shot options to that attack. You decide to use the option when you hit a creature and deal damage to it unless the option doesn't involve an attack roll.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Arcane Shot Die. Arcane Shot options refer to your Arcane Shot Die. Your Arcane Shot Die is a d6.

Saving Throws. If an Arcane Shot option requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 plus your Intelligence modifier plus your Proficiency Bonus.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
        <roll description="Arcane Shot">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Curving Shot (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn how to direct an errant shot toward a new target. If you make an attack roll with a weapon with the Ammunition property and miss, you can cause the shot to ricochet toward a new target as a Bonus Action immediately after the attack misses. The new target must be a creature you can see within the weapon's range and within 60 feet of the attack's original target. Make an attack roll against the new target.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Magical Ammunition (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn to imbue your ammunition with magical properties. As a Magic action, you can imbue a piece of nonmagical ammunition with one of the following magical properties and fire it at a solid surface you can see within the weapon's range. On a hit, the ammunition's effect activates, and the ammunition attaches to the surface it hit for the duration of the effect; when the effect ends, the ammunition is destroyed.
	Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a Short or Long Rest. You can also restore your use of this feature by expending a use of your Second Wind (no action required).

Darkening Shot. Magical shadows fill a 15foot Emanation originating from the ammunition for 1 minute. Nonmagical flames in the Emanation are extinguished, and creatures in the Emanation have a -5 penalty to Wisdom (Perception) checks and Passive Perception.

Unlocking Shot. A burst of magic fills a 15-foot Emanation originating from the ammunition. A loud knock, audible up to 300 feet away, also emits from the ammunition. Any object in the Emanation that is held shut by a mundane lock or that is stuck or barred becomes unlocked, unstuck, or unbarred. If the object has multiple locks, only one of them is unlocked.

Vine Shot. A 60-foot-long vine grows from the ammunition. You and other creatures can then climb it. The vine withers away after 10 minutes.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Arcane Shot Improvement (1) (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice from the "Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options" spell list when you reach Fighter levels 7. Each time you learn a new Arcane Shot option, you can also replace one option you know with a different one.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Ever Ready Shot (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>When you roll Initiative, you can regain one expended use of Arcane Shot.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Arcane Shot Improvement (2) (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice from the "Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options" spell list when you reach Fighter levels 10. Each time you learn a new Arcane Shot option, you can also replace one option you know with a different one.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Arcane Burst (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You can push creatures away from you with your arcane mastery. When you use Indomitable, each creature of your choice in a 10-foot Emanation originating from you must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your Arcane Shot DC or be pushed up to 20 feet straight away from you.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Arcane Shot Improvement (3) (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice from the "Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options" spell list when you reach Fighter level 18. Each time you learn a new Arcane Shot option, you can also replace one option you know with a different one.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Masterful Shots (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You employ agility in your sharpshooting When a creature you can see misses you with an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to move up to half your Speed away from the attacker without provoking Opportunity Attacks. You can then make a ranged attack roll against the attacker as part of this Reaction if the attacker is within the weapon's range.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Arcane Shot Improvement (4) (Arcane Archer (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice from the "Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options" spell list when you reach Fighter levels 7, 10, 15, and 18. Each time you learn a new Arcane Shot option, you can also replace one option you know with a different one.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Shot: Banishing Shot</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options</classes>
    <text>Your ammunition temporarily sequesters your target in a harmless demiplane. The creature you hit takes additional Psychic damage equal to one roll of your Arcane Shot Die and must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be banished. While banished, the creature has the Incapacitated condition and a Speed of 0. At the end of its next turn, the target reappears in the space it left or, if that space is occupied, in the nearest unoccupied space.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 3</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Shot: Beguiling Shot</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options</classes>
    <text>Your ammunition beguiles your target. The creature you hit takes additional Psychic damage equal to two rolls of your Arcane Shot Die and must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Charmed condition until the start of your next turn, treating either you or one of your allies within 30 feet of the target (your choice) as the charmer. The Charmed condition ends early if the charmer attacks the target, deals damage to it, or forces it to make a saving throw.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 3</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Shot: Bursting Shot</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options</classes>
    <text>You imbue your ammunition with explosive force energy. Immediately after you deal damage to the creature, your target and each creature within a 10-foot Emanation originating from the target take Force damage equal to two rolls of your Arcane Shot Die.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 3</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Shot: Enfeebling Shot</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options</classes>
    <text>Your ammunition saps your target's strength. The creature you hit takes additional Necrotic damage equal to two rolls of your Arcane Shot Die. The target must also succeed on a Constitution saving throw or have the Poisoned condition until the end of its next turn. Whenever a target Poisoned in this way hits with an attack roll, it subtracts an amount equal to one roll of your Arcane Shot Die from the total damage of that attack.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 3</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Shot: Grasping Shot</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options</classes>
    <text>Your ammunition creates clutching brambles around your target. The creature you hit takes additional Slashing damage equal to one roll of your Arcane Shot Die and must succeed on a Strength saving throw or have the Restrained condition for 1 minute or until you use this option again. The target or a creature within reach of it can take an action to make a Strength (Athletics) check against your Arcane Shot DC, removing the brambles and ending the Restrained condition on the target on a successful check.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 3</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Shot: Piercing Shot</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options</classes>
    <text>You give your ammunition an ethereal quality. When you use this option, you don't make an attack roll for the attack. Instead, the ammunition shoots forward in a 30-foot Line that is 1 foot wide, originating from you, then vanishes. The Line ignores cover, as the ammunition phases through solid objects. Each creature in the Line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes damage as if it were hit plus additional Piercing damage equal to two rolls of your Arcane Shot Die. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 4</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Shot: Seeking Shot</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options</classes>
    <text>Your ammunition can seek out a target. When you use this option, you don't make an attack roll for the attack. Instead, choose one creature you have seen in the last minute. The ammunition flies toward that creature, moving around corners if necessary and ignoring Half Cover and Three-Quarters Cover. If the target is within your weapon's long range, the target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes damage as if it were hit plus additional Force damage equal to two rolls of your Arcane Shot Die, and you learn the target's current location. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage only. If the target is beyond your weapon's long range, the ammunition disappears after traveling as far as it can.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 4</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Shot: Shadow Shot</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Fighter [2024] (Arcane Archer (UA)): Arcane Shot Options</classes>
    <text>Your ammunition occludes your foe's vision with shadows. The creature you hit takes additional Psychic damage equal to one roll of your Arcane Shot Die, and it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Blinded condition until the end of its next turn.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 4</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>
