<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Monk [2024]</name>
    <!-- Monk Subclass: Tattooed Warrior (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monk Subclass: Tattooed Warrior (UA)</name>
        <text>Enhance Martial Arts with Your Magic Tattoos

Drawing from body-marking traditions from across the multiverse, Tattooed Warriors can use arcane power imbued in their magic tattoos. These Monks gain tattoos as they grow in martial prowess and insight. Tattooed Warriors can reshape their tattoos to access a suite of physical and magical effects.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 4</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Magic Tattoos (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the magic tattoos described by other features of this subclass. The tattoos appear on your body wherever you wish. Damage or injury doesn't impair your magic tattoos' function. A magic tattoo can look like a brand, scarification, a birthmark, patterns of scales, or any other cosmetic alteration.
	If a tattoo's effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 plus your Wisdom modifier plus your Proficiency Bonus. Your spellcasting ability for spells granted by a tattoo is Wisdom.
	Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can reshape one of your magic tattoos, changing the option you chose from one list to another option on the same list.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 4</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Beast Tattoos (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain two animal tattoos. Choose two tattoos from the following options.

Bat. You know the Dancing Lights cantrip. You also gain Blindsight with a range of 10 feet.

Butterfly. You know the Light cantrip. When you make a High Jump, you can use your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier to determine how high you can jump.

Crane. You know the Guidance cantrip. When you miss a creature with an attack granted by your Flurry of Blows, you have Advantage on your next attack roll against that creature before the end of your next turn.

Horse. You know the Message cantrip. When you expend 1 Focus Point to use Step of the Wind, your Speed increases by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.

Tortoise. You know the Spare the Dying cantrip. When you expend 1 Focus Point to use Patient Defense, you have a + 1 bonus to AC until the start of your next turn.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Celestial Tattoo (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain an additional magic tattoo depicting a celestial phenomenon. Choose a tattoo from the following options.

Comet. When you take the Search action, you can expend 1 Focus Point to roll your Martial Arts die and add the number rolled to the Wisdom check.

Eclipse. When you take the Hide action, you can expend 1 Focus Point to roll your Martial Arts die and add the number rolled to the Dexterity (Stealth) check.

Sunburst. When you take the Study action, you can expend 1 Focus Point to roll your Martial Arts die and add the number rolled to the Intelligence check.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Nature Tattoo (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain an additional magic tattoo depicting a natural feature. Choose a tattoo from the following options.

Sea Storm. You gain Resistance to one of the following damage types of your choice: Cold, Lightning, or Thunder. Whenever you finish a Short or Long Rest, or use your Uncanny Metabolism feature, you can change this choice.

Volcano. You gain Resistance to one of the following damage types of your choice: Acid, Fire, or Poison. Whenever you finish a Short or Long Rest, or use your Uncanny Metabolism feature, you can change this choice.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Monster Tattoo (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain a magic tattoo depicting a mighty creature. Choose a tattoo from the following options.

Beholder. At the start of your turn, you can expend 1 Focus Point to gain a Ply Speed equal to your Speed for 10 minutes. While you have this Fly Speed, you can hover.
	Additionally, as a Magic action, you can expend 1 Focus Point to fire four rays from your eyes. You can fire them at one target you can see within 120 feet or at several. Make a ranged spell attack for each ray, using Wisdom as your spellcasting ability. On a hit, the attack deals Force damage equal to one roll of your Martial Arts die plus your Wisdom modifier.

Chromatic Dragon. When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can expend 1 Focus Point to replace one of your attacks with an exhalation of magical energy in a 30-foot Cone. Choose a damage type: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Poison. Each creature in that area makes a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes damage of the chosen type equal to two rolls of your Martial Arts die plus your Wisdom modifier. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage.

Displacer Beast. When you expend a Focus Point to use Flurry of Blows or Step of the Wind, you can expend 1 Focus Point to cast the Mirror Image spell as part of that Bonus Action.

Troll. At the start of each of your turns, you regain Hit Points equal to 5 plus your Wisdom modifier if you are Bloodied and have at least 1 Hit Point. Any severed body part regrows after you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclassesUpdate p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
