<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Wizard [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: Convoker (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: Convoker (HB)</name>
        <text>Summon Aid and Scatter Enemies

As a Convoker you specialise in the Conjuration school of magic, summoning extraplanar spirits to your side and teleporting great distances in the blink of an eye. Convokers are as valued for their practical abilities as they are feared for their control of battlefields.

Source:	Convoker by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Conjuration Savant (Convoker (HB))</name>
        <text>Choose two Wizard spells from the Conjuration school, each of which must be no higher than level 2, and add them to your spellbook for free.
	In addition, whenever you gain access to a new level of spell slots in this class, you can add one Wizard spell from the Conjuration school to your spellbook for free. The chosen spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	Finally, while a spellbook of yours exists and contains at least one of your spells, you can summon it to your hand at any time as a Magic Action. If the spellbook is torn into multiple pieces, you summon the largest piece.

Source:	Convoker by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Consummate Convoker (Convoker (HB))</name>
        <text>Focused study has improved your command of summoning and teleportation magic, granting you the following benefits:

	Convoker's Companion. You always have the Find Familiar spell prepared. When you cast Find Familiar you choose from the normal forms, the form of an Homunculus, or the form of any type of Mephit. When your familiar forces a creature to make a saving throw, you use your spell save DC. In addition, when your familiar is about to take damage, you can take a Reaction and expend a level 1+ Wizard spell slot to dismiss the familiar instead.

	Convoker's Jaunt. You always have the Misty Step spell prepared, and you can cast it once without expending a spell slot. You regain your use of this feature when you finish a Short or Long Rest, or when you expend a level 2+ Wizard spell slot to recharge it (no action required).

Source:	Convoker by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Misty Fling (Convoker (HB))</name>
        <text>When you cast Misty Step, you can change its range to Touch and target one creature other than yourself that is Large size or smaller. A willing target is teleported up to the spell's maximum distance to a space you can see.
	An unwilling target must succed a Charisma saving throw against your spell save DC to resist being teleported.

Source:	Convoker by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Extraplanar Bond (Convoker (HB))</name>
        <text>When you summon a creature with a Conjuration spell that requires Concentration, taking damage can't break your Concentration on this spell, and you can apply the Find Familiar spell's 'Telepathic Connection' benefit to the summoned creature as if it were your familiar.

Source:	Convoker by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Dimensional Mastery (Convoker (HB))</name>
        <text>Misty Fling now increases Misty Step's range to 30 feet, its maximum teleport distance to 60 feet, and enables the spell to teleport Huge or Gargantuan creatures other than yourself if cast with a spell slot of level 4+.

Source:	Convoker by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
