<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Artificer</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artificer Specialist: Effigist (HB)</name>
        <text>Effigists use a combination of arcane and eldritch arts to manipulate the bodies of other creatures by way of dolls and figurines. Many effigists come from rural tribes, but the tradition is slowly gaining students in more populated areas.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Effigist (HB): Tool Proficiency</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency with one of the following: mason's tools, potter's tools, or weaver's tools.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Effigist (HB): Effigist Spells</name>
        <text>You always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Effigist Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don't count against the number of artificer spells you prep.

Effigist Spells:
Artificer Level | Spells
3rd | hex, sleep
5th | hold person, silence
9th | bestow curse, slow
13th | compulsion, dominate beast
17th | dominate person, hold monster

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Effigist (HB): Effigy Connection</name>
        <text>You learn how to create magical effigies. Using any set of artisan's tools of your choice, you can take an action to magically create a Tiny figurine in your hands. This figurine can be held in one hand, and you can use it as a spellcasting focus. When you create the effigy, you determine its appearance. It may be a jade figurine, a sackcloth doll, a clay mock-up, or even spoons in a pickle jar.

Once you create a magical effigy, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest or until you expend a spell slot of 1st level or higher to create one. You can only have one magical effigy at a time. If you create a new one, the original one loses its magic. The effigy also loses its magic after 1 hour, and you can dismiss its magic early as an action.

When you create an effigy, you designate a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see or hear for it to represent. This connection remains even if the creature moves out of range. As an action on each of your turns, you can designate for the effigy to represent a new qualifying creature. This connection ends when the effigy loses its magic.

You can target the represented creature with spells that have a range of Touch, by casting such a spell on the effigy. The effigy counts as a creature that you can see for the purposes of what you can target with such a spell.

As a bonus action on each of your turns, you can expose the effigy to a harmful effect within 5 feet of you to potentially damage the represented creature. The harmful effect must deal bludgeoning, piercing, slashing, acid, cold, fire, lightning, necrotic, radiant, or thunder damage. When you harm the effigy, the represented creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or else take 2d8 of the corresponding damage type.

If you use your action to cast a spell that deals a qualifying type of damage, you can choose for the effigy connection to deal that type of damage. For example, if you use your action to cast frostbite, you can choose for the effigy connection to deal cold damage, regardless of whether you exposed the effigy to the actual spell effects or not.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Effigist (HB): Modify Movement</name>
        <text>If your represented creature makes a Strength or Dexterity based saving throw, attack roll, or ability check, you can use your reaction to force them to do it with advantage or disadvantage (your choice).

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Effigist (HB): Concentrated Connection</name>
        <text>The damage rolls caused by your effigy increase by 1d8.

As an action, you can see through the creature's eyes and hear what it hears, and continue to do so until you use your action to return to your normal senses or until the effigy disappears. The creature is aware someone is perceiving through its senses, but does not necessarily know who it is or how they can do it.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Effigist (HB): Complete Control</name>
        <text>You have become a master of control. You can cast dominate monster on a represented creature once without expending a spell slot, provided that you use your effigy as the spellcasting focus. Once you have used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    
    <!-- Kobold Engineer -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artificer Specialist: Kobold Engineer (HB)</name>
        <text>Kobold engineers aren't all kobolds, but many are. The practice was named after the most prominent practitioners, kobold inventors that specialize in devising madcap, improvised weapons and traps designed to distract enemies while their companions attack. These weapons often include odd chemicals and animals collected from nature or conjured from thin air.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Kobold Engineer (HB): Kobolt Engineer Spells</name>
        <text>You always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Kobold Engineer spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don't count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.

Kobolt Engineer Spells:
Artificer Level | Spells
3rd | find familiar, speak with animals
5th | darkness, find traps
9th | conjure animals, fireball
13th | greater invisibility, polymorph
17th | passwall, telekinesis

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Kobold Engineer (HB): Bonus Proficiency</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in Animal Handling.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Kobold Engineer (HB): Supply Bag</name>
        <text>You have a magical bag that you can pull supplies for quickly improvised weapons and traps from. When you finish a long rest, you prepare a number of Improvised Attacks, described below, equal to half your level in this class (rounded up). You can choose which ones to prepare or roll 1d10 to determine randomly. You can use each prepared Improvised Attack three times, and you regain expended uses when you finish a long rest. You can also expend a spell slot of 1st level or higher to use an Improvised Attack that you have not prepared or that you have expended all uses for.

Improvised Attacks and creatures made by them use your spell attack bonus and spell save DC for their attacks and saving throw effects. Creatures conjured by these attacks have a number of hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier + the creature's Constitution modifier + twice your level in this class. Such creatures use your spell save DC for their abilities that require saving throws.

Unless otherwise noted, Improvised Attacks can target creatures, objects, structures, and spaces, and require a ranged spell attack roll.

You can expend a spell slot of 1st level or higher to use an Improvised Attack of your choice.

Improvised Attacks:

Angry Cat:
As a bonus action, you toss an angry cat at a target of your choice within 15 feet. The creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw, or else take 1d6 slashing damage and have an angry cat on it. A creature with an angry cat on it is distracted, and attack rolls against it are made with advantage. A creature with an angry cat on it repeats this saving throw at the start of each of its turns, taking 1d6 on a failed save, or ending the effect on a success. The cat then disappears.

Basket of Centipedes:
As a bonus action, you throw a wicker basket of centipedes onto a target within 20 feet. A swarm of insects (centipedes) emerges from the basket and rolls initiative, attacking any creatures that occupy its space. At the end of each of the swarm's turns, there's a 25% chance that the swarm and basket disappear.

Bear Trap:
As a bonus action, you throw a bear trap at a target within 20 feet. On a hit, the creature takes 1d6 piercing damage, and its speed is halved until it regains at least 1 hit point. If the attack is a critical hit and it reduces a creature to 0 hit points, the creature is decapitated.

Green Slime:
As a bonus action, you throw a pot of green slime at a target within 30 feet. On a hit, a target is covered in green slime and takes 1d6 acid damage, or 2d6 acid damage if it is a nonmagical object or struc ture made of wood or metal. A target covered in green slime takes this damage again at the start of each of its turns. Sunlight, any effect that cures disease, and any effect that deals cold, fire, or radiant damage destroys the green slime. A creature can also use its action to scrape green slime off of a target. The slime disappears after 1 minute.

Otyugh Bile:
As a bonus action, you throw a vial of acid at a target of your choice within 30 feet. On a hit, the target takes 3d6 acid damage.

Sack of Frogs:
As a bonus action, you throw a burlap sack of frogs at a target within 20 feet. A swarm of frogs (see chapter 3) emerges from the sack and rolls initiative, attacking any creatures that occupy its space. At the end of each of the swarm's turns, there's a 25% chance that the swarm disappears.

Scorpion on a Stick:
As a bonus action, you pull a 10-foot-long pole out of your supply bag and make a melee spell attack with it at a creature within 10 feet of you. On a hit, the creature takes 1d6 poison damage and is poisoned for 1 minute. The creature can make a Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.

Skunk:
As a bonus action, you pull a friendly skunk out of your bag and toss it into an unoccupied space within 15 feet. It rolls initiative. It is friendly to all crea tures, has a speed of 15 feet, has no meaningful attacks, and always walks towards the nearest creature. At the end of each of its turns, there is a 50% chance it sprays a random adjacent creature. A sprayed creature makes a Constitution saving throw at the start of each of its turns. On a failed save, the creature spends its action on that turn retching and reeling. On a success, the effect ends. After 1 minute, the effect ends. Once the skunk has sprayed its musk, it disappears.

Smoke Bomb:
As a bonus action, you throw a small packet of questionable contents at a space within 30 feet of you. Thick black smoke quietly erupts from that space, filling a 15-foot cube centered on that spot. The area of the smoke is heavily obscured. The smoke disappears after 1 minute or until a strong wind disperses it.

Wasp Nest:
As a bonus action, you throw a nest of angry wasps at a target within 20 feet. A swarm of insects (wasps) emerges from the nest and rolls initia tive. It always moves towards and attacks the nearest creature with more than 0 hit points remaining. At the end of each of the swarm's turns, there's a 50% chance that the swarm and nest disappear.

Oops:
Consider asking your Dungeon Master if your supply bag can function as a bag of holding as well. If so, any time you attempt to pull an item out of the bag, there is a 10% chance you accidentally pull a random Improvised Attack out instead, targeting yourself. This does not count as one of your uses for each prepared Improvised Attack.

d10 | Random Improvised Attack
1 | Angry cat
2 | Basket of centipedes
3 | Bear trap
4 | Green slime
5 | Otyugh bile
6 | Sack of frogs
7 | Scorpion on a stick
8 | Skunk
9 | Smoke bomb
10 | Wasp nest

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Kobold Engineer (HB): Better Bag</name>
        <text>The initial damage of all of your Improvised Attacks increases by 1d6, and increases by another 1d6 again at 9th level.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Kobold Engineer (HB): Warrens Excavator</name>
        <text>You've discovered esoteric secrets of civil engineering magic. You gain a burrowing speed of 10 feet and can choose to leave a tunnel behind you that is just big enough to fit a creature of your size. This speed can't be used to burrow through solid rock, ice, metal, wood, or similar substances.

Creatures one size larger than you can also fit in the area, but must squeeze to do so. While squeezing, such a creature's speed is halved, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and Dexterity saving throws, and attack rolls against it have advantage.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Kobold Engineer (HB): Look Over There!</name>
        <text>When you see a creature take the Dash, Dodge, Help, Hide, or Search action, you can use your reaction to take the same action or to use one of your prepared Improvised Attacks.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
