<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data version="5">
  <campaign>
    <version>32</version>
    <uid>4147</uid>
    <name>Dragon War</name>
    <pc>
      <uid>4170</uid>
      <label>DW Rogue</label>
      <name>Halfling, Lightfoot Rogue 20</name>
      <size>1</size>
      <abilities>10,20,20,14,14,9,</abilities>
      <hpMax>156</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>156</hpCurrent>
      <hd>20d8</hd>
      <ac>19</ac>
      <armor>Studded Leather Armor +2</armor>
      <speed>25 ft.</speed>
      <init>5</init>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>3</ability>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>4</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>8</id>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>14</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>15</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>17</modifier>
      </skill>
      <passive>24</passive>
      <languages>You can speak, read, and write Common and Halfling. The Halfling language isn&#39;t secret, but halflings are loath to share it with others. They write very little, so they don&#39;t have a rich body of literature. Their oral tradition, however, is very strong. Almost all halflings speak Common to converse with the people in whose lands they dwell or through which they are traveling.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 28</languages>
      <cr>20</cr>
      <action>
        <name>Shortsword +1</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 6 piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>12</atk>
          <dmg>1d6+6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Dagger</name>
        <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 1d4 + 5 piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>11</atk>
          <dmg>1d4+5</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Shortbow</name>
        <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, range 80/320 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 5 piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>11</atk>
          <dmg>1d6+5</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Sneak Attack </name>
        <text>Attack: +0 to hit. Hit: 10d6 damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Attack</name>
          <dmg>10d6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
    </pc>
    <pc>
      <uid>4171</uid>
      <label>DW Bard</label>
      <name>Half-Elf Bard 20</name>
      <abilities>8,20,16,12,10,20,</abilities>
      <hpMax>152</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>152</hpCurrent>
      <hd>20d8</hd>
      <ac>18</ac>
      <armor>Studded Leather Armor +1</armor>
      <speed>30 ft.</speed>
      <init>8</init>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>2</id>
        <modifier>13</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>3</id>
        <modifier>5</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>4</id>
        <modifier>17</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>5</id>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>6</id>
        <modifier>12</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>12</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>12</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>13</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>15</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <passive>22</passive>
      <languages>You can speak, read, and write Common, Elvish, and Halfling.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 39</languages>
      <cr>20</cr>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots>
      <slotsCurrent>0,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slotsCurrent>
      <action>
        <name>Rapier +2</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +13 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d8 + 7 piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>13</atk>
          <dmg>1d8+7</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Hand Crossbow</name>
        <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>11</atk>
          <dmg>1d6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <spell>
        <name>Charm Person</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>You attempt to charm a humanoid you can see within range. It must make a Wisdom saving throw, and does so with advantage if you or your companions are fighting it. If it fails the saving throw, it is charmed by you until the spell ends or until you or your companions do anything harmful to it. The charmed creature regards you as a friendly acquaintance. When the spell ends, the creature knows it was charmed by you.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 221</text>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Counterspell</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 reaction, which you take when you see a creature within 60 feet of you casting a spell</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You attempt to interrupt a creature in the process of casting a spell. If the creature is casting a spell of or lower, its spell fails and has no effect. If it is casting a spell of or higher, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell&#39;s level. On a success, the creature&#39;s spell fails and has no effect.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the interrupted spell has no effect if its level is less than or equal to the level of the spell slot you used.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 228</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Crown of Madness</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>One humanoid of your choice that you can see within range must succeed on a W Wisdom saving throw or become charmed by you for the duration. While the target is charmed in this way, a twisted crown of jagged iron appears on its head, and a madness glows in its eyes.
	The charmed target must use its action before moving on each of its turns to make a melee attack against a creature other than itself that you mentally choose. The target can act normally on its turn if you choose no creature or if none are within its reach.
	On your subsequent turns, you must use your action to maintain control over the target, or the spell ends. Also, the target can make a Wisdom saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, the spell ends.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 229</text>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Dimension Door</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>500 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You teleport yourself from your current location to any other spot within range. You arrive at exactly the spot desired. It can be a place you can see, one you can visualize, or one you can describe by stating distance and direction, such as 200 feet straight downward or upward to the northwest at a 45-degree angle, 300 feet.
	You can bring along objects as long as their weight doesn&#39;t exceed what you can carry. You can also bring one willing creature of your size or smaller who is carrying gear up to its carrying capacity. The creature must be within 5 feet of you when you cast this spell.
	If you would arrive in a place already occupied by an object or a creature, you and any creature traveling with you each take 4d6 force damage, and the spell fails to teleport you.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 233</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Dispel Magic</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Choose any creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10+the spell&#39;s level. On a successful check, the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell&#39;s level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 234</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer (Clockwork)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Dominate Monster</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <text>You attempt to beguile a creature that you can see within range. It must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you for the duration. If you or creatures that are friendly to you are fighting it, it has advantage on the saving throw.
	While the creature is charmed, you have a telepathic link with it as long as the two of you are on the same plane of existence. You can use this telepathic link to issue commands to the creature while you are conscious (no action required), which it does its best to obey. You can specify a simple and general course of action, such as Attack that creature, Run over there, or Fetch that object. If the creature completes the order and doesn&#39;t receive further direction from you, it defends and preserves itself to the best of its ability.
	You can use your action to take total and precise control of the target. Until the end of your next turn, the creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn&#39;t do anything that you don&#39;t allow it to do. During this time, you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own reaction as well.
	Each time the target takes damage, it makes a new Wisdom saving throw against the spell. If the saving throw succeeds, the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell with a 9th-level spell slot, the duration is concentration, up to 8 hours.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 235</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Dominate Person</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You attempt to beguile a humanoid that you can see within range. It must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you for the duration. If you or creatures that are friendly to you are fighting it, it has advantage on the saving throw.
	While the target is charmed, you have a telepathic link with it as long as the two of you are on the same plane of existence. You can use this telepathic link to issue commands to the creature while you are conscious (no action required), which it does its best to obey. You can specify a simple and general course of action, such as Attack that creature, Run over there, or Fetch that object. If the creature completes the order and doesn&#39;t receive further direction from you, it defends and preserves itself to the best of its ability.
	You can use your action to take total and precise control of the target. Until the end of your next turn, the creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn&#39;t do anything that you don&#39;t allow it to do. During this time you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own reaction as well.
	Each time the target takes damage, it makes a new Wisdom saving throw against the spell. If the saving throw succeeds, the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a 6th-level spell slot, the duration is concentration, up to 10 minutes. When you use a 7th-level spell slot, the duration is concentration, up to 1 hour. When you use a spell slot of 8th level or higher, the duration is concentration, up to 8 hours.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 235</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Great Old One)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Enhance Ability</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>fur or a feather from a beast</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <text>You touch a creature and bestow upon it a magical enhancement. Choose one of the following effects: the target gains the effect until the spell ends.
	Bear&#39;s Endurance: The target has advantage on Constitution checks. It also gains 2d6 temporary hit points, which are lost when the spell ends.
	Bull&#39;s Strength: The target has advantage on Strength checks, and his or her carrying capacity doubles.
	Cat&#39;s Grace: The target has advantage on Dexterity checks. It also doesn&#39;t take damage from falling 20 feet or less if it isn&#39;t incapacitated.
	Eagle&#39;s Splendor: The target has advantage on Charisma checks.
	Fox&#39;s Cunning: The target has advantage on Intelligence checks.
	Owl&#39;s Wisdom: The target has advantage on Wisdom checks.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 237</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Eyebite</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>For the spell&#39;s duration, your eyes become an inky void imbued with dread power. One creature of your choice within 60 feet of you that you can see must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be affected by one of the following effects of your choice for the duration. On each of your turns until the spell ends, you can use your action to target another creature but can&#39;t target a creature again if it has succeeded on a saving throw against this casting of Eyebite.
	Asleep: The target galls unconscious. It wakes up if it takes any damage or if another creature uses its action to shake the sleeper awake.
	Panicked: The target is frightened of you. On each of its turns, the frightened creature must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest and shortest available route, unless there is nowhere to move. If the target moves to a place at least 60 feet away from you where it can no longer see you, this effect ends.
	Sickened: The target has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks. At the end of each of its turns, it can make another Wisdom saving throw. If it succeeds, the effect ends.

• The creature can&#39;t willingly move closer to the source of its fear.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 238</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Faerie Fire</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>Each object in a 20-foot cube within range is outlined in blue, green, or violet light (your choice). Any creature in the area when the spell is cast is also outlined in light if it fails a Dexterity saving throw. For the duration, objects and affected creatures shed dim light in a 10-foot radius.
	Any attack roll against an affected creature or object has advantage if the attacker can see it, and the affected creature or object can&#39;t benefit from being invisible.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 239</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Swarmkeeper)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Greater Invisibility</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You or a creature you touch becomes invisible until the spell ends. Anything the target is wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target&#39;s person.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 246</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Gloom Stalker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Djinni)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Greater Invisibility</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You or a creature you touch becomes invisible until the spell ends. Anything the target is wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target&#39;s person.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 246</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Gloom Stalker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Djinni)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Healing Word</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 250</text>
        <roll>1d4+%0</roll>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Invisibility</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>an eyelash encased in gum arabic</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <text>A creature you touch becomes invisible until the spell ends. Anything the target is wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target&#39;s person. The spell ends for a target that attacks or casts a spell.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 254</text>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Mage Hand</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <text>A spectral, floating hand appears at a point you choose within range. The hand lasts for the duration or until you dismiss it as an action. The hand vanishes if it is ever more than 30 feet away from you or if you cast this spell again.
	You can use your action to control the hand. You can use the hand to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can move the hand up to 30 feet each time you use it.
	The hand can&#39;t attack, activate magical items, or carry more than 10 pounds.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 256</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Swarmkeeper)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Mending</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>two lodestones</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>This spell repairs a single break or tear in an object you touch, such as broken chain link, two halves of a broken key, a torn cloak, or a leaking wineskin. As long as the break or tear is no larger than 1 foot in any dimension, you mend it, leaving no trace of the former damage.
	This spell can physically repair a magic item or construct, but the spell can&#39;t restore magic to such an object.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 259</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Mind Blank</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>24 hours</duration>
        <text>Until the spell ends, one willing creature you touch is immune to psychic damage, any effect that would sense its emotions or read its thoughts, divination spells, and the charmed condition. The spell even foils wish spells and spells or effects of similar power used to affect the target&#39;s mind or to gain information about the target.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 259</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Minor Illusion</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a bit of fleece</materials>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <text>You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration. The illusion also ends if you dismiss it as an action or cast this spell again.
	If you create a sound, its volume can range from a whisper to a scream. It can be your voice, someone else&#39;s voice, a lion&#39;s roar, a beating of drums, or any other sound you choose. The sound continues unabated throughout the duration, or you can make discrete sounds at different times before the spell ends.
	If you create an image of an object, such as a chair, muddy footprints, or a small chest, it must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. The image can&#39;t create sound, light, smell, or any other sensory effect. Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it.
	If a creature uses its action to examine the sound or image, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 260</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Modify Memory</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You attempt to reshape another creature&#39;s memories. One creature that you can see must make a Wisdom saving throw. If you are fighting the creature, it has advantage on the saving throw. On a failed save, the target becomes charmed by you for the duration. The charmed target is incapacitated and unaware of its surroundings, though it can still hear you. If it takes any damage or is targeted by another spell, this spell ends, and none of the target&#39;s m emeries are modified.
	While this charm lasts, you can affect the target&#39;s memory of an event that it experienced within the last 24 hours and that lasted no more than 10 minutes. You can permanently eliminate all memory of the event, allow the target to recall the event with perfect clarity and exacting detail, change its memory of the details of the event, or create a memory of some other event.
	You must speak to the target to describe how its memories are affected, and it must be able to understand your language for the modified memories to take root. Its mind fills in any gaps in the details of your description. If the spell ends before you have finished describing the modified memories, the creature&#39;s memory isn&#39;t altered. Otherwise, the modified memories take hold when the spell ends.
	A modified memory doesn&#39;t necessarily affect how a creature behaves, particularly if the memory contradicts the creature&#39;s natural inclinations, alignment, or beliefs. An illogical modified memory, such as implanting a memory of how much the creature enjoyed dousing itself in acid, is dismissed, perhaps as a bad dream. The DM might deem a modified memory too nonsensical to affect a creature in a significant manner.
	A remove curse or greater restoration spell cast on the target restores the creature&#39;s true memory.

At Higher Levels: If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can alter the target&#39;s memories of an event that took place up to 7 days ago (6th level), 30 days ago (7th level), 1 year ago (8th level), or any time in the creature&#39;s past (9th level).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 261</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Mordenkainen&#39;s Magnificent Mansion</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>300 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a miniature portal carved from ivory, a small piece of polished marble, and a tiny silver spoon, each item worth at least 5 gp</materials>
        <duration>24 hours</duration>
        <text>You conjure an extradimensional dwelling in range that lasts for the duration. You choose where its one entrance is located. The entrance shimmers faintly and is 5 feet wide and 10 feet tall. You and any creature you designate when you cast the spell can enter the extradimensional dwelling as long as the portal remains open. You can open or close the portal if you are within 30 feet of it. While closed, the portal is invisible.
	Beyond the portal is a magnificent foyer with numerous chambers beyond. The atmosphere is clean, fresh, and warm.
	You can create any floor plan you like, but the space can&#39;t exceed 50 cubes, each cube being 10 feet on each side. The place is furnished and decorated as you choose. It contains sufficient food to serve a nine course banquet for up to 100 people. A staff of 100 near-transparent servants attends all who enter. You decide the visual appearance of these servants and their attire. They are completely obedient to your orders. Each servant can perform any task a normal human servant could perform, but they can&#39;t attack or take any action that would directly harm another creature. Thus the servants can fetch things, clean, mend, fold clothes, light fires, serve food, pour wine, and so on. The servants can go anywhere in the mansion but can&#39;t leave it. Furnishings and other objects created by this spell dissipate into smoke if removed from the mansion. When the spell ends, any creatures or objects left inside the extradimensional space are expelled into the open spaces nearest to the entrance.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 261</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Otto&#39;s Irresistible Dance</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>Choose one creature that you can see within range. The target begins a comic dance in place: shuffling, tapping its feet, and capering for the duration. Creatures that can&#39;t be charmed are immune to this spell.
	A dancing creature must use all its movement to dance without leaving its space and has disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws and attack rolls. While the target is affected by this spell, other creatures have advantage on attack rolls against it. As an action, a dancing creature makes a Wisdom saving throw to regain control of itself. On a successful save, the spell ends.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 264</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Polymorph</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a caterpillar cocoon</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <text>This spell transforms a creature that you can see within range into a new form. An unwilling creature must make a Wisdom saving throw to avoid the effect. The spell has no effect on a shapechanger or a creature with 0 hit points.
	The transformation lasts for the duration, or until the target drops to 0 hit points or dies. The new form can be any beast whose challenge rating is equal to or less than the target&#39;s (or the target&#39;s level, if it doesn&#39;t have a challenge rating). The target&#39;s game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen beast. It retains its alignment and personality.
	The target assumes the hit points of its new form. When it reverts to its normal form, the creature returns to the number of hit points it had before it transformed. If it reverts as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to its normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn&#39;t reduce the creature&#39;s normal form to 0 hit points, it isn&#39;t knocked unconscious.
	The creature is limited in the actions it can perform by the nature of its new form, and it can&#39;t speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech.
	The target&#39;s gear melds into the new form. The creature can&#39;t activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of its equipment.
	This spell can&#39;t affect a target that has 0 hit points.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 266</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Power Word Kill</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>9</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You utter a word of power that can compel one creature you can see within range to die instantly. If the creature you chose has 100 hit points or fewer, it dies. Otherwise, the spell has no effect.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 266</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Raise Dead</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 hour</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a diamond worth at least 500 gp, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You return a dead creature you touch to life, provided that it has been dead no longer than 10 days. If the creature&#39;s soul is both willing and at liberty to rejoin the body, the creature returns to life with 1 hit point.
	This spell also neutralizes any poison and cures nonmagical diseases that affected the creature at the time it died. This spell doesn&#39;t, however, remove magical diseases, curses, or similar effects, if these aren&#39;t first removed prior to casting the spell, they take effect when the creature returns to life. The spell can&#39;t return an undead creature to life.
	This spell closes all mortal wounds, but it doesn&#39;t restore missing body parts. If the creature is lacking body parts or organs integral for its survival — its head, for instance — the spell automatically fails.
	Coming back from the dead is an ordeal. The target takes a -4 penalty to all attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks. Every time the target finishes a long rest, the penalty is reduced by 1 until it disappears.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 270</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Seeming</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>8 hours</duration>
        <text>This spell allows you to change the appearance of any number of creatures that you can see within range. You give each target you choose a new, illusory appearance. An unwilling target can make a Charisma saving throw, and if it succeeds, it is unaffected by this spell.
	The spell disguises physical appearances as well as clothing, armor, weapons, and equipment. You can make each creature seem 1 foot shorter or taller and appear thin, fat, or in-between. You can&#39;t change a target&#39;s body type, so you must choose a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs. Otherwise, the extent of the illusion is up to you. The spell lasts for the duration, unless you use your action to dismiss it sooner.
	The changes wrought by this spell fail to hold up to physical inspections. For example, if you use this spell to add a hat to a creature&#39;s outfit objects pass through the hat, and anyone who touches it would feel nothing or would feel the creature&#39;s head and hair. If you use this spell to appear thinner then you are, the hand of someone who reaches out to touch you would bump into you while it was seemingly still in midair.
	A creature can use its action to inspect a target and make an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If it succeeds, it becomes aware that the target is disguised.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 274</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Gloom Stalker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Djinni)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Teleport</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>10 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>This spell instantly transports you and up to eight willing creatures of your choice that you can see within range, or a single object that you can see within range, to a destination you select. If you target an object, it must be able to fit entirely inside a 10-foot cube, and it can&#39;t be held or carried by an unwilling creature. The destination you choose must be known to you, and it must be on the same plane of existence as you. Your familiarity with the destination determines whether you arrive there successfully. The DM rolls d100 and consults the table.
	Familiarity:
	Permanent Circle — On Target 01-100
	Associated object — On Target 01-100
	Very familiar — Mishap 01-05, Similar Area 06-13, Off Target 14-24, On Target 25-100
	Seen casually — Mishap 1-33, Similar Area 34-43, Off Target 44-53, On Target 54-100
	Viewed once — Mishap 01-43, Similar Area 44-53, Off Target 54-73, On Target 74-100
	Description — Mishap 01-43, Similar Area 44-53, Off Target 54-73, On Target 74-100
	False destination — Mishap 01-50, Similar Area 51-100
	Familiarity: "Permanent circle" means a permanent teleportation circle whose sigil sequence you know. "Associated object" means that you possess an object taken from the desired destination within the last six months, such as a book from a wizard&#39;s library, bed linen from a royal suite, or a chunk of marble from a lich&#39;s secret tomb.
	"Very familiar" is a place you have been very often, a place you have carefully studied, or a place you can see when you cast the spell. "Seen casually" is someplace you have seen more than once but with which you aren&#39;t very familiar. "Viewed once" is a place you have seen once, possibly using magic. "Description" is a place whose location and appearance you know through someone else&#39;s description, perhaps from a map. "False destination" is a place that doesn&#39;t exist. Perhaps you tried to scry an enemy&#39;s sanctum but instead viewed an illusion, or you are attempting to teleport to a familiar location that no longer exists.
	On Target: You and your group (or the target object) appear where you want to.
	Off Target: You and your group (or the target object) appear a random distance away from the destination in a random direction. Distance off target is 1d10 x 1d10 percent of the distance that was to be traveled. For example, if you tried to travel 120 miles, landed off target, and rolled a 5 and 3 on the two d 10s, then you would be off target by 15 percent, or 18 miles. The DM determines the direction off target randomly by rolling a d8 and designating 1 as north, 2 as northeast, 3 as east, and so on around the points of the compass. If you were teleporting to a coastal city and wound up 18 miles out at sea, you could be in trouble.
	Similar Area: You and your group (or the target object) wind up in a different area that&#39;s visually or thematically similar to the target area. If you are heading for your home laboratory, for example, you might wind up in another wizard&#39;s laboratory or in an alchemical supply shop that has many of the same tools and implements as your laboratory. Generally, you appear in the closest similar place, but since the spell has no range limit, you could conceivably wind up anywhere on the plane.
	Mishap: The spell&#39;s unpredictable magic results in a difficult journey. Each teleporting creature (or the target object) takes 3d10 force damage, and the DM rerolls on the table to see where you wind up (multiple mishaps can occur, dealing damage each time).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 281</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Teleportation Circle</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>10 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>rare chalks and inks infused with precious gems with 50 gp, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>As you cast the spell, you draw a 10-foot-diameter circle on the ground inscribed with sigils that link your location to a permanent teleportation circle of your choice whose sigil sequence you know and that is on the same plane of existence as you. A shimmering portal opens within the circle you drew and remains open until the end of your next turn. Any creature that enters the portal instantly appears within 5 feet of the destination circle or in the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied.
	Many major temples, guilds, and other important places have permanent teleportation circles inscribed somewhere within their confines. Each such circle includes a unique sigil sequence — a string of magical runes arranged in a particular pattern. When you first gain the ability to cast this spell, you learn the sigil sequences for two destinations on the Material Plane, determined by the DM. You can learn additional sigil sequences during your adventures. You can commit a new sigil sequence to memory after studying it for 1 minute.
	You can create a permanent teleportation circle by casting this spell in the same location every day for one year. You need not use the circle to teleport when you cast the spell in this way.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 282</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Horizon Walker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Tongues</name>
        <school>3</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a small clay model of a ziggurat</materials>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>This spell grants the creature you touch the ability to understand any spoken language it hears. Moreover, when the target speaks, any creature that knows at least one language and can hear the target understands what it says.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 283</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Vicious Mockery</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You unleash a string of insults laced with subtle enchantments at a creature you can see within range. If the target can hear you (thought it need not understand you), it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 1d4 psychic damage and have disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes before the end of its next turn.
	This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4) and 17th level (4d4).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 285</text>
        <roll>1d4</roll>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
      </spell>
    </pc>
    <pc>
      <uid>4172</uid>
      <label>DW Druid</label>
      <name>Human Druid 20</name>
      <abilities>9,20,14,11,20,13,</abilities>
      <hpMax>140</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>140</hpCurrent>
      <hd>20d8</hd>
      <ac>17</ac>
      <armor>Studded Leather Armor</armor>
      <speed>30 ft.</speed>
      <init>5</init>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>3</ability>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>1</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>5</id>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>6</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>9</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>10</id>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>17</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <passive>15</passive>
      <languages>You can speak, read, and write Common and Draconic. Humans typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects. They are fond of sprinkling their speech with words borrowed from other tongues: Orc curses, Elvish musical expressions, Dwarvish military phrases, and so on.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 31</languages>
      <cr>20</cr>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots>
      <slotsCurrent>0,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slotsCurrent>
      <action>
        <name>Scimitar +1</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 6 slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>12</atk>
          <dmg>1d6+6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Scimitar +1</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 1 slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>12</atk>
          <dmg>1d6+1</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <spell>
        <name>Awaken</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>8 hours</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>an agate worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>After spending the casting time tracing magical pathways within a precious gemstone, you touch a huge or smaller beast or plant. The target must have either no Intelligence score or an Intelligence of 3 or less. The target gains an Intelligence of 10. The target also gains the ability to speak one language you know. If the target is a plant, it gains the ability to move its limbs, roots, vines, creepers, and so forth, and it gains senses similar to a human&#39;s. Your DM chooses statistics appropriate for the awakened plant, such as the statistics for the awakened shrub or the awakened tree.
	The awakened beast or plant is charmed by you for 30 days or until you and your companions do anything harmful to it. When the charmed condition ends, the awakened creature chooses whether to remain friendly to you, based on how you treated it while it was charmed.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 216</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Blight</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Necromantic energy washes over a creature of your choice that you can see within range, draining moisture and vitality from it. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. The target takes 8d8 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.
	If you target a plant creature or a magical plant, it makes the saving throw with disadvantage, and the spell deals maximum damage to it.
	If you target a nonmagical plant that isn&#39;t a creature, such as a tree or shrub, it doesn&#39;t make a saving throw, it simply withers and dies.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 219</text>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Call Lightning</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>A storm cloud appears in the shape of a cylinder that is 10 feet tall with a 60-foot radius, centered on a point you can see within range directly above you. The spell fails if you can&#39;t see a point in the air where the storm cloud could appear (for example, if you are in a room that can&#39;t accommodate the cloud).
	When you cast the spell, choose a point you can see under the cloud. A bolt of lightning flashes down from the cloud to that point. Each creature within 5 feet of that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d10 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. On each of your turns until the spell ends, you can use your action to call down lightning in this way again, targeting the same point or a different one.
	If you are outdoors in stormy conditions when you cast this spell, the spell gives you control over the existing storm instead of creating a new one. Under such conditions, the spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d10.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher level, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 3rd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 220</text>
        <roll>3d10</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Contagion</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>7 days</duration>
        <text>Your touch inflicts disease. Make a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach. On a hit, the target is poisoned.
	At the end of each of the poisoned target&#39;s turns, the target must make a Constitution saving throw. If the target succeeds on three of these saves, it is no longer poisoned, and the spell ends. If the target fails three of these saves, the target is no longer poisoned, but choose one of the diseases below. The target is subjected to the chosen disease for the spell&#39;s duration.
	Since this spell induces a natural disease in its target, any effect that removes a disease or otherwise ameliorates a disease&#39;s effects apply to it.
	Blinding Sickness: Pain grips the creature&#39;s mind, and its eyes turn milky white. The creature has disadvantage on Wisdom checks and Wisdom saving throws and is blinded.
	Filth Fever: A raging fever sweeps through the creature&#39;s body. The creature has disadvantage on Strength checks, Strength saving throws, and attack rolls that use Strength.
	Flesh Rot: The creature&#39;s flesh decays. The creature has disadvantage on Charisma checks and vulnerability to all damage.
	Mindfire: The creature&#39;s mind becomes feverish. The creature has disadvantage on Intelligence checks and Intelligence saving throws, and the creature behaves as if under the effects of the confusion spell during combat.
	Seizure: The creature is overcome with shaking. The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity checks, Dexterity saving throws, and attack rolls that use Dexterity.
	Slimy Doom: The creature begins to bleed uncontrollably. The creature has disadvantage on Constitution checks and Constitution saving throws. In addition, whenever the creature takes damage, it is stunned until the end of its next turn.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 227</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Undying)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Control Water</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>300 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a drop of water and a pinch of dust</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>Until the spell ends, you control any freestanding water inside an area you choose that is a cube up to 100 feet on a side. You can choose from any of the following effects when you cast this spell. As an action on your turn, you can repeat the same effect or choose a different one.
	Flood: You cause the water level of all standing water in the area to rise by as much as 20 feet. If the area includes a shore, the flooding water spills over onto dry land. If you choose an area in a large body of water, you instead create a 20-foot tall wave that travels from one side of the area to the other and then crashes down. Any Huge or smaller vehicles in the wave&#39;s path are carried with it to the other side. Any Huge or smaller vehicles struck by the wave have a 25 percent chance of capsizing. The water level remains elevated until the spell ends or you choose a different effect. If this effect produced a wave, the wave repeats on the start of your next turn while the flood effect lasts.
	Part Water: You cause water in the area to move apart and create a trench. The trench extends across the spell&#39;s area, and the separated water forms a wall to either side. The trench remains until the spell ends or you choose a different effect. The water then slowly fills in the trench over the course of the next round until the normal water level is restored.
	Redirect Flow: You cause flowing water in the area to move in a direction you choose, even if the water has to flow over obstacles, up walls, or in other unlikely directions. The water in the area moves as you direct it, but once it moves beyond the spell&#39;s area, it resumes its flow based on the terrain conditions. The water continues to move in the direction you chose until the spell ends or you choose a different effect.
	Whirlpool: This effect requires a body of water at least 50 feet square and 25 feet deep. You cause a whirlpool to form in the center of the area. The whirlpool forms a vortex that is 5 feet wide at the base, up to 50 feet wide at the top, and 25 feet tall. Any creature or object in the water and within 25 feet of the vortex is pulled 10 feet toward it. A creature can swim away from the vortex by making a Strength (Athletics) check against your spell save DC. When a creature enters the vortex for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage and is caught in the vortex until the spell ends. On a successful save, the creature takes half damage, and isn&#39;t caught in the vortex. A creature caught in the vortex can use its action to try to swim away from the vortex as described above, but has disadvantage on the Strength (Athletics) check to do so. The first time each turn that an object enters the vortex, the object takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage, this damage occurs each round it remains in the vortex.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 227</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fathomless)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Marid)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Dispel Magic</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Choose any creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10+the spell&#39;s level. On a successful check, the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell&#39;s level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 234</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer (Clockwork)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Druidcraft</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Whispering to the spirits of nature, you create one of the following effects within range:
	• You create a tiny, harmless sensory effect that predicts what the weather will be at your location for the next 24 hours. The effect might manifest as a golden orb for clear skies, a cloud for rain, falling snowflakes for snow, and so on. This effect persists for 1 round.
	• You instantly make a flower blossom, a seed pod open, or a leaf bud bloom.
	• You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as falling leaves, a puff of wind, the sound of a small animal, or the faint odor of skunk. The effect must fit in a 5-foot cube.
	• You instantly light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 236</text>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Earthquake</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>500 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a pinch of dirt, a piece of rock, and a lump of clay</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You create a seismic disturbance at a point on the ground that you can see within range. For the duration, an intense tremor rips through the ground in a 100-foot- radius circle centered on that point and shakes creatures and structures in contact with the ground in that area.
	The ground in the area becomes difficult terrain. Each creature on the ground that is concentrating must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature&#39;s concentration is broken.
	When you cast this spell and at the end of each turn you spend concentrating on it, each creature on the ground in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is knocked prone.
	This spell can have additional effects depending on the terrain in the area, as determined by the DM.
	Fissures: Fissures open throughout the spell&#39;s area at the start of your next turn after you cast the spell. A total of 1d6 such fissures open in locations chosen by the DM. Each is 1d10 x 10 feet deep, 10 feet wide, and extends from one edge of the spell&#39;s area to the opposite side. A creature standing on a spot where a fissure opens must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or fall in. A creature that successfully saves moves with the fissure&#39;s edge as it opens. A fissure that opens beneath a structure causes it to automatically collapse (see below).
	Structures: The tremor deals 50 bludgeoning damage to any structure in contact with the ground in the area when you cast the spell and at the start of each of your turns until the spell ends. If a structure drops to 0 hit points, it collapses and potentially damages nearby creatures. A creature within half the distance of a structure&#39;s height must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 5d6 bludgeoning damage, is knocked prone, and is buried in the rubble, requiring a DC 20 Strength (Athletics) check as an action to escape. The DM can adjust the DC higher or lower, depending on the nature of the rubble. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and doesn&#39;t fall prone or become buried.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 236</text>
        <roll>5d6</roll>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Faerie Fire</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>Each object in a 20-foot cube within range is outlined in blue, green, or violet light (your choice). Any creature in the area when the spell is cast is also outlined in light if it fails a Dexterity saving throw. For the duration, objects and affected creatures shed dim light in a 10-foot radius.
	Any attack roll against an affected creature or object has advantage if the attacker can see it, and the affected creature or object can&#39;t benefit from being invisible.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 239</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Swarmkeeper)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Feeblemind</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a handful of clay, crystal, glass, or mineral spheres</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You blast the mind of a creature that you can see within range, attempting to shatter its intellect and personality. The target takes 4d6 psychic damage and must make an Intelligence saving throw.
	On a failed save, the creature&#39;s Intelligence and Charisma scores become 1. The creature can&#39;t cast spells, activate magic items, understand language, or communicate in any intelligible way. The creature can, however, identify its friends, follow them, and even protect them.
	At the end of every 30 days, the creature can repeat its saving throw against this spell. If it succeeds on its saving throw, the spell ends.
	The spell can also be ended by greater restoration, heal or wish.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 239</text>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Find the Path</name>
        <school>3</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a set of divinatory tools — such as bones, ivory sticks, cards, teeth, or carved runes — worth 100 gp and an object from the location you wish to find</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 day</duration>
        <text>This spell allows you to find the shortest, most direct physical route to a specific fixed location that you are familiar with on the same plane of existence. If you name a destination on another plan of existence, a destination that moves (such as a mobile fortress), or a destination that isn&#39;t specific (such as a green dragon&#39;s lair), the spell fails.
	For the duration, as long as you are on the same plane of existence as the destination, you know how far it is and in what direction it lies. While you are traveling there, whenever you are presented with a choice of paths along the way, you automatically determine which path is the shortest and most direct route (but not necessarily the safest route) to the destination.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 240</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Flame Blade</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>leaf of sumac</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>You evoke a fiery blade in your free hand. The blade is similar in size and shape to a scimitar, and it lasts for the duration. If you let go of the blade, it disappears, but you can evoke the blade again as a bonus action.
	You can use your action to make a melee spell attack with the fiery blade. On a hit, the target takes 3d6 fire damage.
	The flaming blade sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for every two slot levels above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 242</text>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Fog Cloud</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <text>You create a 20-foot-radius sphere of fog centered on a point within range. The sphere spreads around corners, and its area is heavily obscured, It lasts for the duration or until a wind of moderate or greater speed (at least 10 miles per hour) disperses it.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the radius of the fog increases by 20 feet for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 243</text>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Marid)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Gust of Wind</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (60-foot line)</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a legume seed</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>A line of strong wind 60 feet long and 10 feet wide blasts from you in a direction you choose for the spell&#39;s duration. Each creature that starts its turn in the line must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 15 feet away from you in a direction following the line.
	Any creature in the line must spend 2 feet of movement for every 1 foot it moves when moving closer to you.
	The gust disperses gas or vapor, and it extinguishes candles, torches, and similar unprotected flames in the area. It causes protected flames, such as those of lanterns, to dance wildly and has a 50 percent chance to extinguish them.
	As a bonus action on each of your turns before the spell ends, you can change the direction in which the line blasts from you.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 248</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fathomless)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Djinni)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Heal</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Choose a creature that you can see within range. A surge of positive energy washes through the creature, causing it to regain 70 hit points. The spell also ends blindness, deafness, and any diseases affecting the target. This spell has no effect on constructs or undead.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the amount of healing increases by 10 for each slot level above 6th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 250</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Healing Word</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 250</text>
        <roll>1d4+%0</roll>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Mass Cure Wounds</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A wave of healing energy washes out from a point of your choice within range. Choose up to six creatures in a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on that point. Each target regains hit points equal to 3d8+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 5th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 258</text>
        <roll>3d8+%0</roll>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Mending</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>two lodestones</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>This spell repairs a single break or tear in an object you touch, such as broken chain link, two halves of a broken key, a torn cloak, or a leaking wineskin. As long as the break or tear is no larger than 1 foot in any dimension, you mend it, leaving no trace of the former damage.
	This spell can physically repair a magic item or construct, but the spell can&#39;t restore magic to such an object.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 259</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Moonbeam</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>several seeds of any moonseed plant and a piece of opalescent feldspar</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>A silvery beam of pale light shines down in a 5-foot-radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered on a point within range. Until the spell ends, dim light fills the cylinder.
	When a creature enters the spell&#39;s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it is engulfed in ghostly flames that cause searing pain, and it must make a Constitution saving throw. It takes 2d10 radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	A shapechanger makes its saving throw with disadvantage. If it fails, it also instantly reverts to its original form and can&#39;t assume a different form until it leaves the spell&#39;s light.
	On each of your turns after you cast this spell, you can use an action to move the beam up to 60 feet in any direction.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 261</text>
        <roll>2d10</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Plane Shift</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a forked, metal rod worth at least 250 gp, attuned to a particular plane of existence</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You and up to eight willing creatures who link hands in a circle are transported to a different plane of existence. You can specify a target destination in general terms, such as the City of Brass on the Elemental Plane of Fire or the palace of Dispater on the second level of the Nine Hells, and you appear in or near that destination. If you are trying to reach the City of Brass, for example, you might arrive in its Street of Steel, before its Gate of Ashes, or looking at the city from across the Sea of Fire, at the DM&#39;s discretion.
	Alternatively, if you know the sigil sequence of a teleportation circle on another plane of existence, this spell can take you to that circle. If the teleportation circle is too small to hold all the creatures you transported, they appear in the closest unoccupied spaces next to the circle.
	You can use this spell to banish an unwilling creature to another plane. Choose a creature within your reach and make a melee spell attack against it. On a hit, the creature must make a Charisma saving throw. If the creature fails the save, it is transported to a random location on the plane of existence you specify. A creature so transported must find its own way back to your current plane of existence.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 266</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Produce Flame</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>10 minutes</duration>
        <text>A flickering flame appears in your hand. The flame remains there for the duration and harms neither you nor your equipment. The flame sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. The spell ends if you dismiss it as an action or if you cast it again.
	You can also attack with the flame, although doing so ends the spell. When you cast this spell, or as an action on a later turn, you can hurl the flame at a creature within 30 feet of you. Make a ranged spell attack. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 fire damage.
	This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 269</text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Regenerate</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a prayer wheel and holy water</materials>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>You touch a creature and stimulate its natural healing ability. The target regains 4d8+15 hit points. For the duration of the spell, the target regains 1 hit point at the start of each of its turns (10 hit points each minute).
	The target&#39;s severed body members (fingers, legs, tails, and so on), if any, are restored after 2 minutes. If you have the severed part and hold it to the stump, the spell instantaneously causes the limb to knit to the stump.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 271</text>
        <roll>4d8+15</roll>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Reverse Gravity</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>100 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a lodestone and iron filings</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>This spell reverses gravity in a 50-foot-radius, 100-foot high cylinder centered on a point within range. All creatures and objects that aren&#39;t somehow anchored to the ground in the area fall upward and reach the top of the area when you cast this spell. A creature can make a Dexterity saving throw to grab onto a fixed object it can reach, thus avoiding the fall.
	If some solid object (such as a ceiling) is encountered in this fall, falling objects and creatures strike it just as they would during a normal downward fall. If an object or creature reaches the top of the area without striking anything, it remains there, oscillating slightly, for the duration.
	At the end of the duration, affected objects and creatures fall back down.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 272</text>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Speak with Plants</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (30-foot radius)</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>10 minutes</duration>
        <text>You imbue plants within 30 feet of you with limited sentience and animation, giving them the ability to communicate with you and follow your simple commands. You can question plants about events in the spell&#39;s area within the past day, gaining information about creatures that have passed, weather, and other circumstances.
	You can also turn difficult terrain caused by plant growth (such as thickets and undergrowth) into ordinary terrain that lasts for the duration. Or you can turn ordinary terrain where plants are present into difficult terrain that lasts for the duration, causing vines and branches to hinder pursuers, for example.
	Plants might be able to perform other tasks on your behalf, at the DM&#39;s discretion. The spell doesn&#39;t enable plants to uproot themselves and move about, but they can freely move branches, tendrils, and stalks.
	If a plant creature is in the area, you can communicate with it as if you shard a common language, but you gain no magical ability to influence it.
	This spell can cause the plants created by the entangle spell to release a restrained creature.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 277</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Storm of Vengeance</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>9</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Sight</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>A churning storm cloud forms, centered on a point you can see and spreading to a radius of 360 feet. Lightning flashes in the area, thunder booms, and strong winds roar. Each creature under the cloud (no more than 5,000 feet beneath the cloud) when it appears must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 thunder damage and becomes deafened for 5 minutes.
	Each round you maintain concentration on this spell, the storm produces different effects on your turn.
	Round 2: Acidic rain falls from the cloud. Each creature and object under the cloud takes 1d6 acid damage.
	Round 3: You call six bolts of lightning from the cloud to strike six creatures or objects of your choice beneath the cloud. A given creature or object can&#39;t be struck by more than one bolt. A struck creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 10d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	Round 4: Hailstones rain down from the cloud. Each creature under the cloud takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage.
	Round 5-10: Gusts and freezing rain assail the area under the cloud. the area becomes difficult terrain and is heavily obscured. Each creature there takes 1d6 cold damage. Ranged weapon attacks in the area are impossible. The wind and rain count as a severe distraction for the purposes of maintaining concentration on spells. Finally, gusts of strong wind (ranging from 20 to 50 miles per hour) automatically disperse fog, mists, and similar phenomena in the area whether mundane or magical.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 279</text>
        <roll>1d6</roll>
        <roll>10d6</roll>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Sunbeam</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (60-foot line)</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a magnifying glass</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>A beam of brilliant light flashes out from your hand in a 5-foot-wide, 60-foot-line. Each creature in the line must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 6d8 radiant damage and is blinded until your next turn. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage and isn&#39;t blinded by this spell. Undead and oozes have disadvantage on this saving throw.
	You can create a new line of radiance as your action on any turn until the spell ends.
	For the duration, a mote of brilliant radiance shines in your hand. It sheds bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. The light is sunlight.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 279</text>
        <roll>6d8</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Thorn Whip</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>the stem of a plant with thorns</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You create a long, vine-like whip covered in thorns that lashes out at your command toward a creature in range. Make a melee spell attack against the target. If the attack hits, the creature takes 1d6 piercing damage, and if the creature is Large or smaller, you pull the creature up to 10 feet closer to you.
	This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 282</text>
        <roll>1d6</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Thunderwave</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot cube)</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A wave of thunderous force sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 thunder damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn&#39;t pushed.
	In addition, unsecured objects that are completely within the area of effect are automatically pushed 10 feet away from you by the spell&#39;s effect, and the spell emits a thunderous boom audible out to 300 feet.

At Higher Levels:
	When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 282</text>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fathomless)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Djinni)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>True Resurrection</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>9</level>
        <time>1 hour</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a sprinkle of holy water and diamonds worth at least 25,000 gp, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You touch a creature that has been dead for no longer than 200 years and that died for any reason except old age. If the creature&#39;s soul is free and willing, the creature is restored to life with all its hit points.
	This spell closes all wounds, neutralizes any poison, cures all diseases, and lifts any curses affecting the creature when it died. The spell replaces damaged or missing organs and limbs. If the creature was undead, it is restored to its non-undead form.
	The spell can even provide a new body if the original no longer exists, in which case you must speak the creature&#39;s name. The creature then appears in an unoccupied space you choose within 10 feet of you.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 284</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Wind Walk</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>fire and holy water</materials>
        <duration>8 hours</duration>
        <text>You and up to ten willing creatures you can see within range assume a gaseous form for the duration, appearing as wisps of cloud. While in this cloud form, a creature has a flying speed of 300 feet and has resistance to damage from nonmagical weapons. The only actions a creature can take in this form are the Dash action or to revert to its normal form. Reverting takes 1 minute, during which time a creature is incapacitated and can&#39;t move. Until the spell ends, a creature can revert to cloud form, which also requires the 1-minute transformation.
	If a creature is in cloud form and flying when the effect ends, the creature descends 60 feet per round for 1 minute until it lands, which it does safely. If it can&#39;t land after 1 minute, the creature falls the remaining distance.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 288</text>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
    </pc>
    <pc>
      <uid>4173</uid>
      <label>DW Fighter</label>
      <name>Elf, High Fighter 20</name>
      <abilities>10,20,19,20,12,8,</abilities>
      <hpMax>158</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>158</hpCurrent>
      <hd>20d10</hd>
      <ac>22</ac>
      <armor>Studded Leather Armor +2</armor>
      <speed>30 ft.</speed>
      <init>5</init>
      <savingThrow>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>2</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>3</id>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>5</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>6</id>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </skill>
      <passive>17</passive>
      <languages>You can speak, read, and write Common, Dwarvish, Draconic, Elvish, and Halfling. 

Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 24</languages>
      <cr>20</cr>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <slotsCurrent>0,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
      <action>
        <name>Silvered Rapier +1</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d8 + 8 piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>12</atk>
          <dmg>1d8+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Dart</name>
        <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 1d4 + 5 piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>11</atk>
          <dmg>1d4+5</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Dagger</name>
        <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 1d4 + 7 piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>11</atk>
          <dmg>1d4+7</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <spell>
        <name>Banishment</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>an item distasteful to the target</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You attempt to send one creature that you can see within range to another plane of existence. The target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be banished.
	If the target is native to the plane of existence you&#39;re on, you banish the target to a harmless demiplane. While there, the target is incapacitated. The target remains there until the spell ends, at which point the target reappears in the space it left or in the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied.
	If the target is native to a different plane of existence that the one you&#39;re on, the target is banished with a faint popping noise, returning to its home plane. If the spell ends before 1 minute has passed, the target reappears in the space it left or in the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied. Otherwise, the target doesn&#39;t return.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 4th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 217</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Horizon Walker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Monster Slayer)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Blade Ward</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>You extend your hand and trace a sigil of warding in the air. Until the end of your next turn, you have resistance against bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage dealt by weapon attacks.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 218</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Blight</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Necromantic energy washes over a creature of your choice that you can see within range, draining moisture and vitality from it. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. The target takes 8d8 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.
	If you target a plant creature or a magical plant, it makes the saving throw with disadvantage, and the spell deals maximum damage to it.
	If you target a nonmagical plant that isn&#39;t a creature, such as a tree or shrub, it doesn&#39;t make a saving throw, it simply withers and dies.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 219</text>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Blur</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>Your body becomes blurred, shifting and wavering to all who can see you. For the duration, any creature has disadvantage on attack rolls against you. An attacker is immune to this effect if it doesn&#39;t rely on sight, as with blindsight, or can see through illusions, as with truesight.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 219</text>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Hexblade)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Marid)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Counterspell</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 reaction, which you take when you see a creature within 60 feet of you casting a spell</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You attempt to interrupt a creature in the process of casting a spell. If the creature is casting a spell of or lower, its spell fails and has no effect. If it is casting a spell of or higher, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell&#39;s level. On a success, the creature&#39;s spell fails and has no effect.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the interrupted spell has no effect if its level is less than or equal to the level of the spell slot you used.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 228</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Enlarge/Reduce</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a pinch of powdered iron</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You cause a creature or an object you can see within range to grow larger or smaller for the duration. Choose either a creature or an object that is neither worn nor carried. If the target is unwilling, it can make a Constitution saving throw. On a success, the spell has no effect.
	If the target is a creature, everything it is wearing and carrying changes size with it. Any item dropped by an affected creature returns to normal size at once.
	Enlarge: The target&#39;s size doubles in all dimensions, and its weight is multiplied by eight. This growth increases its size by one category — from Medium to Large, for example. If there isn&#39;t enough room for the target to double its size, the creature or object attains the maximum possible size in the space available. Until the spell ends, the target also has advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws. The target&#39;s weapons also grow to match its new size. While these weapons are enlarged, the target&#39;s attack with them deal 1d4 extra damage.
	Reduce: The target&#39;s size is halved in all dimensions, and its weight is reduced to one-eighth of normal. This reduction decreases its size by one category — from Medium to Small, for example. Until the spell ends, the target also has disadvantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws. The target&#39;s weapons also shrink to match its new size. While these weapons are reduced, the target&#39;s attacks with them deal 1d4 less damage (this can&#39;t reduce the damage below 1).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 237</text>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Fire Bolt</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You hurl a mote of fire at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 fire damage. A flammable object hit by this spell ignites if it isn&#39;t being worn or carried.
	This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 242</text>
        <roll>1d10</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Fireball</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a tiny ball of bat guano and sulfur</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A bright streak flashes from your pointing finger to a point you choose within range then blossoms with a low roar into an explosion of flame. Each creature in a 20-foot radius must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren&#39;t being worn or carried.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 241</text>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Efreeti)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Haste</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a shaving of licorice root</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>Choose a willing creature that you can see within range. Until the spell ends, the target&#39;s speed is doubled, it gains a +2 bonus to AC, it has advantage on Dexterity saving throws, and it gains an additional action on each of its turns. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.
	When the spell ends, the target can&#39;t move or take actions until after its next turn, as a wave of lethargy sweeps over it.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 250</text>
        <sclass>Ranger (Horizon Walker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Invisibility</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>an eyelash encased in gum arabic</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <text>A creature you touch becomes invisible until the spell ends. Anything the target is wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target&#39;s person. The spell ends for a target that attacks or casts a spell.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 254</text>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Magic Missile</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You create three glowing darts of magical force. Each dart hits a creature of your choice that you can see within range. A dart deals 1d4+1 force damage to its target. The darts all strike simultaneously and you can direct them to hit one creature or several.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell creates one more dart for each slot above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 257</text>
        <roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Misty Step</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Briefly surrounded by silvery mist, you teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 260</text>
        <sclass>Ranger (Horizon Walker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Shield</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack or targeted by the magic missile spell</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 275</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Hexblade)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Shocking Grasp</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Lightning springs from your hand to deliver a shock to a creature you try to touch. Make a melee spell attack against the target. You have advantage on the attack roll if the target is wearing armor made of metal. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 lightning damage, and it can&#39;t take reactions until the start of its next turn.
	The spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 275</text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Suggestion</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a snake&#39;s tongue and either a bit of honeycomb or a drop of sweet oil</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 8 hours</duration>
        <text>You suggest a course of activity (limited to a sentence or two) and magically influence a creature you can see within range that can hear and understand you. Creatures that can&#39;t be charmed are immune to this effect. The suggestion must be worded in such a manner as to make the course of action sound reasonable. Asking the creature to stab itself, throw itself onto a spear, immolate itself, or do some other obviously harmful act ends the spell.
	The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it pursues the course of action you described to the best of its ability. The suggested course of action can continue for the entire duration. If the suggested activity can be completed in a shorter time, the spell ends when the subject finishes what it was asked to do.
	You can also specify conditions that will trigger a special activity during the duration. For example, you might suggest that a knight five her warhorse to the first beggar she meets. If the condition isn&#39;t met before the spell expires, the activity isn&#39;t preformed.
	If you or any of your companions damage the target, the spell ends.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 279</text>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Thunderwave</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot cube)</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A wave of thunderous force sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 thunder damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn&#39;t pushed.
	In addition, unsecured objects that are completely within the area of effect are automatically pushed 10 feet away from you by the spell&#39;s effect, and the spell emits a thunderous boom audible out to 300 feet.

At Higher Levels:
	When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 282</text>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fathomless)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Djinni)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>True Strike</name>
        <school>3</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 round</duration>
        <text>You extend your hand and point a finger at a target in range. Your magic grants you a brief insight into the target&#39;s defenses. On your next turn, you gain advantage on your first attack roll against the target, provided that this spell hasn&#39;t ended.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 284</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
    </pc>
    <pc>
      <uid>4174</uid>
      <label>DW Cleric</label>
      <name>Dwarf, Hill Cleric 20</name>
      <abilities>18,8,17,10,20,12,</abilities>
      <hpMax>172</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>172</hpCurrent>
      <hd>20d8</hd>
      <ac>19</ac>
      <armor>Chain Mail +1</armor>
      <speed>25 ft.</speed>
      <init>-1</init>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>6</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>9</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>13</id>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>14</id>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </skill>
      <passive>15</passive>
      <languages>You can speak, read, and write Common, Giant, and Dwarvish. Dwarvish is full of hard consonants and guttural sounds, and those characteristics spill over into whatever other language a dwarf might speak.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 20</languages>
      <cr>20</cr>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots>
      <slotsCurrent>0,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slotsCurrent>
      <action>
        <name>Warhammer +2</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d8 + 6 bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>12</atk>
          <dmg>1d8+6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Handaxe</name>
        <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 4 slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>10</atk>
          <dmg>1d6+4</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Handaxe</name>
        <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 4 slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>10</atk>
          <dmg>1d6+4</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Devine Strike </name>
        <text>Attack: +0 to hit. Hit: 2d8 damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Attack</name>
          <dmg>2d8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <spell>
        <name>Banishment</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>an item distasteful to the target</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You attempt to send one creature that you can see within range to another plane of existence. The target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be banished.
	If the target is native to the plane of existence you&#39;re on, you banish the target to a harmless demiplane. While there, the target is incapacitated. The target remains there until the spell ends, at which point the target reappears in the space it left or in the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied.
	If the target is native to a different plane of existence that the one you&#39;re on, the target is banished with a faint popping noise, returning to its home plane. If the spell ends before 1 minute has passed, the target reappears in the space it left or in the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied. Otherwise, the target doesn&#39;t return.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 4th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 217</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Horizon Walker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Monster Slayer)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Calm Emotions</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You attempt to suppress strong emotions in a group of people. Each humanoid in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range must make a Charisma saving throw a creature can choose to fail this saving throw if it wishes. If a creature fails its saving throw, choose one of the following two effects.
	You can suppress any effect causing a target to be charmed or frightened. When this spell ends, any suppressed effect resumes, provided that its duration has not expired in the meantime.
	Alternatively, you can make a target indifferent about creatures of your choice that it is hostile toward. This indifference ends if the target is attacked or harmed by a spell or if it witnesses any of its friends being harmed. When the spell ends, the creature becomes hostile again, unless the DM rules otherwise.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 221</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer (Aberrant)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Control Weather</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>10 minutes</time>
        <range>Self (5-mile radius)</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>burning incense and bits of earth and wood mixed in water</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 8 hours</duration>
        <text>You take control of the weather within 5 miles of you for the duration. You must be outdoors to cast this spell. Moving to a place where you don&#39;t have a clear path to the sky ends the spell early.
	When you cast the spell, you change the current weather conditions, which are determined by the DM based on the climate and season. You can change precipitation, temperature, and wind. It takes 1d4 x 10 minutes for the new conditions to take effect. Once they do so, you can change the conditions again. When the spell ends, the weather gradually returns to normal.
	When you change the weather conditions, find a current condition on the following tables and change its stage by one, up or down. When changing the wind, you can change its direction.

Precipitation:
	Stage 1 — Clear
	Stage 2 — Light clouds
	Stage 3 — Overcast or ground fog
	Stage 4 — Rain, hail or snow
	Stage 5 — Torrential rain, driving hail or blizzard

Temperature:
	Stage 1 — Unbearable heat
	Stage 2 — Hot
	Stage 3 — Warm
	Stage 4 — Cool
	Stage 5 — Cold
	Stage 6 — Arctic cold

Wind:
	Stage 1 — Calm
	Stage 2 — Moderate wind
	Stage 3 — Strong wind
	Stage 4 — Gale
	Stage 5 — Storm

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 228</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Detect Evil and Good</name>
        <school>3</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>For the duration, you know if there is an aberration, celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead within 30 feet of you, as well as where the creature is located. Similarly, you know if there is a place or object within 30 feet of you that has been magically consecrated or desecrated. The spell can penetrate most barriers, but it is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 231</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Dao)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Djinni)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Efreeti)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Marid)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Detect Magic</name>
        <school>3</school>
        <ritual>1</ritual>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.
	The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 231</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Detect Poison and Disease</name>
        <school>3</school>
        <ritual>1</ritual>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a yew leaf</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>For the duration, you can sense the presence and location of poisons, poisonous creatures, and diseases within 30 feet of you. You also identify the kind of poison, poisonous creature, or disease in each case.
	The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 231</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Dispel Magic</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Choose any creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10+the spell&#39;s level. On a successful check, the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell&#39;s level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 234</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer (Clockwork)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Geas</name>
        <school>4</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>30 days</duration>
        <text>You place a magical command on a creature that you can see within range, forcing it to carry out some service or refrain from some action or course of activity as you decide. If the creature can understand you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become charmed by you for the duration. While the creature is charmed by you, it takes 5d10 psychic damage each time it acts in a manner directly counter to your instructions, but no more than once each day. A creature that can&#39;t understand you is unaffected by the spell.
	You can issue any command you choose, short of an activity that would result in certain death. Should you issue a suicidal command, the spell ends.
	You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it. A remove curse, greater restoration, or wish spell also ends it.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th or 8th level, the duration is 1 year. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of the spell lasts until it is ended by one of the spells mentioned above.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 244</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Guiding Bolt</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>A flash of light streaks toward a creature of your choice within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 4d6 radiant damage, and the next attack roll made against this target before the end of your next turn has advantage, thanks to the mystical dim light glittering on the target until then.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 248</text>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Celestial)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Hallow</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>24 hours</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>herbs, oils, and incense worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>Until dispelled</duration>
        <text>You touch a point and infuse an area around it with holy (or unholy) power. The area can have a radius up to 60 feet, and the spell fails if the radius includes an area already under the effect a hallow spell. The affected area is subject to the following effects.
	First, celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead can&#39;t enter the area, nor can such creatures charm, frighten, or possess creatures within it. Any creature charmed, frightened, or possessed by such a creature is no longer charmed, frightened, or possessed upon entering the area. You can exclude one or more of those types of creatures from this effect.
	Second, you can bind an extra effect to the area. Choose the effect from the following list, or choose an effect offered by the DM. Some of these effects apply to creatures in the area, you can designate whether the effect applies to all creatures, creatures that follow a specific deity or leader, or creatures of a specific sort, such as ores or trolls. When a creature that would be affected enters the spell&#39;s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it can make a Charisma saving throw. On a success, the creature ignores the extra effect until it leaves the area.
	Courage: Affected creatures can&#39;t be frightened while in the area.
	Darkness: Darkness fills the area. Normal light, as well as magical light created by spells of a lower level than the slot you used to cast this spell, can&#39;t illuminate the area.
	Daylight: Bright light fills the area. Magical darkness created by spells of a lower level than the slot you used to cast this spell can&#39;t extinguish the light.
	Energy Protection:. Affected creatures in the area have resistance to one damage type of your choice, except for bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing.
	Energy Vulnerability: Affected creatures in the area have vulnerability to one damage type of your choice, except for bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing.
	Everlasting Rest: Dead bodies interred in the area can&#39;t be turned into undead.
	Extradimensional Interference: Affected creatures can&#39;t move or travel using teleportation or by extradimensional or interplanar means.
	Fear: Affected creatures are frightened while in the area.
	Silence: No sound can emanate from within the area, and no sound can reach into it.
	Tongues: Affected creatures can communicate with any other creature in the area, even if they don&#39;t share a common language.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 249</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Harm</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You unleash a virulent disease on a creature that you can see within range. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 14d6 necrotic damage, or half as much damage on a successful save. The damage can&#39;t reduce the target&#39;s hit points below 1. If the target fails the saving throw, its hit point maximum is reduced for 1 hour by an amount equal to the necrotic damage it took. Any effect that removes a disease allows a creature&#39;s hit point maximum to return to normal before that time passes.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 249</text>
        <roll>14d6</roll>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Heal</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Choose a creature that you can see within range. A surge of positive energy washes through the creature, causing it to regain 70 hit points. The spell also ends blindness, deafness, and any diseases affecting the target. This spell has no effect on constructs or undead.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the amount of healing increases by 10 for each slot level above 6th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 250</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Healing Word</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 250</text>
        <roll>1d4+%0</roll>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Heroes&#39; Feast</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>10 minutes</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a gem-encrusted bowl worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You bring forth a great feast, including magnificent food and drink. The feast takes 1 hour to consume and disappears at the end of that time, and the beneficial effects don&#39;t set in until this hour is over. Up to twelve creatures can partake of the feast.
	A creature that partakes of the feast gains several benefits. The creature is cured of all diseases and poison, becomes immune to poison and being frightened, and makes all Wisdom saving throws with advantage. Its hit point maximum also increases by 2d10, and it gains the same number of hit points. These benefits last for 24 hours.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 250</text>
        <roll>2d10</roll>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Holy Aura</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a tiny reliquary worth at least 1,000 gp containing a sacred relic, such as a scrap of cloth from a saint&#39;s robe or a piece of parchment from a religious text</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>Divine light washes out from you and coalesces in a soft radiance in a 30-foot radius around you. Creatures of your choice in that radius when you cast this spell shed dim light in a 5-foot radius and have advantage on all saving throws, and other creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls against them until the spell ends. In addition, when a fiend or an undead hits an affected creature with a melee attack, the aura flashes with brilliant light. The attacker must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the spell ends.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 251</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Mass Heal</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>9</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A flood of healing energy flows from you into injured creatures around you. You restore up to 700 hit points, divided as you choose among any number of creatures that you can see within range. Creatures healed by this spell are also cured of all diseases and any effect making them blinded or deafened. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 258</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Mending</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>two lodestones</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>This spell repairs a single break or tear in an object you touch, such as broken chain link, two halves of a broken key, a torn cloak, or a leaking wineskin. As long as the break or tear is no larger than 1 foot in any dimension, you mend it, leaving no trace of the former damage.
	This spell can physically repair a magic item or construct, but the spell can&#39;t restore magic to such an object.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 259</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Prayer of Healing</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>10 minutes</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Up to six creatures of your choice that you can see within range each regain hit points equal to 2d8+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 267</text>
        <roll>2d8+%0</roll>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Protection from Evil and Good</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>holy water or powdered silver and iron, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>Until the spell ends, one willing creature you touch is protected against certain types of creatures: aberrations, celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead.
	The protection grants several benefits. Creatures of those types have disadvantage on attack rolls against the target. The target also can&#39;t be charmed, frightened, or possessed by them. If the target is already charmed, frightened, or possessed by such a creature, the target has advantage on any new saving throw against the relevant effect.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 270</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Horizon Walker)</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Monster Slayer)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer (Clockwork)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Regenerate</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a prayer wheel and holy water</materials>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>You touch a creature and stimulate its natural healing ability. The target regains 4d8+15 hit points. For the duration of the spell, the target regains 1 hit point at the start of each of its turns (10 hit points each minute).
	The target&#39;s severed body members (fingers, legs, tails, and so on), if any, are restored after 2 minutes. If you have the severed part and hold it to the stump, the spell instantaneously causes the limb to knit to the stump.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 271</text>
        <roll>4d8+15</roll>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Resistance</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a miniature cloak</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You touch one willing creature. Once before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to one saving throw of its choice. It can roll the die before or after the saving throw. The spell then ends.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 272</text>
        <roll>1d4</roll>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Resurrection</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 hour</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a diamond worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You touch a dead creature that has been dead for no more than a century, that didn&#39;t die of old age, and that isn&#39;t undead. If its soul is free and willing, the target returns to life with all its hit points.
	This spell neutralizes any poisons and cures normal diseases afflicting the creature when it died. It doesn&#39;t, however, remove magical diseases, curses, and the like, if such affects aren&#39;t removed prior to casting the spell, they afflict the target on its return to life.
	This spell closes all mortal wounds and restores any missing body parts.
	Coming back from the dead is an ordeal. The target takes a -4 penalty to all attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks. Every time the target finishes a long rest, the penalty is reduced by 1 until it disappears.
	Casting this spell to restore life to a creature that has been dead for one year or longer taxes you greatly. Until you finish a long rest, you can&#39;t cast spells again, and you have disadvantage on all attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 272</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Sacred Flame</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Flame-like radiance descends on a creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d8 radiant damage. The target gains no benefit from cover for this saving throw.
	The spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 272</text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Spare the Dying</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You touch a living creature that has 0 hit points. The creature becomes stable. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 277</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Speak with Dead</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>10 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>burning incense</materials>
        <duration>10 minutes</duration>
        <text>You grant the semblance of life and intelligence to a corpse of your choice within range, allowing it to answer the questions you pose. The corpse must still have a mouth and can&#39;t be undead. The spell fails if the corpse was the target of this spell within the last 10 days.
	Until the spell ends, you can ask the corpse up to five questions. The corpse knows only what it knew in life, including the languages it knew. Answers are usually brief, cryptic, or repetitive, and the corpse is under no compulsion to offer a truthful answer if you are hostile to it or it recognizes you as an enemy. This spell doesn&#39;t return the creature&#39;s soul to its body, only its animating spirit. Thus, the corpse can&#39;t learn new information, doesn&#39;t comprehend anything that has happened since it died, and can&#39;t speculate about future events.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 277</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Undying)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Thaumaturgy</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You manifest a minor wonder, a sign of supernatural power, within range. You create one of the following magical effects within range:
	• Your voice booms up to three times as loud as normal for 1 minute.
	• You cause flames to flicker, brighten, dim, or change color for 1 minute.
	• You cause harmless tremors in the ground for 1 minute.
	• You create an instantaneous sound that originates from a point of your choice within range, such as a rumble of thunder, the cry of a raven, or ominous whispers.
	• You instantaneously cause an unlocked door or window to fly open or slam shut.
	• You alter the appearance of your eyes for 1 minute.
	If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its 1-minute effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 282</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>True Resurrection</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <level>9</level>
        <time>1 hour</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a sprinkle of holy water and diamonds worth at least 25,000 gp, which the spell consumes</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You touch a creature that has been dead for no longer than 200 years and that died for any reason except old age. If the creature&#39;s soul is free and willing, the creature is restored to life with all its hit points.
	This spell closes all wounds, neutralizes any poison, cures all diseases, and lifts any curses affecting the creature when it died. The spell replaces damaged or missing organs and limbs. If the creature was undead, it is restored to its non-undead form.
	The spell can even provide a new body if the original no longer exists, in which case you must speak the creature&#39;s name. The creature then appears in an unoccupied space you choose within 10 feet of you.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 284</text>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
      </spell>
    </pc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4155</uid>
      <label>CARLOS ALVES SOUSA</label>
      <name>Commoner</name>
      <type>human</type>
      <alignment>Lawful Good</alignment>
      <abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
      <hpMax>4</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>4</hpCurrent>
      <hd>1d8</hd>
      <speed>30 ft.</speed>
      <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
      <cr>-3</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 345, Lost Laboratory of Kwalish p. 38, Dragon of Icespire Peak p. 55</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Club</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>2</atk>
          <dmg>1d4</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <text>Older brother to Rodrigo, Carlos is a farmer with little to his name. Believing his brother to be dead, the usually good-natured Carlos has lost his joyful nature.

Now depressed and unsure of how to move forward, Carlos is considering selling his farm and moving elsewhere, hoping for a fresh start.</text>
      <environment>1087</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4156</uid>
      <label>RODRIGO ALVES SOUSA</label>
      <name>Commoner</name>
      <type>human</type>
      <alignment>Lawful Good</alignment>
      <abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
      <hpMax>4</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>4</hpCurrent>
      <hd>1d8</hd>
      <speed>30 ft.</speed>
      <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
      <cr>-3</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 345, Lost Laboratory of Kwalish p. 38, Dragon of Icespire Peak p. 55</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Club</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>2</atk>
          <dmg>1d4</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <text>A stubborn man who just wants to help his older brother out, Rodrigo can be a bit overconfident and arrogant at times. 

Despite this, he can still be fun to be around, usually only getting himself into trouble... usually.</text>
      <environment>1087</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4157</uid>
      <label>MARCOS RAVENWING</label>
      <name>Commoner</name>
      <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
      <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
      <abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
      <hpMax>4</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>4</hpCurrent>
      <hd>1d8</hd>
      <speed>30 ft.</speed>
      <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
      <cr>-3</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 345, Lost Laboratory of Kwalish p. 38, Dragon of Icespire Peak p. 55</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Club</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>2</atk>
          <dmg>1d4</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <text>Owner of the Raven’s Nest, Marcos is a generous and kind man who truly listens to his customers and their problems. 

Often offering sagely advice, he is well-respected throughout the town for his wisdom.</text>
      <environment>1087</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4158</uid>
      <label>MATEO MANTIS</label>
      <name>Commoner</name>
      <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
      <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
      <abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
      <hpMax>4</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>4</hpCurrent>
      <hd>1d8</hd>
      <speed>30 ft.</speed>
      <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
      <cr>-3</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 345, Lost Laboratory of Kwalish p. 38, Dragon of Icespire Peak p. 55</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Club</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <atk>2</atk>
          <dmg>1d4</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <text>The somewhat awkward owner of a local shop (Mateo’s Mercantile), Mateo is a bit odd. Wheezing and speaking in the third person, he’s probably harmless, but has a habit of staring off into space.</text>
      <environment>1087</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4159</uid>
      <label>Nightscale</label>
      <name>Ancient Black Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
      <abilities>27,14,25,16,15,19,</abilities>
      <hpMax>367</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>367</hpCurrent>
      <hd>21d20+147</hd>
      <ac>22</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., fly 80 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>9</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>14</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>9</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>16</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>9</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>acid</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>26</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>21</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 87</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Amphibious</name>
        <text>The dragon can breathe air and water.</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack:+ 15 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d10+8) piercing damage plus 9 (2d8) acid damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>15</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+8+2d8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d6+8) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>15</atk>
          <dmg>2d6+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d8+8) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>15</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 19 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Acid Breath (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon exhales acid in a 90-foot line that is 10 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 22 Dexterity saving throw, taking 67 (15d8) acid damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 23 Dexterity saving throw or take 15 (2d6+8) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>A bit maddened in his growing age, the Black Dragon finds himself having laughing fits at inappropriate times, such as during battle or after being injured.</text>
      <environment>128</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4161</uid>
      <label>Skybolt</label>
      <name>Ancient Blue Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
      <abilities>29,10,27,18,17,21,</abilities>
      <hpMax>481</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>481</hpCurrent>
      <hd>26d20+208</hd>
      <ac>22</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., burrow 40 ft., fly 80 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>15</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>12</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>17</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>lightning</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>27</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>23</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 90</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +16 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 20 (2d10+9) piercing damage plus 11 (2d10) lightning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>16</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+9+2d10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +16 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 16 (2d6+9) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>16</atk>
          <dmg>2d6+9</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +16 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 18 (2d8+9) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>16</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+9</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 20 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Lightning Breath (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon exhales lightning in a 120-foot line that is 10 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 23 Dexterity saving throw, taking 88 (16d10) lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Lightning Breath</name>
          <dmg>16d10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 24 Dexterity saving throw or take 16 (2d6+9) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>Focused and sick of feeling trapped by this cursed prison, the Blue Dragon will carefully stare down his prey before attacking. If he’s been watching you this round, you’re next.</text>
      <environment>6</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4162</uid>
      <label>Venomscythe</label>
      <name>Ancient Green Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
      <abilities>27,12,25,20,17,19,</abilities>
      <hpMax>385</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>385</hpCurrent>
      <hd>22d20+154</hd>
      <ac>21</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., fly 80 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>14</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>4</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>6</id>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>17</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>13</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>poison</immune>
      <conditionImmune>poisoned</conditionImmune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>27</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>22</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 93</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Amphibious</name>
        <text>The dragon can breathe air and water.</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d10+8) piercing damage plus 10 (3d6) poison damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>15</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+9+3d6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 22 (4d6+8) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>15</atk>
          <dmg>4d6+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d8+8) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>16</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 19 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Poison Breath (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon exhales poisonous gas in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 22 Constitution saving throw, taking 77 (22d6) poison damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Poison Breath</name>
          <dmg>22d6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 23 Dexterity saving throw or take 15 (2d6+8) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>Bitter and cunning, the Green Dragon is confident in their ability to escape any world-ending monster which might be released
from this prison. However, that doesn’t mean they want it to happen. They simply consider
themselves to be a survivor, against all odds.</text>
      <environment>8</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4163</uid>
      <label>Brimsongon</label>
      <name>Ancient Red Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
      <abilities>30,10,29,18,15,23,</abilities>
      <hpMax>546</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>546</hpCurrent>
      <hd>28d20+252</hd>
      <ac>22</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., climb 40 ft., fly 80 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>16</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>9</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>13</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>16</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>fire</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>26</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>24</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 97</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (2d10+10) piercing damage plus 14 (4d6) fire damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+10+4d6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d6+10) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d6+10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d8+10) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 21 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Fire Breath (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon exhales fire in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 24 Dexterity saving throw, taking 91 (26d6) fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Fire Breath</name>
          <dmg>26d6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 25 Dexterity saving throw or take 17 (2d6+10) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>Perhaps the eldest of the dragons present, the Red Dragon once had big plans, long ago. Now she instead diverts all of her energy into fighting for her life, trying to escape the curse. 

You’ll want to keep an eye on her - she’ll likely do something unexpectedly brutal if you’re not careful.</text>
      <environment>96</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4164</uid>
      <label>Iceblade</label>
      <name>Ancient White Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
      <abilities>26,10,26,10,13,14,</abilities>
      <hpMax>333</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>333</hpCurrent>
      <hd>18d20+144</hd>
      <ac>20</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., burrow 40 ft., fly 80 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>14</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>13</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>cold</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>23</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>20</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 100</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Ice Walk</name>
        <text>The dragon can move across and climb icy surfaces without needing to make an ability check. Additionally, difficult terrain composed of ice or snow doesn&#39;t cost it extra moment.</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d10+8) piercing damage plus 9 (2d8) cold damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>14</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+8+2d8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d6+8) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>14</atk>
          <dmg>2d6+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d8+8) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>14</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Cold Breath (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon exhales an icy blast in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 22 Constitution saving throw, taking 72 (16d8) cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Cold Breath</name>
          <dmg>16d8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <text>Having been here the longest, the White Dragon was the first to enter this place, eons ago.

Following their imprisonment, a Gold Dragon came to stand guard; this dragon has now long-since died, their statue destroyed by dueling dragons.

Through all of it, only the White Dragon can truly say how much death and destruction she has seen - dozens of heroes and monsters have died here.

Still seeking vengeance, the White Dragon holds onto a primal anger, seeking to slay and destroy the latest Gold Dragon before escaping this prison. For her, vengeance is worth far more than freedom.</text>
      <environment>1</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4166</uid>
      <label>Topher</label>
      <name>Ancient Brass Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>chaotic good</alignment>
      <abilities>27,10,25,16,15,19,</abilities>
      <hpMax>297</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>297</hpCurrent>
      <hd>17d20+119</hd>
      <ac>20</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., burrow 40 ft., fly 80 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>13</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>5</id>
        <modifier>9</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>14</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>13</id>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>6</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>fire</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>24</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>20</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 104</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d10+8) piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>14</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d6+8) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>14</atk>
          <dmg>2d6+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d8+8) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>14</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Breath Weapons (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon uses one of the following breath weapons:
	Fire Breath. The dragon exhales fire in an 90-foot line that is 10 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 21 Dexterity saving throw, taking 56 (16d6) fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	Sleep Breath. The dragon exhales sleep gas in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must succeed on a DC 21 Constitution saving throw or fall unconscious for 10 minutes. This effect ends for a creature if the creature takes damage or someone uses an action to wake it.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Fire Breath</name>
          <dmg>16d6</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Change Shape</name>
        <text>The dragon magically polymorphs into a humanoid or beast that has a challenge rating no higher than its own, or back into its true form. It reverts to its true form if it dies. Any equipment it is wearing or carrying is absorbed or borne by the new form (the dragon&#39;s choice).
	In a new form, the dragon retains its alignment, hit points, Hit Dice, ability to speak, proficiencies, Legendary Resistance, lair actions, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores, as well as this action. Its statistics and capabilities are otherwise replaced by those of the new form, except any class features or legendary actions of that form.</text>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 22 Dexterity saving throw or take 15 (2d6+8) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>One of three dragons who took up the mantle of guardian after Scrying to learn that the original protector (a now-dead Gold Dragon, as mentioned) had perished, the Brass Dragon stoically stands as guard and sentinel of this place, acting with great purpose.</text>
      <environment>4</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4167</uid>
      <label>Wardancer</label>
      <name>Ancient Bronze Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>lawful good</alignment>
      <abilities>29,10,27,18,17,21,</abilities>
      <hpMax>444</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>444</hpCurrent>
      <hd>24d20+192</hd>
      <ac>22</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., fly 80 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>15</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>12</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>6</id>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>17</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>lightning</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>27</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>22</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 107</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Amphibious</name>
        <text>The dragon can breathe air and water.</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +16 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 20 (2d10+9) piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>16</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+9</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +16 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 16 (2d6+9) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>16</atk>
          <dmg>1d6+9</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +16 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 18 (2d8+9) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>16</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+9</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 20 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Breath Weapons (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon uses one of the following breath weapons.
	Lightning Breath. The dragon exhales lightning in a 120-foot line that is 10 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 23 Dexterity saving throw, taking 88 (16d10) lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	Repulsion Breath. The dragon exhales repulsion energy in a 30-foot cone. Each creature in that area must succeed on a DC 23 Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is pushed 60 feet away from the dragon.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Lightning Breath</name>
          <dmg>16d10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Change Shape</name>
        <text>The dragon magically polymorphs into a humanoid or beast that has a challenge rating no higher than its own, or back into its true form. It reverts to its true form if it dies. Any equipment it is wearing or carrying is absorbed or borne by the new form (the dragon&#39;s choice).
	In a new form, the dragon retains its alignment, hit points, Hit Dice, ability to speak, proficiencies, Legendary Resistance, lair actions, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores, as well as this action. Its statistics and capabilities are otherwise replaced by those of the new form, except any class features or legendary actions of that form.</text>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 24 Dexterity saving throw or take 16 (2d6+9) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>Having initially arrived with his twin, the Bronze Dragon lost his brother in battle several decades ago.

Never able to properly mourn, the Bronze Dragon has become a bit rageful, throwing themselves aggressively into battle - no matter
the cost.</text>
      <environment>2</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4168</uid>
      <label>Twopenny</label>
      <name>Ancient Copper Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>chaotic good</alignment>
      <abilities>27,12,25,20,17,19,</abilities>
      <hpMax>350</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>350</hpCurrent>
      <hd>20d20+140</hd>
      <ac>21</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., climb 40 ft., fly 80 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>14</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>4</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>17</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>8</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>acid</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>27</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>21</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 110</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d10+8) piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>15</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d6+8) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>15</atk>
          <dmg>2d6+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d8+8) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>15</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 19 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Breath Weapons (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon uses one of the following breath weapons.
	Acid Breath. The dragon exhales acid in an 90-foot line that is 10 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 22 Dexterity saving throw, taking 63 (14d8) acid damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	Slowing Breath. The dragon exhales gas in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must succeed on a DC 22 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature can&#39;t use reactions, its speed is halved, and it can&#39;t make more than one attack on its turn. In addition, the creature can use either an action or a bonus action on its turn, but not both. These effects last for 1 minute. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself with a successful save.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Acid Breath</name>
          <dmg>14d8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Change Shape</name>
        <text>The dragon magically polymorphs into a humanoid or beast that has a challenge rating no higher than its own, or back into its true form. It reverts to its true form if it dies. Any equipment it is wearing or carrying is absorbed or borne by the new form (the dragon&#39;s choice).
	In a new form, the dragon retains its alignment, hit points, Hit Dice, ability to speak, proficiencies, Legendary Resistance, lair actions, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores, as well as this action. Its statistics and capabilities are otherwise replaced by those of the new form, except any class features or legendary actions of that form.</text>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 23 Dexterity saving throw or take 15 (2d6+8) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>This Copper Dragon once liberated a small city from the rule of a tyrannical Blue Dragon.

Upon mingling with the commoners afterward, one attempted to offer treasure, as they had to their old ruler. From this offering, the Copper Dragon took only two copper, stating that this payment was all that would ever be required - for the entire city.

For this, he earned their respect and love, along with his name. Humble, he doesn’t often go into detail about his past, although your Bard (or anyone with a high enough History check) may recognize them and their battle scars from stories past.</text>
      <environment>32</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4165</uid>
      <label>Gildenfire</label>
      <name>Ancient Gold Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>lawful good</alignment>
      <abilities>30,14,29,18,17,28,</abilities>
      <hpMax>546</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>546</hpCurrent>
      <hd>28d20+252</hd>
      <ac>22</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., fly 80 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>9</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>16</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>16</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>6</id>
        <modifier>10</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>17</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>13</id>
        <modifier>16</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>9</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>fire</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>27</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>24</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 113</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Amphibious</name>
        <text>The dragon can breathe air and water.</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (2d10+10) piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d6+10) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d6+10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d8+10) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 24 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Breath Weapons (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon uses one of the following breath weapons.
	Fire Breath. The dragon exhales fire in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 24 Dexterity saving throw, taking 71 (13d10) fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	Weakening Breath. The dragon exhales gas in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must succeed on a DC 24 Strength saving throw or have disadvantage on Strength-based attack rolls, Strength checks, and Strength saving throws for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Fire Breath</name>
          <dmg>13d10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Change Shape</name>
        <text>The dragon magically polymorphs into a humanoid or beast that has a challenge rating no higher than its own, or back into its true form. It reverts to its true form if it dies. Any equipment it is wearing or carrying is absorbed or borne by the new form (the dragon&#39;s choice).
	In a new form, the dragon retains its alignment, hit points, Hit Dice, ability to speak, proficiencies, Legendary Resistance, lair actions, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores, as well as this action. Its statistics and capabilities are otherwise replaced by those of the new form, except any class features or legendary actions of that form.</text>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 25 Dexterity saving throw or take 17 (2d6+10) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>Powerful and ancient, the Gold Dragon is gladly willing to protect the lives of innocents, even at high personal cost or pain.

Defending this prison, they go to great lengths to protect any Commoners who may have stumbled into the chamber, keeping them and their statues alive while also preventing them from leaving.</text>
      <environment>24</environment>
    </npc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4169</uid>
      <label>Starglimmer Brightmoon</label>
      <name>Ancient Silver Dragon</name>
      <size>5</size>
      <type>dragon</type>
      <alignment>lawful good</alignment>
      <abilities>30,10,29,18,15,23,</abilities>
      <hpMax>487</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>487</hpCurrent>
      <hd>25d20+225</hd>
      <ac>22</ac>
      <armor>natural armor</armor>
      <speed>40 ft., fly 80 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>16</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>9</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>13</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>2</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>5</id>
        <modifier>11</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>16</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>16</id>
        <modifier>7</modifier>
      </skill>
      <immune>cold</immune>
      <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
      <passive>26</passive>
      <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
      <cr>23</cr>
      <trait>
        <name>Source</name>
        <text>Monster Manual p. 116</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
        <text>If the dragon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Multiattack</name>
        <text>The dragon can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Bite</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (2d10+10) piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Bite</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d10+10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Claw</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d6+10) slashing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Claw</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d6+10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Tail</name>
        <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +17 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d8+10) bludgeoning damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Tail</name>
          <atk>17</atk>
          <dmg>2d8+10</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Frightful Presence</name>
        <text>Each creature of the dragon&#39;s choice that is within 120 feet of the dragon and aware of it must succeed on a DC 21 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the dragon&#39;s Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.</text>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Breath Weapons (Recharge 5-6)</name>
        <text>The dragon uses one of the following breath weapons.
	Cold Breath. The dragon exhales an icy blast in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 24 Constitution saving throw, taking 67 (15d8) cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	Paralyzing Breath. The dragon exhales paralyzing gas in a 90- foot cone. Each creature in that area must succeed on a DC 24 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Cold Breath</name>
          <dmg>15d8</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Change Shape</name>
        <text>The dragon magically polymorphs into a humanoid or beast that has a challenge rating no higher than its own, or back into its true form. It reverts to its true form if it dies. Any equipment it is wearing or carrying is absorbed or borne by the new form (the dragon&#39;s choice).
	In a new form, the dragon retains its alignment, hit points, Hit Dice, ability to speak, proficiencies, Legendary Resistance, lair actions, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores, as well as this action. Its statistics and capabilities are otherwise replaced by those of the new form, except any class features or legendary actions of that form.</text>
      </action>
      <legendary>
        <name>Legendary Actions (3/Turn)</name>
        <text>The dragon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The dragon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Detect</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Tail Attack</name>
        <text>The dragon makes a tail attack.</text>
      </legendary>
      <legendary>
        <name>Wing Attack (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
        <text>The dragon beats its wings. Each creature within 15 ft. of the dragon must succeed on a DC 25 Dexterity saving throw or take 17 (2d6+10) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. The dragon can then fly up to half its flying speed.</text>
      </legendary>
      <text>Proud to serve as a protector, deep down the Silver Dragon sometimes regrets her choice, wishing she had instead remained behind.

Missing the often trivial problems of humanoids, she enjoyed living among them, admiring their resilience.</text>
      <environment>1088</environment>
    </npc>
    <encounter>
      <name>Dragon War</name>
      <uid>4176</uid>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4170</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4171</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4172</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4173</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4174</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4169</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4165</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4168</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4167</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4166</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4164</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4163</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4162</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4161</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
      <combatant>
        <monster>
          <uid>4159</uid>
        </monster>
      </combatant>
    </encounter>
    <note>
      <name>-READING THIS ADVENTURE</name>
      <text>This adventure is written for 3-5 characters at level 20, forming an adventure of epic level and consequence. These pages will provide notes for adjusting the difficulty based on party size at the end (see Appendix E).

Intended as a one-shot, single session adventure (around 3-5 hours), this can instead be dropped into most existing settings and/or campaigns.

Please read this entire adventure before playing, to ensure everything is understood and prepared for.

At the end of this document, after the adventure, you will find several appendices, providing supplementary information such as stat blocks. Additionally, five pre-generated character sheets can be found after the appendices. These are not required to enjoy this adventure, but are available for those that wish to use them.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>-PREMISE
      </name>
      <text>Entering a mysterious ruin, the party finds cryptic inscriptions and warnings carved into the stone walls.

Moving deeper, they discover a massive cavern, filled with stone rubble and gargantuan statues. As they watch, two of these statues come to life, revealing a Copper Dragon and a Green Dragon, both clearly ancient.

As a standoff ensues, the party learns that they have triggered an ancient trap. Having been cursed by entering, they will find themselves forced to choose sides as more dragons awaken, leading to an epic battle testing their fears, abilities, and even their very alignments.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>THE RAVEN’S NEST</name>
      <text>The local bar and inn, the Raven’s Nest is well-kept and busy each night. Many down-on-their-luck men and women have found the mental willpower and motivation to push forward after spending a night here, pouring their hearts out to the kind barkeep.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -THE MISSING FARMER</name>
      <text>Traversing the countryside, the party enters a small village, living in the shadow of a large
mountain.

Opening in a tavern, the party is eating and drinking the night away. Speaking to the locals, the evening is light-hearted and fun until a dour middle-aged man enters the bar.
Eyebrows furrowed and eyes puffy from lack of sleep, this man takes a seat in a lonely corner of the bar, quietly ordering a drink from the bartender.

This man is Carlos Alves Sousa, as described in Appendix A. The mood in the tavern becomes a bit less joyful as he takes his seat, and an Insight check (DC 13) will show that people are not afraid - in fact, they seem to pity him.

If the party asks about Carlos, they’ll be sadly (and quietly) told a simple story: Carlos’s brother Rodrigo recently went up to the mountain, chasing ancient rumors of great treasure. Many people have sought this treasure throughout the years, but none have ever returned... including Rodrigo. Due to the fabled curse upon the mountain, he is presumed dead.

Carlos had begged him not to go, but Rodrigo didn’t listen, wanting to help his impoverished older brother afford better farm tools. Now in mourning, Carlos blames himself for his brother’s death.

Hopefully, this will be enough to entice the party up the mountain to explore for themselves. If for any reason they seem uninterested, the bartender (Marcos, also detailed in Appendix A) will quietly approach the party, of a modest amount of gold for this expedition, mostly to cover costs of food and supplies - including a small handful of Potions of Healing or Potions of Greater Healing, if desired. These can be purchased from another shop in town (Appendix B).</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>MATEO’S MERCANTILE</name>
      <text>Your average general store, this place contains basic supplies such as climbing gear, rations, canteens, and even a few Potions of Healing. No other enchanted items are available here.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>THE SNOWY MOUNTAIN</name>
      <text>Stretching high into the clouds, this mountain may not be comparable to Everest, but it does provide a steep climb for those willing to spare a day to climb it.

Not much plant life grows in the high snowy areas, which means fewer animals bother to venture that far up the mountain.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -A MYSTERIOUS RUIN</name>
      <text>Resting and gearing up, the party will ascend the mountain. If desired, you can describe the rough terrain and dangerous cliff that must be scaled along the way, requiring Athletics checks (DC 15) to climb successfully.

Any who fail this check will slip, potentially falling. If the party has thought to use climbing gear or rope, perhaps tying themselves together, require a Strength saving throw (DC 15) from the next party member as their body weight tugs at them suddenly.
If this party member fails their check, move on to the next, increasing the DC. They may find themselves each pulled from the ciffs if they’re not careful!

If they did not use rope or find themselves falling anyway, these characters will take 3d6 bludgeoning damage as they fall around 25-30 feet, landing hard on the gravel below.

Continuing the climb, they will eventually reach an area near the top, where they find an immense cave entrance. Over one hundred feet wide and tall, they may not realize it, but this cave is big enough for an ancient dragon to fly through... or worse, something bigger.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>THE YAWNING CORRIDOR</name>
      <text>Large in size and covered in ribbons of flowing script, these carvings have faded over years of
wind erosion. 

Nearly a mile in length, a creature trapped inside would need to fully exit this cave entrance into the outside world if they wish to escape the curse.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -STRANGE WARNINGS</name>
      <text>Allow them a short rest near the cave entrance if they wish. A full day hasn’t passed, so it’s a bit too early for a long rest (not that they need it) Assuming they began their trek at dawn, it’s likely noon by now - perhaps a couple hours
later if they struggled or have lower walking speeds.

Entering the cavern, it doesn’t take long before carvings start to gradually take form from the
rough rock. Although ancient, it is clear that these walls, floors, and ceiling were all polished smooth once, many centuries or millennia ago.

On these now-crumbling walls, the party will find strange hieroglyphs and writing. Some of it is illegible due to sections of the wall falling
away, and others are in unknown runic languages.

However, a History check (DC 18) will allow a character to recognize sections which resemble the languages of the Giants and the Abyss, along with various pieces of Elemental languages. Realizing this is a form of Primordial, any character who speaks this language will require only a History check of DC 13 to read it. 

Oddly cryptic and foreign, this Primordial writing seems to be an early dialect, potentially pre-dating anything else they’ve ever seen. If this writing can be translated, the players will find odd warnings and stories of some terrible monster or being, which is never fully described or explained.

Disturbingly, as the party presses forward, the clearest phrases soon shift from warnings to stay away to pleadings to never leave. Eerie and spine-chilling, these glyphs now seem determined to convince them that they will spend eternity within these halls.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>THE COLOSSAL CHAMBER</name>
      <text>Enormous in size, this place must have taken years to carve out. Even with magic, it would still take months and dozens of magic users, speaking to a truly impressive power wielded by the creators... especially considering the horrors trapped beneath the once-polished stone floors.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -CAVERN OF STATUES</name>
      <text>After walking a fair distance, the party eventually reaches a point where the already-massive passage opens up into an incredible cavern. Big enough to house a town - perhaps a city - this cavern is several hundred feet tall, stretching far into the darkness opposite the entry tunnel.

With dozens of immense stone pillars, this room - for it is a room, as your highest Passive Perception characters soon notice - has been
carefully carved, with the same once-smooth walls, floors, and ceilings as the entrance tunnel.

However, eons of time have caused several pillars to crumble, allowing various stone debris
and sections of the ceiling above to scatter below, forming massive blockages in the central areas of the room.

Along the walls, dirt and sand has begun to collect, as if massive winds pushed ancient piles of rock and dust against them.

Looking ahead, the party begins to see several gargantuan shapes in the darkness between the pillars, unmoving.

Approaching, these are clearly life-size statues of ancient dragons. As the party comes closer, a resounding crack echoes through the room, followed by the cacophonous sound of grating
stone.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -WE SHOULD NOT HAVE COME</name>
      <text>As the party watches on, two of these statues quickly spring to life, their rock prisons cracking open and crumbling around their feet. Battle-scarred and clearly dangerous, one of these is an Ancient Green Dragon, while the
other is an Ancient Copper Dragon. 

Roaring at each other, the sound causes the floor to quake, as dust drifts from the ceiling above. With multiple sparks of blue light, several of their open wounds begin to close, clearly being healed by an unknown, powerful magic.

Noticing the party, the Copper Dragon will growl, moving to protect them from the Green
Dragon. Standing between them, this dragon will speak. “You should have heeded the warnings,” he rumbles, before continuing. “But it’s too late now. This prison houses terrible evil, and I stand as protector. If you wish to protect this world, let none escape this place.”

As the party readies to assist him (presuming a good-aligned party) or begins to speak, the Green Dragon begins to cackle with grating laughter. Interrupting the party if they are clearly planning to aid the Copper Dragon, the Green Dragon will choose their words carefully if the party hesitates.

“Fools. If you aid him, this place will become your prison also! For the curse to remain, none may leave... including you.”

As the Green Dragon speaks, allow a Perception check (DC 13). On a success a party member will notice faint movement in the corner of the room. Rock still crumbling from his shoulders and back, a man with similar facial features to Carlos is sneaking toward the exit, ducking behind pillars. Looking terrified, he motions for the party to stay silent.

However, both dragons quickly notice him. Eyes flicking in his direction, the Green Dragon continues speaking. “Are you prepared to spend eternity defending this place? Because that is what he asks of you.”

As Rodrigo bolts for the exit in a mad dash, the Copper Dragon roars, beating his wings. Forcing everyone nearby (within 15 feet) to make a Dexterity saving throw (DC 23), any who fail are knocked prone, taking 2d6+8 bludgeoning damage.

As they watch on in horror, Rodrigo is sent flying, crumpling against a pillar in a heap. Clearly dead, the party witnesses his skin slowly become stone once more.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -CHOOSING SIDES</name>
      <text>At this point, the party has limited time to choose sides before the other dragons awaken and Initiative is rolled.

Having just seen a good-aligned dragon kill an innocent man, a party who typically opposes evil may be stunned, unsure of who to help.

Allow them a couple quick questions, but keep answers brief, with both dragons attempting to sway them to their side.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -THE DRAGONS AWAKEN</name>
      <text>As can be quickly explained, any chromatic dragons present entered without knowing of the curse, planning to make this place their new lair.

Wise metallic dragons who knew the truth recognized the threat posed if a chromatic dragon escaped, and slowly gathered over time to prevent anyone from leaving, as is the point of the stone curse - to collect ‘immortal’ guardians, revived through the ages to defend the prison. 

With the basic details, the party must choose. As the party aligns with either the chromatic or metallic dragons, this choice will affect the upcoming battle.

As more cracks echo through the chamber, several more dragons begin to awaken in the further reaches of the room. Too far for the party to interfere, one awakened dragon will crash through three other stone dragons, destroying and killing them - after all, the only way to die within this chamber is to have your statue broken. These three slain dragons are of the same type aligned with the party, leaving two allied dragons against five opposing (one CR 21/22 and one CR 23/24 - your choice). For example, if the party decides to align with the Green Dragon (whatever their reasons), three chromatic dragons will be destroyed, leaving the party with only two chromatic allies against five metallic enemies.

This balances this encounter, as dragons would quickly tear each other apart in a boring battle if their numbers were even. This way, the dragons need the party if they wish to succeed.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -RUNNING THIS ENCOUNTER</name>
      <text>Rolling for Initiative, 
be sure to roll separately for each dragon. This will help space their turns throughout those of your party, so they don’t get bored. 

With seven dragons and 3-5 players, there are 10-12 turns each round. With Legendary Actions, dragons are able to act after another creature’s turn, which could bog down combat if used poorly. To avoid this, only allow two Legendary Actions per turn. This way, you won’t get distracted, keeping each turn manageable. Even with ten turns per round, this means only a single Legendary Action will go unspent, which could be used for a Wing Attack if you’d like a 3-Action round. Even still, you’ll need to be quick. Decide which Dragons will take Legendary Actions next as your players take their turns, to keep things moving.

Additionally, keep in mind that if a Legendary Action costs two actions, that’s it for the round! Two counts as two, whether two dragons make Tail Attacks or one is making a Wing Attack. This can be a deadly encounter for your players if they’re not careful, or if the dice don’t go their way. But, that’s the fun of an Epic Level adventure - high stakes!

To help you keep track of everything, we’ve provided cheat sheets in Appendix F, detailing each dragon and info you’ll need during battle.

Although full stats are provided in Appendix C, you likely won’t need them if you use the cheat sheets instead.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>      =ALLIES OF CONSEQUENCE</name>
      <text>Keep in mind, their allies do matter. All the chromatic dragons need to do in order to win is escape, which means the metallic dragons are
going to be playing defense, trying to prevent anyone from leaving.

Additionally, the chromatic dragons aren’t exactly allies here, unlike the unified metallic dragons. If a breath weapon or Wing Attack
accidentally hits another chromatic dragon or even a member of the party, they won’t really care. Their own survival is of the utmost importance.

Also, feel free to substitute in Gem Dragons from Fizban’s Treasury of Dragons if you like, or even other dragon types if that sounds fun!</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>      =MORALITY TWIST</name>
      <text>If you’d like to put an interesting morality spin on this adventure, you could even have the lawful chromatic dragons (Blue and Green) ally themselves with the lawful metallic dragons (Bronze, Gold, and Silver).

For this scenario, providing an interesting twist, lawful evil dragons may recognize the danger of allowing anything to escape the chamber, thus working together with unlikely allies. Meanwhile more chaotic dragons may view themselves as strong enough to escape or defeat the coming apocalypse themselves, causing a
strange clash of alignment.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    -PURPOSE... OR DOOM</name>
      <text>Having defeated their enemies, the party still has an important choice to make. They’re free to change their minds, after all... however, the
guardian dragons might require convincing to allow this. If failed, the party may find themselves fighting their once-allies for their
desired freedom.

Are they willing to remain here as protectors, preventing the apocalypse for eternity? It’s a
worthy purpose.

Or, is the party willing to risk it all, unleashing chaos upon the world on the gamble that they can defeat it?

This is a battle they might not win. Are they truly strong enough to stop the apocalypse? Or will their hubris doom this world forever?</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>MOVING FORWARD</name>
      <text>Greater Restoration can cure Rodrigo of his petrification. If they all survive the end of the world, he might be able to return to his brother, with treasure left behind by the dragons. 

If they choose to stay, Wish or Divine Intervention may be enough to save a player character. However, some may be left behind to their new destiny, if they desire it.

So, what will these heroes choose? To tempt the fates, or to partake in eternal battle? Either way, there will be consequences...</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>THE END</name>
      <text>With that, you’ve reached the ending of this one-shot adventure. Thank you for reading! I hope you enjoyed it. There will be many more to come (including a sequel), so keep an eye out.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
  </campaign>
</data>