<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <monster>
    <name>Homunculus Servant (UA) [2024]</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <type>construct</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>13</ac>
    <hp>15</hp>
    <speed>20 ft., Fly 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>4</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
        <resist/>
    <immune>Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5 + 5 per spell level. (the homunculus has a number of Hit Dice [d4s] equal to the spell's level)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Evasion</name>
      <text>If the homunculus is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, the homunculus instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the save and only half damage if it fails. It can't use this trait if it has the Incapacitated condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Bond</name>
      <text>Add the spell level to any ability check or saving throw the homunculus makes.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Force Strike</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: Bonus equals your spell attack modifier, reach 5 ft. or range 30 ft. Hit: 1d6 plus the spell's level of Force damage.</text>
      <attack>Force Strike||1d6</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Channel Magic</name>
      <text>Trigger: You cast a spell that has a range of touch while the homunculus is within 120 feet of you. Response: The homunculus delivers the spell through its touch.</text>
    </reaction>
    <reaction>
      <name>Combat</name>
      <text>The homunculus is an ally to you and your allies. In combat, it shares your Initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys your commands (no action required by you). If you don't issue any, it takes the Dodge action and uses its movement to avoid danger.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: Use the spell slot's level for the spell's level in the stat block.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>Source:	UA2024-Artificer p. 13,
		UA2024-Eberron Updates p. 8</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Eldritch Cannon (UA) [2024]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>object</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>18</ac>
    <hp>5</hp>
    <speed>15 ft.</speed>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
        <resist/>
    <immune>Poison, Psychic</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5 × your Artificer level (casting Mending on the cannon restores 2d6 Hit Points to it)</text>
      <attack>Mending||2d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Activate Cannon (Requires You to be within 60 Feet of the Cannon)</name>
      <text>As a Bonus Action, you order the cannon to use the Flamethrower, Force Ballista, or Protector option below; you can direct the cannon to move up to 15 feet before or after that option:</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Flamethrower (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The cannon exhales fire in a 15-foot Cone. Each creature in that area makes a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 2d8 Fire damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. Flammable objects in the Cone that aren't being worn or carried start burning.</text>
      <attack>Flamethrower||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Force Ballista (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>Make a ranged spell attack originating from the cannon at one creature or object within 120 feet of it. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 Force damage, and if the target is a creature, it is pushed up to 5 feet away from the cannon.</text>
      <attack>Force Ballista||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Protector (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The cannon emits a burst of positive energy that grants itself and each creature of your choice within 10 feet of it a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d8 plus your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1).</text>
      <attack>Protector||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>Source:	UA2024-Artificer p. 10</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Steel Defender (UA) [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>construct</type>
    <alignment/>
    <ac>15</ac>
    <hp>15</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>4</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Understands the languages you know</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
        <resist/>
    <immune>Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5 + five times your Artificer level (the defender has a number of Hit Dice [d8s] equal to your Artificer level)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>PB equals your Proficiency Bonus</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Steel Bond</name>
      <text>Add your Proficiency Bonus to any ability check or saving throw the defender makes.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Force-Empowered Rend</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: Bonus equals your spell attack modifier, reach 5 ft. Hit: 1d8 + 2 plus your Intelligence modifier Force damage.</text>
      <attack>Force-Empowered Rend||1d8+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Repair (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/DAY</recharge>
      <text>The defender, or one Construct or object it can see within 5 feet of it, regains a number of Hit Points equal to 2d8 plus your Intelligence modifier.</text>
      <attack>Repair||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Deflect Attack</name>
      <text>Trigger: A creature the defender can see within 5 feet of it makes an attack roll targeting a different creature. Response: The triggering creature makes the attack roll with Disadvantage.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>Source:	UA2024-Artificer p. 12</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
</compendium>
