<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <!-- Martial or Simple weapons -->
  <itemtemplate>
    <name>Radiant %name% (UA)</name>
    <detail>Rare (Requires Attunement by a Spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>M,R</type>
    <text>This magic weapon grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. While holding it, you can take a Bonus Action to cause it to shed 13 Bright Light in a 30-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 30 feet. You can extinguish the light as a Bonus Action.

The weapon has 4 charges. You can take a Reaction immediately after being hit by an attack roll to expend 1 of the weapon's charges and force the attacker to make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the attacker has the Blinded condition until the end of its next turn. The weapon regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
    <source>UA2024-Artificer p. 13, UA2024-Eberron Updates p. 8</source>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
    <roll>1d4</roll>
  </itemtemplate>
  <!-- Repeating Shot weapons with Ammunition -->
  <itemtemplate>
    <name>Repeating Shot %name% (UA)</name>
    <detail>Uncommon (Requires Attunement)</detail>
    <property>A</property>
    <text>This magic weapon grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it when it's used to make a ranged attack roll, and it ignores the Loading property if it has it.

If the weapon lacks ammunition, it produces its own, automatically creating one piece of magic ammunition when the wielder makes a ranged attack with it. The ammunition created by the weapon vanishes the instant after it hits or misses a target.</text>
    <source>UA2024-Artificer p. 14, UA2024-Eberron Updates p. 8</source>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
  </itemtemplate>
  <!-- Returning Weapon with Thrown -->
  <itemtemplate>
    <name>Returning %name% (UA)</name>
    <detail>Uncommon (Requires Attunement)</detail>
    <property>T</property>
    <text>This magic weapon grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it, and it returns to your hand immediately after it is used to make a ranged attack roll.</text>
    <source>UA2024-Artificer p. 14, UA2024-Eberron Updates p. 9</source>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
  </itemtemplate>
</compendium>
