<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  
  
  
  
  <monster>
    <name>Molten Ooze</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>ooze</type>
    <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>8</ac>
    <hp>115 (11d10 + 55)</hp>
    <speed>20 ft.</speed>
    <str>16</str><dex>7</dex><con>20</con><int>1</int><wis>7</wis><cha>2</cha>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>fire</immune>
    <conditionImmune>blinded, charmed, deafened, exhausted, frightened, prone</conditionImmune>
    <senses>blindsight 60 ft. (blind beyond this radius)</senses><passive>8</passive>
    <languages>-</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <trait>
      <name>Parasitic Pal</name>
      <text>Gourdon and Jack are bound together as one entity, they can not move away from each other and any spell or damage targeting one of them effects the other as well. Though each have their own turn in the initiative order.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>Gourdon has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Combat Preparation</name>
      <text>Gourdon casts stoneskin and mind blank on himself before combat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>Gourdon is an 18th-level spellcaster. His spellcasting ability is Intelligence (spell save DC 17, +9 to hit with spell attacks). Gourdon can cast detect magic and misty Step at will and has the following wizard spells prepared:</text>
      <text>Cantrips (at will): fire bolt, light, mage hand, prestidigitation, shocking grasp</text>
      <text>1st level (4 slots): shield, identify, feather fall magic missile</text>
      <text>2nd level (3 slots): detect thoughts, mirror image, hold person</text>
      <text>3rd level (3 slots): counterspell, fly, lightning bolt</text>
      <text>4th level (3 slots): banishment, fire shield, stoneskin</text>
      <text>5th level (3 slots): cone of cold, scrying, wall of force</text>
      <text>6th level (1 slot): globe of invulnerability</text>
      <text>7th level (1 slot): teleport</text>
      <text>8th level (1 slot): mind blank</text>
      <text>9th level (1 slot): time stop</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Slam</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d10 + 3) bludgeoning damage plus 7 (2d6) fire damage.</text>
      <attack>Slam|6|1d10 + 3 + 2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Constrict</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one Large or smaller target. Hit: 7 (1d8 + 3) bludgeoning damage plus 10 (3d6) fire damage, and if the target is a creature, it is grappled (escape DC 14). Until the grapple ends, the target is restrained, the ooze can't constrict another target, and at the start of each of the ooze's turns, the target takes 21 (6d6) fire damage.</text>
      <attack>Constrict|6|1d8 + 3 + 3d6</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/><slots/>
    <description>Volcanoes are not-too-seldom used as dumping grounds for all sorts of undesirable objects or materials. Their unfathomable temperatures and churning magma make them ideal for the disposal of just about anything that one doesn't want to see again.

      Sometimes creatures can even be created in this extreme crucible of immeasurable heat and elemental energy. These creatures are born from the elemental heat and amorphous nature of magma, and they take the form of a writhing blob of any number of (now unidentifiable) substances melted in the volcano's caldera. A blob that wanders with intention—an intention to melt and absorb more material into its mass.
      
      Source: Team Superhydra, The Kobolds' Cauldron</description>
    <environment>Any</environment>
  </monster> <!-- Molten Ooze-->
</compendium>
