<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Haunted One [5.5e]</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are haunted by the events of your past. Whether it was a lone terrible incident or an accumulation of painful moments, you bear the unshakable weight of what happened to you. You've tried to bury it and run away from it, to no avail; it can't be slain with a sword or banished via magic. Nevertheless, you persist.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Constitution, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Survivor or a Dark Gift feat of your choice</name>
      <text>Survivor or a Dark Gift feat of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Gaming Set</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Gaming Set (same as above), Crowbar, Holy Water (1 flask), Mirror, Oil (2 flasks), Signal Whistle, Tinderbox, Traveler's Clothes, 5 Torches, Waterskin, and 14 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Investigator [5.5e]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Investigation</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You relentlessly seek the truth. Perhaps you witnessed something remarkable or terrible and now desire to unravel its mystery, or maybe you're motivated by universal justice and honesty. Whether the cases you're embroiled in are local crimes or eldritch conspiracies, you're driven to reveal what others would keep hidden.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Intelligence, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Sharp Eye or a Dark Gift feat of your choice</name>
      <text>Sharp Eye or a Dark Gift feat of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Disguise Kit</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Disguise Kit, Manacles, Shovel, Traveler's Clothes, 3 Vials, and 16 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Mist Wanderer [5.5e]</name>
    <proficiency>Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You once knew your home. But one day, the Mists rose and drew you into a Domain of Dread. Ever since, you have wandered between domains, braving the mercurial Mists as you search for a way home. Your time in these cursed realms has changed you, yet you find solace in communities of fellow wanderers throughout the Mists.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Constitution, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: A Dark Gift feat of your choice (Mist Walker is recommended)</name>
      <text>A Dark Gift feat of your choice. (Mist Walker is recommended)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Artisan's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Artisan's Tools (same as above), Lamp, Oil (5 flasks), Pouch, Rope, Tinderbox, Traveler's Clothes, and 30 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Spirit Medium [5.5e]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Religion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Through strange rituals and fateful encounters, you've discovered that you bear a unique connection to the spirits of the dead and damned. Your body is a conduit for such spirits, granting you prescient insight from beyond. But these spirits' intentions aren't always innocent, and their gifts come at a haunting cost.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Constitution, Intelligence, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: A Dark Gift feat of your choice (Gathered Whispers is recommended)</name>
      <text>A Dark Gift feat of your choice. (Gathered Whispers is recommended)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Gaming Set</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Disguise Kit, Manacles, Shovel, Traveler's Clothes, 3 Vials, and 16 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
