<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Warlock [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: Undead Patron -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: Undead Patron</name>
        <text>Defy Death for Profane Power

You've made a pact with a creature that defies the cycle of life and death: a powerful lich, a vampire, or another entity of undeath. Having once been mortal, these ancient patrons know firsthand the paths of ambition and the routes past the doors of death. They eagerly share this profane knowledge and other secrets with those who work their will among the living.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Form of Dread (Undead Patron)</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you transform into an avatar of your patron's dreadful power, gaining the benefits below for 1 minute, until you have the Incapacitated condition, or until you end the form (no action required). You can transform a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Facsimile of Life. You gain Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d10 plus your Warlock level.

	Fearless Form. You have Immunity to the Frightened condition. If you are Frightened when you transform, the condition immediately ends for you.

	Frightful Avatar. Once per turn, when you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can force it to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the target has the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
        <roll description="Temporary Hit Points">1d10+%7</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Undead Spells (Undead Patron)</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Warlock level specified in the Undead Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Undead Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3 | Bane, Blindness/Deafness, Phantasmal Force, Ray of Sickness
5 | Speak with Dead, Summon Undead
7 | Greater Invisibility, Phantasmal Killer
9 | Antilife Shell, Cloudkill

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Grave Touched (Undead Patron)</name>
        <text>Your patron's powers have a profound effect on your body and magic, granting you the following benefits.

	Arcane Necrosis. Necrotic damage from your attacks, Warlock spells, and Warlock features ignores Resistance to Necrotic damage. Once per turn when you cast a spell that deals damage, you can change that spell's damage type to Necrotic.

	Dreaded Necrosis. When you hit a creature with an attack roll and deal Necrotic damage while using your Form of Dread, you can roll one additional damage die when determining the Necrotic damage the target takes. You can use this benefit only once per turn.

	Undead Endurance. You don't gain Exhaustion levels from dehydration, malnutrition, or suffocation. In addition, you don't need to sleep, and magic can't put you to sleep.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Necrotic Husk (Undead Patron)</name>
        <text>Your connection to undeath saturates your body. You gain the following benefits.

	Necrotic Resilience. You have Resistance to Necrotic damage. While using your Form of Dread, you have Immunity to Necrotic damage.

	Unholy Resuscitation. If you drop to 0 Hit Points and don't die outright, you can cause your body to erupt with deathly energy. Each creature of your choice in a 30-foot Emanation originating from you makes a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, taking Necrotic damage equal to 2d10 plus your Charisma modifier on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. Your Hit Points then change to twice your Warlock level, and you gain 1 Exhaustion level.
	Once you use this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">2d10+%6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Superior Dread (Undead Patron)</name>
        <text>Your Form of Dread improves, granting you the following benefits while you are using it.

	Dread Resistance. You have Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.

	Ghostly Flight. You have a Fly Speed equal to your Speed and can hover. You can move through creatures and objects as if they were Difficult Terrain, but you take 1d10 Force damage if you end your turn inside a creature or an object.

	Profane Casting. Whenever you cast a Warlock spell from the Conjuration or Necromancy school, you cast it without any Verbal, Somatic, or Material components, except Material components that are costly or consumed.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
        <roll description="Force Damage">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Bane [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blindness/Deafness [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Force [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ray of Sickness [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Speak with Dead [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Summon Undead [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Killer [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Antilife Shell [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cloudkill [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Undead Patron)</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
