<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Sharp Eye [5.5e]</name>
    <text>When you take the Search or Study action, you can give yourself Advantage on any ability check made as part of that action. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest. If the check fails, the use of this feature isn't expended.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Survivor [5.5e]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Hypervigilance. Whenever you roll Initiative, you can reroll the d20 if the number rolled is 9 or lower. You must use the new roll.

	Steel Yourself. When you fail a saving throw to avoid or end the Charmed or Frightened condition, you can take a Reaction to add a bonus to the roll, potentially causing it to succeed. The bonus is equal to your Proficiency Bonus.
	Once you take this Reaction, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Aberrant Anatomy (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <text>Exposure to alien horrors like those of the Far Realm has warped your physical form in supernatural ways. You gain the following features.

	Breathless. You can hold your breath for 1 hour.

	Extrasensory Perception. You have proficiency in the Perception skill, if you lack it. You also gain Expertise in that skill. In addition, you have Blindsight with a range of 15 feet.

	Warping Flesh. Immediately after you make a D20 Test and roll a 1 on the d20, the aberrant influence infecting your form flares, wrenching control of your flesh. Make a Constitution saving throw (DC 13 plus your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, you have the Stunned condition until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Echoing Soul (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>You experience echoes from a past or alternate life. You gain the following features.

	Channeled Prowess. You have proficiency in two skills of your choice. In addition, choose one skill you have proficiency in. You gain Expertise in that skill. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can change your choice for this benefit.

	Inherent Tongues. You know one additional language of your choice, which you choose from the language tables in the Player's Handbook.

	Intrusive Echoes. Immediately after you make a D20 Test and roll a 1 on the d20, memories and sensations from your soul's other life threaten to overtake you. Make a Constitution saving throw (DC 13 plus your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, you have the Incapacitated condition until the end of your next turn. While you are Incapacitated in this way, your Speed is halved.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Gathered Whispers (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>You are haunted by a cacophony of whispering spirits only you can hear. You gain the following features.

	Spirit Whispers. You learn the Message spell and can cast it without Material components. Additionally, you always have the Augury spell prepared. You can cast it without a spell slot or spell components, and you must finish a Long Rest before you can cast it in this way again. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this benefit (choose when you select this feat).

	Unearthly Scream. When you are hit by an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to channel your haunting spirits into a protective, otherworldly scream. You can add your Proficiency Bonus to your AC against that attack, potentially causing it to miss. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Voices from Beyond. Immediately after you make a D20 Test and roll a 1 on the d20, the haunting voices rise to a ghastly volume. Make a Wisdom saving throw (DC 13 plus your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, you have the Deafened condition until the end of your next turn. While Deafened, you have Disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Living Shadow (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>The shadow you cast is animate and ever-present—sometimes it even acts according to its own will. You gain the following features.

	Grasping Shadow. You learn the Mage Hand spell and can cast it without spell components. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

	Lengthened Strike. When you make a melee attack roll as part of the Attack or Magic action on your turn, you can increase your reach for that attack by 10 feet, as your shadow stretches to aid you. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Ominous Will. Immediately after you make a D20 Test and roll a 1 on the d20, your shadow attempts to exert its will. Make a Wisdom saving throw (DC 13 plus your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, you have the Incapacitated condition until the start of your next turn, at which point you must roll on the Shadow's Will table to determine what you do during that turn.

Shadow's Will:
1d8 | Behavior
1 | You don't take an action or a Bonus Action, and you use all your movement to move. Roll 1d4 for the direction: 1, north; 2, east; 3, south; or 4, west.
2-6 | You don't move or take a Bonus Action, and you take the Attack action to make one melee attack against a random creature within reach. If none are within reach, you take no action.
7-8 | You have the Prone condition, and your turn ends.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
    <roll description="Behavior">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Direction">1d4</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Mist Walker (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>You know how to slip through the Mists' grasp, but this freedom comes at a price: If you remain in one area for too long, the Mists find you and drain your life force. You gain the following features.

	Domain Traveler. When you enter the Mists intent on reaching a specific domain, you are treated as if you possess a Mist talisman keyed to that domain. To use this feature, you must know the name of the domain you have chosen as your destination, but you don't need to have previously visited that land. This trait doesn't allow you to bypass domain borders closed by a Darklord's will.

	Mist Walk. When you take damage or fail a saving throw to avoid or end the Grappled or Restrained condition, you can take a Reaction and teleport up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Poisoned Roots. When you finish a Long Rest, the world around you in a 10-mile radius becomes a siphon that leeches away at your vitality. Whenever you finish a Short Rest in that area, make a Constitution saving throw (DC 13 plus your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, you get no benefits from finishing that rest.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Second Skin (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>There is another side of you that most people never see: a beast, a terrifying avenger, or a walking nightmare. You gain the following features.

	Alternate Form. You always have the Alter Self spell prepared. You can cast it without a spell slot or spell components, and you must finish a Long Rest before you can cast it in this way again. You can also cast it using spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). When you cast Alter Self without a spell slot using this feature, it doesn't require Concentration.

	Involuntary Change. Certain circumstances can involuntarily trigger your transformation. When you select this feat, roll on the Change Catalyst table to determine what triggers your change. After you experience the catalyst, at the start of your next turn, make a Charisma saving throw (DC 13 plus your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, you immediately use Alternate Form to cast Alter Self without a spell slot. If you've already expended the use of that feature, you instead have the Stunned condition until the start of your next turn.

Change Catalyst:
1d6 | Catalyst
1 | Seeing a particular phase of the moon
2 | Smelling the scent of a certain type of flower
3 | Hearing temple bells ringing
4 | Hearing a particular melody
5 | Touching pure silver with your bare skin
6 | Seeing someone who resembles a specific individual

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
    <roll description="Catalyst">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Symbiotic Being (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>A second being resides within your body, offering knowledge and assistance while furthering its own agenda. You gain the following features.

	Entwined Existence. The symbiote can't be targeted. If you die, so does your symbiote. If you are returned to life, your symbiote also revives.

	Second Mind. You gain proficiency in one of the following skills: Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Religion, Perception, or Persuasion. You also know one additional language of your choice, chosen from the language tables in the Player's Handbook.

	Sustained Symbiosis. When you fail a saving throw, you can take a Reaction and expend one of your Hit Dice. Roll the die and add the number rolled to the saving throw, potentially turning the failure into a success. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Symbiotic Agenda. Immediately after you make a D20 Test and roll a 1 on the d20, your symbiote attempts to assert control. Make a Charisma saving throw (DC 13 plus your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, you have the Charmed condition for 1d12 hours. While Charmed, you must try to follow the symbiote's commands and further its goals, as determined by the DM. Whenever you take damage, you can repeat this save, ending the effect on a success.
	At the DM's discretion, you might make this saving throw whenever you act contrary to the symbiote's agenda.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
    <roll description="Hours">1d12</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Touch of Death (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>Deathly power resides within you, bursting out at the slightest provocation. You gain the following features.

	Death Touch. You learn the Chill Touch spell and can cast it without spell components. Necrotic damage you deal with this spell ignores Resistance. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

	Pull of the Grave. You have Disadvantage on Death Saving Throws.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Watchers (Dark Gift) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Ravenloft Campaign</prerequisite>
    <text>Something unnatural is always watching you, taking the form of scurrying vermin and other eerie creatures. You gain the following features.

	Borrowed Eyes. You always have the Beast Sense and Speak with Animals spells prepared. You can cast each spell without a spell slot, and you must finish a Long Rest before you can cast it in this way again. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level.

	Heightened Suspicion. Whenever you take the Search action, you can roll 1d4 and add the number rolled to any ability check made as part of that action.

	Incessant Watchers. You have Disadvantage on saving throws made against the Scrying spell. In addition, immediately after you make a D20 Test and roll a 1 on the d20, paranoia threatens to overwhelm you. Make a Wisdom saving throw (DC 13 plus your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, you have Disadvantage on D20 Tests for 1 minute. You can repeat the save at the end of each of your turns, ending the effect early on a success.

Source:	Ravenloft: The Horrors Within</text>
    <roll description="Add to Roll">1d4</roll>
  </feat>
</compendium>
