<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Fighter [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Fighter Subclass: Hell Knight (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighter Subclass: Hell Knight (UA)</name>
        <text>Inflict Hellish Wounds and Damn Enemies

Hell Knights are the champions of archdevils and other high-ranking fiends of the Nine Hells, such as cambions and night hags. Armed with the techniques of the Nine Hells' fiercest warriors, Hell Knights inflict infernal wounds and fight with the tenacity of a devil.
	Devils and other sinister figures employ Hell Knights to enact their will across the multiverse. A Hell Knight might serve as a soldier on the front lines of the Blood War, while another might be tasked with punishing creatures that violate infernal contracts or flee their consequences. Others act as interplanar bounty hunters, hastening the journey of wicked souls to the River Styx.
	A Hell Knight's relationship with the Nine Hells is transactional. Archdevils see Hell Knights as an investment, and Hell Knights benefit in turn. The Hell Knight Pursuits table lists reasons why a Fighter might become a Hell Knight.

Hell Knight Pursuits:
1d6 | You Became a Hell Knight Because You ...
1 | Desired treasures only the Nine Hells could grant you.
2 | Hungered for power beyond mortal bounds.
3 | Made a wager with a devil-and lost.
4 | Sacrificed your soul to spare someone else's.
5 | Sought vengeance on an adversary who wronged you deeply.
6 |  Were fooled by fine print in an infernal contract.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Pursuits">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Diabolical Gift (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>As a soldier for the agents of the Nine Hells, you've been given fiendish powers. You gain the following benefits.

	Devil's Sight. You can see normally in Dim Light and Darkness—both magical and nonmagical—within 120 feet of yourself.

	Devil's Tongue. You know Infernal, the language of devils. If you already know Infernal, you learn another language of your choice.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hellfire Weapon (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>When you take the Attack action, you can imbue one weapon that you are holding with hellfire, transforming it into a Hellfire Weapon. It remains transformed in this way for 10 minutes or until you use this feature again, you die, or the weapon is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. You can also end this effect early (no action required).
	While transformed into a Hellfire Weapon, a weapon emits Dim Light in a 5-foot Emanation, and whenever you deal damage with the weapon, it can deal your choice of Fire damage or its normal damage type.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Infernal Wound (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Hellfire Weapon can inflict infernal wounds.

	Infernal Wound Die. You have one Infernal Wound Die, which is a d6.

	Inflicting Infernal Wounds. Once per turn when you hit a creature with your Hellfire Weapon, you can deal extra Fire damage equal to one roll of your Infernal Wound Die and give the target an infernal wound.
	While wounded in this way, the target takes Fire damage equal to one roll of your Infernal Wound Die at the start of each of its turns. This effect lasts for 1 minute, until the target regains Hit Points, or until the target or a creature within 5 feet of the target takes an action to stanch the wound. A target can be affected by only one instance of this feature at a time.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Infernal Wound</name>
        <value>%3</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Hell Knight (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Advanced Wounds (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>When you roll your Infernal Wound Die and roll a 6, you can apply one of the following effects.

	Purulence of Minauros. Caustic pus erupts from the wound. Each creature in a 5-foot Emanation originating from the target takes Acid damage equal to your Constitution modifier, and the target has the Poisoned condition until the start of its next turn.

	Rupture of Cania. The wound ruptures with a spurt of arcane energy. The target takes Force damage equal to your Constitution modifier.

	Stygian Gangrene. Infernal rime spreads out from the wound. The target takes Cold damage equal to your Constitution modifier, and it can't take Reactions until the start of its next turn.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Hell-Forged Equipment (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>Your armor and weapons embody infernal armaments forged in the fires of Avernus, granting you the following benefits.

	Fire Resistance. While wearing armor or wielding a Shield, you have Resistance to Fire damage.

	Unholy Fire. Damage from your weapon attacks and Fighter features ignores Resistance to Fire damage.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Hellfire Surge (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>When you use your Action Surge while wearing armor or wielding a Shield, you can superheat your equipment, causing it to erupt with hellfire in a 10-foot Emanation originating from you. Each creature of your choice in the Emanation must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC equals 8 plus your Constitution modifier and Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, a target takes Fire damage equal to one roll of your Infernal Wound Die and is burning. On a successful save, a target takes half as much damage only.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 7 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Blister of Avernus (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>Your hellfire leaves painful, boiling blisters. When you roll a 6 on your Infernal Wound Die, you can roll another d6 and add it to the damage. The maximum number of d6s you can add to the Infernal Wound's damage on a turn is three.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 7 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Hellfire Condemnation (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>Whenever damage from your Hellfire Weapon or Infernal Wound reduces a creature to 0 Hit Points, the creature dies, and its soul rises from the River Styx as a Lemure in a layer of the Nine Hells of your choice in 1d4 hours. If the creature isn't revived before then, only a Wish spell can return the creature to life.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 7 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Hours">1d4</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Infernal Bargain (Hell Knight (UA))</name>
        <text>When you roll your Infernal Wound Die, you can treat a roll of 1 as a 6.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 7 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
