<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Sorcerer [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Sorcerer Subclass: Demonic Sorcery (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerer Subclass: Demonic Sorcery (UA)</name>
        <text>Summon the Powers of the Abyss

The corruptive magic of demons courses through you, making you a conduit for the infinite layers of the Abyss and their horrors. Your gift might stem from a distant demonic ancestry, a fated encounter with a demon that cursed you, or a brush with the dark hunger of the Abyss.
	The Abyss is a plane of wickedness and disorder, and this chaos echoes in your innate magic. Abyssal energy erupts from you, warping your body and surroundings in tandem with your sorcery.
	These Abyssal eruptions manifest in strange and gruesome ways. Roll on or choose from the Abyssal Manifestations table to inspire how your connection to the Abyss might manifest when you channel your demonic power.

Abyssal Manifestations:
1d6 | Manifestation
1 | Abyssal fissures mar your flesh, revealing windows into a vast demonic realm.
2 | Insects writhe beneath your skin and escape from your mouth, nose, and ears.
3 | Sheets of scorched skin peel from your body.
4 | Your flesh bubbles and froths like a toxic bog.
5 | Your fingers or other extremities discolor as if frostbitten.
6 | You grow a second head. (This has no impact on your game statistics.)

Source:	Villainous Options p. 7 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Manifestation">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Abyssal Rupture (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>When you spend at least 1 Sorcery Point as part of a Magic action or a Bonus Action on your turn, you can unleash one of the following magical effects of your choice. You can do so only once per turn.

	Demonic Lash. One creature you can see within 20 feet of you takes 1d4 Slashing damage, and if it is Large or smaller, you can pull it up to 10 feet closer to you.

	Fiendish Carapace. Until the start of your next turn, attack rolls against you have Disadvantage.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 7 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Slashing Damage">1d4</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Demonic Spells (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Sorcerer level specified in the Demonic Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Demonic Spells:
Sorcerer Level | Spells
3 | Detect Magic, Entangle, Misty Step, Spider Climb
5 | Dispel Magic, Gaseous Form
7 | Confusion, Hallucinatory Terrain
9 | Contact Other Plane, Hallow

Source:	Villainous Options p. 8 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Abyssal Aura (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>When you use Innate Sorcery, you can infuse the chaos of the Abyss into your surroundings. While this use of Innate Sorcery is active, reality warps in a 10-foot Emanation originating from you, filling the area with a demonic effect. Roll on the Abyssal Effects table to determine the effect. If an effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals your spell save DC.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by spending 2 Sorcery Points (no action required).

Abyssal Effects:
1d6 | Effect
1 | Sticky Webs. Thick webs fill the Emanation, making it Difficult Terrain for your enemies. Each enemy that starts its turn in the Emanation must succeed on a Strength saving throw or have the Restrained condition. A creature Restrained by the webs can take an action to make a Strength (Athletics) check against your spell save DC, ending the effect on itself with a successful check.
2 | Caustic Ooze. Slick, oily gunk covers the ground in the Emanation, making it Difficult Terrain for your enemies. Each enemy that starts its turn on the ground in the Emanation takes 1d6 Acid damage and must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or have the Prone condition. This damage increases by 1d6 when you reach Sorcerer levels 11 (2d6) and 16 (3dб).
3 | Terrifying Screams. Each enemy that starts its turn in the Emanation takes 1d6 Psychic damage and must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition until the start of its next turn. This damage increases by 1d6 when you reach Sorcerer levels 11 (2d6) and 16 (3d6).
4 | Enthralling Spores. Intoxicating spores fill the Emanation, which is Heavily Obscured for creatures of your choice. When you reach Sorcerer level 11, each enemy that starts its turn in the Emanation must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Charmed condition until the start of its next turn.
5 | Poisonous Foliage. The Emanation is Lightly Obscured by demonic flora. Each enemy that starts its turn in the Emanation takes 1d6 Poison damage and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or have the Poisoned condition until the start of its next turn. This damage increases by 1d6 when you reach Sorcerer levels 11 (2d6) and 16 (3d6).
6 | Enervating Bones. Spectral limbs erupt from the ground, reaching to sap the life around them. Each enemy that starts its turn in the Emanation takes 1d10 Necrotic damage and can't regain Hit Points until the start of its next turn. The Necrotic damage increases by 1d10 when you reach Sorcerer levels 11 (2d10) and 16 (3d10).

Source:	Villainous Options p. 8 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Effect">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="Acid Damage">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="When">1d6</roll>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll description="Psychic Damage">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="When">1d6</roll>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll description="Poison Damage">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="When">1d6</roll>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">1d10</roll>
        <roll description="When">1d10</roll>
        <roll>2d10</roll>
        <roll>3d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Abyssal Aura</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Demonic Sorcery (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Abyssal Conduit (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Abyssal powers reach their full potential. You gain the following benefits.

	Aura Expansion. Your Abyssal Aura is now a 20-foot Emanation.

	Controlled Chaos. Whenever you would roll on the Abyssal Effects table, you can roll twice and choose which of the two effects to use. If you roll the same number on both dice, you can instead choose any effect on the table.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 8 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Fiendish Servant (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>You can cast Summon Fiend without a Material component. You can also cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in this way when you finish a Long Rest. When you cast it in this way, you must choose Demon for the summoned Fiend's type.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 8 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Fiendish Servant</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Demonic Sorcery (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Magic</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Entangle</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Misty Step</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spider Climb</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Magic</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Gaseous Form</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Confusion</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallucinatory Terrain</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contact Other Plane</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallow</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [5.5e] (Demonic Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
