<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <text>Death knights are dastards, deserters, and disgraced champions, undead warriors who march toward perdition to fulfill selfish desires and slake their bloodthirst. A death knight's martial prowess is inextricably tied to their evil nature, but their heinous deeds extend far beyond the battlefield.

Death Knight Journeys:
While each death knight is unique, every death knight's descent into villainy begins with a significant and dishonorable act—a deliberate wrongdoing or shameful mistake that marks their disgrace. You can roll on or choose from the Death Knight Journeys table to determine why your character has chosen to walk this path.

Death Knight Journeys:
1d6 | You Fell from Grace When You ...
1 | Abandoned your companions in battle.
2 | Betrayed a loved one.
3 | Intentionally harmed an innocent.
4 | Made a pact with a malevolent entity such as a demon lord.
5 | Offended a benevolent god.
6 | Violated a sworn oath.

Death Knights Across the Multiverse:
The death knights of D&amp;D are dramatic figures whose tragic fates result from equally tragic sins. On many worlds, death knights' misdeeds spell doom not just for themselves and their companions but for entire kingdoms.
	Notable death knights across the multiverse include the following:

	Lord Soth, Knight of the Black Rose and ruler of Dargaard Keep on the world of Krynn.

	Olanthius, former general of the angel Zariel who became a death knight after Zariel's fall from grace.

	Saint Kargoth, favored servant of the demon lord Demogorgon and Greyhawk's first death knight.

While most death knights refuse to atone for the acts that made them, it's possible for a death knight to repent and end their curse. Such was the fate of Lord Vanrak Moonstar of Waterdeep, who repented to Selûne for betraying her in favor of her nemesis, Shar.
	For more on death knights, see the Monster Manual.

Path of the Death Knight Feats:
The following feats represent one path a character can take to become a death knight. To complete the Path of the Death Knight, begin by taking the Death Knight Initiate feat, followed by any other Path of the Death Knight feat you choose. Finally, when you reach level 12 or higher, take the Death Knight Ascension feat.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 9 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <roll description="Death Knight Journeys">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Death Knight Initiate (Strength) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Weapon Mastery Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Death Points. Your dedication to the path of the Death Knight gives you access to profane powers of undeath. Your ability to use such powers is represented by Death Points. You have a number of Death Points equal to your Proficiency Bonus. You regain all expended Death Points when you finish a Long Rest.
	You can expend Death Points to use certain Path of the Death Knight benefits. This feat gives you one such benefit: Dread Strike.

	Dread Strike. You always have the Wrathful Smite spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. When you expend Death Points to cast Wrathful Smite, the target has Disadvantage on Wisdom saving throws to avoid or end the spell's effect. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 9 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Death Knight Initiate (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Weapon Mastery Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Death Points. Your dedication to the path of the Death Knight gives you access to profane powers of undeath. Your ability to use such powers is represented by Death Points. You have a number of Death Points equal to your Proficiency Bonus. You regain all expended Death Points when you finish a Long Rest.
	You can expend Death Points to use certain Path of the Death Knight benefits. This feat gives you one such benefit: Dread Strike.

	Dread Strike. You always have the Wrathful Smite spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. When you expend Death Points to cast Wrathful Smite, the target has Disadvantage on Wisdom saving throws to avoid or end the spell's effect. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 9 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Dread Authority (Constitution) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Constitution or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Dread Command. You always have the Command spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. When you expend Death Points to cast Command, Undead targeted by it have Disadvantage on the saving throw against the spell.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 9 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Dread Authority (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Constitution or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Dread Command. You always have the Command spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. When you expend Death Points to cast Command, Undead targeted by it have Disadvantage on the saving throw against the spell.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 9 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Harbinger of Doom (Strength) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Ill Omen. You always have the Bane spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. When you expend Death Points to cast Bane, affected targets subtract 1d6 from attack rolls and saving throws instead of 1d4.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Subtract from Roll">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Harbinger of Doom (Constitution) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Ill Omen. You always have the Bane spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. When you expend Death Points to cast Bane, affected targets subtract 1d6 from attack rolls and saving throws instead of 1d4.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Subtract from Roll">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Harbinger of Doom (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Ill Omen. You always have the Bane spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. When you expend Death Points to cast Bane, affected targets subtract 1d6 from attack rolls and saving throws instead of 1d4.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Subtract from Roll">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Deathly Presence (Strength) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 8+, Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Awful Presence. You always have the Fear spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. When you expend Death Points to cast Fear, you deal 7 (2d6) Psychic damage to each creature that fails its saving throw against the spell, in addition to the spell's normal effects.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Psychic Damage">2d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Deathly Presence (Constitution) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 8+, Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Awful Presence. You always have the Fear spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. When you expend Death Points to cast Fear, you deal 7 (2d6) Psychic damage to each creature that fails its saving throw against the spell, in addition to the spell's normal effects.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Psychic Damage">2d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Deathly Presence (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 8+, Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Awful Presence. You always have the Fear spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have. When you expend Death Points to cast Fear, you deal 7 (2d6) Psychic damage to each creature that fails its saving throw against the spell, in addition to the spell's normal effects.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Psychic Damage">2d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Unholy Steed (Strength) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 8+, Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Spectral Steed. You always have the Find Steed spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. When you expend Death Points to cast Find Steed, the summoned steed is a Fiend, and targets you choose have Disadvantage on the Wisdom saving throw against its Fell Glare. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Unholy Steed (Constitution) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 8+, Death Knight Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Spectral Steed. You always have the Find Steed spell prepared. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can cast it without expending a spell slot by expending 1 Death Point. When you expend Death Points to cast Find Steed, the summoned steed is a Fiend, and targets you choose have Disadvantage on the Wisdom saving throw against its Fell Glare. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Death Knight Ascension (Strength) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 12+, two Path of the Death Knight Feats</prerequisite>
    <text>Your path to becoming a death knight is complete. You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Undead. Your creature type is Undead.

	Unholy Anatomy. You have Resistance to Necrotic and Poison damage. You don't gain Exhaustion levels from dehydration, malnutrition, or suffocation.

	Hellfire Orb. As a Magic action, you can expend 1 to 5 Death Points to throw an orb of pure hellfire at a point you can see within 120 feet. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius Sphere centered on the chosen point makes a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Charisma modifier and Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, a target takes 2d6 Fire damage and 2d6 Necrotic damage per Death Point expended. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Death Knight: Death Knight Ascension (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 12+, two Path of the Death Knight Feats</prerequisite>
    <text>Your path to becoming a death knight is complete. You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Undead. Your creature type is Undead.

	Unholy Anatomy. You have Resistance to Necrotic and Poison damage. You don't gain Exhaustion levels from dehydration, malnutrition, or suffocation.

	Hellfire Orb. As a Magic action, you can expend 1 to 5 Death Points to throw an orb of pure hellfire at a point you can see within 120 feet. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius Sphere centered on the chosen point makes a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Charisma modifier and Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, a target takes 2d6 Fire damage and 2d6 Necrotic damage per Death Point expended. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 10 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <text>Liches are powerful spellcasters who have conquered death through the relentless pursuit of arcane power. All liches undergo a ritual that binds their soul to a spirit jar, a personal and well-protected object that allows the lich's destroyed body to re-form as long as the object is intact.

Lich Rites:
The path to lichdom is unique to each who walks it. To complete the transformation, aspirants must fulfill a personal and often profane ritual. The Lich Rites table contains examples of such rituals to inspire your journey.

Lich Rites:
1d6 | To Conduct Your Ritual, You Must...
1 | Consume one hundred souls to strengthen your magic.
2 | Decipher and recite a forbidden incantation from a lost tome written in a dead language.
3 | Use ancient abjuration magic to conceal yourself from the gods of death.
4 | Pen a blasphemous verse and perform it in a defiled temple.
5 | Craft a potion from your victims' remains and imbibe it beneath a full moon.
6 | Corrupt your soul so completely no afterlife will accept it.

Liches Across The Multiverse:
While the most infamous liches in D&amp;D represent evil incarnate, liches can vary in alignments, motivations, and deeds. Those who achieve lichdom make their mark on the multiverse as demigods and despots, mentors and protectors, masters and manipulators. These storied beings include the following:

	Renwick Caradoon, founder of the Knights of Samular in the city of Waterdeep

	Szass Tam, Thay's zulkir of necromancy

	Vecna the Archlich, Oerthian king and demigod of secrets and evil magic

	Vlaakith the Lich-Queen, the ironfisted leader of the githyanki

	Zlan, the frozen amalgamation of the seven liches who created the Crystal Shard

All liches have in common their arcane prowess, their undead nature, and the sequestering of their souls. For more on liches, see the Monster Manual.

Path of the Lich Feats:
The following Path of the Lich feats represent one path a character can take to become a lich. To complete the Path of the Lich, begin by taking the Lich Initiate feat, followed by any other Path of the Lich feat you choose. Finally, when you reach level 12 or higher, take the Lich Ascension feat.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 11</text>
    <roll description="Lich Rites">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Lich Initiate (Intelligence) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Spellcasting or Pact Magic Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>You take the first steps toward lichdom, which involve creating your spirit jar, a magical vessel that anchors your soul to the world of the living in the event of your body's destruction.
	You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Creating Your Spirit Jar. Choose a Tiny object of great significance to you. Roll on or choose from the Spirit Jars table to inspire this object. You spend a Long Rest anchoring your soul to this object, allowing you to consume the souls of the living to bolster your own power. You can have only one spirit jar at a time. If you create a second spirit jar, the old one is destroyed.

Spirit Jars:
1d6 | Your Spirit Jar Is...
1 | An acorn from a forest destroyed long ago.
2 | A love letter from a deceased paramour.
3 | The inkwell that you used to scribe your first spell or prayer.
4 | The defaced holy symbol of a god you've denounced.
5 | A bell whose toll becomes lower with each soul you collect.
6 | A desiccated body part—such as an eye, finger, or horn-that was once part of you or someone you knew.

	Spirit Jar Destruction. Your spirit jar's Armor Class equals your spell save DC, and it has a number of Hit Points equal to your spellcasting ability modifier plus your character level. If your spirit jar is destroyed, you gain 2 Exhaustion levels, and you can't use the Soul Siphon ability until you create a new one.

	Soul Siphon. When you reduce a Humanoid enemy to 0 Hit Points, you can consume its soul and gain a boost of arcane energy (no action required). On your next turn, the first creature you hit with an attack takes extra Necrotic damage equal to 1d6 plus your spellcasting ability modifier. You also gain this benefit if someone else reduces a Humanoid enemy within 10 feet of you to 0 Hit Points. A soul consumed in this way can be restored only by a True Resurrection or Wish spell.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 11</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Spirit Jar">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Extra Necrotic Damage">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Lich Initiate (Wisdom) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Spellcasting or Pact Magic Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>You take the first steps toward lichdom, which involve creating your spirit jar, a magical vessel that anchors your soul to the world of the living in the event of your body's destruction.
	You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Creating Your Spirit Jar. Choose a Tiny object of great significance to you. Roll on or choose from the Spirit Jars table to inspire this object. You spend a Long Rest anchoring your soul to this object, allowing you to consume the souls of the living to bolster your own power. You can have only one spirit jar at a time. If you create a second spirit jar, the old one is destroyed.

Spirit Jars:
1d6 | Your Spirit Jar Is...
1 | An acorn from a forest destroyed long ago.
2 | A love letter from a deceased paramour.
3 | The inkwell that you used to scribe your first spell or prayer.
4 | The defaced holy symbol of a god you've denounced.
5 | A bell whose toll becomes lower with each soul you collect.
6 | A desiccated body part—such as an eye, finger, or horn-that was once part of you or someone you knew.

	Spirit Jar Destruction. Your spirit jar's Armor Class equals your spell save DC, and it has a number of Hit Points equal to your spellcasting ability modifier plus your character level. If your spirit jar is destroyed, you gain 2 Exhaustion levels, and you can't use the Soul Siphon ability until you create a new one.

	Soul Siphon. When you reduce a Humanoid enemy to 0 Hit Points, you can consume its soul and gain a boost of arcane energy (no action required). On your next turn, the first creature you hit with an attack takes extra Necrotic damage equal to 1d6 plus your spellcasting ability modifier. You also gain this benefit if someone else reduces a Humanoid enemy within 10 feet of you to 0 Hit Points. A soul consumed in this way can be restored only by a True Resurrection or Wish spell.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 11</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Spirit Jar">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Extra Necrotic Damage">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Lich Initiate (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Spellcasting or Pact Magic Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>You take the first steps toward lichdom, which involve creating your spirit jar, a magical vessel that anchors your soul to the world of the living in the event of your body's destruction.
	You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Creating Your Spirit Jar. Choose a Tiny object of great significance to you. Roll on or choose from the Spirit Jars table to inspire this object. You spend a Long Rest anchoring your soul to this object, allowing you to consume the souls of the living to bolster your own power. You can have only one spirit jar at a time. If you create a second spirit jar, the old one is destroyed.

Spirit Jars:
1d6 | Your Spirit Jar Is...
1 | An acorn from a forest destroyed long ago.
2 | A love letter from a deceased paramour.
3 | The inkwell that you used to scribe your first spell or prayer.
4 | The defaced holy symbol of a god you've denounced.
5 | A bell whose toll becomes lower with each soul you collect.
6 | A desiccated body part—such as an eye, finger, or horn-that was once part of you or someone you knew.

	Spirit Jar Destruction. Your spirit jar's Armor Class equals your spell save DC, and it has a number of Hit Points equal to your spellcasting ability modifier plus your character level. If your spirit jar is destroyed, you gain 2 Exhaustion levels, and you can't use the Soul Siphon ability until you create a new one.

	Soul Siphon. When you reduce a Humanoid enemy to 0 Hit Points, you can consume its soul and gain a boost of arcane energy (no action required). On your next turn, the first creature you hit with an attack takes extra Necrotic damage equal to 1d6 plus your spellcasting ability modifier. You also gain this benefit if someone else reduces a Humanoid enemy within 10 feet of you to 0 Hit Points. A soul consumed in this way can be restored only by a True Resurrection or Wish spell.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 11</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Spirit Jar">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Extra Necrotic Damage">1d6</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Arcane Restoration (Intelligence) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Essence Rejuvenation. When you use Soul Siphon to consume a soul, you can choose one or more expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level equal to no more than 4. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Arcane Restoration (Wisdom) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Essence Rejuvenation. When you use Soul Siphon to consume a soul, you can choose one or more expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level equal to no more than 4. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Arcane Restoration (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Essence Rejuvenation. When you use Soul Siphon to consume a soul, you can choose one or more expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level equal to no more than 4. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Transfer Life (Intelligence) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Soul Transference. When you use Soul Siphon to consume a soul, you can choose a creature within 60 feet of yourself to gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your Proficiency Bonus plus your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of 1 Temporary Hit Point.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Transfer Life (Wisdom) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Soul Transference. When you use Soul Siphon to consume a soul, you can choose a creature within 60 feet of yourself to gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your Proficiency Bonus plus your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of 1 Temporary Hit Point.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Transfer Life (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Soul Transference. When you use Soul Siphon to consume a soul, you can choose a creature within 60 feet of yourself to gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your Proficiency Bonus plus your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of 1 Temporary Hit Point.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Undead Grasp (Intelligence) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Paralyzing Touch. You know the Chill Touch cantrip. If you already know it, you learn another cantrip of your choice. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

When you deal damage with Chill Touch, you can expend a level 1+ spell slot to attempt to paralyze the target. The target takes an extra 1d10 Necrotic damage per level of the spell slot expended and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or have the Paralyzed condition until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Extra Necrotic Damage">1d10</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Undead Grasp (Wisdom) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Paralyzing Touch. You know the Chill Touch cantrip. If you already know it, you learn another cantrip of your choice. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

When you deal damage with Chill Touch, you can expend a level 1+ spell slot to attempt to paralyze the target. The target takes an extra 1d10 Necrotic damage per level of the spell slot expended and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or have the Paralyzed condition until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Extra Necrotic Damage">1d10</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Undead Grasp (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Lich Initiate Feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Paralyzing Touch. You know the Chill Touch cantrip. If you already know it, you learn another cantrip of your choice. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat).

When you deal damage with Chill Touch, you can expend a level 1+ spell slot to attempt to paralyze the target. The target takes an extra 1d10 Necrotic damage per level of the spell slot expended and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or have the Paralyzed condition until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Extra Necrotic Damage">1d10</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Lich Ascension (Intelligence) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 12+, at least two Path of the Lich Feats</prerequisite>
    <text>Your path to lichdom is complete. You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Undead. Your creature type is Undead.

	Unholy Anatomy. You have Resistance to Necrotic and Poison damage. You don't gain Exhaustion levels from dehydration, malnutrition, or suffocation.

	Frightening Gaze. You learn the Fear spell if you don't already know it, and you always have it prepared. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast the spell without expending a spell slot a number of times equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Rejuvenation. If you die, you re-form in 1d10 days if you have a spirit jar and aren't revived before then. You gain a new body, appearing with all your Hit Points in the nearest unoccupied space within 5 feet of your spirit jar.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Days">1d10</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Lich Ascension (Wisdom) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 12+, at least two Path of the Lich Feats</prerequisite>
    <text>Your path to lichdom is complete. You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Undead. Your creature type is Undead.

	Unholy Anatomy. You have Resistance to Necrotic and Poison damage. You don't gain Exhaustion levels from dehydration, malnutrition, or suffocation.

	Frightening Gaze. You learn the Fear spell if you don't already know it, and you always have it prepared. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast the spell without expending a spell slot a number of times equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Rejuvenation. If you die, you re-form in 1d10 days if you have a spirit jar and aren't revived before then. You gain a new body, appearing with all your Hit Points in the nearest unoccupied space within 5 feet of your spirit jar.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Days">1d10</roll>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Path of the Lich: Lich Ascension (Charisma) (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 12+, at least two Path of the Lich Feats</prerequisite>
    <text>Your path to lichdom is complete. You gain the following benefits.

	Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	Undead. Your creature type is Undead.

	Unholy Anatomy. You have Resistance to Necrotic and Poison damage. You don't gain Exhaustion levels from dehydration, malnutrition, or suffocation.

	Frightening Gaze. You learn the Fear spell if you don't already know it, and you always have it prepared. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast the spell without expending a spell slot a number of times equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Rejuvenation. If you die, you re-form in 1d10 days if you have a spirit jar and aren't revived before then. You gain a new body, appearing with all your Hit Points in the nearest unoccupied space within 5 feet of your spirit jar.

Source:	Villainous Options p. 12</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
    <roll description="Days">1d10</roll>
  </feat>
</compendium>
