<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <!--<monster><name>Siege Staff</name><size>H</size><type>arcane artillery (staff), requires attunement by a spellcaster</type><ac>15</ac><hp>120</hp><languages/><cr/><vulnerable/><resist/><immune>poison, psychic</immune><conditionImmune/><senses/><description>Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 18 (Third Party)</description><environment/></monster>-->
  <monster>
    <name>Siege Staff, Black</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>arcane artillery (staff), requires attunement by a spellcaster</type>
    <ac>15</ac>
    <hp>120</hp>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>poison, psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <action>
      <name>Blast Staff</name>
      <text>This model was typically used to bombard massed troops or villages, unleashing a wide burst of energy. It has a range of 300/1200 feet and targets all creatures within a 60-foot-radius sphere. This attack deals 9 (2d8) force damage, or half on a successful Dexterity save.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Siege staffs, the primary form of arcane artillery, are made of wood-typically around fifteen feet long-engraved with mystic sigils and inlaid with dragonshards.
	Activating a siege staff takes three actions: one to prime the staff; one action to aim it; and one action to release the spell.
	There are several basic models, each of which serves a different purpose. When activated, it produces one effect, determined by its model.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 18 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Siege Staff, Force</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>arcane artillery (staff), requires attunement by a spellcaster</type>
    <ac>15</ac>
    <hp>120</hp>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>poison, psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <action>
      <name>Force Staff</name>
      <text>This model releases focused blasts of pure energy. Developed late in the war, these were primarily used to target fortifications, warforged titans, and airships. It has a range of 600/2400 feet and deals 44 (8d10) force damage.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage||8d10</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Siege staffs, the primary form of arcane artillery, are made of wood-typically around fifteen feet long-engraved with mystic sigils and inlaid with dragonshards.
	Activating a siege staff takes three actions: one to prime the staff; one action to aim it; and one action to release the spell.
	There are several basic models, each of which serves a different purpose. When activated, it produces one effect, determined by its model.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 18 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Siege Staff, Focus</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>arcane artillery (staff), requires attunement by a spellcaster</type>
    <ac>15</ac>
    <hp>120</hp>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>poison, psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <action>
      <name>Focus Staff</name>
      <text>This model amplifies the spells cast by an attuned spellcaster. Any spell that requires an attack roll or saving throw can be cast through this model of siege staff. The range is magnified by a factor of 5, with a long range of up to 10 times the spell's standard range—so a fire bolt cast through a siege staff has a range of 600 feet and a long range of 1,200 feet. The spell's area of effect is doubled. If the spell normally affects a single target, it instead affects a 20-foot-radius sphere; if the spell normally requires an attack roll, targets must instead make a Dexterity saving throw. On a successful save, the target takes half damage and suffers no other effect.</text>
    </action>
    <description>Siege staffs, the primary form of arcane artillery, are made of wood-typically around fifteen feet long-engraved with mystic sigils and inlaid with dragonshards.
	Activating a siege staff takes three actions: one to prime the staff; one action to aim it; and one action to release the spell.
	There are several basic models, each of which serves a different purpose. When activated, it produces one effect, determined by its model.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 18 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <!--<monster><name>Long Rod</name><size>H</size><type>arcane artillery (staff), requires attunement by a spellcaster</type><ac>15</ac><hp>40</hp><languages/><cr/><vulnerable/><resist/><immune>poison, psychic</immune><conditionImmune/><senses/><description>A long rod is a more portable version of a siege staff, measuring around 8 feet long. Including the stand required to brace it, it weighs close to 350 pounds.
	It takes five actions to set up a long rod, and the same to tear down for transport. Once set up, it takes one action to prime the rod, one to aim it, and one to fire it.
	Any spell that requires an attack roll or saving throw can be cast through the long rod. The range is magnified by a factor of 3, with a long range of up to 6 times the spell's standard range. The spell's area of effect is increased to 150%. If the spell normally affects a single target, it instead affects a 10-foot-radius sphere; if the spell normally requires an attack roll, targets must instead make a Dexterity saving throw. On a successful save, the target takes half damage and suffers no other effect.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 19 (Third Party)</description><environment/></monster>-->
  <monster>
    <name>Valaara</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>aberration</type>
    <alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
    <ac>20 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>275 (29d8+145)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft., fly 40 ft. (hover)</speed>
    <str>21</str>
    <dex>25</dex>
    <con>21</con>
    <int>24</int>
    <wis>22</wis>
    <cha>25</cha>
    <save>Int +14, Wis +13, Cha +14</save>
    <skill>Arcana +14, Deception +14, Nature +14, Perception +13</skill>
    <passive>23</passive>
    <languages>Deep Speech, telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>23</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>poison, psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune>blinded, charmed, frightened, poisoned, prone</conditionImmune>
    <senses>truesight 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+7</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alien Mind</name>
      <text>If a creature tries to read Valaara's thoughts or deals psychic damage to it, that creature must succeed on a DC 22 Intelligence saving throw or be stunned for 1 minute. The stunned creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/DAY</recharge>
      <text>If Valaara fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>Valaara has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regeneration</name>
      <text>Valaara regains 20 hit points at the start of its turn. If Valaara takes radiant damage, this trait doesn't function at the start of Valaara's next turn. Valaara dies only if it starts its turn with 0 hit points and doesn't regenerate.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Teleport</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, Valaara can teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space it can see.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>Valaara makes two attacks with its chitinous claw or chitinous spine, and can use its Summon Swarm once.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Chitinous Claw</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 18 (2d10 + 7) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+14|2d10+7</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Chitinous Spine</name>
      <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, range 60/180 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (3d6 + 7) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+14|3d6+7</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Summon Swarms</name>
      <text>Valaara summons a swarm of insects and arachnids that cover a 10-foot-radius sphere at a point of its choosing within 120 feet, afflicting all creatures in the area with one of the following effects (roll a d6 or choose one), to which Valaara is immune:

d6 | Swarm
1. Stinging Wasps. Each creature must make a DC 22 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 32 (5d12) piercing damage and has disadvantage on attack rolls until the end of its next turn. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and doesn't have disadvantage on attack rolls.
2. Spinning Spiders. Each creature must succeed on a DC 22 Dexterity saving throw or take 27 (6d8) bludgeoning damage and be restrained for 1 minute as it is squeezed by the webbing. A restrained creature can escape with a successful DC 22 Strength (Athletics) check as an action.
3. Venomous Centipedes. Each creature must make a DC 22 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 22 (4d10) poison damage and is poisoned for 1 minute. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage, but is still poisoned.
4. Infesting Grubs. Each creature must succeed on a DC 22 Dexterity saving throw or be infested by 4 (1d4+2) rot grubs. At the start of each of an infected creature's turns, it takes 1d6 piercing damage per rot grub infesting it. Applying fire to the bite wound before the end of the creature's next turn deals 1 fire damage to the creature and kills these rot grubs, ending the effect. After this time, these ro grubs are too far under the skin to be burned. If a target infested by rot grubs ends its turn with 0 hit points, it dies as the rot grubs burrow into its heart and kill it. Any effect that cures disease kills all rot grubs infesting the target, ending the effect.
5. Discordant Cicadas. Each creature must succeed on a DC 22 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. While a creature is frightened in this way, it is incapacitated. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature's saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature has advantage against future saves against this swarm for the next 24 hours.
6. Psychoactive Beetles. Each creature must succeed on a DC 22 Intelligence saving throw or take 33 (6d10) psychic damage as it suffers from intense hallucinations.</text>
      <attack>Summon Swarm||1d6</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage||5d12</attack>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage||6d8</attack>
      <attack>Poison Damage||4d10</attack>
      <attack>Rot Grubs||1d4+2</attack>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||6d10</attack>
      <attack>Piercing Damage||1d6</attack>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <name>Legendary Actions</name>
      <recharge>3/TURN</recharge>
      <text>Valaara can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. Valaara regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Throw Spine</name>
      <text>Valaara makes one chitinous spine attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Synthesize Worm (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
      <text>Valaara fuses the swarms under its command, forming a carrion crawler (see its entry in the Monster Manual) in an unoccupied space of Valaara's choosing within 90 feet of it. The carrion crawler is under Valaara's control and acts immediately after Valaara in the initiative order.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Imaginary Crawlers (Costs 3 Actions)</name>
      <text>Valaara touches the mind of mortals, implanting a suggestion that her creatures have burrowed under their skin. One target of Valaara's choice within 60 feet that she can see must succeed on a DC 22 Wisdom saving throw or take 22 (4d10) psychic damage and immediately lose concentration on any spell it is concentrating on.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||4d10</attack>
    </legendary>
    <legendary category="lair">
      <name>Valaara's Lair
like Other Daelkyr, Valaara Is Bound Within a Demiplane In
khyber</name>
      <text>Like other daelkyr, Valaara is bound within a demiplane in Khyber. However, Valaara has bred burrowing worms that chew through the fabric of reality, carving a web of passages between her Deepest Hive and the world above. An organization that discovers the upper layers of these tunnels could use them to move swiftly across the world, entering a tunnel in the Lhazaar Principalities, traveling five miles, and emerging in Sarlona or the Eldeen Reaches. Smugglers or explorers might make use of this wonder, never knowing what lies in the deeper tunnelsuntil Valaara's minions seize them, or until they are consumed by the psychic influence of the Crawling Queen. While tunnels to the Deepest Hive can appear anywhere that suits the story, they are also less permanent than the ties between Eberron and the realms of many other daelkyr. A tunnel to the Deepest Hive can appear wherever it suits the needs of a story, but it's also possible to collapse a passage and break a connection.
	The upper tunnels of Valaara's realm are usually formed of fused glass-like material, then as explorers delve deeper, they find the walls formed of chitin and muscle, with insects swarming across every surface. One might discover pulsing cocoons, nests of slumbering purple worms, or chambers lined with thousands of glowing eggs. And in the heart is the Deepest Hive itself, where Valaara weaves its webs and conducts its sinister experiments.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary category="lair">
      <name>Lair Actions</name>
      <text>While within its lair, Valaara can invoke the ambient magic to take lair actions. On initiative count 20 (losing initiative ties), Valaara can take a lair action to cause one of the following effects; it can't use the same lair action two rounds in a row:

	• Valaara chooses one target and use its Summon Swarm ability against it.

	• Valaara subsumes creatures into its hive consciousness. Each creature it can see within its lair must succeed on a DC 22 Wisdom saving throw or be charmed for 1 minute. While charmed in this way, a creature must use its action at the start of its turn before moving to make a melee attack against another creature of Valaara's choice within reach. If there are no creatures within reach, the charmed creature can act normally for that turn. A charmed creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turn, ending the effect on itself on a success.

	• A 50-foot-radius area of ground within 120 feet of Valaara becomes swarmed by fear moths until initiative count 20 on the round after next. During that time, each creature that starts or ends its turn in the area must make a DC 22 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, any immunity to or advantage against fear is negated and it has disadvantage on saves against fear for one minute.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary category="lair">
      <name>Regional Effects</name>
      <text>Tunnels to the Deepest Hive can appear anywhere. A region containing a passage to the Deepest Hive can be warped in one or more of these ways:

	• Insect and arachnid presence increases dramatically within 5 miles of the passage, and insects display unnatural swarming behavior.

	• Beasts that live within a mile of the passage may undergo physical transformation, developing insect characteristics such as compound eyes, extra limbs, chitinous plating, and hive behavior.

	• If a humanoid creature spends at least 1 hour within 1 mile of the passage, it must succeed on a DC 22 Wisdom saving throw or descend into a type of madness (see "Madness of Valaara" below). A creature that succeeds on this saving throw can't be affected by this regional effect again for 24 hours.

These regional effects build over time. If a passage has just appeared, there may be a slight increase in insect activity and the saving throw on the madness effect will be much lower. The longer the passage remains, the more notable the effects become. If Valaara dies or if the passage is destroyed, the effects fade away after 1d10 days.</text>
      <attack>Days||1d10</attack>
    </legendary>
    <legendary category="lair">
      <name>Madness of Valaara</name>
      <text>If a creature goes mad in Valaara's lair or while it can see the daelkyr, it gains a form of indefinite madness. Roll on the Madness of Valaara table to determine the nature of this madness, which takes the form of a character flaw that lasts until cured. Chapter 8 of the Dungeon Master's Guide has more information on madness.

Madness of Valaara:
d6 | Flaw (lasts until cured)
1 | "There are worms crawling through my flesh."
2 | "I hear secrets in the buzzing of insects."
3 | "I am undergoing a metamorphosis into a glorious insect form."
4 | "I have a psychic connection to one or more people."
5 | "I must serve my hive and protect my queen."
6 | "I am an insect that's evolved into humanoid form."</text>
    </legendary>
    <description>Valaara is known as the Crawling Queen, the Watcher in the Walls, and the Keeper of Worms. It's said that you can hear Valaara's voice in the rustling of roaches and the keening of locusts. In some tales, Valaara crafts worms that crawl through the ear and consume a creature's brain; in others, when its maggots devour a corpse, Valaara can recreate the victim in its Deepest Hive. No one knows what Valaara wants, but its minions could be all around you even now, crawling in your walls and moving beneath your feet.

	Chitin Consciousness. Valaara embodies the alien nature of insects in all aspects. Valaara's symbionts may be formed from chitin, but it also has creations like the spellburrow and the throwing scarab (detailed in chapter 7)—insects that burrow into the skin of the bearer. Those touched by Valaara may undergo a physical metamorphosis and manifest insect traits, but Valaara's touch can also transform the mind. Some who hear the whispers of the Crawling Queen become fascinated by insects, while others suffer more dramatic transformations. Valaara's most persistent cults spread by forming a hive; one creature becomes the queen, and others touched by this cultist find their original personality and desires fading, consumed by the need to fulfill their purpose in the hive. Usually this effect is limited, a psychic connection that only binds a few people;
but in a few cases, this psychic contagion has been virulent and contagious, consuming entire towns.

	Valaara's Minions. The cults of the Crawling Queen are described in detail in chapter 3. Valaara doesn't use dolgaunts or dolgrims; rather, it often transforms humanoids into insect forms. These creatures use the statistics of thri-kreen, driders, or umber hulks, but their appearance can vary dramatically; a group of servitors could be roach-people as opposed to the typical mantis form of the thri-kreen. In other places it works through consuming worms, producing creatures with the statistics of spawn of Kyuss. In general, Valaara may employ any sort of creature thematically related to insects or worms, from simple swarms and giant spiders to carrion crawlers, ankhegs, remorhazes, or even purple worms. But these monsters should be seen as a starting point. Like all daelkyr, Valaara is constantly experimenting and creating new things. Imagine a purple worm with malign intelligence and psychic powers, or teleporting ankhegs that burrow through the fabric of space.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 234 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>The Forest Queen</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>fey</type>
    <alignment>neutral</alignment>
    <ac>15 (20 in the Endless Weald)</ac>
    <hp>238 (28d10+84)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>20</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>20</int>
    <wis>22</wis>
    <cha>26</cha>
    <save>Dex +12, Wis +13, Cha +15</save>
    <skill>Animal Handling +13, Deception +22, Insight +13, Nature +19, Perception +13, Stealth +12</skill>
    <passive>23</passive>
    <languages>all, telepathy 120ft.</languages>
    <cr>23</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>cold, necrotic, psychic</resist>
    <immune>poison; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from metal weapons</immune>
    <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, frightened, grappled, poisoned, restrained</conditionImmune>
    <senses>truesight 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+7</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Grace of the Forest Queen</name>
      <text>As long as the Forest Queen is within the Endless Weald, her AC is 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen's innate spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 23, +15 to hit with spell attacks). She can innately cast the following spells, requiring no material components:

	• At will: dominate beast, druidcraft, entangle, thorn whip (17th level)
	• 3/Day each: conjure fey, heat metal, polymorph, spike growth, tree stride, wall of thorns
	• 1/Day each: dominate monster, mirage arcane</text>
      <attack>Innate Spellcasting|+15|</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Inscrutable</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen is immune to any effect that would sense her emotions or read her thoughts, as well as any divination spell that she refuses. Wisdom (Insight) checks made to ascertain the Forest Queen's intentions or sincerity have disadvantage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/DAY</recharge>
      <text>If the Forest Queen fails a saving throw, she can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speak with Beasts and Plants</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen can communicate with beasts and plants as if they and the Forest Queen shared a language.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Thelanian Protagonist</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen cannot be permanently killed. If reduced to 0 hit points, she collapses into a pile of quickly drying leaves that fall to the ground and blow away. 1d4 days later, she reforms in the Endless Weald, regaining all her hit points.</text>
      <attack>Days||1d4</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tree Stride</name>
      <text>Once on her turn, the Forest Queen can use 10 feet of her movement to step magically into one living tree within her reach and emerge from a second living tree within 60 feet of the first tree, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the second tree. Both trees must be Large or bigger.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Woodland Camouflage</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide in wooded terrain.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen makes two melee attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Grasping Vine</name>
      <text>Melee Spell Attack: +15 to hit, reach 40 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (3d8 + 8) bludgeoning damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 23). The Forest Queen spawns new vines from the ground, so she has no limit on the number of creatures that she can grapple.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+15|3d8+8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Verdant Staff</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 12(2d6 + 5) bludgeoning damage and 17(5d6) force damage.</text>
      <attack>Verdant Staff|+12|(2d6+5)+(5d6)</attack>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+12|2d6+5</attack>
      <attack>Force Damage||5d6</attack>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <name>Legendary Actions</name>
      <recharge>3/TURN</recharge>
      <text>The Forest Queen can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. The Forest Queen regains spent legendary actions at the start of her turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Attack</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen makes a Grasping Vine or Verdant Staff attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Constrict</name>
      <text>One creature that is grappled by the Forest Queen's Grasping Vine takes 27 (5d10) points of bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage||5d10</attack>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Touch of Nature</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen casts a spell.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary category="lair">
      <name>The Forest Queen's Lair</name>
      <text>The Forest Queen watches over the Endless Weald in Thelanis. Fauns and dryads dance in clearings lit by gleaming sprites, and peaceful beasts congregate by glittering springs. A series of path connects the safe spaces within the woods. But for those who stray from the path, the Endless Weald lives up to its name; such fools can be lost indefinitely, until the Queen takes mercy and leads them out.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary category="lair">
      <name>Lair Actions</name>
      <text>While within the Endless Weald, the Forest Queen can invoke the ambient magic to take lair actions. On initiative count 20 (losing initiative ties), the Forest Queen can take a lair action to cause one of the following effects; she can't use the same effect two rounds in a row:

	• Thick, tangled bushes grow in a 50-foot-square area within 120 feet of the Forest Queen. Each creature within these bushes must use 4 feet of movement for every 1 foot moved. In addition, a creature in the bushes must succeed on a DC 23 Wisdom saving throw or fall asleep due to the sleep-inducing properties of the bush's blooms. A creature sleeping in this manner awakens if it takes damage, if someone uses an action to shake or slap it awake, or at initiative count 20 on the round atter next.

	• The Forest Queen summons a mass of vines and roots from the ground beneath her, forming a nearly impenetrable weave of protection. Until initiative count 20 in the next round, she has total cover.

	• One creature within 90 feet of the Forest Queen must make a DC 23 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target's spellcasting is hampered until initiative count 20 on the round after next. During that time, when the target casts a spell of 1st level or higher, it must expend a spell slot one level higher than the level at which it casts the spell. If the target doesn't have a spell slot of a level higher than the spell, it can't cast that spell.</text>
    </legendary>
    <spells>Dominate Beast, Druidcraft, Entangle, Thorn Whip, Conjure Fey, Heat Metal, Polymorph, Spike Growth, Tree Stride, Wall of Thorns, Dominate Monster, Mirage Arcane</spells>
    <description>There was a time when the world was the wood, when there were no towns or steel. The Forest Gueen ruled the Endless Weald, maintaining peace between people and beasts. But as ages passed, her children grew restless in the shade of her leaves. Her eldest son came to her and said, "Mother, I dream of war! I want to build a fortress and wield a blade of steel." The Queen replied, "Then leave the wood, but do not bring your metal into my domain." And so he left the wood and founded the kingdom of Karrnath. The next day the eldest daughter came before the Queen. "Mother, I dream of magic! I want to build a tower and conjure fire!" The Gueen replied, "Then leave the wood, but do not cast your spells in my domain." And so she left the wood and founded the kingdom of Thaliost. One by one, the Queen's children left her, until she was alone in the woods with the spirits and the beasts. And as each child raised a kingdom, the woods grew smaller and farther apart, and the heart of the Forest Queen grew bitter and cold. The people are her greatgrandchildren, and she will not harm those who stay on the path and respect the beasts of the forest. But those who stray from the path, who conjure fire or hunt with steel, those fools will be lost in the Endless Weald and never again see the light of day. From the Towering Wood in the Eldeen Reaches to the Harrowcrowns of Thrane, from the Greenhaunt of Breland to the Shadowmount Forest of Karrnath, wherever people dwell by the deep forest, they share stories of the Forest Queen. She is the archdryad, linked to every root and bough. She is proud, and when protecting her subjects, she can be ruthless; but she shares many wonders with those who enter her woods with empty hands and open eyes. The story above is clearly apocryphal, but it's a common tale with many variations, such as her children founding nearby towns instead of nations. Regardless, the message is the same: there is a power that watches over the woods. Stories often depend on the character of the local forest; near the Towering Woods, the Forest Queen is often depicted as benevolent, while near the Nightwood of Karnath, they talk of how the betrayals of her children froze the heart of the Forest Queen, leaving her cruel and hungry for revenge.

	The Queen of Weald and Wood. The Forest Queen rules the Endless Weald within Thelanis, an arboreal realm inhabited by dire beasts and wild fey. The Weald often leaks into the wood through manifest zones found in deep forests;
in such places, dryads lurk in the trees and beasts may possess unusual cunning. Under the right circumstances, travelers passing through a zone might even slip into the Weald. Such forests typically have well-worn paths that avoid these pitfalls, thus strengthening the story of stay on the path. The Greensinger druids know rituals to connect a forest to the Endless Weald, establishing a temporary manifest zone in any deep wood. The Queen's influence can also be felt in any forest in times when Eberron and Thelanis are coterminous. Just like the stories, the Queen's personality often reflects the forest where she's currently manifesting; the Forest Queen is more likely to be benevolent in the Twilight Demesne and cruel in the Nightwood.

	The Queen as Ally or Patron. The Forest Queen has close ties to the Greensingers, and any Greensinger druid or ranger could have the Forest Queen as a patron. Shes an option for a warlock with an Archfey patron, but the magic she teaches is primal in nature, not arcane. This doesn't change the spells available to the warlock; their spells simply draw on elemental forces and the power of the fey rather than arcane formulas. As a more exotic option, a character with the Outlander background could have slipped into the Endless Weald as a child and been raised in the court of the Forest Queen.
	Regardless of origin, any character allied with the Forest Queen is expected to follow her rules.

	• Don't use weapons or armor of metal.
	• Don't kill a natural beast with magic or for sport.
	• Protect those who travel on a marked path, unless they harm the forest with their actions.
	• Help any fey of the forest who comes to you in need.

Beyond these basic principles, the Forest Queen's quests typically relate to the woods in some way. An agent of the Forest Queen could be tasked to reconsecrate a grove, to destroy an infestation of aberrations or other unnatural predators, or to prevent an ambitious dragonmarked house from expanding into woodlands. Beyond the forest, an agent could be tasked to recover a relic stolen from the Endless Weald (and once reclaimed, perhaps entrusted to carry this artifact on their adventures). Agents of the Forest Queen might be charged to act as envoys, negotiating with agents of other archfey or dealing with the Feyspires. Or perhaps there's a darkness in the Endless Weald, a canker that appeared when the forests of Cyre were consumed by the Mourning. The Forest Queen could task mortals to explore this region within the Weald, or charge them to explore the Mournland and to seek a cure for the wounded land.

	The Queen as an Enemy. One could make an enemy of the Queen by breaking one of her rules while in her woods, or perhaps by killing one of her favored beasts or devoted agents. Such a personal enmity could lead to a character being targeted by natural threats—singled out by aggressive beasts, led astray on journeys through wild regions, or targeted by malicious sprites. A character could also earn her ire by taking one of her relics from a forest, perhaps not knowing that the magic item is tied to the wood. On a larger scale, the Forest Queen could grow tired of civilization itself. The forests containing her manifest zones could expand, with fey and feral beasts attacking villages and towns as they're overgrown. Could adventurers find a way to placate the bitter Queen, or must they defeat her to end this advance?

Weapons of Wood and Bone:
The Forest Queen charges those who follow her rules to never kill with steel or wear metal armor. This can be a serious limitation for a ranger or other character that has access to martial weapons or medium or heavy armor. However, they could seek out equipment of bronzewood, an exotic lumber that only grows in Aerenal and in a few groves hidden deep in the Towering Wood. This exceptionally dense wood can be used to fashion armor without metal, which could use the same statistics as any medium or heavy armor. Arrows and crowssbow bolts can also be fashioned from bronzewood, and this exceptionally durable ammunition breaks no more often than its steel counterpart. Similarly, leafweave armor is made from alchemically treated leaves of the bronzewood tree, and can offer the same level of protection as studded leather or a chain shirt.
	Armor and weapons made using these substances are generally only available in Aerenal or within the Towering Woods, but if it fits a character's background, the DM could choose to allow a character's starting equipment to be made from such materials. Another option is a weapon formed from the bones of a monstrosity; here again, the principle is that the weapon is mechanically identical to a standard weapon, but doesn't violate the Forest Queen's ban on metal. If a character is using a bone weapon, there should certainly be a story to it: What creature is it from?
Who killed the beast and shaped the weapon, and how did the character come by it?

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 236 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>The Forgotten Prince</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>fey</type>
    <alignment>chaotic neutral</alignment>
    <ac>22 (Cloaked by Shadows)</ac>
    <hp>237 (25d8+125)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>20</str>
    <dex>26</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>21</int>
    <wis>22</wis>
    <cha>26</cha>
    <save>Dex +15, Int +12, Wis +13, Cha +15</save>
    <skill>Acrobatics +15, Deception +22, Intimidation +15, Perception +13, Sleight of Hand +15, Stealth +15, Survival +13</skill>
    <passive>23</passive>
    <languages>all</languages>
    <cr>21</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>necrotic, psychic; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune>blinded, charmed, exhaustion, frightened, petrified</conditionImmune>
    <senses>truesight 120ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+7</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cloaked by Shadows</name>
      <text>The Prince adds half of his Charisma modifier as a bonus to his AC.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Step</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, the Prince can teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space he can see.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The Prince's innate spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 23, +15 to hit with spell attacks). He can innately cast the following spells, requiring no material components:

	• At will: chill touch (17th level), hex (as a 5th-level spell), mage hand, nondetection, pass without trace
	• 3/Day each: glibness, greater invisibility
	• 1/Day each: mass suggestion, modify memory</text>
      <attack>Innate Spellcasting|+15|</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/DAY</recharge>
      <text>If the Prince fails a saving throw, he can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>The Prince has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Weapons</name>
      <text>The Prince's weapon attacks are magical.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shadow Stealth</name>
      <text>While in dim light or darkness, the Prince can take the Hide action as a bonus action.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stolen Gifts</name>
      <text>The Prince steals away others' gifts with hands as swift as darkness. As a bonus action, the Prince causes one creature he can see within 60 feet of him to make a DC 25 Wisdom (Perception) check. On a failed save, the Forgotten Prince steals one of the following from the target until the start of his next turn:

	1. Weapon Skill. For the duration, the target has disadvantage on weapon attacks, and the Prince has advantage on Dark Scythe attacks.
	2. Spellcasting Ability. For the duration, the target has disadvantage on spell attack rolls, and all creatures have advantage on saving throws made to resist the target's spells. Additionally, all creatures have disadvantage on saving throws to resist the Prince's spells.
	3. Speed. The target's walking speed is reduced by 20 feet (minimum of 5 feet). Additionally, the Prince's walking speed is increased by 20 feet, and he can Disengage as a bonus action.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Thelanian Protagonist</name>
      <text>The Prince can't be permanently killed. If reduced to 0 hit points, he implodes in a burst of shadows, dealing 36 (8d8) points of necrotic damage to any creature within 15 feet of him. 1d4 days later, he reforms in the Castle of Forgotten Things, regaining all his hit points.</text>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||8d8</attack>
      <attack>Days||1d4</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The Prince makes two Dark Scythe attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Dark Scythe</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d6 + 8) slashing damage and 14 (4d6) necrotic damage.</text>
      <attack>Dark Scythe|+15|(2d6+8)+(4d6)</attack>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+15|2d6+8</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||4d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Threads of Memory (Recharge 5-6)</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>The Prince steals the memories of nearby foes, hampering their abilities. The Prince causes up to three creatures within 60 feet of him to make a DC 23 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, a target takes 28 (8d6) points of psychic damage and has its memories stolen for 1 minute. During that time, whenever the target makes an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, it must roll a d4 and subtract the number rolled from the attack roll, ability check, or saving throw. The target can make a Wisdom saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||8d6</attack>
      <attack>Subtract from Roll||1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <name>Legendary Actions</name>
      <recharge>3/TURN</recharge>
      <text>The Prince can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. The Forgotten Prince regains spent legendary actions at the start of his turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Dark Scythe</name>
      <text>The Prince makes one Dark Scythe attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Fey Step</name>
      <text>The Prince uses his Fey Step.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Marked for Vengeance</name>
      <text>The Prince casts hex as a 5th-level spell.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary category="lair">
      <name>The Forgotten Prince's Lair</name>
      <text>The Prince dwells in the Castle of Forgotten Things in Thelanis. The castle seems to be its own distinct layer of Thelanis; if it exists in some other realm, its location has been forgotten. There are no doors that allow exit from the castle, and all windows are sealed and show scenes of places that have been forgotten. The only way to enter or leave the castle is through magic, whether by spell, through a manifest zone, or through a portal. Such portals can take many forms, such as the sack described in the legend above; normal people forget the location of a portal within an hour of discovering it, though player characters and other remarkable people could be immune to this effect. It's possible characters could discover that what they assumed to be a normal bag of holding can serve as a portal to the Castle of Lost Things.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary category="lair">
      <name>Lair Actions</name>
      <text>While within his castle, the Forgotten Prince can invoke the ambient magic to take lair actions. On initiative count 20 (losing initiative ties), the Forgotten Prince can take a lair action to cause one of the following effects; he can't use the same effect two rounds in a row:

	• Each creature that has dealt damage to the Forgotten Prince within the last round must succeed on a DC 23 Dexterity saving throw or take 26 (4d12) points of psychic damage from his vengeance made manifest.

	• The Forgotten Prince can steal the very life away from his foes. One creature that the Forgotten Prince can see must make a DC 23 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 27 (6d8) points of necrotic damage, and the Forgotten Prince regains hit points equal to the amount of necrotic damage dealt.

	• The Forgotten Prince uses his Stolen Gifts trait on a creature he can see anywhere within his lair, regardless of distance. The duration of the effect lasts until initiative count 20 on the round after next.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||4d12</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage||6d8</attack>
    </legendary>
    <spells>Chill Touch, Hex, Mage Hand, Nondetection, Pass without Trace, Glibness, Greater Invisibility, Mass Suggestion, Modify Memory</spells>
    <description>Once there was a prince of a grand kingdom, the youngest of eight sons. His brothers were celebrated as heroes of the realm, but whatever the youngest prince did, his deeds were never noticed; the shadows cast by his brothers were too long. Even when he saved the kingdom from a cruel dragon, the people assumed one of his brothers had done the deed. But in that dragon's lair, the prince discovered a strange sack. Reaching inside it, he found a toy he'd loved as a child and long forgotten about, a comb lost by his sister, and a map of a nation that no longer exists. Curious, he climbed into the sack and found a castle within it, filled with forgotten wonders. No one ever noticed he was gone, and no one remembers his name or his deeds. But the Forgotten Prince still dwells in his Castle of Lost Things. When you forget something you love, or when something you need is nowhere to be found, it's because the Forgotten Prince has taken it for his hoard.

When a sock goes missing or a tool is misplaced, people curse the Forgotten Prince for stealing it away. When someone forgets what they were about to say, they might remark "The Prince has taken my thought." Needless to say, his reach is not truly as wide as such stories make out; but the Forgotten Prince and his minions do indeed steal unappreciated things, both material items and even ideas themselves, keeping them in the vaults and library of his Castle of Lost Things. Often such thefts are never noticed, but he might take things that are quite valuable if he believes them to be unloved or unappreciated by those who have them. Sometimes this is done to teach a lesson, how the loss of a simple and undervalued item or idea can have disastrous consequences. Battles have been lost and cities fallen because of the Prince's thefts-though often people fail to appreciate the lesson, as they never recall what was lost to begin with.

	The Prince of All Things Forgotten and Unloved. The Forgotten Prince dwells in the Castle of Lost Things in Thelanis. His attendants are sly and cunning fey, along with mortals who were unappreciated in their mundane lives. Some say that the kenku are servants of the Forgotten Prince who fled from his service-that he stole their voices as punishment for their betrayal, but that a kenku can earn it back with clever deeds. True or not, the Prince has followers scattered across Khorvaire-thieves who sacrifice unloved objects and undervalued secrets to the Prince in exchange for his guidance and gifts. Followers of the Forgotten Prince rarely work together, but they can be found in many positions of influence. There are elves in the Shadow Houses who receive visions from the Prince when they trance, and changelings among the Tyrants of Sharn who engage in more subtle thefts on behalf of the Prince, stealing hearts or faces. While his thefts often go unnoticed by the greater world, the Forgotten Prince also takes pleasure in seeing celebrated people whose reputations are undeserved brought low, and his agents may act to expose such poseurs. Adventurers could also be forced to deal with the Prince if he has something they need—perhaps an artifact or secret long forgotten, now sealed away in the vaults of his dark castle.

	The Prince as Ally or Patron. The Forgotten Prince may reach out to people who have themselves been forgotten or unappreciated, provided he sees potential in them. Sometimes he brings them to the Castle of Lost Things; in other cases, he offers these agents purpose, rewarding them for their service with gifts or secrets. The urchin background is an excellent option for someone forgotten by the world but chosen by the Prince, while the hermit background could reflect someone who spent much of their life in the Castle of Lost Things, with the Discovery feature being tied to a long-forgotten secret or artifact they discovered in the Castle. The Forgotten Prince could be an Archfey patron for a warlock, or a Hexblade warlock could also receive their weapon as a gift from the Prince; what is the forgotten history and destiny of this weapon? The Forgotten Prince can also be an interesting patron for a bard of the College of Lore; the Prince values secrets no one else considers valuable, and the Cutting Words feature can be depicted as stealing opportunity from a foe—a trick taught by the Forgotten Prince. The Forgotten Prince could teach a rogue the talents of an Arcane Trickster or the skills of a Thief, provided they are willing to use those skills on his behalf.
	Missions issued by the Prince typically involve the theft of an object or a secret. These things may not be seen as valuable by the people that possess them, and such a task could easily be added on top of the mission for an existing adventure-"While you're in Dreadhold, steal the ring under the warden's bed." The Prince could teach his agents a ten-minute ritual which allows him to pull the requested item into Thelanis (this only works with objects the Prince wants, so it's not a way to dispose of just any item). The Prince may also task agents with actions to expose or bring down people whose reputations are undeserved, or to assist those who are unappreciated. Note that good and evil don't enter into these judgments; the Prince could call on agents to bring down someone who's using their undeserved reputation for a good cause, or to help an unappreciated serial killer!

	The Prince as an Enemy. The simplest way for the Prince to enter a story is for one of his agents to steal something that the adventurers need, or to take actions that cripple an organization or patron that the characters work for. This ties to the idea that the Prince may target someone with an undeserved reputation even if they are using it to do good; the adventurers themselves could be targeted if they acquire fame that the Prince considers unearned. Or the characters might discover they need something stolen long ago by the Princeor an object they've recently acquired and desperately need has gone missing, and no one else seems to remember it. Characters could also be set against the Prince by another immortal patron; perhaps the Prince has stolen one of the memories of the Forest Queen, and she wants it back

	The Power of Secrets. A defining part of the Forgotten Prince's story is that he himself has been forgotten. Should a character somehow learn the true name of the Forgotten Prince during their adventures, they gain advantage on saving throws against all of his lair actions.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 239 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Meld</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>undead</type>
    <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
    <ac>11</ac>
    <hp>119 (14d10+42)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>8</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>17</cha>
    <skill>Stealth +4</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>understands all it spoke in life but can't speak</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical weapons</resist>
    <immune>necrotic, poison, psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ethereal Sight</name>
      <text>The meld can see 60 feet into the Ethereal Plane when it is on the Material Plane, and vice versa.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Incorporeal Form</name>
      <text>The meld ignores nonmagical difficult terrain, and can walk on liquid surfaces without breaking through, as though the water walk spell was cast on it.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
      <text>The meld can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage||1d10</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The meld makes four attacks. Alternatively, it makes two attacks and uses its Conflicted Soul ability.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Withering Slam</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) necrotic damage.</text>
      <attack>Necrotic Damage|+7|2d6+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Conflicted Soul</name>
      <text>The meld causes one creature of its choice within 30 feet of it to make a DC 14 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target suffers the effect of the confusion spell (no concentration required).</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Etherealness</name>
      <text>The meld enters the Ethereal Plane from the Material Plane, or vice versa. It is visible on the Material Plane while it is in the Border Ethereal, and vice versa, yet it can't affect or be affected by anything on the other plane.</text>
    </action>
    <description>A meld is formed from the faded souls of mortals-husks whose memories have been consumed by Dolurrh. These husks are typically harmless, but sometimes an aggressive nucleus gathers other husks, forming a deadly gestalt. In essence, a meld is a fusion of half-formed ghosts; it has an amorphous shape, with vague faces and limbs projecting from the mass, then being consumed once more. It makes no sound when it moves, but mortals around a meld hear cries of pain, pleading voices, and unearthly moans. Its Conflicted Soul action reflects it projecting some of its husks into a mortal body, temporarily overwhelming the victim with conflicting desires and visions.

	Denizens of Dolurrh. Melds are born in Dolurrh, and prowl the endless caverns searching for scraps of memory. This hunger can draw them to Eberron through manifest zones or when planes are coterminous. A meld can also manifest when someone is raised from the dead, following in the wake of the soul being drawn back to the world of the living. Melds that enter Eberron rarely stray more than one mile from the point where they arrived.

	Hunger for Memory. A meld has the barest traces of dozens of souls. It remembers scraps of the most powerful moments of its component husks, but it can't place these in any context. The meld yearns to consume other spirits, to feast on their memories and emotions. While highly unusual, it's possible for a powerful personality within a meld to exert temporary control; this might cause the meld to pursue a particular individual or draw it to a specific location. When a meld kills a living creature and consumes its spirit, the flood of memories can also shift the purpose of the meld, as it suddenly acts on the desires of its most recent victim. A meld loose in Eberron retains the spirits it consumes, preventing them from transitioning to Dolurrh. This prevents the spirit from fading; a character could hear the whispers of a trapped spirit within a meld, and a husk could hold the souls of people who died long ago. A side effect of this is that creatures slain by a meld cannot be resurrected or raised from the dead until the meld is destroyed.

	Undead Nature. A meld doesn't require air, food, drink, or sleep.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 242 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Merfolk Stormcaller</name>
    <sortname>Merfolk, Stormcaller</sortname>
    <ancestry>Merfolk</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (merfolk)</type>
    <alignment>neutral</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>156 (24d8+48)</hp>
    <speed>10ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>11</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>13</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <save>Con +5, Wis +6</save>
    <skill>Nature +4, Perception +6, Survival +6</skill>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>Aquan, Common, Druidic</languages>
    <cr>8</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>The stormcaller can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The stormcaller's innate spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 14, +6 to hit with spell attacks). It can innately cast the following spells, requiring no material components:

	• 3/Day each: maelstrom, thunderwave (as a 5th-level spell), tidal wave, watery sphere
	• 1/Day each: chain lightning</text>
      <attack>Innate Spellcasting|+6|</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Summon Storm</name>
      <text>Once per day, one or more stormcallers can cast control weather as a ritual that takes 10 minutes to perform. For every additional stormcaller involved in performing the ritual, the radius of the spell's effect increases by 1 mile, the duration increases by 2 hours, and they can change the weather by one additional stage every 1d4 × 10 minutes. During the ritual, if the stormcallers take any action other than performing the ritual, they must start over.</text>
      <attack>Minutes||1d4x10</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The stormcaller makes three Lightning Lash attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Lightning Lash</name>
      <text>Melee Spell Attack: +6 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 14 (4d6) lightning damage.</text>
      <attack>Lightning Damage|+6|4d6</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Thunderous Rebuke</name>
      <text>In response to another creature the stormcaller can see within 60 feet dealing damage to the stormcaller, it can channel the power of the storm. The creature that damaged it must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or take 11 (2d10) thunder damage and be knocked prone.</text>
      <attack>Thunder Damage||2d10</attack>
    </reaction>
    <spells>Maelstrom, Thunderwave, Tidal Wave, Watery Sphere, Chain Lightning</spells>
    <description>A stormcaller feels the flow of the tides around, currents below, and shifting storms above the water, and can direct this power against those who threaten their people. Working together, a circle of stormcallers can bring down an entire fleet of ships. The greatest stormcallers have powers beyond what's shown here; the merfolk tell stories of stormcallers who can command the beasts of the sea and transform into mighty squids or whales.

	Wardens of the Water. Most merfolk stormcallers seek to maintain balance within their realm. Like the Wardens of the Wood, they strive to protect their region from outside threats, but also to protect foolish outsiders from the dangers of the deeps and the manifest zones the stormcallers guard. However, there are stormcallers who view any intrusion into their waters as an affront that must be punished.

	Druidic Speech. Stormcallers know the Druidic language, which they believe to be the language of the world itself. Most stormcallers will parley with any creature who speaks Druidic, but they have high expectations of such beings. A stormcaller may ask a foreign druid to help with an unnatural threat or to serve as a mediator in a local dispute.

Merfolk:
Touched by Lamannia, the merfolk of the Thunder Sea have a deep connection to primal forces and planar power. The merfolk shepherd underwater manifest zones, and many can channel druidic magic. At the DM's discretion, merfolk encountered in the Thunder Sea could know a cantrip from the druid spell list.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 243 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Du'ulora Quori</name>
    <sortname>Quori, Du'ulora</sortname>
    <ancestry>Quori</ancestry>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>aberration</type>
    <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>168 (16d10+80)</hp>
    <speed>10 ft., fly 60 ft. (hover)</speed>
    <str>20</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>15</int>
    <wis>18</wis>
    <cha>19</cha>
    <save>Wis +8, Cha +8</save>
    <skill>Intimidation +8, Perception +12, Survival +8</skill>
    <passive>22</passive>
    <languages>Common, Quori, Riedran, telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>11</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>fire, psychic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune>charmed, frightened, prone</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>All-Around Vision</name>
      <text>The quori can't be surprised while it isn't incapacitated.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aura of Fury</name>
      <text>Any creature of the quori's choice that ends its turn within 60 of the quori must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or become enraged for 1 minute. During that time, the enraged target has advantage on all melee attack rolls, and all attack rolls made against that target have advantage. An enraged target is subject to the quori's Incite Fury reaction.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting (Psionics)</name>
      <text>The quori's innate spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 16, +8 to hit with spell attacks). It can innately cast the following spells, requiring no components:

	• At will: mage hand
	• 3/Day each: crown of madness, flaming sphere, shield
	• 1/Day each: enemies abound</text>
      <attack>Innate Spellcasting|+8|</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>The quori has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Track Hatred</name>
      <text>When the quori deals damage to any creature, it forms a psychic link with the target for 24 hours. During that time, the quori has advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track the target. The quori can attempt to track the target at any range, even if it is on another plane of existence, and abilities such as the pass without trace spell or the ranger's Vanish feature do not impede the quori's ability to track its target. Even when the quori is tracking while traveling, it remains alert to danger.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The quori makes three tentacle attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tentacle</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d6 + 5) bludgeoning damage plus 7 (2d6) fire damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 17). Until this grapple ends, the target takes 10 (3d6) fire damage and 10 (3d6) psychic damage at the start of each of the quori's turns, and the quori can't use that tentacle against a different target. The quori has three tentacles.</text>
      <attack>Tentacle|+9|(2d6+5)+(2d6)</attack>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+9|2d6+5</attack>
      <attack>Fire Damage||2d6</attack>
      <attack>Grappled||(3d6)+(3d6)</attack>
      <attack>Fire Damage||3d6</attack>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||3d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Possession (Recharge 6)</name>
      <recharge>D6</recharge>
      <text>One humanoid that the quori can see within 5 feet of it must succeed on a DC 16 Charisma saving throw or be possessed by the quori; the quori then disappears, and the target is incapacitated and loses control of its body. The quori now controls the body but doesn't deprive the target of awareness. The quori can't be targeted by any attack, spell, or other effect, and it retains its alignment, Intelligence, Wisdom, Charisma, and immunity to being charmed and frightened. It otherwise uses the possessed target's statistics, but doesn't gain access to the target's knowledge, class features, or proficiencies.
	The possession lasts until the body drops to 0 hit points, the quori ends it as a bonus action, or the quori is forced out by an effect like the dispel evil and good spell. When the possession ends, the quori reappears in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the body. The target is immune to this quori's Possession for 24 hours after succeeding on the saving throw or after the possession ends.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Recall Agony (Recharge 5-6)</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>The quori makes a creature recall the most agonizing moments of its past—or future. One creature within 60 feet of the quori must make a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw, taking 67 (15d8) psychic damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||15d8</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Incite Fury</name>
      <text>When an enraged creature targets the quori with an attack, the quori can cause it to instead target another creature of the quori's choice within range.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells>Mage Hand, Crown of Madness, Flaming Sphere, Shield, Enemies Abound</spells>
    <description>Duulora are spirits of fury that feed on anger and inspire rage in mortals. A duulora is a maelstrom of eyes and wings, bound together by flesh that seems like solidified shadow. It can extend up to three tentacles from this dark mass. A duulora can turn a victim's anger into manifested heat; in battle, it grapples its victims and burns them with their own fury.

	Manipulating Fury. While they feed on anger and hatred, du'ulora rarely act rashly. They are cunning and calculating strategists who excel at inspiring fury in others and turning it against them. In battle this can cause their victims to lower their guard and even to strike their own allies in heedless rage. As servants of the Dreaming Dark, the dưulora craft dreams that stir buried anger and incite hatred; they excel at igniting feuds and inspiring vendettas. So where a tsucora agent of the Dreaming Dark manipulates peoples' fears and a hashalaq employs seduction, the duulora excel at inciting violence.

	The Fists of Dal Guor. The duulora are martial champions of the quori. They thrive on conflict and love to personally crush their enemies. While they enjoy fighting in the vanguard, the du'ulora are also skilled strategists. In Dal Quor, the du'ulora command squads of tsucora and lesser quori. In Riedra, military commanders are typically Inspired bound to du'ulora spirits.

	Rage Against The Darkness. The dưulora bound to the kalashtar serve the light, but they still manipulate fury. Dư'ulora kalashtar learn to harness and channel their own aggression, and are often fighters or barbarians; others are dispassionate monks, who provoke rage in their enemies while never allowing it to distract them from their goals.

Quori:
The quori are the spirits that rule Dal Quor, the Region of Dreams. Quori are immortal, but they can be slain; when a quori dies, its essence returns to the Dreaming Dark, where it is reconstituted as a new spirit. Quori spirits are bound to emotions, and they feed on those emotions and excel at manipulating them in mortals. The tsucora thrive on fear, the hashalaq manipulate pleasure, the du'ulora are driven by anger, and the kalaraq consume pride and ambition. These are the most common quori, but there are many others; the spiteful tsoreva and the domineering usvapna have already been mentioned in previous editions.
	The quori are the creations of il-Lashtavar, the malevolent force that shapes Dal Quor. Cruelty is a part of their nature. However, when a quori is reborn, there is a microscopic chance that it will be touched by il-Yannah, the incarnation of light that will one day replace the Dreaming Dark. It's possible for a quori to carry this seed of light and never embrace it. The kalaraq Taratai was the first to rally those quori who could sense the light, teaching them to push back the darkness and embrace il-Yannah. These rebels are the spirits who are now bound to the kalashtar. They are still quori-tsucora, hashalaq, du'ulora, kalaraq—and they are still tied to the emotion associated with their quori type. But they are driven by their vision of the light that is to come rather than the darkness of the present. Taratai's rebels fled Dal Quor long ago, and there have surely been new quori touched by il-Yannah since then. But today, the Dreaming Dark are constantly policing their own ranks and searching for such "corrupted" spirits. Any that are found will be destroyed, so their spirits can be reborn as proper servants of il-Lashtavar.
	All quori have powerful psionic abilities. DMs could choose to represent this by granting each quori from Eberron: Rising from the Last War telepathy with a range of 120 feet. If a quori has any Inspired hosts, as do all that interact with the Material Plane, it would also speak the Riedran language.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 244 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Claw of Sha'argon</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>humanoid (sahuagin)</type>
    <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
    <ac>18 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>142 (15d10+60)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft., swim 50 ft.</speed>
    <str>21</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>19</con>
    <int>15</int>
    <wis>18</wis>
    <cha>15</cha>
    <save>Str +9, Dex +6, Con +8, Wis +8</save>
    <skill>History +6, Perception +12, Religion +6</skill>
    <passive>22</passive>
    <languages>Aquan, Common, Sahuagin</languages>
    <cr>11</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Blood Frenzy</name>
      <text>The Claw of Sha'argon has advantage on melee attack rolls against any creature that doesn't have all its hit points.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Limited Amphibiousness</name>
      <text>The Claw of Sha'argon can breathe air and water, but it needs to be submerged at least once every 4 hours to avoid suffocating.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Toughened Carapace</name>
      <text>Any critical hit against the Claw of Sha'argon becomes a normal hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shark Telepathy</name>
      <text>The Claw of Sha'argon can magically command any shark within 120 feet of it, using a limited telepathy.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The Claw of Sha'argon is a 11-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 16, +8 to hit with spell attacks). The Claw of Sha'argon has the following cleric spells prepared:

	• Cantrips (at will): guidance, mending, resistance, thaumaturgy, toll the dead
	• 1st level (4 slots): bane, command, inflict wounds, shield of faith
	• 2nd level (3 slots): blindness/deafness, hold person, spiritual weapon
	• 3rd level (3 slots): bestow curse, dispel magic, spirit guardians
	• 4th level (3 slots): banishment, freedom of movement
	• 5th level (2 slots): contagion, flame strike
	• 6th level (1 slot): harm</text>
      <attack>Spellcasting|+8|</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The Claw of Sha'argon makes one attack with its crushing claw, one attack with its cutter claw, and casts one spell.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Crushing Claw</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 10ft., one target. Hit: 16 (2d10 + 5) bludgeoning damage. If the target is a Medium or smaller creature, it is grappled (escape DC 15).</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+9|2d10+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Cutter Claw</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 24 (3d12 + 5) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+9|3d12+5</attack>
    </action>
    <slots>0,4,3,3,3,2,1</slots>
    <spells>Guidance, Mending, Resistance, Thaumaturgy, Toll the Dead, Bane, Command, Inflict Wounds, Shield of Faith, Blindness/Deafness, Hold Person, Spiritual Weapon, Bestow Curse, Dispel Magic, Spirit Guardians, Banishment, Freedom of Movement, Contagion, Flame Strike, Harm</spells>
    <description>The aboleths created the lobster-like chuuls as living weapons and unleashed them against the sahuagin. The high priests of the Eternal Dominion responded by consuming the chuuls and taking their power. A Claw of Sha'argon is a mighty sahuagin champion-an armored powerhouse possessing deep faith and wielding divine power. While barons lead sahuagin into battle, the Claws of Sha'argon are the spiritual leaders of the Eternal Dominion who lead its inquisitions and crush its enemies with claw and spell.

	Claw and Tentacle. The powerful claws of a sahuagin priest are deadly weapons. It manipulates objects and casts spells using its facial tentacles. These tentacles are fully prehensile limbs capable of delicate work, but a Claw of Sha'argon has disadvantage on Strength checks made using its tentacles.

	Devoted Priests. Only the greatest spiritual leaders of the sahuagin are nominated for the ritual that produces a Claw of Shaargon, and only those possessing the most unshakable faith survive this agonizing process. The Claws of Sha'argon see themselves as chosen vessels of the Devourer, channeling the fury of the wild. A Claw of Sha'argon casts spells as an 11th-level spellcaster, and those spells listed are typical for a Claw of Sha'argon, but can be replaced with any spell available to a Tempest cleric.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 246 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Plasmid</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>monstrosity (shapechanger)</type>
    <alignment>neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>127 (15d10+45)</hp>
    <speed>20 ft., swim 20 ft.</speed>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>17</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>5</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>8</cha>
    <skill>Stealth +6</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>cold</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune>prone</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Adaptive Shapeshifting (Amorphous Form Only)</name>
      <text>When in its true, amorphous form, the plasmid gains one of the following benefits. As an action, it can select a different benefit.

	• The plasmid gains truesight with a range of 30 feet.
	• The plasmid gains blindsense with a range of 60 feet.
	• The plasmid's walking and swimming speeds increase to 30 feet.
	• The plasmid's vicious pseudopod deals an extra 1d6 acid damage on a hit.
</text>
      <attack>Acid||1d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>The plasmid can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>False Appearance (Object Form Only)</name>
      <text>While the plasmid remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from an ordinary object.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fast Shapechanger</name>
      <text>The plasmid can use its bonus action to polymorph into an object or back into its true, amorphous form. Its statistics are the same in each form. Any equipment it is wearing or carrying isn't transformed. It reverts to its true form if it dies.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Receptive Telepathy</name>
      <text>The plasmid is considered a shark for the purpose of being magically commanded by any sahuagin's Shark Telepathy feature.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Solid State (Object Form Only)</name>
      <text>When formed into an inanimate object, the plasmid has an AC of 18 and regains 10 hit points at the start of each of its turn. However, the plasmid's speed becomes 0 in this form and it cannot attack. It can be used as an item or a set of artisan's tools when it is in this form.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The plasmid makes three vicious pseudopod attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Vicious Pseudopod</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 10ft., one target. Hit: 10(2d6 + 3) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+6|2d6+3</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Plasmids are shapeshifters, magebred by the sahuagin of the Thunder Sea using mimic stock infused with the ichor of the dreamers. Plasmids serve both as deadly guardians and living tools, reshaping their mutable bodies to serve the needs of their sahuagin masters.

	Skin of Stone and Steel. A plasmid can change the texture of its flesh as well as its appearance. In addition to making the plasmid resistant to injury, this allows the creature to assume many functional forms. A plasmid can serve as a door with no lock or a chest with no lid, creating an obstacle that can only be opened by killing the plasmid. Plasmids can also be trained to assume shapes that serve as functional tools. A plasmid can become an alchemist's lab or a smith's forge, providing all the elements needed to pursue a trade. While this allows the plasmid to "serve as a tool," the plasmid remains a Large creature; it essentially becomes a workbench, with individual smaller tools connected to the primary mass by fibrous strands.

	Loyal Servants... For Now. Plasmids possess a passive form of telepathy that allows them to sense the commands of nearby sahuagin. While they are conscious, they have a limited sense of self and no desires beyond service. At least, that's how they were designed and what the sahuagin believe. But it might be possible for a plasmid to develop greater intellect and independence—or for the plasmids of a city to be shaped by the desires of the local dreamer.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 246 (Third Party)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
</compendium>
