<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Bard [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Bard College: College of the Dirge Singers (EE) (TP) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard Subclass: College of the Dirge Singers (EE) (TP) (Legacy)</name>
        <text>Bards of the College of the Dirge Singer are trained to inspire their people and direct soldiers on the battlefield. Students of both history and war, dirge singers use tales of past glory and their knowledge of great victories to inspire their allies and provide keen strategic insight, directing allies to strike when enemies are weak.
	This ancient tradition was developed in the Empire of Dhakaan, and is largely unknown beyond the goblinoids of the Kech Dhakaan. The duur'kala-Goblin for dirge singerare the historians, diplomats, and spiritual leaders of the empire. Duur'kala are discussed in more detail in chapter 4 of this book. If you're not one of the dar, consider how you came to learn this tradition. Did you train with a ghaal'dar mentor? Or did you find your own path to these techniques?

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 216 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Broad Inspiration (College of the Dirge Singers (EE) (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>When you join the College of Dirge Singers at 3rd level, you learn to strengthen the hearts of your troops and stir them to greatness. You learn the guidance cantrip, which is considered a bard spell for you, but doesn't count against your number of cantrips known.
	Additionally, as a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to inspire multiple allies. When you do so, choose two creatures within 60 feet of you that can hear you. Each creature gains one Bardic Inspiration die.
	Your Bardic Inspiration die does not change at 5th level, but remains a d6; it becomes a d8 at 10th level, and a d10 at 15th level.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 216 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Keeper of History (College of the Dirge Singers (EE) (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in either History or Performance. If you are already proficient in both of these skills, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Arcana, Intimidation, or Persuasion.
	In addition, choose either History or Performance. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses that skill.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 216 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Commanding Voice (College of the Dirge Singers (EE) (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, you excel at inspiring and directing soldiers in battle. When a creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you takes the Attack action on its turn, you can use your reaction to allow it an additional weapon attack. The creature rolls the Bardic Inspiration die, adding the number rolled to its weapon damage roll.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 216 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Master Commander (College of the Dirge Singers (EE) (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, you unflaggingly maintain the spirits and discipline of your unit. During your turn, you can use Countercharm as a bonus action. When you start a Countercharm performance, if any creature that gains its benefit is currently charmed or frightened, it can immediately make another saving throw against the effect that imposed the condition.
	In addition, when a creature that gains the benefit of your Countercharm performance makes an ability check or saving throw, it can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check or saving throw.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 216 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
