<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Divine Domain: The Mind Domain (TP) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy)</name>
        <text>This path blends divine devotion and psychic power. The forces tied to the Mind domain teach followers that the mind is the greatest tool and the mightiest weapon in creation. A cleric of the Mind domain learns to harness their own mental power, then uses this gift to protect the faithful and smite enemies.
	In Eberron, the Mind domain is most associated with the kalashtar Path of Light and the Riedran Path of Inspiration. However, followers of the cults of the Dragon Below might also follow this path. While visions of Xoriat can certainly drive a priest into madness, they might also reveal deeper secrets and mental powers.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 217 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Domain Spells (The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>You gain domain spells at the cleric levels listed in the Mind Domain Spells table. See the Divine Domain class feature in the Player's Handbook for how domain spells work.

Mind Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
1st | command, dissonant whispers
3rd | detect thoughts, phantasmal force
5th | enemies abound, fear
7th | confusion, phantasmal killer
9th | dominate person, telekinesis

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 217 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Flash of Insight (The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can summon power from a well of mental energy at your core. When you make an ability check, you can choose to reroll it after you see the result, but before you know if it succeeds or fails. You get a bonus to this reroll equal to half of your cleric level (minimum of 1).
	You can use this feature twice. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 217 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Psychic Force (The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to buffet your foes with mental power. When you cast a cleric spell or cantrip that inflicts radiant damage, you can choose to have it inflict psychic damage instead.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 217 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Flash of Insight</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Channel Divinity: Psychic Feedback (the Mind Domain (Tp) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Beginning at 3rd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to disrupt a foe's mind. When a creature within 30 feet of you has to make a Wisdom saving throw, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on it using your Channel Divinity. You must use this feature before you know the outcome of the roll.
	If the spell or effect that caused the Wisdom saving throw is not created by a spell you cast, you can also choose to deal psychic damage to the target, equal to half your cleric level, immediately before the target makes its saving throw.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 217 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Gestalt Anchor (The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, your mental power increases, settling the minds of those around you with your mere presence. Whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw, the creature gains a +2 bonus to the saving throw. You must be conscious to grant this bonus.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 217 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 8: Potent Spellcasting (The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 217 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Bend Reality (The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 17th level, when you see an ally within 30 feet of you fail a saving throw, you can replace the roll with a 20, potentially changing the outcome. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Exploring Eberron p. 217 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Bend Reality</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>The Mind Domain (TP) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Command</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dissonant Whispers</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Thoughts</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Force</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Enemies Abound</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fear</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Confusion</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Killer</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dominate Person</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Telekinesis</name>
    <classes>Cleric (The Mind Domain (TP))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
</compendium>
