<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <spell>
    <name>Homunculus Servant [5.5e]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>YES</ritual>
    <time>1 hour</time>
    <range>10 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a gem worth 100+ GP)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>School: Conjuration, Artificer [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>You summon a special homunculus in an unoccupied space within range. This creature uses the Homunculus Servant stat block. If you already have a homunculus from this spell, the homunculus is replaced by the new one. You determine the homunculus's appearance, such as a mechanical-looking bird, winged vial, or miniature animate cauldron.

Combat: The homunculus is an ally to you and your allies. In combat, it shares your Initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys your commands (no action required by you). If you don't issue any, it takes the Dodge action and uses its movement to avoid danger.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: Use the spell slot's level for the spell's level in the stat block.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 21</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Alchemy Jug [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon
Weight: 12 lb.

This ceramic jug appears to be able to hold a gallon of liquid and weighs 12 pounds whether full or empty. The jug sloshes when it is shaken, even if the jug is empty.

You can take a Magic action and name one liquid from the Alchemy Jug Liquids table to cause the jug to produce the chosen liquid. Afterward, you can uncork the jug as a Utilize action and pour that liquid out, up to 2 gallons per minute. The maximum amount of liquid the jug can produce depends on the liquid you named.

Once the jug starts producing a liquid, it can't produce a different one, or more of one that has reached its maximum, until the next dawn.

Liquid | Max. Amount
Acid | 8 ounces
Basic Poison | 4 ounces
Beer | 4 gallons
Honey | 1 gallon
Mayonnaise | 2 gallons
Oil | 1 quart
Vinegar | 2 gallons
Water, fresh | 8 gallons
Water, salt | 12 gallons
Wine | 1 gallon

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 227

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Bag of Holding [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon
Weight: 5 lb.

This bag has an interior space considerably larger than its outside dimensions—roughly 2 feet square and 4 feet deep on the inside. The bag can hold up to 500 pounds, not exceeding a volume of 64 cubic feet. The bag weighs 5 pounds, regardless of its contents. Retrieving an item from the bag requires a Utilize action.

If the bag is overloaded, pierced, or torn, it is destroyed, and its contents are scattered in the Astral Plane. If the bag is turned inside out, its contents spill forth unharmed, but the bag must be put right before it can be used again. The bag holds enough air for 10 minutes of breathing, divided by the number of breathing creatures inside.

Placing a Bag of Holding inside an extradimensional space created by a Heward's Handy Haversack, Portable Hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within a 10-foot-radius Sphere centered on the gate is sucked through it to a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way and can't be reopened.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 234

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Cap of Water Breathing [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

While wearing this cap underwater, you can take a Magic action to create a bubble of air around your head. This bubble allows you to breathe normally underwater. This bubble stays with you until the cap is removed or you are no longer underwater.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 242

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Goggles of Night [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

While wearing these dark lenses, you have Darkvision out to 60 feet. If you already have Darkvision, wearing the goggles increases its range by 60 feet.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 265

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Manifold Tool [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, common (requires attunement)

This tool takes the form of a wrench, a screwdriver, or another basic tool. As a Magic action, you can touch the item and transform it into a type of Artisan's Tools of your choice. Whatever form the tool takes, you have proficiency with it when you use it.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 112

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Repeating Shot Weapon [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Weapon, uncommon (requires attunement)

This magic weapon grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it when it's used to make a ranged attack, and it ignores the Loading property if it has that property.

If the weapon lacks ammunition, it produces its own, automatically creating one piece of magic ammunition when the wielder makes a ranged attack roll with it. The ammunition created by the weapon vanishes the instant after it hits or misses a target.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Returning Weapon [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Weapon, uncommon

This magic weapon grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it, and it returns to your hand immediately after you use it to make a ranged attack roll.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Rope of Climbing [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

This 60-foot length of rope can hold up to 3,000 pounds. While holding one end of the rope, you can take a Magic action to command the other end of the rope to animate and move toward a destination you choose, up to the rope's length away from you. That end moves 10 feet on your turn when you first command it and 10 feet at the start of each of your subsequent turns until reaching its destination or until you tell it to stop. You can also tell the rope to fasten itself securely to an object or to unfasten itself, to knot or unknot itself, or to coil itself for carrying.

If you tell the rope to knot, large knots appear at 1-foot intervals along the rope. While knotted, the rope shortens to a 50-foot length and grants Advantage on ability checks made to climb using the rope.

The rope has AC 20, HP 20, and Immunity to Poison and Psychic damage. It regains 1 Hit Point every 5 minutes as long as it has at least 1 Hit Point. If the rope drops to 0 Hit Points, it is destroyed.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 301

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Sending Stones [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

Sending Stones come in pairs, with each stone carved to match the other so the pairing is easily recognized. While you touch one stone, you can cast Sending from it. The target is the bearer of the other stone. If no creature bears the other stone, you know that fact as soon as you use the stone, and you don't cast the spell.

Once Sending is cast using either stone, the stones can't be used again until the next dawn. If one of the stones in a pair is destroyed, the other one becomes nonmagical.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 303

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Shield +1 [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Shield, uncommon
Weight: 6 lb.

While holding this Shield, you have a +1 bonus to Armor Class, in addition to the Shield's normal bonus to AC.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 303

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Wand of Magic Detection [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wand, uncommon
Weight: 1 lb.

This wand has 3 charges. While holding it, you can expend 1 charge to cast Detect Magic from it. The wand regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 320

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Wand of Secrets [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wand, uncommon
Weight: 1 lb.

This wand has 3 charges and regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding it, you can take a Magic action to expend 1 charge, and if a secret door or trap is within 60 feet of you, the wand pulses and points at the one nearest to you.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 322

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Wand of the War Mage +1 [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wand, uncommon (requires attunement by a spellcaster)
Weight: 1 lb.

While holding this wand, you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls. In addition, you ignore Half Cover when making a spell attack roll.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 322

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Weapon +1 [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Weapon, uncommon

You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Wraps of Unarmed Power +1 [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

While wearing these wraps, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with your Unarmed Strikes. Those strikes deal your choice of Force damage or their normal damage type.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 325

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Common Magic Item [5.5e]</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Common magic item that isn’t a Potion, a Scroll, or cursed.

You can learn this option multiple times and must select a different item each time; each item selected counts as a different plan.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 8</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Armor +1 (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Armor, rare

You have a +1 bonus to Armor Class while wearing this armor.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Boots of Elvenkind (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

While you wear these boots, your steps make no sound, regardless of the surface you are moving across. You also have Advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 239

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Boots of the Winding Path (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon (requires attunement)

While wearing these boots, you can take a Bonus Action to teleport up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. You must have occupied that space at some point during the current turn.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 112

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Cloak of Elvenkind (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon (requires attunement)

While you wear this cloak, Wisdom (Perception) checks made to perceive you have Disadvantage, and you have Advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 244

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Cloak of the Manta Ray (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon (requires attunement)

While wearing this cloak, you can breathe underwater, and you have a Swim Speed of 60 feet.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 245

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Dazzling Weapon (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Weapon, rare (requires attunement)

This magic weapon grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. While holding it, you can take a Bonus Action to cause it to shed Bright Light in a 30-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 30 feet. You can extinguish the light as a Bonus Action.

The weapon has 4 charges. You can take a Reaction immediately after being hit by an attack roll to expend 1 of the weapon's charges and force the attacker to make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the attacker has the Blinded condition until the end of its next turn. The weapon regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Eyes of Charming (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon (requires attunement)

These crystal lenses fit over the eyes. They have 3 charges. While wearing them, you can expend 1 or more charges to cast Charm Person (save DC 13). For 1 charge, you cast the level 1 version of the spell. You increase the spell's level by one for each additional charge you expend. The lenses regain all expended charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 261

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Eyes of Minute Seeing (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

These crystal lenses fit over the eyes. While wearing them, your vision improves significantly out to a range of 1 foot, granting you Darkvision within that range and Advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) checks made to examine something within that range.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 261

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Gloves of Thievery (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

These gloves are invisible while worn. While wearing them, you gain a +5 bonus to Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) checks and Dexterity checks made to pick locks.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 265

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Helm of Awareness (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

While wearing this helmet, you have Advantage on Initiative rolls.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 112

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Lantern of Revealing (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

While lit, this hooded lantern burns for 6 hours on 1 pint of oil, shedding Bright Light in a 30-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 30 feet. Invisible creatures and objects are visible as long as they are in the lantern's Bright Light. You can take a Utilize action to lower the hood, reducing the lantern's light to Dim Light in a 5-foot radius.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 275

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Mind Sharpener (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, uncommon (requires attunement)

The item has 4 charges. When you fail a Constitution saving throw to maintain Concentration, you can take a Reaction and expend 1 of the item's charges to succeed instead. The item regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 112

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Necklace of Adaptation (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon (requires attunement)
Weight: 1 lb.

While wearing this necklace, you can breathe normally in any environment, and you have Advantage on saving throws made to avoid or end the Poisoned condition.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 280

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Pipes of Haunting (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, uncommon

These pipes have 3 charges and regain 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. You can take a Magic action to play them and expend 1 charge to create an eerie, spellbinding tune. Each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition for 1 minute. A creature that fails the save repeats it at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. A creature that succeeds on its save is immune to the effect of these pipes for 24 hours.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 285

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Repulsion Shield (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Shield, uncommon

You gain a +1 bonus to Armor Class while wielding this shield.

The shield has 4 charges. While holding it, when a Large or smaller creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack roll, you can take a Reaction to expend 1 of the shield's charges and push the attacker up to 15 feet straight away. The shield regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn.

Shields require the Utilize action to Don or Doff. You gain the Armor Class benefit of a Shield only if you have training with it and are holding it.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 112

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Ring of Swimming (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, uncommon

You have a Swim Speed of 40 feet while wearing this ring.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 295

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Ring of Water Walking (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, uncommon

While wearing this ring, you cast Water Walk from it, targeting only yourself.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 296

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Sentinel Shield (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Shield, uncommon
Weight: 6 lb.

While holding this Shield, you have Advantage on Initiative rolls and Wisdom (Perception) checks. The Shield is emblazoned with a symbol of an eye.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 303

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Spell-Refueling Ring (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, uncommon (requires attunement by a spellcaster)

While wearing this ring, you can recover one expended spell slot as a Bonus Action. The recovered slot can be of level 3 or lower. Once used, the ring can't be used again until the next dawn.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 112

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Wand of Magic Missiles (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wand, uncommon
Weight: 1 lb.

This wand has 7 charges. While holding it, you can expend no more than 3 charges to cast Magic Missile from it. For 1 charge, you cast the level 1 version of the spell. You can increase the spell's level by 1 for each additional charge you expend.

Regaining Charges: The wand regains 1d6 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the wand's last charge, roll 1d20. On a 1, the wand crumbles into ashes and is destroyed.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 320

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Wand of Web (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wand, uncommon (requires attunement by a spellcaster)
Weight: 1 lb.

This wand has 7 charges. While holding it, you can expend 1 charge to cast Web (save DC 13) from it.

Regaining Charges: The wand regains 1d6 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the wand's last charge, roll 1d20. On a 1, the wand crumbles into ashes and is destroyed.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 322

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Weapon of Warning (Level 6) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Weapon, uncommon (requires attunement)

As long as this weapon is within your reach and you are attuned to it, you and allies within 30 feet of you gain the following benefits.

Alarm: The weapon magically awakens each subject who is sleeping naturally when combat begins. This benefit doesn't wake a subject from magically induced sleep.

Supernatural Readiness: Each subject has Advantage on its Initiative rolls.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Armor of Resistance (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Armor, rare (requires attunement)

You have Resistance to one damage type while you wear this armor. The damage type is chosen when the item is created: Acid, Cold, Fire, Force, Lightning, Necrotic, Poison, Psychic, Radiant, or Thunder.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Dagger of Venom +1 (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Melee Weapon, rare
Weight: 1 lb.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

You can take a Bonus Action to magically coat the blade with poison. The poison remains for 1 minute or until an attack using this weapon hits a creature. That creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or take 2d10 Poison damage and have the Poisoned condition for 1 minute. The weapon can't be used this way again until the next dawn.

Nick (Mastery): When you make the extra attack of the Light property, you can make it as part of the Attack action in· stead of as a Bonus Action. You can make this extra attack only once per turn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: When you take the Attack action on your turn and. attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.

Proficiency: simple, dagger
Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 248

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Elven Chain +1 (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Heavy Armor, rare
Weight: 55 lb.

You gain a +1 bonus to Armor Class while you wear this armor. You are considered trained with this armor even if you lack training with Medium or Heavy armor.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 257

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Ring of Feather Falling (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, rare (requires attunement)

When you fall while wearing this ring, you descend 60 feet per round and take no damage from falling.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 293

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Ring of Jumping (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, uncommon (requires attunement)

While wearing this ring, you can cast Jump from it, but can target only yourself when you do so.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 293

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Ring of Mind Shielding (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, uncommon (requires attunement)

While wearing this ring, you are immune to magic that allows other creatures to read your thoughts, determine whether you are lying, know your alignment, or know your creature type. Creatures can telepathically communicate with you only if you allow it.

You can take a Magic action to cause the ring to become imperceptible until you take another Magic action to make it perceptible, until you remove the ring, or until you die.

If you die while wearing the ring, your soul enters it, unless it already houses a soul. You can remain in the ring or depart for the afterlife. As long as your soul is in the ring, you can telepathically communicate with any creature wearing it. A wearer can't prevent this telepathic communication.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 293

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Shield +2 (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Shield, rare
Weight: 6 lb.

While holding this Shield, you have a +2 bonus to Armor Class, in addition to the Shield's normal bonus to AC.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 303

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Wand of the War Mage +2 (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wand, rare (requires attunement by a spellcaster)
Weight: 1 lb.

While holding this wand, you gain a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls. In addition, you ignore Half Cover when making a spell attack roll.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 322

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Weapon +2 (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Weapon, rare

You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Wraps of Unarmed Power +2 (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Wondrous Item, rare

While wearing these wraps, you have a +2 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with your Unarmed Strikes. Those strikes deal your choice of Force damage or their normal damage type.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 325

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Uncommon Magic Item (Level 10) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Uncommon Wondrous Item that isn't cursed.

You can learn this option multiple times and must select a different item each time; each item selected counts as a different plan.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 10</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Armor +2 (Level 14) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Armor, very rare

You have a +2 bonus to Armor Class while wearing this armor.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 11</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Arrow-Catching Shield (Level 14) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Shield, rare (requires attunement)
Weight: 6 lb.

You gain a +2 bonus to Armor Class against ranged attack rolls while you wield this Shield. This bonus is in addition to the Shield's normal bonus to AC.

Whenever an attacker makes a ranged attack roll against a target within 5 feet of you, you can take a Reaction to become the target of the attack instead.

Proficiency: shield
Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 231

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 11</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Flame Tongue (Level 14) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Weapon, rare (requires attunement)

While holding this magic weapon, you can take a Bonus Action and use a command word to cause flames to engulf the damage-dealing part of the weapon. These flames shed Bright Light in a 40-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 40 feet. While the weapon is ablaze, it deals an extra 2d6 Fire damage on a hit. The flames last until you take a Bonus Action to issue the command again or until you drop, stow, or sheathe the weapon.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 11</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Ring of Free Action (Level 14) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, rare (requires attunement)

While you wear this ring, Difficult Terrain doesn't cost you extra movement. In addition, magic can neither reduce any of your Speeds nor cause you to have the Paralyzed or Restrained condition.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 293

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 11</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Ring of Protection (Level 14) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, rare (requires attunement)

You gain a +1 bonus to Armor Class and saving throws while wearing this ring.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 294

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 11</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Ring of the Ram (Level 14) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Type: Ring, rare (requires attunement)

This ring has 3 charges and regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. While wearing the ring, you can take a Magic action to expend 1 to 3 charges to make a ranged spell attack against one creature you can see within 60 feet of yourself. The ring produces a spectral ram's head and makes its attack roll with a +7 bonus. On a hit, for each charge you spend, the target takes 2d10 Force damage and is pushed 5 feet away from you.

Alternatively, you can expend 1 to 3 of the ring's charges as a Magic action to try to break a nonmagical object you can see within 60 feet of yourself that isn't being worn or carried. The ring makes a Strength check with a +5 bonus for each charge you spend.

Source:	Dungeon Master's Guide (2024) p. 296

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 11</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plan: Rare Magic Item (Level 14) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <classes>Magic Item Plans [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Rare Wondrous Item that isn't cursed.

You can learn this option multiple times and must select a different item each time; each item selected counts as a different plan.

Source:	Eberron: Forge of the Artificer p. 11</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>
