<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Monk [2024]</name>
    <!-- Monk Subclass: Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monk Subclass: Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</name>
        <text>Weave Martial and Mystic Arts

Warriors of the Mystic Arts wield magic to supplement their martial skill. They harness their supernatural focus to enhance their magical and physical abilities.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 1 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Spellcasting (Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA))</name>
        <text>You have learned to cast spells. See the Player's Handbook for the rules on spellcasting. The information below details how you use those rules as a Warrior of the Mystic Arts.

Cantrips. You know two cantrips of your choice from the Sorcerer spell list. Blade Ward and Thunderclap are recommended. Whenever you gain a Monk level, you can replace one of these cantrips with another cantrip of your choice from the Sorcerer spell list.
	When you reach Monk level 10, you learn another Sorcerer cantrip of your choice.

Spell Slots. The Warrior of the Mystic Arts Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your level 1+ spells. You regain all expended slots when you finish a Long Rest.

Prepared Spells of Level 1+. You prepare the list of level 1+ spells that are available for you to cast with this feature. To start, choose three level 1 spells from the Sorcerer spell list. Jump, Magic Missile, and Shield are recommended.
	The number of spells on your list increases as you gain Monk levels, as shown in the Prepared Spells column of the Warrior of the Mystic Arts Spellcasting table. Whenever that number increases, choose additional spells from the Sorcerer spell list until the number of spells on your list matches the number on the table. The chosen spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For example, if you're a level 7 Monk, your list of prepared spells can include five Sorcerer spells of levels 1 and 2 in any combination.

Changing Your Prepared Spells. Whenever you gain a Monk level, you can replace one spell on your list with another Sorcerer spell for which you have spell slots.

Spellcasting Ability. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your Sorcerer spells.

Spellcasting Focus. You can use an Arcane Focus as a Spellcasting Focus for your Sorcerer spells.

Multiclassing. If you multiclass and have the Spellcasting feature from more than one class, add one third of your Monk levels (round down) to determine your available spell slots.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 1 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Mystic Focus (Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA))</name>
        <text>You keep your magical power and martial focus in perfect balance, allowing you to convert spell slots into Focus Points, or convert Focus Points into spell slots.

Converting Spell Slots to Focus Points. You can expend a spell slot to regain a number of expended Focus Points equal to the slot's level (no action required).

Recovering Spell Slots. As a Bonus Action, you can transform unexpended Focus Points to recover one expended spell slot. The Recovering Spell Slots table shows the cost of recovering a spell slot of a given level, and it lists the minimum Monk level you must be to recover a slot. You can recover a spell slot no higher than level 4.

Recovering Spell Slots:
Spell Slot Level | Focus Point Cost | Min. Monk Level
1 | 2 | 6
2 | 3 | 7
3 | 5 | 13
4 | 6 | 19

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Mystic Fighting Style (Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA))</name>
        <text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of the attacks with a casting of one of your Sorcerer cantrips that has a casting time of an action.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>7</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Centered Focus (Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA))</name>
        <text>Whenever you expend a Focus Point to use Flurry of Blows, Patient Defense, or Step of the Wind, you have Advantage on any saving throw you make to maintain Concentration until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>8</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>9</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>10</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>11</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Improved Mystic Fighting Style (Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA))</name>
        <text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace two of the attacks with a casting of one of your level 1 or 2 Sorcerer spells that has a casting time of an action.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>12</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Prepared</name>
        <value>13</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Warrior of the Mystic Arts (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
