<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Paladin [2024]</name>
    <!-- Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Spellguard (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Spellguard (UA)</name>
        <text>Protect Your Allies from Villainous Magic

Paladins who take the Oath of the Spellguard are sworn to battle those who use magic to harm others. They often serve as bodyguards to upstanding mages, but their most important role is protecting allies from devastating magical attacks. Those who swear this oath ensure that villains who misuse magic are brought to justice.
	These paladins share the following tenets:

	• Protect the innocent from wicked mages.
	• Prevent magic from falling into villains' hands.
	• Protect mages who use magic honorably.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Guardian Bond (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you can expend one use of your Channel Divinity to forge a divine bond with a willing creature within 5 feet of yourself. The bond lasts for 1 hour or until you have the Unconscious condition. For the duration, while the bonded creature is within your reach and is hit by an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to that creature's AC, possibly causing the attack to miss.
	You can end your divine bond at any time (no action required). If you already have a divine bond when you forge a new one, the previous bond ends.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oath Of The Spellguard Spells (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</name>
        <text>The magic of your oath ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Paladin level specified in the Oath of the Spellguard Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Oath Of The Spellguard Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3 | Detect Magic, Shield
5 | See Invisibility, Silence
9 | Counterspell, Dispel Magic
13 | Freedom of Movement, Otiluke's Resilient Sphere
17 | Circle of Power, Hallow

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Spellguard Strike (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</name>
        <text>When you see a creature within your reach casting a spell with Verbal, Somatic, or Material components, you can take a Reaction to make a melee attack with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike against that creature.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Aura Of Concentration (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</name>
        <text>Your aura of protection fosters mental focus. You and your allies have Advantage on Constitution saving throws to maintain Concentration while in your Aura of Protection.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Spell-Breaking Blade (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</name>
        <text>Immediately after you hit a creature with your Spellguard Strike, you can cast Counterspell as part of the same Reaction.
	When you cast Counterspell with a spell slot, that slot isn't expended if the spell fails to stop a spell.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 20: Eternal Spellguard (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can empower your Aura of Protection, granting the benefits below for 1 minute or until you end them (no action required). Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can restore your use of this ability by expending a level 5 spell slot (no action required).

Bodyguard. While the target of your Guardian Bond is in the aura, that creature has Resistance to all damage.

Protection from Magic. You and your allies in the aura have Advantage on saving throws against spells.

Spell Ward. Spell attack rolls against you and your allies in the aura have Disadvantage.

Source:	Mystic Subclasses p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Magic [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shield [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>See Invisibility [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Silence [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Counterspell [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Magic [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Freedom of Movement [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Otiluke's Resilient Sphere [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Circle of Power [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallow [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oath of the Spellguard (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
