<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Fighter [2024]</name>
    <!-- Fighter subclass: Gladiator (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighter subclass: Gladiator (UA)</name>
        <text>Master Brutality and Blood Sport

Gladiators are just as much performers as they are warriors. Whether brawling in underground fighting rings or fighting for survival in bloodstained arenas, a Gladiator combines martial skill with theatrics to awe and intimidate their audiences.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Brutality (Gladiator (UA))</name>
        <text>Shaped by the intensity of the arena, you've learned to execute brutal martial moves. Once per turn, when you hit a creature with an attack roll using a Melee weapon, you can add one of the following Brutality effects of your choice. You can do this a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Bleed. You can activate the Sap mastery property in addition to a different mastery property you're using with that weapon, and the target takes extra damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). The extra damage's type is the same type as the weapon's type.

Bluff. You can activate the Vex mastery property in addition to a different mastery property you're using with that weapon, and you have Advantage on the next saving throw you make before the end of your next turn.

Stumble. You can activate the Topple mastery property in addition to a different mastery property you're using with that weapon, and on its next turn, the target can take only an action or a Bonus Action, not both.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Combat Theatrics (Gladiator (UA))</name>
        <text>You've honed your combat skills to entertain, devastating opponents and dazzling onlookers. You gain the following benefits.

Athletic Flair. Whenever you make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) or Strength (Athletics) check, you gain a bonus to the check equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1).

Bonus Proficiency. You gain proficiency in one of these skills of your choice: Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Intimidation, or Performance.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Flourish Parry (Gladiator (UA))</name>
        <text>You've learned to stylishly counter blows from your opponents. When an enemy hits you with a melee attack roll, you can take a Reaction to add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to your AC against the attack, potentially causing the attack to miss.

Flourish Counter. If this Reaction causes the attack to miss, you can retaliate with a powerful counterattack as part of the same Reaction. Make an attack roll with a Melee weapon against the triggering creature. If this attack hits, you can use one of your Brutality effects on the target without expending a use of that feature.
	Once this counterattack hits, you can't use this feature to make another counterattack until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of this counterattack by expending a use of Second Wind (no action required).

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Flourish Counter</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Gladiator (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Bolder Brutalities (Gladiator (UA))</name>
        <text>Your brutal martial prowess has improved. The following effects are added to your Brutality options.

Rive. You can activate the Cleave mastery property in addition to a different mastery property you're using with that weapon, and you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the additional attack made as part of that property's activation.

Rush. You can activate the Push mastery property in addition to a different mastery property you're using with that weapon, and you can immediately move up to your Speed without provoking Opportunity Attacks.

Stagger. You can activate the Slow mastery property in addition to a different mastery property you're using with that weapon, and the target has Disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Brutal Resurgence (Gladiator (UA))</name>
        <text>Whenever you use your Second Wind to regain Hit Points, you regain an expended use of Brutality. You also regain an expended use of Brutality whenever you use your Action Surge.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Mutilate (Gladiator (UA))</name>
        <text>When you hit a Bloodied creature with an attack roll, you can attempt to critically injure it. The target makes a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 plus your Charisma modifier and Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, the target suffers the following effects:

Maimed. If the target takes the Attack action, it can make only one attack.

Sluggish. The target's Speed is halved, and it has a -2 penalty to its Armor Class.

These effects last until the target regains Hit Points.
	Once a target fails its saving throw against this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Mutilate</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Gladiator (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
