<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Druid [2024]</name>
    <!-- Druid subclass: Circle of Preservation (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Druid subclass: Circle of Preservation (UA)</name>
        <text>Safeguard Nature and Heal the World

Druids of the Circle of Preservation work tirelessly to conserve natural resources and restore places once ruined by greed and exploitation. Through a combination of conservation and restorative magic, Druids of this order shield and spread life across the land. The most powerful members of this order can return vitality to barren fields, transforming wastelands into thriving wildernesses once more.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Circle of Preservation Spells (Circle of Preservation (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Druid level specified in the Circle of Preservation Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Circle of Preservation Spells:
Druid Level | Spells
3 | Bless, Lesser Restoration, Protection from Poison, Sanctuary
5 | Beacon of Hope, Plant Growth
7 | Aura of Life, Death Ward
9 | Greater Restoration, Hallow

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Preserved Land (Circle of Preservation (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can expend a use of your Wild Shape to fill a 15-foot Cube originating from a point on the ground you can see within 120 feet of yourself with revitalizing energy. The effect lasts for 1 minute or until you have the Incapacitated condition, are more than 120 feet away from the Cube, or die.
	Whenever a creature (including you) ends its turn in the Cube, you can grant the creature one of the following benefits:

Bolster. The creature gains Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d4 plus your Druid level.

Purify. You end one effect on the creature causing it to have the Frightened or Poisoned condition.

In addition, nonmagical vegetation native to the region sprouts on ground within the Cube. This vegetation disappears when the effect ends.
	As a Bonus Action on subsequent turns, you can move the Cube up to 30 feet to another area on the ground within 120 feet of yourself.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Student of Preservation (Circle of Preservation (UA))</name>
        <text>Your studies have improved your understanding of the order and resilience of nature, granting you the following benefits.

Frugal Casting. When you cast a Druid spell, you can cast it without Material components, except Material components that are consumed by the spell or that have a cost specified in the spell.
	Additionally, whenever you cast a Druid spell that requires a Material component that is consumed by the spell, there is a 10 percent chance that the component isn't consumed as part of that casting.

Tool Proficiency. You gain proficiency with one type of Artisan's Tools of your choice.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Improved Preservation (Circle of Preservation (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Preserved Land becomes more powerful in the following ways.

Fortify Protectors. While inside the Cube created by your Preserved Land, you and your allies gain a bonus to Constitution saving throws equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of + 1).

Reject Desecrators. Whenever the Cube created by your Preserved Land enters an enemy's space and whenever an enemy enters the Cube or ends its turn there, that enemy makes a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the enemy takes 2d10 Radiant damage, and its Speed is halved until the end of its next turn as new growth rises to hinder it. On a successful save, the enemy takes half as much damage only. An enemy makes this save only once per turn.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 2</text>
        <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Facilitated Restoration (Circle of Preservation (UA))</name>
        <text>You can cast Lesser Restoration or Greater Restoration without expending a spell slot or requiring spell components. You can use this feature to cast a spell in this way a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Sacrosanct Land (Circle of Preservation (UA))</name>
        <text>The size of the Cube created by your Preserved Land increases to a 30-foot Cube.
	In addition, when a creature you can see in the area of your Preserved Land is hit by an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to halve that attack's damage against the creature.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Bless [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Lesser Restoration [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Protection from Poison [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sanctuary [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Beacon of Hope [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plant Growth [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Life [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Death Ward [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Restoration [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallow [2024]</name>
    <classes>Druid [2024] (Circle of Preservation (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
