<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Warlock [2024]</name>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: Sorcerer-king Patron (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: Sorcerer-king Patron (UA)</name>
        <text>Herald Tyrannical Might of Monstrous Rulers Your pact draws from the power of a monstrous, tyrannical force akin to a demigod or an overwhelmingly powerful magic-user. Through your pact, you herald this tyrant's interests in the world, channeling their influence and mind-bending, psionic power.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Sorcerer-king Spells (Sorcerer-King Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready; whenever you reach a Warlock level specified in the Sorcerer-King Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Psionic Casting. When you cast a spell from the Sorcerer-King Spells table, you can do so without Verbal or Material components, except Material components that are consumed by the spell or that have a cost specified in the spell.

Sorcerer-King Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3 | Command, Compelled Duel, Hold Person, Mind Spike, Wrathful Smite
5 | Fear, Sending
7 | Compulsion, Staggering Smite
9 | Dominate Person, Synaptic Static

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Tyrant's Herald (Sorcerer-King Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

Intimidating Presence. You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill if you don't already have it You also have Expertise in Intimidation.

Voice of Tyranny. You can cast Command as a Bonus Action without expending a spell slot. You can do so a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Decisive Edict (Sorcerer-King Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>Your patron's power surges through you, allowing you to rally your allies and subjugate your enemies. When you cast a spell using a Pact Magic spell slot, you can cause profane power to erupt in a 30-foot Emanation originating from you. For each creature you can see in the Emanation, choose one of the following effects:

Marshal. The creature has Advantage on attack rolls until the end of its next turn.

Oppress. The creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or have the Frightened condition until the end of its next turn.

Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a Short or Long Rest. You also regain use of this feature when you use Magical Cunning.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Decisive Edict</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Sorcerer-king Patron (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Vindictive Rebuke (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn to rebuff those who challenge you or the might of your patron. When an enemy hits you with an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to force the enemy to reroll the d20, and the enemy must use the new roll. If this Reaction turns the attack roll into a miss, the triggering creature takes Psychic damage equal to your Warlock level.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Absolute Tyranny (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>You wield your patron's tyrannical might with absolute conviction. Whenever you cast Command, you can target one additional creature within the spell's range. Additionally, a creature Frightened by you automatically fails its saving throw against any Command you cast.

Source:	UA25-ApocalypticSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Command [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Compelled Duel [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Person [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mind Spike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wrathful Smite [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fear [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sending [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Compulsion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Staggering Smite [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dominate Person [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Synaptic Static [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [2024] (Sorcerer-king Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
