<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <!-- Regional Backgrounds -->
  <background>
    <name>Chondathan Freebooter [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Athletics, Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are a pirate or privateer from the Vilhon Reach, skilled in maritime combat and plunder.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Skilled</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in any combination of three skills or tools of your choice.

Repeatable: You can take this feat more than once.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024) p. 201</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Dead Magic Dweller [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Medicine, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You have lived in or near the dead magic zones of Anauroch, where magic fails and strange phenomena occur.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Healer</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Battle Medic. If you have a Healer's Kit, you can expend one use of it and tend to a creature within 5 feet of yourself as a Utilize action. That creature can expend one of its Hit Point Dice, and you then roll that die. The creature regains a number of Hit Points equal to the roll plus your Proficiency Bonus.

Healing Rerolls. Whenever you roll a die to determine the number of Hit Points you restore with a spell or with this feat's Battle Medic benefit, you can reroll the die if it rolls a 1, and you must use the new roll.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024) p. 201</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Flaming Fist Mercenary [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Intimidation, Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You served with the Flaming Fist mercenary company of Baldur's Gate on the Sword Coast.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Tough</name>
      <text>Your Hit Point maximum increases by an amount equal to twice your character level when you gain this feat. Whenever you gain a character level thereafter, your Hit Point maximum increases by an additional 2 Hit Points.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024) p. 202</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Genie Touched [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Perception, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You have been influenced by the elemental magic of genies in the Lands of Intrigue.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Magic Initiate (Wizard)</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Two Cantrips. You learn two cantrips of your choice from the Cleric, Druid, or Wizard spell list. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this feat's spells (choose when you select this feat).

Level 1 Spell. Choose a level 1 spell from the same list you selected for this feat's cantrips. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Spell Change. Whenever you gain a new level, you can replace one of the spells you chose for this feat with a different spell of the same level from the chosen spell list.

Repeatable. You can take this feat more than once, but you must choose a different spell list each time.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024) p. 201</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Ice Fisher [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Animal Handling, Athletics</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You make your living fishing the icy waters of the North, braving harsh conditions and dangerous creatures.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Alert</name>
      <text>When you roll Initiative, you can add your Proficiency Bonus to the roll. Additionally, you and allies within 5 feet of you can't be surprised.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024)</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Moonwell Pilgrim [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Nature, Performance</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You have traveled between the sacred moonwells of the Trackless Sea islands, seeking their mystical power.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Magic Initiate (Druid)</name>
      <text>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the Druid spell list. You also learn one level 1 spell of your choice from that list. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells. You can cast the level 1 spell without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in this way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024)</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Mulhorandi Tomb Raider [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Investigation, Religion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You explore the ancient tombs and ruins of the Old Empires, seeking treasure and knowledge.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Lucky</name>
      <text>You have a number of Luck Points equal to your Proficiency Bonus and regain all expended Luck Points when you finish a Long Rest. You can spend a Luck Point to give yourself Advantage on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, or to impose Disadvantage on an attack roll made against you.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024)</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Mythalkeeper [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana, History</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are a guardian or scholar of the ancient mythals in the Heartlands region.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Crafter</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency with three different Artisan's Tools of your choice. Whenever you buy a nonmagical item, you receive a 20 percent discount on it.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024)</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Rashemi Wanderer [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Intimidation, Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are a traveler from Rashemen in the Arcane Empires, experienced in wilderness survival.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Tough</name>
      <text>Your Hit Point maximum increases by an amount equal to twice your character level when you gain this feat. Whenever you gain a character level thereafter, your Hit Point maximum increases by an additional 2 Hit Points.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024) p. 202</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Shadowmasters Exile [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics, Stealth</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You were exiled from the shadow-touched lands of the Forgotten Lands region.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Savage Attacker</name>
      <text>You have trained to deal particularly damaging strikes. Once per turn when you hit a target with a weapon, you can roll the weapon's damage dice twice and use either roll.

Source:	Player's Handbook (2024)</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <!-- Faction Backgrounds -->
  <background>
    <name>Dragon Cultist [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Deception, Stealth</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You were once a member of the Cult of the Dragon, worshipping dragons and seeking their power.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Cult of the Dragon Initiate</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Dragon's Tongue. You know Draconic. If you already know Draconic when you select this feat, you instead learn one language of your choice from the language tables in the Player's Handbook or Chapter 2 of this book.

Dragon's Terror. You can take a Magic action to instill terror in a creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC 8 plus your Wisdom modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or have the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn. If the target succeeds on the save or when the effect ends for a target, the target is immune to this effect for 24 hours.

Inspired by Fear. When you cause a creature to have the Frightened condition and you are the source of its fear, you can gain Heroic Inspiration if you lack it. Once you use this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn p. 37</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Emerald Enclave Caretaker [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Nature, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You serve the Emerald Enclave, protecting the natural world from those who would exploit it.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Emerald Enclave Fledgling</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Speak with Animals. You always have the Speak with Animals spell prepared and can cast it with any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). When you cast this spell as a Ritual, its duration is 8 hours.

Tag Team. When you take the Help action, you can switch places with a willing ally within 5 feet of yourself as part of that same action. This movement doesn't provoke Opportunity Attacks. You can't use this benefit if the ally has the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn p. 37</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Harper [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Performance, Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are an agent of the Harpers, working in secret to promote good and oppose tyranny.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Harper Agent</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Thieves' Cant. You know Thieves' Cant.

Instrument Training. You gain proficiency with a Musical Instrument of your choice.

Distracting Melody. When you take the Help action to assist an ally's attack roll, the enemy you're distracting can be within 30 feet of you, rather than within 5 feet of you, provided the enemy can see or hear you.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn p. 37</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Knight of the Gauntlet [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Athletics, Medicine</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are a member of the Knights of the Gauntlet, dedicated to fighting evil and protecting the innocent.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Tyro of the Gauntlet</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Stand as One. When an ally within 5 feet of you is subjected to an effect that would push or pull it, you can take a Reaction to prevent that ally from being pushed or pulled. To receive this benefit, the ally can't have the Incapacitated condition.

Vigilant. When you take the Ready action, the next attack roll made against you has Disadvantage before the start of your next turn.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn p. 38</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Lords' Alliance Vassal [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You serve a member of the Lords' Alliance, working to maintain order and prosperity in civilized lands.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Lords' Alliance Agent</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Inspiring Strike. Once per turn when you score a Critical Hit against a creature, you can choose an ally within 30 feet of yourself who can see or hear you and who lacks Heroic Inspiration. That ally gains Heroic Inspiration.

Reassert Honor. When an enemy you can see deals damage to an ally of yours that is within 5 feet of you, you have Advantage on your next attack roll against that enemy before the end of your next turn.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn p. 38</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Purple Dragon Squire [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Animal Handling, Insight</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You trained as a squire to the Purple Dragon Knights of Cormyr.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Purple Dragon Rook</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Entreat. You gain proficiency in one of the following skills: Insight, Performance, or Persuasion.

Rallying Cry. When you roll Initiative and don't have the Incapacitated condition, you can choose a number of creatures equal to your Proficiency Bonus that you can see within 30 feet of yourself. Those creatures gain Heroic Inspiration.

Once you use this benefit, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn p. 38</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <background>
    <name>Zhentarim Mercenary [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Intimidation, Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You work for the Zhentarim, a shadowy network of merchants and mercenaries.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Zhentarim Ruffian</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Exploit Opening. When you roll damage for an Opportunity Attack, you can roll the damage dice twice and use either roll against the target.

Family First. If you have Heroic Inspiration when you roll Initiative, you can expend it to give yourself and your allies Advantage on that Initiative roll.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn p. 38</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  
  <!-- Special Background -->
  <background>
    <name>Spellfire Initiate [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana, Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You were born with the rare ability to manipulate spellfire, a dangerous and powerful magical force.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Spellfire Spark</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Magic Absorption. Once per turn, when you take damage from a spell or magical effect, you reduce the total damage taken by 1d4. You can't use this benefit if you have the Incapacitated condition.

Spellfire Flame. You learn the Sacred Flame cantrip. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can also cast this cantrip as a Bonus Action a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>