<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Ranger [2024]</name>
    <!-- Ranger Subclass: Winter Walker -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Subclass: Winter Walker</name>
        <text>Withstand the Horrors of Frigid Wastelands

Winter Walkers hone their craft in the bleak and frozen wilds of places like Icewind Dale. These ruthless, rimed Rangers hunt monsters that haunt arctic wastelands, eventually becoming frigid terrors themselves. Winter Walkers are well versed in the phenomena of Icewind Dale, including the latent magic of fallen Netherese cities, endemic monsters like yetis and crag cats, and the rising threat of Underdark invaders. Due to their cold pragmatism, terrifying magic, and mastery of the region, Winter Walkers are regarded with equal parts respect and fear. Ten-Towns citizens say that Winter Walkers' frequent exposure to malignant entities gives them their fearsome powers. Many Reghed nomads, on the other hand, believe that nature spirits bestow on Winter Walkers a unique curse.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Frigid Explorer (Winter Walker)</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

Biting Cold. Damage from your weapon attacks, Ranger spells, and Ranger features ignores Resistance to Cold damage.

Frost Resistance. You have Resistance to Cold damage.

Polar Strikes. When you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon, you can deal an extra 1d4 Cold damage to the target, which can take this extra damage only once per turn. When you reach Ranger level 11, this extra damage increases to 1d6.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
        <roll description="Polar Strikes Cold Damage" level="3">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Polar Strikes Cold Damage" level="11">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hunter's Rime (Winter Walker)</name>
        <text>Ice rimes you and your prey, protecting you and slowing them. When you cast Hunter's Mark, you gain Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d10 plus your Ranger level.
	Additionally, while a creature is marked by your Hunter's Mark, it can't take the Disengage action.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
        <roll description="Temporary Hit Points">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Winter Walker Spells (Winter Walker)</name>
        <text>When you reach a Ranger level specified in the Winter Walker Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Ranger Level | Spells
3 | Ice Knife
5 | Hold Person
9 | Remove Curse
13 | Ice Storm
17 | Cone of Cold

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Fortifying Soul (Winter Walker)</name>
        <text>Your experience surviving harrowing environments allows you to bolster your allies in addition to yourself. As a Magic action, choose a number of creatures you can see equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of one). Each chosen creature regains Hit Points equal to 1d10 plus your Ranger level and has Advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Frightened condition for 1 hour.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
        <roll description="Hit Points Regained">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Fortifying Soul</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Winter Walker</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Chilling Retribution (Winter Walker)</name>
        <text>When a creature hits you with an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to force the creature to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the target has the Stunned condition until the end of your next turn. While the target is Stunned, its Speed is reduced to 0 feet.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Polar Strikes Improvement (Winter Walker)</name>
        <text>Your Polar Strikes damage increases to 1d6 Cold damage.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Chilling Retribution</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Winter Walker</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Frozen Haunt (Winter Walker)</name>
        <text>When you cast Hunter's Mark, you can adopt a ghostly, snowy form. This form lasts until the spell ends, and while you are in this form, you gain the following benefits. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest unless you expend a level 4+ spell slot (no action required).

Frozen Soul. You have Immunity to Cold damage. When you first adopt this form and at the start of each of your subsequent turns, each creature of your choice in a 15-foot Emanation originating from you takes 2d4 Cold damage.

Partially Incorporeal. You have Immunity to the Grappled, Prone, and Restrained conditions. You can move through creatures and objects as if they were Difficult Terrain, but you take 1d10 Force damage if you end your turn inside a creature or an object. If the form ends while you are inside a creature or an object, you are shunted to the nearest unoccupied space.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
        <roll description="Frozen Soul Cold Damage">2d4</roll>
        <roll description="Force Damage (Inside Object)">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Frozen Haunt</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Winter Walker</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Ice Knife [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Winter Walker)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Person [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Winter Walker)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Remove Curse [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Winter Walker)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ice Storm [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Winter Walker)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cone of Cold [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Winter Walker)</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
