<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <!-- Origin Feats -->
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Cult of the Dragon Initiate [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Dragon's Tongue. You know Draconic. If you already know Draconic when you select this feat, you instead learn one language of your choice from the language tables in the Player's Handbook or Chapter 2 of this book.

Dragon's Terror. You can take a Magic action to instill terror in a creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC 8 plus your Wisdom modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or have the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn. If the target succeeds on the save or when the effect ends for a target, the target is immune to this effect for 24 hours.

Inspired by Fear. When you cause a creature to have the Frightened condition and you are the source of its fear, you can gain Heroic Inspiration if you lack it. Once you use this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 37</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Emerald Enclave Fledgling [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Speak with Animals. You always have the Speak with Animals spell prepared and can cast it with any spell slots you have. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). When you cast this spell as a Ritual, its duration is 8 hours.

Tag Team. When you take the Help action, you can switch places with a willing ally within 5 feet of yourself as part of that same action. This movement doesn't provoke Opportunity Attacks. You can't use this benefit if the ally has the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 37</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Harper Agent [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Thieves' Cant. You know Thieves' Cant.

Instrument Training. You gain proficiency with a Musical Instrument of your choice.

Distracting Melody. When you take the Help action to assist an ally's attack roll, the enemy you're distracting can be within 30 feet of you, rather than within 5 feet of you, provided the enemy can see or hear you.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 37</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Lords' Alliance Agent [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Inspiring Strike. Once per turn when you score a Critical Hit against a creature, you can choose an ally within 30 feet of yourself who can see or hear you and who lacks Heroic Inspiration. That ally gains Heroic Inspiration.

Reassert Honor. When an enemy you can see deals damage to an ally of yours that is within 5 feet of you, you have Advantage on your next attack roll against that enemy before the end of your next turn.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 38</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Purple Dragon Rook [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Entreat. You gain proficiency in one of the following skills: Insight, Performance, or Persuasion.

Rallying Cry. When you roll Initiative and don't have the Incapacitated condition, you can choose a number of creatures equal to your Proficiency Bonus that you can see within 30 feet of yourself. Those creatures gain Heroic Inspiration.

Once you use this benefit, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 38</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Spellfire Spark [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Magic Absorption. Once per turn, when you take damage from a spell or magical effect, you reduce the total damage taken by 1d4. You can't use this benefit if you have the Incapacitated condition.

Spellfire Flame. You learn the Sacred Flame cantrip. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can also cast this cantrip as a Bonus Action a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 38</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Tyro of the Gauntlet [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Stand as One. When an ally within 5 feet of you is subjected to an effect that would push or pull it, you can take a Reaction to prevent that ally from being pushed or pulled. To receive this benefit, the ally can't have the Incapacitated condition.

Vigilant. When you take the Ready action, the next attack roll made against you has Disadvantage before the start of your next turn.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 38</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Zhentarim Ruffian [2024]</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Exploit Opening. When you roll damage for an Opportunity Attack, you can roll the damage dice twice and use either roll against the target.

Family First. If you have Heroic Inspiration when you roll Initiative, you can expend it to give yourself and your allies Advantage on that Initiative roll.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 38</text>
  </feat>
  <!-- General Feats -->
  <feat>
    <name>Cold Caster [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Cantrip. You learn the Ray of Frost cantrip. If you already know it, you learn a different Wizard cantrip of your choice. The spell's spellcasting ability is the ability increased by this feat.

Frostbite. Once per turn when you hit a creature with an attack roll and deal Cold damage, you can temporarily negate the creature's defenses. The creature subtracts 1d4 from the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 39</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dragonscarred [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Cult of the Dragon Initiate</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Constitution or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Damage Resistance. When you gain this feat, choose Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Poison. You have Resistance to the chosen damage type.

Fearsome Power. When you deal damage to a creature as part of the Attack or Magic action on your turn, you can use the Dragon's Terror benefit of the Cult of the Dragon Initiate feat as a Bonus Action this turn.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 39</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Enclave Magic [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Emerald Enclave Fledgling</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Friend to Animals. You have Advantage on ability checks when taking the Influence action with Beasts.

Two Hearts, One Mind. You always have the Beast Sense spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. When you cast it without a spell slot using this feature, it doesn't require Concentration. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. The spell's spellcasting ability is the ability increased by this feat.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 39</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fairy Trickster [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Dexterity or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Faerie Trod Trotter. When you take the Disengage action on your turn, Difficult Terrain doesn't cost you extra movement for the rest of that turn.

Flustering Strike. When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can attempt to fluster the target. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC 8 plus the ability modifier of the score increased by this feat and your Proficiency Bonus) or have Disadvantage on saving throws until the end of your next turn.

You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 39</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Genie Magic [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Wish Magic. As a Magic action, you can cast a level 1 spell of your choice from the Sorcerer spell list that has a casting time of an action. Once you use this benefit, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest. The spell's spellcasting ability is the ability increased by this feat.

When you reach level 11, the spell you cast with this feat is cast as though using a level 2 spell slot.

When you reach level 17, the spell is cast as though using a level 3 spell slot.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 39</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Harper Teamwork [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Harper Agent</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Dexterity or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Withering Wordplay. When you take the Help action to assist an ally's attack roll against an enemy, that enemy also has Disadvantage on the first saving throw it makes before the start of your next turn.

Inspiring Willpower. If you succeed on a saving throw to end the Frightened or Paralyzed condition on yourself, you can choose one ally you can see within 30 feet of yourself that has the same condition. That condition immediately ends for that ally.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 39</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lordly Resolve [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Lords' Alliance Agent</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Standard Bearer. As a Bonus Action, choose up to three creatures within 60 feet of yourself that can see you. Each target can immediately take a Reaction to right itself and end the Prone condition, provided its Speed isn't 0. Additionally, you bolster the targets' resolve, which lasts for 1 minute or until you have the Incapacitated condition. While bolstered, a target can't be possessed or gain the Charmed or Frightened condition; if a target is already possessed, Charmed, or Frightened, the target has Advantage on any new saving throw against the relevant effect.

Once you use this benefit, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 40</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mythal Touched [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Mythal Ward. If a spell attack hits you or you fail a saving throw against a spell, you can take a Reaction to roll on the Mythal-Touched Magic table to create a magical effect. If an effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 plus the modifier of the ability increased by this feat and your Proficiency Bonus.

You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 40</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Order's Resilience [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Tyro of the Gauntlet</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength, Wisdom, or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Resurge. When you have the Prone condition, you can right yourself with only 5 feet of movement.

Stronger Together. If you are within 5 feet of an ally that doesn't have the Incapacitated condition, you and that ally have Advantage on Strength saving throws. You can't use this benefit while you have the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 40</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Purple Dragon Commandant [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Purple Dragon Rook or Martial Weapon Proficiency</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Dexterity by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Encourage Ally. As a Bonus Action, you bolster one ally you can see within 30 feet. The ally gains Temporary Hit Points equal to 2d6 plus the modifier of the ability score increased by this feat. You can take this Bonus Action a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Last Stand. You have Advantage on attack rolls while Bloodied.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 40</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Spellfire Adept [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Spellfire Spark or Spellcasting or Pact Magic Features</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Fueled Spellfire. Once per turn, when a spell you cast deals Radiant damage, you can expend up to two Hit Point Dice, roll them, and add the total rolled to one damage roll of the spell.

Searing Spellfire. When you make a damage roll that deals Radiant damage, it ignores Resistance to Radiant damage.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 41</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Street Justice [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Strength or Dexterity by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Headlock. Your allies have Advantage on attack rolls against a creature Grappled by you.

Sturdy Knot. When you use Chain, Manacles, or Rope to bind a creature, add your Proficiency Bonus to the DC to escape or burst the Chain, Manacles, or Rope.

Tough Talk. A creature's Hostile attitude doesn't impose Disadvantage on your Charisma (Intimidation) checks to influence that creature.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 41</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Zhentarim Tactics [2024]</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+, Zhentarim Ruffian</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Ability Score Increase. Increase your Dexterity or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.

Retaliate. Immediately after a creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack, you can make an Opportunity Attack against that creature.

Versatile Merc. When you finish a Long Rest, choose a skill in which you have proficiency. You have Expertise in that skill until you finish your next Long Rest.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 41</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
</compendium>
