<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <item>
    <name>Axe Beak [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>Use the Axe Beak stat block.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bandore [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <value>65</value>
    <text>If you have proficiency with a tool, add your Proficiency Bonus to any ability check you make that uses the tool. If you have proficiency in a skill that's used with that check, you have Advantage on the check too.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bright Fungal Cloak [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>While wearing a Bright Fungal Cloak, you can take a Bonus Action to furl or unfurl it. When the cloak is unfurled, it sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.
	One pound of fungus is sewn into a Bright Fungal Cloak. This fungus can be eaten as food. Once all the fungus is consumed, the cloak becomes a mundane set of Traveler's Clothes.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cittern [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <value>65</value>
    <text>If you have proficiency with a tool, add your Proficiency Bonus to any ability check you make that uses the tool. If you have proficiency in a skill that's used with that check, you have Advantage on the check too.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Covered Wagon [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1300</weight>
    <value>250</value>
    <text>This vehicle is a Wagon covered by durable canvas. A creature has Three-Quarters Cover while riding inside this vehicle.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Desert Clothing [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <value>10</value>
    <text>When you are wearing Desert Clothing and not wearing Medium or Heavy armor, you automatically succeed on saving throws against the effects of extreme heat.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Devil Mask [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>While you are wearing a Devil Mask, other creatures have Disadvantage on Intelligence (Investigation) and Wisdom (Insight) checks made to discern your true identity or intentions.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Flying Snake [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>Pet flying snakes use the Flying Snake stat block.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Garb of Light and Shadow [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>This garb appeals to Fey from one Domain of Delight, such as the Gloaming Court or the Summer Court. While wearing the garb, you have Advantage on ability checks to influence Fey associated with that Domain of Delight.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Genie Robe [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>This robe appeals to Elementals associated with a particular Elemental Plane (Air, Earth, Fire, Water). While wearing a Genie Robe, you have Advantage on ability checks made to influence Elementals associated with that plane.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Locking Spellbook [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <value>35</value>
    <text>This 100-page leather-bound tome can be used as a Spellbook. It is closed with a lock that comes with a key. As a Utilize action, a creature can try to pick the lock using Thieves' Tools, doing so with a successful DC 15 Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Monster Camouflage [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>A suit of Monster Camouflage looks like a Beast or Monstrosity, such as an owlbear. To discern that you're disguised, a creature must take the Study action to inspect your appearance and succeed on a DC 10 Intelligence (Investigation or Nature) check. The creature has Advantage on this check if it is within 30 feet of you and automatically succeeds on this check if you do anything the monster you're disguised as couldn't do.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Sled Dog [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>A sled dog uses the Wolf stat block (see the Monster Manual). A sled dog pulling a sled alone must take a Short Rest after pulling a sled for 1 hour; otherwise, it gains 1 Exhaustion level.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Warm Fungal Clothing [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <value>15</value>
    <text>When you're wearing Warm Fungal Clothing, you automatically succeed on saving throws against the effects of extreme cold. See chapter 3 of the Dungeon Master's Guide for rules on extreme cold. One pound of fungus is sewn into Fungal Clothing. This fungus can be eaten as food. Once all the fungus is consumed, this becomes a mundane set of Traveler's Clothes.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Winter Camouflage [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>While you wear Winter Camouflage in an appropriate environment, you have Advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Yarting [2024]</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <value>40</value>
    <text>If you have proficiency with a tool, add your Proficiency Bonus to any ability check you make that uses the tool. If you have proficiency in a skill that's used with that check, you have Advantage on the check too.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Adventurer's Ring [2024]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>RG</type>
    <text>While the cover on this ring is open, the ring produces a flame that creates no heat and consumes no fuel. It sheds Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet. As a Bonus Action, you can close the cover, smothering the flame, or open it again.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 132</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Prosthetic Limb [2024]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <value>0</value>
    <text>This magic item replaces a lost limb—a hand, an arm, a foot, a leg, or a similar body part. While the prosthetic is attached, it functions identically to the part it replaces. You can detach or reattach it as a Magic action, and it can't be removed against your will while you are alive.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 132</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Thayan Spell Tattoo [2024]</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>This magical tattoo contains the essence of a level 1-3 spell chosen by the tattoo's creator. While the tattoo is on your body, you always have the associated spell prepared, and you can cast the spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic feature, the spell uses your spellcasting ability; otherwise, if the spell requires a saving throw or an attack roll, the spell save DC is 13 and the attack bonus is +5. If your Attunement to the tattoo ends, the tattoo vanishes.
	You can also cast the spell once without a spell slot and spell components. Once the spell is cast in this way, the tattoo vanishes.

Inking Thayan Spell Tattoos:
The Thayan art of magical tattooing is highly guarded by its practitioners, and thus, Thayan Spell Tattoos can't be crafted like other magic items. To learn how to ink Thayan Spell Tattoos, you must have a Renown Score of 50+ with the Red Wizards.
	To ink a Thayan Spell Tattoo, you must have proficiency in the Arcana skill and with Calligrapher's Supplies and have the spell prepared each day of the inking. You must also have at hand any Material components required by the spell; if the spell consumes its Material components, they are consumed when you complete the tattoo. Inking a Thayan Spell Tattoo takes the same amount of time and money as scribing a Spell Scroll of an equivalent level.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 176</text>
  </item>
</compendium>
