<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <spell>
    <name>Scatterspray [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a handful of pebbles)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>Ranger [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You hurl pebbles that transform into a spray of hard projectiles. Choose a point within range. Each creature in a 15-foot Cone originating from that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 3d8 Bludgeoning damage and has the Prone condition. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage only.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 142</text>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage" level="2">3d8</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage" level="3">4d8</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage" level="4">5d8</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage" level="5">6d8</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage" level="6">7d8</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage" level="7">8d8</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage" level="8">9d8</roll>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage" level="9">10d8</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Laeral's Cutting Words [2024]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>EN</school>
    <time>1 reaction, which you take when a creature within range makes an attack roll, ability check, or damage roll</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>V</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>Bard [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Warlock [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You unleash a string of insults laced with subtle enchantments at a creature you can see within range. The target must subtract 1d8 from the roll that triggered this spell. You can cast this spell after the creature makes its roll, but before the DM determines the results.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 142</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Laeral's Crowning Touch [2024]</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>EN</school>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>24 hours</duration>
    <classes>Bard [2024], Sorcerer [2024], Warlock [2024], Wizard [2024]</classes>
    <text>You touch a willing creature and imbue it with regal authority. For the duration, the target adds your spellcasting ability modifier to any Charisma check it makes, and creatures have Disadvantage on attack rolls against the target.
	Additionally, if the target deals damage to a hostile creature, the target can choose another creature within 30 feet of itself. The chosen creature gains Temporary Hit Points equal to the damage dealt.

Source:	Forgotten Realms: Heroes of Faerûn (2024) p. 142</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>
