<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Monk [2024]</name>
    <!-- Monk Subclass: Tattooed Warrior (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monk Subclass: Tattooed Warrior (UA)</name>
        <text>Enhance Martial Arts with Your Magic Tattoos

Drawing from diverse body-marking traditions from across the multiverse, Tattooed Warriors can use arcane power imbued in their magic tattoos. These Monks gain tattoos as they grow in martial prowess and insight. Tattooed Warriors can cause their tattoos to change shape to access a versatile suite of physical and magical effects to overcome foes.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 4</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Magic Tattoos (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the magic tattoos described by other features of this subclass. The tattoos appear on your body wherever you wish. Damage or injury doesn't impair your magic tattoos' function. A magic tattoo's depiction can look like a brand, scarification, a birthmark, patterns of scale, or any other cosmetic alteration.
	If a tattoo's effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 plus your Wisdom modifier plus your Proficiency Bonus. Your spellcasting ability for spells granted by a tattoo is Wisdom.
	Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can reshape one of your magic tattoos, changing the option you chose from one list to another option on the same list.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 4</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Beast Tattoos (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain two animal tattoos. Choose two tattoos from the following options.

Bat. You know the Dancing Lights cantrip. When you expend 1 Focus Point to use Patient Defense or Step of the Wind, you gain Blindsight with a range of 10 feet for 1 minute.

Butterfly. You know the Light cantrip. You can expend 1 Focus Point to cast Silent Image without Material components.

Chameleon. You know the Minor Illusion cantrip. You can expend 1 Focus Point to cast Disguise Self.

Crane. You know the Guidance cantrip. When you miss a creature with an attack granted by your Flurry of Blows, you have Advantage on attack rolls for any remaining Unarmed Strikes with that use of Flurry of Blows.

Horse. You know the Message cantrip. You can expend 1 Focus Point to cast Longstrider without Material components.

Spider. You know the Mending cantrip. When you hit a creature with an attack granted by your Flurry of Blows, the creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Tortoise. You know the Spare the Dying cantrip. You can expend 1 Focus Point to cast False Life without Material components.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Celestial Tattoo (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain an additional magic tattoo depicting a celestial phenomenon. Choose a tattoo from the following options.

Comet. You can expend 2 Focus Points to cast Find Traps.

Crescent Moon. You can expend 2 Focus Points to cast Misty Step.

Eclipse. You can expend 2 Focus Points to cast Invisibility without Material components.

Sunburst. You can expend 2 Focus Points to cast Lesser Restoration.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Nature Tattoo (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain an additional magic tattoo depicting a natural feature. Choose a tattoo from the following options.

Mountain. As a Magic action, you can expend 3 Focus Points to gain Resistance to Acid damage and Advantage on Constitution saving throws for 1 minute.

Storm. As a Magic action, you can expend 3 Focus Points to gain Resistance to Lightning damage and Advantage on Dexterity saving throws for 1 minute.

Volcano. As a Magic action, you can expend 3 Focus Points to gain Resistance to Fire damage and Advantage on Strength saving throws for 1 minute.

Wave. As a Magic action, you can expend 3 Focus Points to gain Resistance to Cold damage and Advantage on Wisdom saving throws for 1 minute.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Monster Tattoo (Tattooed Warrior (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain a magic tattoo depicting a supernatural creature. Choose a tattoo from the following options.

Beholder. You have a Fly Speed of 10 feet and can hover. Additionally, you can expend 3 Focus Points to cast Counterspell.

Blink Dog. When you expend a Focus Point to use Patient Defense, you can expend 3 Focus Points to cast Blink immediately after that Bonus Action.

Displacer Beast. When you expend a Focus Point to use Flurry of Blows or Step of the Wind, you can expend 2 Focus Points to cast Mirror Image immediately after that Bonus Action.

Guardian Naga. When you would be reduced to 0 Hit Points but not killed outright, your Hit Points instead change to a number equal to twice your Monk level. Once you use this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
