<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Wizard [2024]</name>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: Conjurer (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: Conjurer (UA)</name>
        <text>Step Across Space and Call Creatures from Thin Air

You consider distance and matter to be flexible guidelines rather than physical laws. Conjurers harness the power of magic that moves creatures instantly through space and summons creatures to fight on their behalf.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Benign Transposition (Conjurer (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Magic action, you teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Alternatively, you can choose a space within range that is occupied by a Medium or smaller creature. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by expending a level 2+ spell slot (no action required).

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Conjuration Savant (Conjurer (UA))</name>
        <text>Choose two Wizard spells from the Conjuration school, each of which must be no higher than level 2, and add them to your spellbook for free.
	In addition, whenever you gain access to a new level of spell slots in this class, you can add one Wizard spell from the Conjuration school to your spellbook for free. The chosen spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Distant Transposition (Conjurer (UA))</name>
        <text>The range of your Benign Transposition feature increases to 60 feet. Additionally, you regain your expended use of it when you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Durable Summons (Conjurer (UA))</name>
        <text>When you cast a Conjuration spell to summon or create another creature using a spell slot, that creature gains Temporary Hit Points equal to twice your Wizard level when it first appears.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Focused Conjuration (Conjurer (UA))</name>
        <text>Taking damage can't break your Concentration on Conjuration spells.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Quick Transposition (Conjurer (UA))</name>
        <text>You can use Benign Transposition as a Bonus Action.
	You can also use Benign Transposition as a Reaction when a creature you can see makes an attack roll against you, but only to swap places with a willing creature. The creature that swaps places with you becomes the target of that attack instead.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: Enchanter (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: Enchanter (UA)</name>
        <text>Entrance and Beguile Others

Your magic clouds or captivates minds. Some Enchanters use their abilities to encourage peace and soften cruelty, while others use their mind-altering magic for selfish ends. Many Enchanters fall somewhere in between.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Enchanting Talker (Enchanter (UA))</name>
        <text>Whenever you make a Charisma check, you gain a bonus to the check equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).
	You also gain proficiency in one of these skills of your choice: Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Enchantment Savant (Enchanter (UA))</name>
        <text>Choose two Wizard spells from the Enchantment school, each of which must be no higher than level 2, and add them to your spellbook for free.
	In addition, whenever you gain access to a new level of spell slots in this class, you can add one Wizard spell from the Enchantment school to your spellbook for free. The chosen spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Vexing Movement (Enchanter (UA))</name>
        <text>Immediately after you cast an Enchantment spell using an action and a spell slot, you can take both the Disengage and Dash actions as a Bonus Action.
	You can use this Bonus Action a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Reflecting Charm (Enchanter (UA))</name>
        <text>When a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to reduce the damage you take by half (round down), and you can force the attacker to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker takes Psychic damage equal to half your Wizard level plus your Intelligence modifier. Once you use this Reaction, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by expending a level 2+ spell slot (no action required).

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Split Enchantment (Enchanter (UA))</name>
        <text>When you cast an Enchantment spell, such as Charm Person, that can be cast with a higher-level spell slot to target an additional creature, increase the spell's effective level by 1.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Bolstering Belief (Enchanter (UA))</name>
        <text>Your enchantments fortify your allies' bodies and minds. You always have Power Word Fortify prepared. With this feature, you can cast the spell without expending a spell slot, and each target of the spell has Advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Charmed and Frightened conditions while it has Temporary Hit Points granted by this spell.
	Once you cast the spell with this feature, you can't do so in this way again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Bolstering Belief</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Enchanter (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: Necromancer (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: Necromancer (UA)</name>
        <text>Command the Powers of Death and Undeath

You explore the cosmic forces of life, death, and undeath. As a Necromancer, you learn to manipulate the energy that animates all creatures. As you progress, you learn to use magic to drain the life force from a creature, transforming its vital energy into magical power. Many see Necromancers as menacing or villainous, though not all Necromancers are evil. Nevertheless, the manipulation of life and death is considered taboo in many societies.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Necromancy Savant (Necromancer (UA))</name>
        <text>Choose two Wizard spells from the Necromancy school, each of which must be no higher than level 2, and add them to your spellbook for free.
	In addition, whenever you gain access to a new level of spell slots in this class, you can add one Wizard spell from the Necromancy school to your spellbook for free. The chosen spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Necromancy Spellbook (Necromancer (UA))</name>
        <text>Secrets of necromancy magic in your spellbook grant you additional powers. You gain the following benefits.

Necrotic Resistance. You have Resistance to Necrotic damage.

Grim Harvest. When you cast a Necromancy spell using a spell slot, choose yourself or a creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself to gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to the level of the spell slot plus your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1 Temporary Hit Point).

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Grave Power (Necromancer (UA))</name>
        <text>You have discovered more necromantic insights and inscribed them into your spellbook. While holding your spellbook, you gain the following benefits.

Grave Resilience. When you use Arcane Recovery, your Exhaustion level, if any, decreases by 1.

Overwhelming Necrosis. Damage from your Wizard spells and Wizard features ignores Resistance to Necrotic damage.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Undead Thralls (Necromancer (UA))</name>
        <text>You always have Summon Undead prepared and can cast it once without expending a spell slot.
	When you cast Summon Undead without a spell slot, you can regain Hit Points equal to half the summoned creature's total Hit Points, but doing so halves the creature's Hit Points. Once you cast the spell without a spell slot, you must finish a Long Rest before you can cast the spell in this way again.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 10</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Undead Secrets (Necromancer (UA))</name>
        <text>You have learned more secrets about the nuances of life and death. When you finish a Long Rest, you can expend a level 4+ spell slot to protect yourself from death. Until you finish a Long Rest, the next time you would drop to 0 Hit Points, your Hit Points instead change to a number equal to ten times the spell slot expended.
	In addition, immediately after you take damage and are Bloodied after taking that damage but not killed outright, you can take a Reaction and teleport to an unoccupied space up to 60 feet from yourself, and each creature within 10 feet of the space you left takes 2d10 Necrotic damage.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 10</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="10">2d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Death's Master (Necromancer (UA))</name>
        <text>Abstruse rituals within your spellbook allow you mastery over forces of death. While holding your spellbook, you gain the following benefits.

Bolster Undead. As a Bonus Action, choose any number of Undead you have created or summoned with a Necromancy spell that are within 60 feet of yourself. Those Undead each gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your Wizard level. Once an Undead gains Temporary Hit Points from this feature, it can't gain them in this way again for the next 24 hours.

Harvest Power. When you use Grim Harvest, the creature that gains Temporary Hit Points gains one of the following benefits of your choice, which lasts until the end of the target's next turn:

	• The target has Advantage on attack rolls.
	• The target has Advantage on the next saving throw it makes.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 10</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: Transmuter (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: Transmuter (UA)</name>
        <text>Transform Energy and Matter

You study spells that modify energy and matter. To you, the world is not a fixed thing, but eminently mutable. Your magic gives you the tools to become a smith on reality's forge.
	Some Transmuters are tinkerers and pranksters. Others pursue their magical studies with deadly seriousness, seeking the power of the gods to make and destroy worlds.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 10</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Transmutation Savant (Transmuter (UA))</name>
        <text>Choose two Wizard spells from the Transmutation school, each of which must be no higher than level 2, and add them to your spellbook for free.
	In addition, whenever you gain access to a new level of spell slots in this class, you can add one Wizard spell from the Transmutation school to your spellbook for free. The chosen spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 10</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Transmuter's Stone (Transmuter (UA))</name>
        <text>When you finish a Long Rest, you can create a magic pebble called a transmuter's stone that lasts until you use this feature again. A creature with the stone in its possession gains a benefit from one of the following options, which you choose when you create the stone. You can change the stone's benefit when you cast a Transmutation spell using a spell slot.

Darkvision. The bearer gains Darkvision with a range of 60 feet or increases the range of its Darkvision by 60 feet.

Speed. The bearer's Speed increases by 10 feet.

Durability. The bearer gains proficiency in Constitution saving throws.

Resistance. The bearer gains Resistance to Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Poison, or Thunder damage (your choice each time you choose this benefit).

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 10</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Wondrous Enhancement (Transmuter (UA))</name>
        <text>You always have Enhance Ability prepared and can cast it once without a spell slot. You regain the ability to cast it in this way when you finish a Long Rest.
	Targets of your Enhance Ability also have Advantage on saving throws using the chosen ability.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Split Transmutation (Transmuter (UA))</name>
        <text>When you cast a Transmutation spell, such as Fly, that can be cast with a higher-level spell slot to target an additional creature, increase the spell's effective level by 1.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Potent Stone (Transmuter (UA))</name>
        <text>Your transmuter's stone is more versatile. You choose up to two options when you create your transmuter's stone. You can choose each option other than Resistance only once. If you choose Resistance twice, you must choose different damage types. You can change either or both benefits when you cast a Transmutation spell using a spell slot.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 11</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Master Transmuter (Transmuter (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Magic action, you can consume the reserve of transmutation magic stored in your transmuter's stone to choose one of the following benefits. After using your transmuter's stone in this way, it crumbles to dust.

Panacea. The bearer regains a number of Hit Points equal to twice your Wizard level and ends a curse, including the target's Attunement to a cursed item.

Restore Life. You cast Raise Dead without a spell slot, using the stone in place of the normally required Material components.

Restore Youth. The bearer permanently appears 3d10 years younger, to a minimum of young adulthood.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 11</text>
        <roll description="Years younger">3d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
