<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Sorcerer [2024]</name>
    <!-- Sorcerer Subclass: Ancestral Sorcery (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerer Subclass: Ancestral Sorcery (UA)</name>
        <text>Bear the Power of a Spellcasting Lineage

Your innate magic comes from a specific ancestor who wielded such awesome magical power that a fragment of their personality guides you. This ancestor grants you guidance and direction as you explore your innate magical abilities. You might be the ancestor's sole surviving descendant, a reincarnation who bears an eerie resemblance to your ancestor, or a victim of a curse gained from handling your ancestor's personal effects.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Ancestor's Lore (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>You use your force of personality to channel your ancestor's knowledge. When you make an Intelligence check, you gain a bonus to the check equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1). You also gain proficiency in one of these skills of your choice: Arcana, History, Investigation, Nature, or Religion.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Ancestral Spells (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach the Sorcerer level specified in the Ancestral Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Lineage Spells:
Sorcerer Level | Spells
3 | Command, Guidance, Locate Object, Protection from Evil and Good, Resistance, Spiritual Weapon
5 | Magic Circle, Spirit Guardians
7 | Divination, Locate Creature
9 | Legend Lore, Yolande's Regal Presence

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Visage of the Ancestor (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>Choose the form your ancestor takes, which might resemble the ancestor in life or a symbolic creature. While your Innate Sorcery feature is active, this form appears in a spectral haze around you, and you have Advantage on any ability check you make as part of the Influence action.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Superior Spell Disruption (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>Your ancestor's spellcasting mastery aids you in breaking spells. You always have Counterspell and Dispel Magic prepared.
	While your Innate Sorcery feature is active, you can cast each spell without expending a spell slot. If you cast Counterspell in this way, the target has Disadvantage on its Constitution saving throw. If you cast Dispel Magic in this way, you have Advantage on your ability checks to end ongoing spells. Once you cast either spell without a spell slot, you must finish a Long Rest before you can cast the spell in this way again.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Ancestral Majesty (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>Your ancestor's visage evokes awe or dread. While your Innate Sorcery feature is active, you are surrounded by a magical aura in a 5-foot Emanation. Whenever a creature you can see enters the Emanation or ends its turn there, you can force that creature to make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target has the Prone condition or has the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn (your choice). A creature makes this save only once per turn.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Steady Spellcaster (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>Your deep connection with your ancestor steadies you. Taking damage can't break your Concentration on Sorcerer spells.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Ancestor's Ward (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>Your ancestor's protection redirects harmful magic away from you. While your Innate Sorcery feature is active, you gain Advantage on saving throws against spells. Once during your use of Innate Sorcery, when you fail a saving throw against a spell, you can choose to succeed instead.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Command [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Guidance [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Locate Object [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Protection from Evil and Good [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Resistance [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spiritual Weapon [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Magic Circle [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spirit Guardians [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Divination [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Locate Creature [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Legend Lore [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Yolande's Regal Presence [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer [2024] (Ancestral Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
