<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric [2024]</name>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Arcana Domain (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Arcana Domain (UA)</name>
        <text>Blend Conviction with Arcane Power

Magic suffuses the multiverse and fuels both destruction and creation. Clerics with this domain view magical knowledge not as power to be used in pursuit of personal ends, but as a gift they have the responsibility to share.
	Gods associated with the Arcana Domain know the secrets and potential of magic intimately. These gods are often connected to knowledge, as learning and arcane power tend to go hand-in-hand, or to secrecy or power.

DESIGN NOTE: ARCANA DOMAIN UPDATES
Here are the main updates in this subclass since its appearance in the Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide:

	• Arcane Domain Spells have been revised.

	• Arcane Initiate now gives you Expertise in the Arcana skill.

	• Modify Magic is a new feature that replaces Arcane Abjuration.

	• Dispelling Recovery (formerly named Spell Breaker) now uses Dispel Magic and also triggers when you remove a condition from a creature.

	• Arcane Mastery now lets you change the Wizard spells you choose.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Arcana Domain Spells (Arcana Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain means you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the Arcana Domain Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Arcana Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Prepared Spells
3 | Detect Magic, Magic Missile, Magic Weapon, Nystul's Magic Aura
5 | Counterspell, Dispel Magic
7 | Arcane Eye, Leomund's Secret Chest
9 | Bigby's Hand, Teleportation Circle

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Arcane Initiate (Arcana Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

Arcane Knowledge. You gain proficiency in the Arcana skill if you don't have it already. You also gain Expertise in the Arcana skill.

Cantrips. You learn two Wizard cantrips of your choice. Whenever you gain a Cleric level, you can replace one of these cantrips with another Wizard cantrip.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 2</text>
        <proficiency>Arcana</proficiency>
        <modifier category="skill">Arcana +%0</modifier>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Modify Magic (Arcana Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>You can use your Channel Divinity to alter your spells as you cast them. When you cast a spell, you can expend one use of your Channel Divinity and change the spell in one of the following ways (no action required).

Fortifying Spell. One target of the spell gains a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to 2d8 plus your Cleric level.

Tenacious Spell. When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw, choose one target of the spell you can see. Roll 1d6 and apply the number rolled as a penalty to the target's saving throw.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 2</text>
        <roll description="Temporary Hit Points">2d8</roll>
        <roll description="Save Throw Reduction">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Dispelling Recovery (Arcana Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>Immediately after you cast a spell with a spell slot that restores Hit Points to a creature or ends a condition on a creature, you can cast Dispel Magic on the creature as a Bonus Action without expending a spell slot.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Arcane Mastery (Arcana Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn four Wizard spells, one from each of levels 6, 7, 8, and 9. You thereafter always have those spells prepared. Whenever you gain a Cleric level, you can replace one of these spells with another Wizard spell of the same level.

Source:	UA25-ArcaneSubclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Magic [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Magic Missile [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Magic Weapon [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Nystul's Magic Aura [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Counterspell [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Magic [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Eye [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Leomund's Secret Chest [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bigby's Hand [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Teleportation Circle [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Arcana Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
