<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <background>
    <name>(Un)Retired Adventurer (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Lore, and Survival
Tools: One type of artisan's tools
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A grappling hook, one tool with which you are proficient, a memento of an unsuccessful expedition (map to a never found treasure, lock of hair from a fallen companion, or another trinket),  and a pouch containing your last 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Bridges Not Yet Burned</name>
      <text>Throughout your adventures you have established a multitude of contacts from all walks of life, but the intervening years have seen those relationships strained. You may use any feature of any other background, but once a particular feature is used, that feature can't be used again until one year has passed.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Empathic
3 | Loremaster
4 | Survivalist
5 | Crafter
6 | Linguist
7 | Athlete
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>The trials and triumphs of retired adventurers have left an impact, shaping their ideals, creating strong bonds, and often leaving them scarred and vulnerable to fear, shame, and hatred.

Personality:
1 | I'm always polite and respectful.
2 | I'm haunted by memories of war. I can't get the images of violence out of my mind.
3 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
4 | I'm full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my adventuring experience relevant to almost every combat situation.
5 | I can stare down a rancor without flinching.
6 | I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.
7 | I have a crude sense of humor.
8 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Light)
2 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
3 | Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)
6 | Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would still lay down my life for the people I adventured with.
2 | Someone saved my life when they could have left me. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | My honor is my life.
4 | I'll never forget the crushing defeat my party suffered or the enemies who dealt it.
5 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
6 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.

Flaw:
1 | The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.
2 | I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven adventurer.
3 | I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives— and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.
4 | My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.
5 | I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.
6 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>(Un)Retired Adventurer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Lore, and Survival
Tools: One type of artisan's tools
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A grappling hook, one tool with which you are proficient, a memento of an unsuccessful expedition (map to a never found treasure, lock of hair from a fallen companion, or another trinket),  and a pouch containing your last 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Bridges Not Yet Burned</name>
      <text>Throughout your adventures you have established a multitude of contacts from all walks of life, but the intervening years have seen those relationships strained. You may use any feature of any other background, but once a particular feature is used, that feature can't be used again until one year has passed.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Empathic
3 | Loremaster
4 | Survivalist
5 | Crafter
6 | Linguist
7 | Athlete
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>The trials and triumphs of retired adventurers have left an impact, shaping their ideals, creating strong bonds, and often leaving them scarred and vulnerable to fear, shame, and hatred.

Personality:
1 | I'm always polite and respectful.
2 | I'm haunted by memories of war. I can't get the images of violence out of my mind.
3 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
4 | I'm full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my adventuring experience relevant to almost every combat situation.
5 | I can stare down a rancor without flinching.
6 | I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.
7 | I have a crude sense of humor.
8 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Light)
2 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
3 | Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)
6 | Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would still lay down my life for the people I adventured with.
2 | Someone saved my life when they could have left me. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | My honor is my life.
4 | I'll never forget the crushing defeat my party suffered or the enemies who dealt it.
5 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
6 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.

Flaw:
1 | The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.
2 | I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven adventurer.
3 | I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives— and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.
4 | My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.
5 | I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.
6 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Addict (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Pick Your Poison</name>
      <text>d16 | Pick Your Poison
1 | Deuterium-pyro
2 | Mummergy
3 | Novanian grog
4 | Raava
5 | Spicebrew
6 | Tihaar
7 | Tsiraki
8 | Vayerbok
9 | Andris
10 | Cilona
11 | Giggledust
12 | Glitterstim
13 | Karrak
14 | Muon gold
15 | Yaladai
16 | Yarrock

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Addict Proficiencies</name>
      <text>You hammer down your fifth bottle of the night, do your last bit of snuff, and bid farewell to the seedy cantina barman. You stagger onto the streets and find a nearby alley in which you empty the night's contents. To many, the next morning's hangovers would be hell. To you, they're a ritual.

Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Deception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand
Tool Proficiencies: Your choice of any gaming set, brewer's kit, or spicer's kit
Languages: One of your choice
Equipment: A chance cube set, a sabaac deck, 2 days field rations, a flask or belt pouch containing your addiction, a set of common clothes, a bedroll, and a belt pouch containing 25 cr</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Addicted</name>
      <text>You've been abusing substances for a long time. You always know who to talk to and where to find substances, and you can often identify them in their raw form.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Performer
3 | Charmer
4 | Quick-Fingered
5 | Entertainer
6 | Specialist
7 | Linguist
8 | Durable</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Characteristics</name>
      <text>Addicts can be rude and uncouth, wearing their addiction visibly, or they might hide that addiction and appear to function normally. Importantly, and varying with every addict, why are you addicted? To forget the past? To drown your sorrows? Or are you simply chasing the dragon?

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | I am guaranteed to fight someone if I'm drunk/high enough.
2 | Life is pain. All I want is to drink/smoke myself into nothingness.
3 | I have a simple rule; life's a party, so grab the deathsticks!
4 | The only thing keeping me from burning down this village is the fact that you make some damn good spice.
5 | I'm quite reserved until the moment I fulfill my addictive needs.
6 | This stuff is a bit weak, do you have anything higher than 60% in the back?
7 | I take pride in my addiction and am often snobbish when talking about it.
8 | I blow up at the slightest insult.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Hope. I hope to one day be free of my addiction. (Light)
2 | Carelessness. I don't care what I have to do, just let me feed my addiction. (Dark)
3 | Isolation. Just let me deal with my demons in peace. (Neutral)
4 | Caution. I will never let my addiction harm others. (Lawful)
5 | Independence. Addiction frees me. (Chaotic)
6 | Comradery. Hey, some of my favorite people are addicts! (Any)

d6 | Bond
1 | I use my addiction as a tool to wash away my past sins.
2 | My family never wanted to be forgotten. I take drugs in the hopes they will be.
3 | I hope to start a drug business myself and give people the same happiness I've found.
4 | Everything I do is in the hopes of getting my hands on my drug.
5 | I traded my former self to my addiction. Now I need to find a way to get him back.
6 | To be addicted is to be truly alive.

d6 | Flaw
1 | This could be rough, let's take something before we go.
2 | Hopefully this will be the one to end it.
3 | The mission can wait, we should find some dealers first.
4 | What? I don't have a problem. You're the one with the problem!
5 | It looks like my drug, so it should be safe to take right?
6 | I'm never myself when I'm on it.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Agent (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Investigation, Lore, and Persuasion
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: Badge or emblem of your faction, a copy of a seminal faction text (or a code-book for a covert faction), a set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Safe Haven</name>
      <text>As a faction agent, you have access to a secret network of supporters and operatives who can provide assistance on your adventures. You know a set of secret signs and passwords you can use to identify such operatives, who can provide you with access to a hidden safe house, free room and board, or assistance in finding information. These agents never risk their lives for you or risk revealing their true identities.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Investigator
3 | Loremaster
4 | Charming Persona
5 | Linguist
6 | Alert
7 | Observant
8 | Practiced</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Agents are shaped by their experience in their faction's communities. Their study of the history and tenets of their faction and their relationships to it affect their mannerisms and ideals. Their flaws might be some hidden hypocrisy or heretical idea, or an ideal or bond taken to an extreme.

Personality:
1 | I idolize a particular hero of my faction, and constantly refer to that person's deeds and example.
2 | I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, empathizing with them and always working towards peace.
3 | I see omens in every event and action.
4 | Nothing can shake my optimistic attitude.
5 | I quote (or misquote) sacred texts and proverbs in almost every situation.
6 | I am tolerant (or intolerant) of other factions and respect (or condemn) them.
7 | I've enjoyed fine food, drink, and high society among my faction's elite. Rough living grates on me.
8 | I have little practical experience dealing with people in the  world.

Ideals:
1 | Tradition. The ancient traditions of worship and sacrifice must be preserved and upheld. (Lawful)
2 | Charity. I always try to help those in need, no matter what the personal cost. (Light)
3 | Change. We must help bring about the changes the gods are constantly working in the world. (Chaotic)
4 | Power. I hope to one day rise to the top of my faith's religious hierarchy. (Lawful)
5 | Faith. I trust that my leader will guide my actions, I have faith that if I work hard, things will go well. (Lawful)
6 | Aspiration. I seek to prove myself worthy of my leader's favor by matching my actions against his or her teachings. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would die to recover an artifact of my faction that was lost long ago.
2 | I will someday get revenge on the corrupt faction hierarchy who branded me a heretic.
3 | I owe my life to the faction member who took me in when my parents died.
4 | Everything I do is for the common people.
5 | I will do anything to protect the faction where I served.
6 | I seek to preserve a sacred text that my enemies consider heretical and seek to destroy.

Flaw:
1 | I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.
2 | I put too much trust in those who wield power within my faction's hierarchy.
3 | My piety sometimes leads me to blindly trust those that profess faith in my faction.
4 | I am inflexible in my thinking.
5 | I am suspicious of strangers and expect the worst of them.
6 | Once I pick a goal, I become obsessed with it to the detriment of everything else in my life.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Barbarian (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Nature, and Survival
Tools: One type of musical instrument or artisan's tools
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A hunting trap, a totemic token or set of tattoos marking your loyalty to your tribe, a set of traveler's clothes, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Barbarian Heritage</name>
      <text>You have an excellent knowledge of not only your tribe's territory, but also the terrain and natural resources of the rest of the worlds. You are familiar enough with any wilderness area that you find twice as much food and water as you normally would when you forage there.

Additionally, you can call upon the hospitality of other tribes in times of need.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Brawny
3 | Naturalist
4 | Survivalist
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Crafter
7 | Athlete
8 | Weapon Expert</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Often considered rude and uncouth among civilized folk, barbarians have little respect for the niceties of life in the cities. The ties of tribe, clan, family, and the natural world of which they are a part are the most important bonds to most outlanders. 
Personality:
1 | I'm driven by a wanderlust that led me away from home.
2 | I watch over my friends as if they were a litter of newborn pups.
3 | I once ran twenty-five miles without stopping to warn to my clan of an approaching orc horde. I'd do it again if I had to.
4 | I have a lesson for every situation, drawn from observing nature.
5 | I place no stock in wealthy or well-mannered folk. Money and manners won't save you from a hungry owlbear.
6 | I'm always picking things up, absently fiddling with them, and sometimes accidentally breaking them.
7 | I feel far more comfortable around animals than people.
8 | I was, in fact, raised by wolves.

Ideals:
1 | Change. Life is like the seasons, in constant change, and we must change with it. (Chaotic)
2 | Greater Good. It is each person's responsibility to make the most happiness for the whole tribe. (Light)
3 | Honor. If I dishonor myself, I dishonor my whole clan. (Lawful)
4 | Might. The strongest are meant to rule. (Dark)
5 | Nature. The natural world is more important than all the constructs of civilization. (Neutral)
6 | Glory. I must earn glory in battle, for myself and my clan. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My family, clan, or tribe is the most important thing in my life, even when they are far from me.
2 | An injury to the unspoiled wilderness of my home is an injury to me.
3 | I will bring terrible wrath down on the Darkdoers who destroyed my homeland.
4 | I am the last of my tribe, and it is up to me to ensure their names enter legend.
5 | I suffer awful visions of a coming disaster and will do anything to prevent it.
6 | It is my duty to provide children to sustain my tribe.

Flaw:
1 | I am too enamored of ale, wine, and other intoxicants.
2 | There's no room for caution in a life lived to the fullest.
3 | I remember every insult I've received and nurse a silent resentment toward anyone who's ever wronged me.
4 | I am slow to trust members of other species, tribes, and societies.
5 | Violence is my answer to almost any challenge.
6 | Don't expect me to save those who can't save themselves. It is nature's way that the strong thrive and the weak perish.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Bounty Hunter (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Persuasion, and Stealth
Tools: Your choice of demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of clothes appropriate to your duties, a set of binders, and a pouch containing 200 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Ear to the Ground</name>
      <text>You are in frequent contact with people in the segment of society that your chosen quarries move through. These people might be associated with the criminal underworld, the rough-and-tumble folk of the streets, or members of high society. This connection comes in the form of a contact in any city you visit, a person who provides information about the people and places of the local area.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Charming Persona
4 | Stealthy
5 | Demolitionist
6 | Bypasser
7 | Slicer
8 | Linguist</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Your bond might involve other bounty hunters or the organizations or individuals that employ you. Your ideal could be associated with your determination always to catch your quarry or your desire to maintain your reputation for being dependable.

Personality:
1 | I always have a plan for what to do when things go wrong.
2 | I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let my emotions control me.
3 | The first thing I do in a new place is note the locations of everything valuable — or where such things could be hidden.
4 | I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy.
5 | I am incredibly slow to trust. Those who seem the fairest often have the most to hide.
6 | I don't pay attention to the risks in a situation. Never tell me the odds.
7 | The best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can't do it.
8 | I blow up at the slightest insult.

Ideals:
1 | Honor. I don't steal from others in the trade. (Lawful)
2 | Freedom. Chains are meant to be broken, as are those who would forge them. (Chaotic)
3 | Charity. I steal from the wealthy so that I can help people in need. (Light)
4 | Greed. I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Neutral)
6 | Redemption. There's a spark of good in everyone. (Light)

Bond:
1 | I'm trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor.
2 | My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.
3 | Something important was taken from me, and I aim to steal it back.
4 | I will become the greatest thief that ever lived.
5 | I'm guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it.
6 | Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made. That will never happen again.

Flaw:
1 | When I see something valuable, I can't think about anything but how to steal it.
2 | When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.
3 | If there's a plan, I'll forget it. If I don't forget it, I'll ignore it.
4 | I have a —tell— that reveals when I'm lying.
5 | I turn tail and run when things look bad.
6 | An innocent person is in prison for a crime that I committed. I'm okay with that.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>City Watch (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Investigation, and Perception
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: A uniform in the style of your unit and indicative of your rank, a horn with which to summon help, a set of binders, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Watcher's Eye</name>
      <text>Your experience in enforcing the law, and dealing with lawbreakers, gives you a feel for local laws and criminals. You can easily find the local outpost of the watch or a similar organization, and just as easily pick out the dens of criminal activity in a community, although you're more likely to be welcome in the former locations rather than the latter.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Empathic
3 | Investigator
4 | Perceptive
5 | Linguist
6 | Alert
7 | Athlete
8 | Durable</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Years of service in the City Watch have led to the rigid discipline most often seen in military service. Working with your comrades has created a strong family bond and pride in your community.

Personality:
1 | I'm always polite and respectful.
2 | I'm haunted by memories of war. I can't get the images of violence out of my mind.
3 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
4 | I'm full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my guard service relevant to almost every combat situation.
5 | I can stare down a hell hound without flinching.
6 | I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.
7 | I have a crude sense of humor.
8 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Light)
2 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
3 | Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)
6 | Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would still lay down my life for the people I served with.
2 | Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | My honor is my life.
4 | I'll never forget the crushing defeat my company suffered or the enemies who dealt it.
5 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
6 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.

Flaw:
1 | The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.
2 | I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven warrior.
3 | I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives— and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.
4 | My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.
5 | I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.
6 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>City Watch (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Investigation, and Perception
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: A uniform in the style of your unit and indicative of your rank, a horn with which to summon help, a set of binders, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Watcher's Eye</name>
      <text>Your experience in enforcing the law, and dealing with lawbreakers, gives you a feel for local laws and criminals. You can easily find the local outpost of the watch or a similar organization, and just as easily pick out the dens of criminal activity in a community, although you're more likely to be welcome in the former locations rather than the latter.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Empathic
3 | Investigator
4 | Perceptive
5 | Linguist
6 | Alert
7 | Athlete
8 | Durable</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Years of service in the City Watch have led to the rigid discipline most often seen in military service. Working with your comrades has created a strong family bond and pride in your community.

Personality:
1 | I'm always polite and respectful.
2 | I'm haunted by memories of war. I can't get the images of violence out of my mind.
3 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
4 | I'm full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my guard service relevant to almost every combat situation.
5 | I can stare down a hell hound without flinching.
6 | I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.
7 | I have a crude sense of humor.
8 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Light)
2 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
3 | Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)
6 | Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would still lay down my life for the people I served with.
2 | Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | My honor is my life.
4 | I'll never forget the crushing defeat my company suffered or the enemies who dealt it.
5 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
6 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.

Flaw:
1 | The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.
2 | I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven warrior.
3 | I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives— and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.
4 | My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.
5 | I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.
6 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Clone Trooper (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Medicine, Perception, and Piloting
Tools: Your choice of demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: Badge or emblem of your rank, your chosen tools, a set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Clone Specialization</name>
      <text>Trooper
Commando
Jet Trooper
Medic
Spec Ops
Ordnance
Officer
Scout</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Republic Rank</name>
      <text>You are a soldier of the Republic. Those loyal to the Republic will respect your status and defer to you if they don't outrank you. You can invoke your position to exert influence over other soldiers, requisition simple equipment, and gain access to military compounds affiliated with the Republic.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Medic
3 | Perceptive
4 | Ace Pilot
5 | Demolitionist
6 | Bypasser
7 | Slicer
8 | Martial Adept</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Clones are trained from birth to be the perfect soldier; over time, they also develop their own personalities. They are universally loyal to the Republic. While clones share genetic coding, no two are completely identical.

Personality:
1 | I always respect my commander.
2 | I can stare down a krayt dragon without flinching.
3 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.
4 | I have a sense of humor. This is rare among my brothers.
5 | I judge people by their actions, not their words.
6 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
7 | I ask a lot of questions.
8 | I'll settle for nothing less than perfection.

Ideals:
1 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
2 | Might. Strength, not compassion, wins battles. (Dark)
3 | Republic. My brothers, the Republic, or people are all that matter. (Any)
4 | Greater Light. We fight not for ourselves, but for countless of others that can't fight for themselves. (Light)
5 | Freedom. Tyrants must not be allowed to oppress the people. (Chaotic)
6 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing or going to war over. (Neutral)

Bond:
1 | My honor is my life.
2 | Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
4 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.
5 | I would still lay down my life for the people I serve with.
6 | A proud commander once gave me a horrible beating, and I will take my revenge on any bully I encounter.

Flaw:
1 | I have little respect for anyone who is of a lesser rank.
2 | I obey the orders without, even if the orders cause misery.
3 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.
4 | I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.
5 | I am inflexible in my thinking.
6 | I can't tell a lie for the life of me.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Clone Trooper (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Medicine, Perception, and Piloting
Tools: Your choice of demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: Badge or emblem of your rank, your chosen tools, a set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Clone Specialization</name>
      <text>Trooper
Commando
Jet Trooper
Medic
Spec Ops
Ordnance
Officer
Scout</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Republic Rank</name>
      <text>You are a soldier of the Republic. Those loyal to the Republic will respect your status and defer to you if they don't outrank you. You can invoke your position to exert influence over other soldiers, requisition simple equipment, and gain access to military compounds affiliated with the Republic.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Medic
3 | Perceptive
4 | Ace Pilot
5 | Specialist
6 | Alert
7 | Athlete
8 | Forceful Vigor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Clones are trained from birth to be the perfect soldier; over time, they also develop their own personalities. They are universally loyal to the Republic. While clones share genetic coding, no two are completely identical.

Personality:
1 | I always respect my commander.
2 | I can stare down a krayt dragon without flinching.
3 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.
4 | I have a sense of humor. This is rare among my brothers.
5 | I judge people by their actions, not their words.
6 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
7 | I ask a lot of questions.
8 | I'll settle for nothing less than perfection.

Ideals:
1 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
2 | Might. Strength, not compassion, wins battles. (Dark)
3 | Republic. My brothers, the Republic, or people are all that matter. (Any)
4 | Greater Light. We fight not for ourselves, but for countless of others that can't fight for themselves. (Light)
5 | Freedom. Tyrants must not be allowed to oppress the people. (Chaotic)
6 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing or going to war over. (Neutral)

Bond:
1 | My honor is my life.
2 | Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
4 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.
5 | I would still lay down my life for the people I serve with.
6 | A proud commander once gave me a horrible beating, and I will take my revenge on any bully I encounter.

Flaw:
1 | I have little respect for anyone who is of a lesser rank.
2 | I obey the orders without, even if the orders cause misery.
3 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.
4 | I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.
5 | I am inflexible in my thinking.
6 | I can't tell a lie for the life of me.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Companion (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Companion Proficiencies</name>
      <text>You are experienced in the arts of companionship, and you provide these services for people who can afford to pay it. This may mean adult favors of the sensual variety, but it just as frequently means conversation, comfort, and company.

Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Acrobatics, Deception, Insight, and Performance
Tool Proficiencies: One instrument of your choice or a disguise kit
Languages: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes, an instrument or disguise kit, and a belt pouch containing 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Sordid Knowledge</name>
      <text>You have or can gain compromising information about people of importance. You may be able to leverage this information in order to acquire lodging, information, or even money. You may also become a target for having this information. Your GM may rule that any particular individual is either above reproach or is too careful in covering their tracks to provide such leverage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Acrobat
2 | Silver-Tongued
3 | Empathic
4 | Performer
5 | Entertainer
6 | Specialist
7 | Linguist
8 | Force of Personality</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Characteristics</name>
      <text>You enjoy people and you enjoy your work and you enjoy the money it brings. There is no shame in your profession and it is often highly regulated and regimented by factions or the local government. It requires outgoing and adventurous personalities to be a success, and often these traits lead them to adventures of a different sort.

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | People are often hurt and damaged. I try to heal them and leave them stronger than when I meet them.
2 | I enjoy being in control and manipulating people. It's important that they like me so they do what I say.
3 | I'm not a laser-brain, although I don't open my mouth to prove people wrong. I let them discover the truth after I have what I want.
4 | I'm better than those who are more prim and proper, and I'm having more fun.
5 | I don't really care what happens, it's an easy way to get money for my habit.
6 | There are so many different kinds of people, and I want to meet them all.
7 | I never thought this was the life for me, perhaps some brave person will rescue me.
8 | I like what I do and I resent those who want to rescue me.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Sacred. My body is a temple I am duty-bound to share. (Lawful)
2 | Hedonism. I fill my urges when and where I wish. (Chaotic)
3 | Loving. Everyone needs attention and love. (Light)
4 | Exploitation. I take pleasure in toying with people, and taking advantage of them. (Dark)
5 | Consent. I respect other's desires and wishes. (Neutral)
6 | Freedom. I want to have the independence to enjoy life. (Any)

d6 | Bond
1 | I seek a relationship with the most powerful people in the land, desiring to be the power behind the throne.
2 | If I can only collect enough credits, I'll be able to pay off my debts and be free.
3 | I have a sick parent to whom I send all my money.
4 | My independence is the most important thing in my world.
5 | I bring happiness to the world one person at a time.
6 | I have a young child who is my world.

d6 | Flaw
1 | I have an incurable disease I acquired from a client.
2 | I am addicted to recreational drugs that dull the pain I feel.
3 | I no longer practice my old profession, and I fear anyone discovering it.
4 | I am suspicious of anyone who tries to be nice to me. They only want me to sleep with them.
5 | Most people are naive children.
6 | I pretend to be tough, but am broken inside.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Courtier (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Performance, and Survival
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: A set of fine clothes and a pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Court Functionality</name>
      <text>Your knowledge of how bureaucracies function lets you gain access to the records and inner workings of any noble court or government you encounter. You know who the movers and shakers are, whom to go to for the favors you seek, and what the current intrigues of interest in the group are.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Performer
4 | Survivalist
5 | Linguist
6 | Actor
7 | Practiced
8 | Gourmand</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>The noble court or bureaucratic organization where you got your start is directly or indirectly associated with your bond (which could pertain to certain individuals in the group, such as your sponsor or mentor). Your ideal might be concerned with the prevailing philosophy of your court or organization.

Personality:
1 | I believe that anything worth doing is worth doing right. I can't help it— I'm a perfectionist.
2 | I'm a snob who looks down on those who can't appreciate fine art.
3 | I always want to know how things work and what makes people tick.
4 | I'm full of witty aphorisms and have a proverb for every occasion.
5 | I'm rude to people who lack my commitment to hard work and fair play.
6 | I like to talk at length about my profession.
7 | I don't part with my money easily and will haggle tirelessly to get the best deal possible.
8 | I'm well known for my work, so I'm always taken aback when people haven't heard of me.

Ideals:
1 | Community. It is the duty of all civilized people to strengthen the bonds of community and the security of civilization. (Lawful)
2 | Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Light)
3 | Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)

Bond:
1 | The location where I learned my trade is the most important place in the world to me.
2 | I created a great work for someone unworthy to receive it. I'm still looking for someone worthy.
3 | I owe someone a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.
4 | I pursue wealth to secure someone's love.
5 | One day I will return to my guild and prove that I am the greatest artisan of them all.
6 | I will get revenge on the Dark forces that destroyed my place of business and ruined my livelihood.

Flaw:
1 | I'll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.
2 | I'm quick to assume that someone is trying to cheat me.
3 | No one must ever learn that I once stole money from guild coffers.
4 | I'm never satisfied with what I have— I always want more.
5 | I would kill to acquire a noble title.
6 | I'm horribly jealous of anyone who can outshine my handiwork. Everywhere I go, I'm surrounded by rivals.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Courtier (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Performance, and Survival
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: A set of fine clothes and a pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Court Functionality</name>
      <text>Your knowledge of how bureaucracies function lets you gain access to the records and inner workings of any noble court or government you encounter. You know who the movers and shakers are, whom to go to for the favors you seek, and what the current intrigues of interest in the group are.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Performer
4 | Survivalist
5 | Linguist
6 | Actor
7 | Practiced
8 | Force of Personality</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>The noble court or bureaucratic organization where you got your start is directly or indirectly associated with your bond (which could pertain to certain individuals in the group, such as your sponsor or mentor). Your ideal might be concerned with the prevailing philosophy of your court or organization.

Personality:
1 | I believe that anything worth doing is worth doing right. I can't help it— I'm a perfectionist.
2 | I'm a snob who looks down on those who can't appreciate fine art.
3 | I always want to know how things work and what makes people tick.
4 | I'm full of witty aphorisms and have a proverb for every occasion.
5 | I'm rude to people who lack my commitment to hard work and fair play.
6 | I like to talk at length about my profession.
7 | I don't part with my money easily and will haggle tirelessly to get the best deal possible.
8 | I'm well known for my work, so I'm always taken aback when people haven't heard of me.

Ideals:
1 | Community. It is the duty of all civilized people to strengthen the bonds of community and the security of civilization. (Lawful)
2 | Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Light)
3 | Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)

Bond:
1 | The location where I learned my trade is the most important place in the world to me.
2 | I created a great work for someone unworthy to receive it. I'm still looking for someone worthy.
3 | I owe someone a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.
4 | I pursue wealth to secure someone's love.
5 | One day I will return to my guild and prove that I am the greatest artisan of them all.
6 | I will get revenge on the Dark forces that destroyed my place of business and ruined my livelihood.

Flaw:
1 | I'll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.
2 | I'm quick to assume that someone is trying to cheat me.
3 | No one must ever learn that I once stole money from guild coffers.
4 | I'm never satisfied with what I have— I always want more.
5 | I would kill to acquire a noble title.
6 | I'm horribly jealous of anyone who can outshine my handiwork. Everywhere I go, I'm surrounded by rivals.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Crime Lord (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Intimidation, and Persuasion
Tools: One type of gaming set
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A fine set of clothes, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a purse containing 250 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Criminal Motivation</name>
      <text>Desperation
Freedom
Infamy
Love
Malice
Profit
Respect
Revenge</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Criminal Network</name>
      <text>You have access to an extensive network of organised crime. You know how to get messages to and from local contacts, even over great distances; you know the local messengers, corrupt caravan masters, and seedy sailors who can deliver messages for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Threatening
4 | Charming Persona
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Linguist
7 | Inspiring Leader
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Crime lords might seem like villains on the surface, and many of them are villainous to the core. But some have an abundance of endearing, if not redeeming, characteristics. Unlike common thieves, some crime lords even have some respect for law and authority, with whom they play a cat-and-mouse type game. 
Personality:
1 | I always have a plan for what to do when things go wrong.
2 | I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let me emotions control me.
3 | My eloquent flattery makes everyone I talk to feel like the most wonderful and important person in the world.
4 | I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy.
5 | I don't like to get my hands dirty, and I won't be caught dead in unsuitable accommodations.
6 | My favor, once lost, is lost forever.
7 | If you do me an injury, I will crush you, ruin your name, and salt your fields.
8 | I blow up at the slightest insult.

Ideals:
1 | Honor. I don't steal from others in the trade. (Lawful)
2 | Freedom. Chains are meant to be broken, as are those who would forge them. (Chaotic)
3 | Charity. I steal from the wealthy so that I can help people in need. (Light)
4 | Greed. I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Neutral)
6 | Redemption. There's a spark of good in everyone. (Light)

Bond:
1 | I'm trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor.
2 | My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.
3 | Something important was taken from me, and I aim to steal it back.
4 | The common folk must see me as a hero of the people.
5 | I'm guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it.
6 | Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made. That will never happen again.

Flaw:
1 | I secretly believe that everyone is beneath me.
2 | When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.
3 | I too often hear veiled insults and threats in every word addressed to me, and I'm quick to anger.
4 | I have a —tell— that reveals when I'm lying.
5 | I turn tail and run when things look bad.
6 | An innocent person is in prison for a crime that I committed. I'm okay with that.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Crime Lord (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Intimidation, and Persuasion
Tools: One type of gaming set
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A fine set of clothes, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a purse containing 250 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Criminal Motivation</name>
      <text>Desperation
Freedom
Infamy
Love
Malice
Profit
Respect
Revenge</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Criminal Network</name>
      <text>You have access to an extensive network of organised crime. You know how to get messages to and from local contacts, even over great distances; you know the local messengers, corrupt caravan masters, and seedy sailors who can deliver messages for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Threatening
4 | Charmer
5 | Entertainer
6 | Linguist
7 | Inspiring Leader
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Crime lords might seem like villains on the surface, and many of them are villainous to the core. But some have an abundance of endearing, if not redeeming, characteristics. Unlike common thieves, some crime lords even have some respect for law and authority, with whom they play a cat-and-mouse type game. 
Personality:
1 | I always have a plan for what to do when things go wrong.
2 | I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let me emotions control me.
3 | My eloquent flattery makes everyone I talk to feel like the most wonderful and important person in the world.
4 | I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy.
5 | I don't like to get my hands dirty, and I won't be caught dead in unsuitable accommodations.
6 | My favor, once lost, is lost forever.
7 | If you do me an injury, I will crush you, ruin your name, and salt your fields.
8 | I blow up at the slightest insult.

Ideals:
1 | Honor. I don't steal from others in the trade. (Lawful)
2 | Freedom. Chains are meant to be broken, as are those who would forge them. (Chaotic)
3 | Charity. I steal from the wealthy so that I can help people in need. (Light)
4 | Greed. I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Neutral)
6 | Redemption. There's a spark of good in everyone. (Light)

Bond:
1 | I'm trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor.
2 | My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.
3 | Something important was taken from me, and I aim to steal it back.
4 | The common folk must see me as a hero of the people.
5 | I'm guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it.
6 | Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made. That will never happen again.

Flaw:
1 | I secretly believe that everyone is beneath me.
2 | When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.
3 | I too often hear veiled insults and threats in every word addressed to me, and I'm quick to anger.
4 | I have a —tell— that reveals when I'm lying.
5 | I turn tail and run when things look bad.
6 | An innocent person is in prison for a crime that I committed. I'm okay with that.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Criminal (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Intimidation, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth
Tools: One type of gaming set, your choice of demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Language: 
Equipment: A set of common clothes with a hood, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Criminal Specialty</name>
      <text>Blackmailer
Burglar
Enforcer
Fence
Highway robber
Hired killer
Pickpocket
Thug</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Criminal Contact</name>
      <text>You have a reliable and trustworthy contact who acts as your liaison to a network of other criminals. You know how to get messages to and from your contact, even over great distances; specifically, you know the local messengers, corrupt caravan masters, and seedy sailors who can deliver messages for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Ace Pilot
3 | Quick-Fingered
4 | Stealthy
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Demolitionist
7 | Bypasser
8 | Slicer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Criminals might seem like villains on the surface, and many of them are villainous to the core. But some have an abundance of endearing, if not redeeming, characteristics. There might be honor among thieves, but criminals rarely show any respect for law or authority. 
Personality:
1 | I always have a plan for what to do when things go wrong.
2 | I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let me emotions control me.
3 | The first thing I do in a new place is note the locations of everything valuable — or where such things could be hidden.
4 | I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy.
5 | I am incredibly slow to trust. Those who seem the fairest often have the most to hide.
6 | I don't pay attention to the risks in a situation. Never tell me the odds.
7 | The best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can't do it.
8 | I blow up at the slightest insult.

Ideals:
1 | Honor. I don't steal from others in the trade. (Lawful)
2 | Freedom. Chains are meant to be broken, as are those who would forge them. (Chaotic)
3 | Charity. I steal from the wealthy so that I can help people in need. (Light)
4 | Greed. I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Neutral)
6 | Redemption. There's a spark of good in everyone. (Light)

Bond:
1 | I'm trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor.
2 | My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.
3 | Something important was taken from me, and I aim to steal it back.
4 | I will become the greatest thief that ever lived.
5 | I'm guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it.
6 | Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made. That will never happen again.

Flaw:
1 | When I see something valuable, I can't think about anything but how to steal it.
2 | When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.
3 | If there's a plan, I'll forget it. If I don't forget it, I'll ignore it.
4 | I have a —tell— that reveals when I'm lying.
5 | I turn tail and run when things look bad.
6 | An innocent person is in prison for a crime that I committed. I'm okay with that.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Dathomir Witch (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Lore, or Nature
Tools: Herbalism kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A copy of your clan's book of laws, a set of traveler's clothes, and a pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Witch Clans</name>
      <text>Singing Mountain
Misty Falls
Red Hills
Dreaming River
Frenzied River
Great Canyon
Nightsisters
Nightbrothers</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Matriarchal Society</name>
      <text>Other Dathomir Witches know, and will look out for you. If you're ever in need of a place to stay, or a meal to eat, other Dathomir Witches will help you as long as your clans aren't feuding. This could be in the form of shelters, meals, even healing. If the Dathomir Witches are of your clan or a clan friendly to you, they may be willing to help you even at cost to themselves.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Acrobat
2 | Animal Handler
3 | Loremaster
4 | Naturalist
5 | Herbalist
6 | Linguist
7 | Force Sensitive
8 | Force of Personality</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Dathomir Witches are shaped by their training. They study their book of laws and use it to uphold order and prevent one's turn to the dark side. Their clan and the people around them affects their mannerisms and ideals. Their flaws might be some hidden hypocrisy or heretical idea, or an ideal or bond taken to an extreme.

Personality:
1 | I try and bring my culture to outsiders.
2 | I always put my clan first.
3 | I follow my clan's book of law to the letter.
4 | I once ran twenty-five miles without stopping to warn to my clan of an approaching rival clan. I'd do it again if I had to.
5 | I place no stock in wealthy or well-mannered folk. Credits and manners won't save you from a hungry rancor.
6 | I have a lesson for every situation, drawn from observing nature.
7 | I feel far more comfortable around wildlife than I do society.
8 | I'm always picking things up, absently fiddling with them, and sometimes accidentally breaking them.

Ideals:
1 | Change. Life is like the seasons, in constant change, and we must change with it. (Chaotic)
2 | Greater Good. It is each person's responsibility to make the most happiness for the whole clan. (Light)
3 | Honor. If I dishonor myself, I dishonor my whole clan. (Lawful)
4 | Might. The strongest are meant to rule. (Dark)
5 | Nature. The natural world is more important than all the constructs of civilization. (Neutral)
6 | Glory. I must earn glory in battle, for myself and my clan. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My family and clan is the most important thing in my life, even when they are far from me.
2 | An injury to the unspoiled wilderness of my home is an injury to me.
3 | I am the last of my clan, and it is up to me to keep the traditions of my ancestors alive.
4 | It is my duty to provide children to sustain my clan.
5 | I suffer awful visions of a coming disaster and will do anything to prevent it.
6 | I will bring terrible wrath down on those who disrespect my clan.

Flaw:
1 | I stick to my traditions no matter what, even at the cost of others.
2 | There's no room for caution in a life lived to the fullest.
3 | I remember every insult I've received and nurse a silent resentment toward anyone who's ever wronged me.
4 | I am slow to trust members of other species, clans, and societies.
5 | Violence is my answer to almost any challenge.
6 | Don't expect me to save those who can't save themselves. It is nature's way that the strong thrive and the weak perish.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Dathomir Witch (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Lore, or Nature
Tools: Herbalism kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A copy of your clan's book of laws, a set of traveler's clothes, and a pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Witch Clans</name>
      <text>Singing Mountain
Misty Falls
Red Hills
Dreaming River
Frenzied River
Great Canyon
Nightsisters
Nightbrothers</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Matriarchal Society</name>
      <text>Other Dathomir Witches know, and will look out for you. If you're ever in need of a place to stay, or a meal to eat, other Dathomir Witches will help you as long as your clans aren't feuding. This could be in the form of shelters, meals, even healing. If the Dathomir Witches are of your clan or a clan friendly to you, they may be willing to help you even at cost to themselves.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Acrobat
2 | Animal Handler
3 | Loremaster
4 | Naturalist
5 | Specialist
6 | Linguist
7 | Force-Sensitive
8 | Force of Personality</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Dathomir Witches are shaped by their training. They study their book of laws and use it to uphold order and prevent one's turn to the dark side. Their clan and the people around them affects their mannerisms and ideals. Their flaws might be some hidden hypocrisy or heretical idea, or an ideal or bond taken to an extreme.

Personality:
1 | I try and bring my culture to outsiders.
2 | I always put my clan first.
3 | I follow my clan's book of law to the letter.
4 | I once ran twenty-five miles without stopping to warn to my clan of an approaching rival clan. I'd do it again if I had to.
5 | I place no stock in wealthy or well-mannered folk. Credits and manners won't save you from a hungry rancor.
6 | I have a lesson for every situation, drawn from observing nature.
7 | I feel far more comfortable around wildlife than I do society.
8 | I'm always picking things up, absently fiddling with them, and sometimes accidentally breaking them.

Ideals:
1 | Change. Life is like the seasons, in constant change, and we must change with it. (Chaotic)
2 | Greater Good. It is each person's responsibility to make the most happiness for the whole clan. (Light)
3 | Honor. If I dishonor myself, I dishonor my whole clan. (Lawful)
4 | Might. The strongest are meant to rule. (Dark)
5 | Nature. The natural world is more important than all the constructs of civilization. (Neutral)
6 | Glory. I must earn glory in battle, for myself and my clan. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My family and clan is the most important thing in my life, even when they are far from me.
2 | An injury to the unspoiled wilderness of my home is an injury to me.
3 | I am the last of my clan, and it is up to me to keep the traditions of my ancestors alive.
4 | It is my duty to provide children to sustain my clan.
5 | I suffer awful visions of a coming disaster and will do anything to prevent it.
6 | I will bring terrible wrath down on those who disrespect my clan.

Flaw:
1 | I stick to my traditions no matter what, even at the cost of others.
2 | There's no room for caution in a life lived to the fullest.
3 | I remember every insult I've received and nurse a silent resentment toward anyone who's ever wronged me.
4 | I am slow to trust members of other species, clans, and societies.
5 | Violence is my answer to almost any challenge.
6 | Don't expect me to save those who can't save themselves. It is nature's way that the strong thrive and the weak perish.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Entertainer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Insight, Performance, and Sleight of Hand
Tools: Disguise kit, one type of musical instrument
Language: 
Equipment: A musical instrument (one of your choice), the favor of an admirer (love letter, lock of hair, or trinket), a costume, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Entertainer Routines</name>
      <text>Actor
Dancer
Fire-eater
Jester
Juggler
Instrumentalist
Poet
Singer
Storyteller
Tumbler</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: By Popular Demand</name>
      <text>You can always find a place to perform, usually in an inn or cantina but possibly with a circus, at a theater, or even in a noble's court. At such a place, you receive free lodging and food of a modest or comfortable standard (depending on the quality of the establishment), as long as you perform each night. In addition, your performance makes you something of a local figure. When strangers recognize you in a town where you have performed, they typically take a liking to you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Acrobat
2 | Empathic
3 | Performer
4 | Quick-Fingered
5 | Master of Disguise
6 | Entertaining Competitor
7 | Practiced
8 | Actor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Successful entertainers have to be able to capture and hold an audience's attention, so they tend to have flamboyant or forceful personalities. They're inclined toward the romantic and often cling to high-minded ideals about the practice of art and the appreciation of beauty.

Personality:
1 | I know a story relevant to almost every situation.
2 | Whenever I come to a new place, I collect local rumors and spread gossip.
3 | I'm a hopeless romantic, always searching for that —special someone.—
4 | Nobody stays angry at me or around me for long, since I can defuse any amount of tension.
5 | I love a good insult, even one directed at me.
6 | I get bitter if I'm not the center of attention.
7 | I'll settle for nothing less than perfection.
8 | I change my mood or my mind as quickly as I change key in a song.

Ideals:
1 | Beauty. When I perform, I make the world better than it was. (Light)
2 | Tradition. The stories, legends, and songs of the past must never be forgotten, for they teach us who we are. (Lawful)
3 | Creativity. The world is in need of new ideas and bold action. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money and fame. (Dark)
5 | People. I like seeing the smiles on people's faces when I perform. That's all that matters. (Neutral)
6 | Honesty. Art should reflect the soul; it should come from within and reveal who we really are. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My instrument is my most treasured possession, and it reminds me of someone I love.
2 | Someone stole my precious instrument, and someday I'll get it back.
3 | I want to be famous, whatever it takes.
4 | I idolize a hero of the old tales and measure my deeds against that person's.
5 | I will do anything to prove myself superior to my hated rival.
6 | I would do anything for the other members of my old troupe.

Flaw:
1 | I'll do anything to win fame and renown.
2 | I'm a sucker for a pretty face.
3 | A scandal prevents me from ever going home again. That kind of trouble seems to follow me around.
4 | I once satirized a noble who still wants my head. It was a mistake that I will likely repeat.
5 | I have trouble keeping my true feelings hidden. My sharp tongue lands me in trouble.
6 | Despite my best efforts, I am unreliable to my friends.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Faction Adventurer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Faction Adventurer Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Adventuring is nothing new to you. Due to the circumstances of how you were raised, you have been involved with wandering heroes for most of your life. Maybe you were part of an adventuring band previously, but split with them after a disagreement or tragedy. Or, perhaps you worked around heroes in a lesser role for most of your young life, and you are now ready to graduate to the front lines.

Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Athletics, Investigation, Nature, and Survival
Tool Proficiencies: Your choice demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Languages: One of your choice
Equipment: 50 feet of rope, a small knife, a trophy, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Faction Membership</name>
      <text>You are an established and respected member of an adventurer's faction, allowing you to rely on certain benefits that membership provides. If you are in a town with a headquarters for your adventurer's faction and you are in good standing with the faction, you will be allowed to look at the job postings and find adventuring work to earn money.

Factions often wield tremendous political power. If you are accused of a crime, your faction will support you if a good case can be made for your innocence or the crime is justifiable. You can also gain access to powerful political figures through the faction, if you are a member in good standing. You must pay dues of 50 cr per month to the faction. Your dues must be current to remain in the faction's good graces.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Investigator
3 | Naturalist
4 | Survivalist
5 | Specialist
6 | Linguist
7 | Alert
8 | Athlete</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Characteristics</name>
      <text>Adventurers are well adjusted to life on the road. They are often comfortable doing dangerous things like dungeoneering and fighting and can stay level-headed in the face of danger, but they may not be so well adapted to other parts of life.

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | I can't bring myself to ignore a cry for help.
2 | I hold onto every mildly interesting item I find, in case it comes in handy someday.
3 | After all the weirdness I've seen on my travels, nothing can surprise me.
4 | I spit and laugh in the face of danger.
5 | Giving up is never an option for me.
6 | I feel more at home in monster-infested dungeons than in civilized society.
7 | I fill silence with wacky stories about my past misadventures, which may or may not be exaggerated.
8 | My sense of humor is as dark and grim as the dungeons I explore.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Adventure. All I want is to travel the world and see amazing things. (Any)
2 | Heroism. I am dedicated to helping people in need. (Light)
3 | Order. I use my power to save the world from the forces of destruction and chaos. (Lawful)
4 | Excitement. An ordinary life is boring, I'd rather travel around and find trouble. (Chaotic)
5 | Power. The more powerful enemies I defeat, the stronger I become. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I want to go down in history as a brave, powerful hero. (Any)

d6 | Bond
1 | I carry with me a strange artifact that I found in a dungeon, but I don't know what it's for.
2 | My adventuring party means the world to me.
3 | I have sworn to hunt down the monster or villain who killed my former adventuring party.
4 | I adventure in order to bring honor (or money) to my family.
5 | There is a faraway place I've always wanted to visit, and I won't stop until I make it there.
6 | All I want is to make the ones who trained me in the way of adventuring proud.

d6 | Flaw
1 | I default to solving problems with violence even when it's unwise or immoral.
2 | I expect to be lavished with praise whenever I do my job, and I get mad when no one acknowledges me.
3 | All members of "Dark" species must be Dark, so I will never trust them.
4 | Waiting around makes me antsy. I'd rather do something stupid than do nothing at all.
5 | My habit of looting dungeons makes me swipe things I shouldn't.
6 | A monstrous enemy I faced in the past still leaves me quivering with fear.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Faction Artisan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Faction Artisan Proficiencies</name>
      <text>You are a member of an artisan's faction, skilled in a particular field and closely associated with other artisans. You are a well-established part of the mercantile world, freed by talent and wealth from the constraints of a feudal social order. You learned your skills as an apprentice to a master artisan, under the sponsorship of your faction, until you became a master in your own right.

Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Persuasion, and Technology
Tool Proficiencies: One type of artisan's implements, biochemist's kit, or chef's kit
Languages: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of tools (one of your choice), a letter of introduction from your faction, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Faction Membership</name>
      <text>As an established and respected member of a faction, you can rely on certain benefits that membership provides. Your fellow faction members will provide you with lodging and food if necessary, and pay for your funeral if needed. In some cities and towns, a factionhall offers a central place to meet other members of your profession, which can be a good place to meet potential patrons, allies, or hirelings.

Factions often wield tremendous political power. If you are accused of a crime, your faction will support you if a good case can be made for your innocence or the crime is justifiable. You can also gain access to powerful political figures through the faction, if you are a member in good standing. You must pay dues of 50 cr per month to the faction. Your dues must be current to remain in the faction's good graces.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Empathic
3 | Charmer
4 | Techie
5 | Crafter
6 | Specialist
7 | Linguist
8 | Haggler</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Characteristics</name>
      <text>faction artisans are among the most ordinary people in the world�until they set down their tools and take up an adventuring career. They understand the value of hard work and the importance of community, but they're vulnerable to sins of greed and covetousness.

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | I believe that anything worth doing is worth doing right. I can't help it� I'm a perfectionist.
2 | I'm a snob who looks down on those who can't appreciate fine art.
3 | I always want to know how things work and what makes people tick.
4 | I'm full of witty aphorisms and have a proverb for every occasion.
5 | I'm rude to people who lack my commitment to hard work and fair play.
6 | I like to talk at length about my profession.
7 | I don't part with my money easily and will haggle tirelessly to get the best deal possible.
8 | I believe I'm well known for my work, and I'm always taken aback when people haven't heard of me.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Community. It is the duty of all civilized people to strengthen the bonds of community and the security of civilization. (Lawful)
2 | Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Light)
3 | Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)

d6 | Bond
1 | The workshop where I learned my trade is the most important place in the world to me.
2 | I created a great work for someone, and then found them unworthy of it; I now search for someone worthy.
3 | I owe my faction a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.
4 | I pursue wealth to secure someone's love.
5 | One day I will return to my faction and prove that I am the greatest artisan of them all.
6 | I will get revenge on the Dark forces that destroyed my place of business and ruined my livelihood.

d6 | Flaw
1 | I'll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.
2 | I'm quick to assume that someone is trying to cheat me.
3 | No one must ever learn that I once stole money from faction coffers.
4 | I'm never satisfied with what I have� I always want more.
5 | I would kill to acquire a noble title.
6 | I'm horribly jealous of anyone who can outshine my handiwork. Everywhere I go, I'm surrounded by rivals.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Faction Merchant (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Faction Merchant Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Instead of an artisans' faction, you might belong to a faction of traders, caravan masters, or shopkeepers. You don't craft items yourself but earn a living by buying and selling the works of others. Your faction might be a large merchant consortium (or family) with interests across the galaxy. Perhaps you transported goods from one place to another, by ship, wagon, or caravan, or bought them from traveling traders and sold them in your own little shop. In some ways, the traveling merchant's life lends itself to adventure far more than the life of an artisan.

Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Performance, and Persuasion
Languages: Two of your choice
Equipment: A letter of introduction from your faction, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Faction Membership</name>
      <text>As an established and respected member of a faction, you can rely on certain benefits that membership provides. Your fellow faction members will provide you with lodging and food if necessary, and pay for your funeral if needed. In some cities and towns, a factionhall offers a central place to meet other members of your profession, which can be a good place to meet potential patrons, allies, or hirelings.

Factions often wield tremendous political power. If you are accused of a crime, your faction will support you if a good case can be made for your innocence or the crime is justifiable. You can also gain access to powerful political figures through the faction, if you are a member in good standing. You must pay dues of 50 cr per month to the faction. Your dues must be current to remain in the faction's good graces.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Performer
4 | Charmer
5 | Linguist
6 | Haggler
7 | Inspiring Leader
8 | Practiced</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Characteristics</name>
      <text>Faction merchants are among the most ordinary people in the world, until they abscond to take up an adventuring career. They understand the value of hard work and the importance of community, but they're vulnerable to sins of greed and covetousness.

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | I believe that anything worth doing is worth doing right. I can't help it; I'm a perfectionist.
2 | I'm a snob who looks down on those who can't appreciate fine art.
3 | I always want to know how things work and what makes people tick.
4 | I'm full of witty aphorisms and have a proverb for every occasion.
5 | I'm rude to people who lack my commitment to hard work and fair play.
6 | I like to talk at length about my profession.
7 | I don't part with my money easily and will haggle tirelessly to get the best deal possible.
8 | I believe I'm well known for my work, and I'm always taken aback when people haven't heard of me.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Community. It is the duty of all civilized people to strengthen the bonds of community and the security of civilization. (Lawful)
2 | Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Light)
3 | Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)

d6 | Bond
1 | The workshop where I learned my trade is the most important place in the world to me.
2 | I commissioned a great work for someone unworthy of it; I now search for someone worthy.
3 | I owe my faction a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.
4 | I pursue wealth to secure someone's love.
5 | One day I will return to my faction and prove that I am the greatest artisan of them all.
6 | I will get revenge on the Dark forces that destroyed my place of business and ruined my livelihood.

d6 | Flaw
1 | I'll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.
2 | I'm quick to assume that someone is trying to cheat me.
3 | No one must ever learn that I once stole money from faction coffers.
4 | I'm never satisfied with what I have. I always want more.
5 | I would kill to acquire a noble title.
6 | I'm horribly jealous of anyone who can outshine my handiwork. Everywhere I go, I'm surrounded by rivals.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Far Traveler (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Perception, and Persuasion
Tools: Any one musical instrument or gaming set of your choice, likely something native to your homeland
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: One set of traveler's clothes, any one musical instrument or gaming set you are proficient with, poorly wrought maps from your homeland, a small piece of jewelry worth 100 cr in the style of your homeland's craftsmanship, and a pouch containing 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Why Are You Here?</name>
      <text>Emissary
Exile
Fugitive
Pilgrim
Sightseer
Wanderer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: All Eyes On You</name>
      <text>Your foreign nature attracts attention, yielding access to people and places you might not otherwise have, for you and your traveling companions. Noble lords, scholars, and merchant princes, to name a few, might be interested in hearing about your distant homeland and people.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Perceptive
4 | Charming Persona
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Linguist
7 | Athlete
8 | Practiced</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>The distance you've traveled manifests itself in the way you speak and carry yourself.

Personality:
1 | I have different assumptions from those around me concerning personal space, invading others' space in innocence, or reacting to invasion of my own.
2 | I have my own ideas about food, and I find the eating habits of others fascinating, confusing, or revolting.
3 | I have a strong code of honor or sense of propriety that others don't comprehend.
4 | I express affection or contempt in ways that are unfamiliar to others.
5 | I honor my deities through practices that are foreign to this land.
6 | I begin or end my day with small traditional rituals that are unfamiliar to those around me.

Ideals:
1 | Open. I have much to learn from the kindly folk I meet along my way. (Light)
2 | Reserved. As someone new to these strange lands, I am cautious and respectful in my dealings. (Lawful)
3 | Adventure. I'm far from home, and everything is strange and wonderful! (Chaotic)
4 | Cunning. Though I may not know their ways, neither do they know mine, which can be to my advantage. (Dark)
5 | Inquisitive. Everything is new, but I have a thirst to learn. (Neutral)
6 | Suspicious. I must be careful, for I have no way of telling friend from foe here. (Any)

Bond:
1 | So long as I have this token from my homeland, I can face any adversity in this strange land.
2 | The gods of my people are a comfort to me so far from home.
3 | I hold no greater cause than my service to my people.
4 | My freedom is my most precious possession. I'll never let anyone take it from me again.
5 | I'm fascinated by the beauty and wonder of this new land.
6 | Though I had no choice, I lament having to leave my loved one (s) behind. I ho pe to see them again one day.

Flaw:
1 | I am secretly (or not so secretly) convinced of the superiority of my own culture over that of this foreign land.
2 | I pretend not to understand the local language in order to avoid interactions I would rather not have.
3 | I have a weakness for the new intoxicants and other pleasures of this land.
4 | I don't take kindly to some of the actions and motivations of folk different from me.
5 | I consider the adherents of other gods to be deluded innocents at best, or ignorant fools at worst.
6 | I have a weakness for the exotic beauty of the people of these lands.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Far Traveler (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Perception, and Persuasion
Tools: Any one musical instrument or gaming set of your choice, likely something native to your homeland
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: One set of traveler's clothes, any one musical instrument or gaming set you are proficient with, poorly wrought maps from your homeland, a small piece of jewelry worth 100 cr in the style of your homeland's craftsmanship, and a pouch containing 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Why Are You Here?</name>
      <text>Emissary
Exile
Fugitive
Pilgrim
Sightseer
Wanderer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: All Eyes On You</name>
      <text>Your foreign nature attracts attention, yielding access to people and places you might not otherwise have, for you and your traveling companions. Noble lords, scholars, and merchant princes, to name a few, might be interested in hearing about your distant homeland and people.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Perceptive
4 | Charmer
5 | Entertainer
6 | Linguist
7 | Athlete
8 | Practiced</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>The distance you've traveled manifests itself in the way you speak and carry yourself.

Personality:
1 | I have different assumptions from those around me concerning personal space, invading others' space in innocence, or reacting to invasion of my own.
2 | I have my own ideas about food, and I find the eating habits of others fascinating, confusing, or revolting.
3 | I have a strong code of honor or sense of propriety that others don't comprehend.
4 | I express affection or contempt in ways that are unfamiliar to others.
5 | I honor my deities through practices that are foreign to this land.
6 | I begin or end my day with small traditional rituals that are unfamiliar to those around me.

Ideals:
1 | Open. I have much to learn from the kindly folk I meet along my way. (Light)
2 | Reserved. As someone new to these strange lands, I am cautious and respectful in my dealings. (Lawful)
3 | Adventure. I'm far from home, and everything is strange and wonderful! (Chaotic)
4 | Cunning. Though I may not know their ways, neither do they know mine, which can be to my advantage. (Dark)
5 | Inquisitive. Everything is new, but I have a thirst to learn. (Neutral)
6 | Suspicious. I must be careful, for I have no way of telling friend from foe here. (Any)

Bond:
1 | So long as I have this token from my homeland, I can face any adversity in this strange land.
2 | The gods of my people are a comfort to me so far from home.
3 | I hold no greater cause than my service to my people.
4 | My freedom is my most precious possession. I'll never let anyone take it from me again.
5 | I'm fascinated by the beauty and wonder of this new land.
6 | Though I had no choice, I lament having to leave my loved one (s) behind. I ho pe to see them again one day.

Flaw:
1 | I am secretly (or not so secretly) convinced of the superiority of my own culture over that of this foreign land.
2 | I pretend not to understand the local language in order to avoid interactions I would rather not have.
3 | I have a weakness for the new intoxicants and other pleasures of this land.
4 | I don't take kindly to some of the actions and motivations of folk different from me.
5 | I consider the adherents of other gods to be deluded innocents at best, or ignorant fools at worst.
6 | I have a weakness for the exotic beauty of the people of these lands.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Farmer (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Nature, Persuasion, and Technology
Tools: One instrument and one type of artisan's tools or herbalist's kit
Language: 
Equipment: A rough instrument you are proficient with, a set of tools (one of your choice), a sturdy knife, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Farming Specialty</name>
      <text>Cereal Crops
Drug Compounds
Fibrous Plants
Herbs &amp; Spices
Insect Products
Livestock
Moisture
Vegetables</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Rustic Hospitality</name>
      <text>Since you are of the common folk, you fit in among them with ease. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other commoners, unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them. They will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Naturalist
3 | Charming Persona
4 | Techie
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Crafter
7 | Herbalist
8 | Haggler</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A farmer is one of the common people and unusually tied to their home and the land. Most farmers look on their humble origins as a virtue, not a shortcoming, and they are quick to defend their home communities and their values, even if they always longed to leave their rural lives and move to the city.

Personality:
1 | I judge people by their actions, not their words.
2 | If someone is in trouble, I'm always ready to lend help.
3 | When I set my mind to something, I follow through no matter what gets in my way.
4 | I have a strong sense of fair play and always try to find the most equitable solution to arguments.
5 | Thinking is for other people. I prefer action.
6 | I misuse long words in an attempt to sound smarter.
7 | I watch over my friends as if they were a litter of newborn pups.
8 | I have a lesson for every situation, drawn from observing nature.

Ideals:
1 | Respect. People deserve to be treated with dignity and respect. (Light)
2 | Honor. My word is my bond. (Lawful)
3 | Freedom. Tyrants must not be allowed to oppress the people. (Light)
4 | Greed. I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Meddling in the affairs of others only causes trouble. (Neutral)
6 | People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I'm trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor.
2 | I worked the land, I love the land, and I will protect the land.
3 | A proud noble once gave me a horrible beating, and I will take my revenge on any bully I encounter.
4 | I wish my childhood sweetheart had come with me to pursue my destiny.
5 | My family, community, or planet is the most important thing in my life, even when they are far from me.
6 | Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made. That will never happen again.

Flaw:
1 | I am too enamored of ale, wine, and other intoxicants.
2 | I remember every insult I've received and nurse a silent resentment toward anyone who's ever wronged me.
3 | I am slow to trust members of other species, planets, and societies.
4 | The tyrant who rules my land will stop at nothing to see me killed.
5 | I turn tail and run when things look bad.
6 | I have a weakness for the vices of the city, especially gambling.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Farmer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Nature, Persuasion, and Technology
Tools: One instrument and one type of artisan's tools or herbalist's kit
Language: 
Equipment: A rough instrument you are proficient with, a set of tools (one of your choice), a sturdy knife, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Farming Specialty</name>
      <text>Cereal Crops
Drug Compounds
Fibrous Plants
Herbs &amp; Spices
Insect Products
Livestock
Moisture
Vegetables</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Rustic Hospitality</name>
      <text>Since you are of the common folk, you fit in among them with ease. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other commoners, unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them. They will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Naturalist
3 | Charmer
4 | Techie
5 | Entertainer
6 | Crafter
7 | Specialist
8 | Haggler</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A farmer is one of the common people and unusually tied to their home and the land. Most farmers look on their humble origins as a virtue, not a shortcoming, and they are quick to defend their home communities and their values, even if they always longed to leave their rural lives and move to the city.

Personality:
1 | I judge people by their actions, not their words.
2 | If someone is in trouble, I'm always ready to lend help.
3 | When I set my mind to something, I follow through no matter what gets in my way.
4 | I have a strong sense of fair play and always try to find the most equitable solution to arguments.
5 | Thinking is for other people. I prefer action.
6 | I misuse long words in an attempt to sound smarter.
7 | I watch over my friends as if they were a litter of newborn pups.
8 | I have a lesson for every situation, drawn from observing nature.

Ideals:
1 | Respect. People deserve to be treated with dignity and respect. (Light)
2 | Honor. My word is my bond. (Lawful)
3 | Freedom. Tyrants must not be allowed to oppress the people. (Light)
4 | Greed. I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Meddling in the affairs of others only causes trouble. (Neutral)
6 | People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I'm trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor.
2 | I worked the land, I love the land, and I will protect the land.
3 | A proud noble once gave me a horrible beating, and I will take my revenge on any bully I encounter.
4 | I wish my childhood sweetheart had come with me to pursue my destiny.
5 | My family, community, or planet is the most important thing in my life, even when they are far from me.
6 | Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made. That will never happen again.

Flaw:
1 | I am too enamored of ale, wine, and other intoxicants.
2 | I remember every insult I've received and nurse a silent resentment toward anyone who's ever wronged me.
3 | I am slow to trust members of other species, planets, and societies.
4 | The tyrant who rules my land will stop at nothing to see me killed.
5 | I turn tail and run when things look bad.
6 | I have a weakness for the vices of the city, especially gambling.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Folk Hero (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Nature, and Performance
Tools: One type of artisan's tools, biochemist's kit, or chef's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of tools (one of your choice), a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Defining Event</name>
      <text>I stood up to a tyrant's agents.
I saved people during a natural disaster.
I stood alone against a terrible monster.
I stole from a corrupt merchant to help the poor.
I led a militia to fight off an invading army.
I broke into a tyrant's castle and stole weapons to arm the people.
I trained the peasantry to use farm implements as weapons against a tyrant's soldiers.
A lord rescinded an unpopular decree after I led a symbolic act of protect against it.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Rustic Hospitality</name>
      <text>Since you are of the common folk, you fit in among them with ease. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other commoners, unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them. They will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Brawny
3 | Naturalist
4 | Performer
5 | Crafter
6 | Gourmand
7 | Biochemist
8 | Healer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A folk hero is one of the common people, for better or for worse. Most folk heroes look on their humble origins as a virtue, not a shortcoming, and their home communities remain very important to them.

Personality:
1 | I judge people by their actions, not their words.
2 | If someone is in trouble, I'm always ready to lend help.
3 | When I set my mind to something, I follow through no matter what gets in my way.
4 | I have a strong sense of fair play and always try to find the most equitable solution to arguments.
5 | I'm confident in my own abilities and do what I can to instill confidence in others.
6 | Thinking is for other people. I prefer action.
7 | I misuse long words in an attempt to sound smarter.
8 | I get bored easily. When am I going to get on with my destiny?

Ideals:
1 | Respect. People deserve to be treated with dignity and respect. (Light)
2 | Fairness. No one should get preferential treatment before the law, and no one is above the law. (Lawful)
3 | Freedom. Tyrants must not be allowed to oppress the people. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. If I become strong, I can take what I want, what I deserve. (Dark)
5 | Sincerity. There's no good in pretending to be something I'm not. (Neutral)
6 | Destiny. Nothing and no one can steer me away from my higher calling. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I have a family, but I have no idea where they are. One day, I hope to see them again.
2 | I worked the land, I love the land, and I will protect the land.
3 | A proud noble once gave me a horrible beating, and I will take my revenge on any bully I encounter.
4 | My tools are symbols of my past life, and I carry them so that I will never forget my roots.
5 | I protect those who cannot protect themselves.
6 | I wish my childhood sweetheart had come with me to pursue my destiny.

Flaw:
1 | The tyrant who rules my land will stop at nothing to see me killed.
2 | I'm convinced of the significance of my destiny, and blind to my shortcomings and the risk of failure.
3 | The people who knew me when I was young know my shameful secret, so I can never go home again.
4 | I have a weakness for the vices of the city, especially hard drink.
5 | Secretly, I believe that things would be better if I were a tyrant lording over the land.
6 | I have trouble trusting in my allies.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Folk Hero (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Nature, and Performance
Tools: One type of artisan's tools, biochemist's kit, or chef's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of tools (one of your choice), a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Defining Event</name>
      <text>I stood up to a tyrant's agents.
I saved people during a natural disaster.
I stood alone against a terrible monster.
I stole from a corrupt merchant to help the poor.
I led a militia to fight off an invading army.
I broke into a tyrant's castle and stole weapons to arm the people.
I trained the peasantry to use farm implements as weapons against a tyrant's soldiers.
A lord rescinded an unpopular decree after I led a symbolic act of protect against it.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Rustic Hospitality</name>
      <text>Since you are of the common folk, you fit in among them with ease. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other commoners, unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them. They will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Brawny
3 | Naturalist
4 | Performer
5 | Crafter
6 | Specialist
7 | Linguist
8 | Healer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A folk hero is one of the common people, for better or for worse. Most folk heroes look on their humble origins as a virtue, not a shortcoming, and their home communities remain very important to them.

Personality:
1 | I judge people by their actions, not their words.
2 | If someone is in trouble, I'm always ready to lend help.
3 | When I set my mind to something, I follow through no matter what gets in my way.
4 | I have a strong sense of fair play and always try to find the most equitable solution to arguments.
5 | I'm confident in my own abilities and do what I can to instill confidence in others.
6 | Thinking is for other people. I prefer action.
7 | I misuse long words in an attempt to sound smarter.
8 | I get bored easily. When am I going to get on with my destiny?

Ideals:
1 | Respect. People deserve to be treated with dignity and respect. (Light)
2 | Fairness. No one should get preferential treatment before the law, and no one is above the law. (Lawful)
3 | Freedom. Tyrants must not be allowed to oppress the people. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. If I become strong, I can take what I want, what I deserve. (Dark)
5 | Sincerity. There's no good in pretending to be something I'm not. (Neutral)
6 | Destiny. Nothing and no one can steer me away from my higher calling. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I have a family, but I have no idea where they are. One day, I hope to see them again.
2 | I worked the land, I love the land, and I will protect the land.
3 | A proud noble once gave me a horrible beating, and I will take my revenge on any bully I encounter.
4 | My tools are symbols of my past life, and I carry them so that I will never forget my roots.
5 | I protect those who cannot protect themselves.
6 | I wish my childhood sweetheart had come with me to pursue my destiny.

Flaw:
1 | The tyrant who rules my land will stop at nothing to see me killed.
2 | I'm convinced of the significance of my destiny, and blind to my shortcomings and the risk of failure.
3 | The people who knew me when I was young know my shameful secret, so I can never go home again.
4 | I have a weakness for the vices of the city, especially hard drink.
5 | Secretly, I believe that things would be better if I were a tyrant lording over the land.
6 | I have trouble trusting in my allies.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Force Adept (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Adept</name>
      <text>You are keenly attuned to the flow of the mysterious energy field known as the Force. With proper training, you could learn to consciously sense and manipulate that energy further. As it is, you may appear to have heightened senses, extremely quick reflexes, an intuitive understanding of others, or an uncanny ability to persuade people to your way of thinking. Your powers may have lain dormant for a long time, perhaps you felt something inside of you but never knew what it was. Perhaps your abilities were awoken by a strong encounter with another force-sensitive with the powers of the Force, or an object associated with the Force, such as a lightsaber.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Perception, and Persuasion
Tool Proficiencies: Two of your choice of artisan's implements, gaming sets, or musical instruments
Equipment: A set of common clothes, a sturdy knife, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Guided by the Force</name>
      <text>When you attempt to learn a piece of knowledge, you often instinctively know where or from whom you can obtain it. Usually, this information comes from a seemingly random person, book, or data file. Your GM might rule that the knowledge you seek is secreted away in an almost inaccessible place, or that it simply cannot be found.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Perceptive
4 | Charmer
5 | Crafter
6 | Entertainer
7 | Force of Personality
8 | Force-Sensitive</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Gambler (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Intimidation, and Sleight of Hand
Tools: Two types of gaming sets
Language: 
Equipment: A set of common clothes, a set of dice, a deck of playing cards, a lucky charm, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Let's Make It Interesting</name>
      <text>You can convince nearly anyone to put up something they aren't normally willing to part with (property or information) in a game of chance. Your GM might rule that they will only agree to a game of their choosing, and they may only agree if they feel the odds are in their favor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Threatening
4 | Quick-Fingered
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Keen Mind
7 | Observant
8 | Practiced</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Gambling is your passion, for better or for worse. Most gamblers see their vices as virtues, and overlook things in their pursuit of the rush.

Personality:
1 | I like to impress everyone I meet with a simple trick or a quick joke.
2 | I constantly make side bets on everything that happens around me.
3 | No matter how high the stakes, I always appear calm.
4 | I try to be unpredictable, so no one will know when I'm bluffing.
5 | I never back down from a challenge.
6 | I can't get satisfaction out of something if the stakes are too low.
7 | I tend to make friends out of enemies, and enemies out of friends.
8 | I prefer one game above all others.

Ideals:
1 | Risk. Nothing worth doing is ever a sure thing. (Chaotic)
2 | Victory. Never make a bet unless you're sure you can win. (Lawful)
3 | Gred. Anything that isn't mine soon will be. (Dark)
4 | Charity. I share my winnings with the less fortunate. (Light)
5 | Surprise. Life is a game worth playing, because you never know how the dice will land. (Any)
6 | Laziness. Working is for chumps. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I owe a lot of money to the wrong kind of people.
2 | I still keep the first coin I ever won. It's my good luck charm.
3 | Most of my winnings go to my home.
4 | Someday I will own my own casino.
5 | I lost a large sum of money to a con artist; I seek to get it back.
6 | I hide my gambling behind a normal life. My friends have no idea who I really am.

Flaw:
1 | I can't step away from the table when I'm losing.
2 | I spend money faster than I can make it.
3 | Everyone has a price. Mine happens to be pretty low.
4 | I assume everyone is hiding something from me.
5 | I tend to value money more than people.
6 | I like to think I could drink anyone under the table, but I'm really a lightweight.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Gladiator (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, Intimidation, and Performance
Tools: One type of musical instrument
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A trophy earned via some sort of competition, clothing suitable to your profession, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: A Champion Well Known</name>
      <text>You can always find a place to perform, usually in an inn or tavern but possibly with a circus, at a theater, or even in a noble's court. At such a place, you receive free lodging and food of a modest or comfortable standard (depending on the quality of the establishment), as long as you perform each night. In addition, your performance makes you something of a local figure. When strangers recognize you in a town where you have performed, they typically take a liking to you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Acrobatics
2 | Brawny
3 | Threatening
4 | Performer
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Linguist
7 | Durable
8 | Martial Adept</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Successful entertainers have to be able to capture and hold an audience's attention, so they tend to have flamboyant or forceful personalities. They're inclined toward the romantic and often cling to high-minded ideals about the practice of art and the appreciation of beauty.

Personality:
1 | I know a story relevant to almost every situation.
2 | Whenever I come to a new place, I collect local rumors and spread gossip.
3 | I'm a hopeless romantic, always searching for that —special someone.—
4 | Nobody stays angry at me or around me for long, since I can defuse any amount of tension.
5 | I love a good insult, even one directed at me.
6 | I get bitter if I'm not the center of attention.
7 | I'll settle for nothing less than perfection.
8 | I change my mood or my mind as quickly as I change key in a song.

Ideals:
1 | Beauty. When I perform, I make the world better than it was. (Light)
2 | Tradition. The stories, legends, and songs of the past must never be forgotten, for they teach us who we are. (Lawful)
3 | Creativity. The world is in need of new ideas and bold action. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money and fame. (Dark)
5 | People. I like seeing the smiles on people's faces when I perform. That's all that matters. (Neutral)
6 | Honesty. Art should reflect the soul; it should come from within and reveal who we really are. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My instrument is my most treasured possession, and it reminds me of someone I love.
2 | Someone stole my precious trophy, and someday I'll get it back.
3 | I want to be famous, whatever it takes.
4 | I idolize a hero of the old tales and measure my deeds against that person's.
5 | I will do anything to prove myself superior to my hated rival.
6 | I would do anything for the other members of my old troupe.

Flaw:
1 | I'll do anything to win fame and renown.
2 | I'm a sucker for a pretty face.
3 | A scandal prevents me from ever going home again. That kind of trouble seems to follow me around.
4 | I once satirized a noble who still wants my head. It was a mistake that I will likely repeat.
5 | I have trouble keeping my true feelings hidden. My sharp tongue lands me in trouble.
6 | Despite my best efforts, I am unreliable to my friends.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Gladiator (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, Intimidation, and Performance
Tools: One type of musical instrument
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A trophy earned via some sort of competition, clothing suitable to your profession, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: A Champion Well Known</name>
      <text>You can always find a place to perform, usually in an inn or tavern but possibly with a circus, at a theater, or even in a noble's court. At such a place, you receive free lodging and food of a modest or comfortable standard (depending on the quality of the establishment), as long as you perform each night. In addition, your performance makes you something of a local figure. When strangers recognize you in a town where you have performed, they typically take a liking to you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Acrobat
2 | Brawny
3 | Threatening
4 | Performer
5 | Entertainer
6 | Linguist
7 | Athlete
8 | Durable</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Successful entertainers have to be able to capture and hold an audience's attention, so they tend to have flamboyant or forceful personalities. They're inclined toward the romantic and often cling to high-minded ideals about the practice of art and the appreciation of beauty.

Personality:
1 | I know a story relevant to almost every situation.
2 | Whenever I come to a new place, I collect local rumors and spread gossip.
3 | I'm a hopeless romantic, always searching for that —special someone.—
4 | Nobody stays angry at me or around me for long, since I can defuse any amount of tension.
5 | I love a good insult, even one directed at me.
6 | I get bitter if I'm not the center of attention.
7 | I'll settle for nothing less than perfection.
8 | I change my mood or my mind as quickly as I change key in a song.

Ideals:
1 | Beauty. When I perform, I make the world better than it was. (Light)
2 | Tradition. The stories, legends, and songs of the past must never be forgotten, for they teach us who we are. (Lawful)
3 | Creativity. The world is in need of new ideas and bold action. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money and fame. (Dark)
5 | People. I like seeing the smiles on people's faces when I perform. That's all that matters. (Neutral)
6 | Honesty. Art should reflect the soul; it should come from within and reveal who we really are. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My instrument is my most treasured possession, and it reminds me of someone I love.
2 | Someone stole my precious trophy, and someday I'll get it back.
3 | I want to be famous, whatever it takes.
4 | I idolize a hero of the old tales and measure my deeds against that person's.
5 | I will do anything to prove myself superior to my hated rival.
6 | I would do anything for the other members of my old troupe.

Flaw:
1 | I'll do anything to win fame and renown.
2 | I'm a sucker for a pretty face.
3 | A scandal prevents me from ever going home again. That kind of trouble seems to follow me around.
4 | I once satirized a noble who still wants my head. It was a mistake that I will likely repeat.
5 | I have trouble keeping my true feelings hidden. My sharp tongue lands me in trouble.
6 | Despite my best efforts, I am unreliable to my friends.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Guild Adventurer (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Investigation, Nature, and Survival
Tools: Your choice demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: 50 feet of rope, a small knife, a trophy, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Adventuring Origin</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Guild Membership</name>
      <text>You are an established and respected member of an adventurer's guild, allowing you to rely on certain benefits that membership provides. If you are in a town with a headquarters for your adventurer's guild and you are in good standing with the guild, you will be allowed to look at the job postings and find adventuring work to earn money. 

Guilds often wield tremendous political power. If you are accused of a crime, your guild will support you if a good case can be made for your innocence or the crime is justifiable. You can also gain access to powerful political figures through the guild, if you are a member in good standing. You must pay dues of 50 cr per month to the guild. Your dues must be current to remain in the guild's good graces.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Investigator
3 | Naturalist
4 | Survivalist
5 | Demolitionist
6 | Bypasser
7 | Slicer
8 | Linguist</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Adventurers are well adjusted to life on the road. They are often comfortable doing dangerous things like dungeoneering and fighting and can stay level-headed in the face of danger, but they may not be so well adapted to other parts of life.

Personality:
1 | I can't bring myself to ignore a cry for help.
2 | I hold onto every mildly interesting item I find, in case it comes in handy someday.
3 | After all the weirdness I've seen on my travels, nothing can surprise me.
4 | I spit and laugh in the face of danger.
5 | Giving up is never an option for me.
6 | I feel more at home in monster-infested dungeons than in civilized society.
7 | I fill silence with wacky stories about my past misadventures, which may or may not be exaggerated.
8 | My sense of humor is as dark and grim as the dungeons I explore.

Ideals:
1 | Adventure. All I want is to travel the world and see amazing things. (Any)
2 | Heroism. I am dedicated to helping people in need. (Light)
3 | Order. I use my power to save the world from the forces of destruction and chaos. (Lawful)
4 | Excitement. An ordinary life is boring, I'd rather travel around and find trouble. (Chaotic)
5 | Power. The more powerful enemies I defeat, the stronger I become. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I want to go down in history as a brave, powerful hero. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I carry with me a strange artifact that I found in a dungeon, but I don't know what it's for.
2 | My adventuring party means the world to me.
3 | I have sworn to hunt down the monster or villain who killed my former adventuring party.
4 | I adventure in order to bring honor (or money) to my family.
5 | There is a faraway place I've always wanted to visit, and I won't stop until I make it there.
6 | All I want is to make the ones who trained me in the way of adventuring proud.

Flaw:
1 | I default to solving problems with violence even when it's unwise or immoral.
2 | I expect to be lavished with praise whenever I do my job, and I get mad when no one acknowledges me.
3 | All members of \Dark\ species must be Dark, so I will never trust them.
4 | Waiting around makes me antsy. I'd rather do something stupid than do nothing at all.
5 | My habit of looting dungeons makes me swipe things I shouldn't.
6 | A monstrous enemy I faced in the past still leaves me quivering with fear.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Guild Artisan (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Persuasion, and Technology
Tools: One type of artisan's tools, biochemist's kit, or chef's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of tools (one of your choice), a letter of introduction from your guild, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Guild Business</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Guild Membership</name>
      <text>As an established and respected member of a guild, you can rely on certain benefits that membership provides. Your fellow guild members will provide you with lodging and food if necessary, and pay for your funeral if needed. In some cities and towns, a guildhall offers a central place to meet other members of your profession, which can be a good place to meet potential patrons, allies, or hirelings.

Guilds often wield tremendous political power. If you are accused of a crime, your guild will support you if a good case can be made for your innocence or the crime is justifiable. You can also gain access to powerful political figures through the guild, if you are a member in good standing. You must pay dues of 50 cr per month to the guild. Your dues must be current to remain in the guild's good graces.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Empathic
3 | Charming Persona
4 | Techie
5 | Crafter
6 | Linguist
7 | Biochemist
8 | Gourmand</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Guild artisans are among the most ordinary people in the world—until they set down their tools and take up an adventuring career. They understand the value of hard work and the importance of community, but they're vulnerable to sins of greed and covetousness.

Personality:
1 | I believe that anything worth doing is worth doing right. I can't help it— I'm a perfectionist.
2 | I'm a snob who looks down on those who can't appreciate fine art.
3 | I always want to know how things work and what makes people tick.
4 | I'm full of witty aphorisms and have a proverb for every occasion.
5 | I'm rude to people who lack my commitment to hard work and fair play.
6 | I like to talk at length about my profession.
7 | I don't part with my money easily and will haggle tirelessly to get the best deal possible.
8 | I believe I'm well known for my work, and I'm always taken aback when people haven't heard of me.

Ideals:
1 | Community. It is the duty of all civilized people to strengthen the bonds of community and the security of civilization. (Lawful)
2 | Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Light)
3 | Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)

Bond:
1 | The workshop where I learned my trade is the most important place in the world to me.
2 | I created a great work for someone, and then found them unworthy of it; I now search for someone worthy.
3 | I owe my guild a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.
4 | I pursue wealth to secure someone's love.
5 | One day I will return to my guild and prove that I am the greatest artisan of them all.
6 | I will get revenge on the Dark forces that destroyed my place of business and ruined my livelihood.

Flaw:
1 | I'll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.
2 | I'm quick to assume that someone is trying to cheat me.
3 | No one must ever learn that I once stole money from guild coffers.
4 | I'm never satisfied with what I have— I always want more.
5 | I would kill to acquire a noble title.
6 | I'm horribly jealous of anyone who can outshine my handiwork. Everywhere I go, I'm surrounded by rivals.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Guild Merchant (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Performance, and Persuasion
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: A letter of introduction from your guild, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Guild Business</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Guild Membership</name>
      <text>As an established and respected member of a guild, you can rely on certain benefits that membership provides. Your fellow guild members will provide you with lodging and food if necessary, and pay for your funeral if needed. In some cities and towns, a guildhall offers a central place to meet other members of your profession, which can be a good place to meet potential patrons, allies, or hirelings.

Guilds often wield tremendous political power. If you are accused of a crime, your guild will support you if a good case can be made for your innocence or the crime is justifiable. You can also gain access to powerful political figures through the guild, if you are a member in good standing. You must pay dues of 50 cr per month to the guild. Your dues must be current to remain in the guild's good graces.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Performer
4 | Charming Persona
5 | Linguist
6 | Inspiring Leader
7 | Gourmand
8 | Practiced</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Guild merchants are among the most ordinary people in the world—until they abscond to take up an adventuring career. They understand the value of hard work and the importance of community, but they're vulnerable to sins of greed and covetousness.

Personality:
1 | I believe that anything worth doing is worth doing right. I can't help it— I'm a perfectionist.
2 | I'm a snob who looks down on those who can't appreciate fine art.
3 | I always want to know how things work and what makes people tick.
4 | I'm full of witty aphorisms and have a proverb for every occasion.
5 | I'm rude to people who lack my commitment to hard work and fair play.
6 | I like to talk at length about my profession.
7 | I don't part with my money easily and will haggle tirelessly to get the best deal possible.
8 | I believe I'm well known for my work, and I'm always taken aback when people haven't heard of me.

Ideals:
1 | Community. It is the duty of all civilized people to strengthen the bonds of community and the security of civilization. (Lawful)
2 | Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Light)
3 | Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)
4 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)

Bond:
1 | The workshop where I learned my trade is the most important place in the world to me.
2 | I commissioned a great work for someone unworthy of it; I now search for someone worthy.
3 | I owe my guild a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.
4 | I pursue wealth to secure someone's love.
5 | One day I will return to my guild and prove that I am the greatest artisan of them all.
6 | I will get revenge on the Dark forces that destroyed my place of business and ruined my livelihood.

Flaw:
1 | I'll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.
2 | I'm quick to assume that someone is trying to cheat me.
3 | No one must ever learn that I once stole money from guild coffers.
4 | I'm never satisfied with what I have— I always want more.
5 | I would kill to acquire a noble title.
6 | I'm horribly jealous of anyone who can outshine my handiwork. Everywhere I go, I'm surrounded by rivals.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Hermit (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Lore, Medicine, and Nature
Tools: Herbalism kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A diary of your experiences, a winter blanket, a set of common clothes, an herbalism kit, and 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Life of Seclusion</name>
      <text>I was partaking of communal living in accordance with the dictates of a religious order.
I retreated from society after a life-altering event.
I needed a quiet place to work on my art, literature, music, or manifesto.
I needed to commune with nature, far from civilization.
I was the caretaker of an ancient ruin or relic.
I was in search of a place of spiritual significance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Discovery</name>
      <text>The seclusion of your hermitage gave you access to a unique and powerful discovery. The nature of this revelation depends on the nature of your seclusion. You might have discoved a great truth about the cosmos or the Force, a fact that has long been forgotten, a relic of the past that could rewrite history, or a place unseen for ages. It might be information that would be damaging to the people who or consigned you to exile, and hence the reason for your return to society. Work with your GM to determine the details of your discovery and its impact on the campaign.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Loremaster
3 | Medic
4 | Naturalist
5 | Herbalist
6 | Alert
7 | Dungeon Delver
8 | Healer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Some hermits are well suited to a life of seclusion, whereas others chafe against it and long for company. Whether they embrace solitude or long to escape it, the solitary life shapes their attitudes and ideals. Some few are driven slightly mad by their isolation.

Personality:
1 | I've been isolated for so long that I rarely speak, preferring gestures and the occasional grunt.
2 | I am utterly serene, even in the face of disaster.
3 | The leader of my community had something wise to say on every topic, and I am eager to share that wisdom.
4 | I feel tremendous empathy for all who suffer.
5 | I'm oblivious to etiquette and social expectations.
6 | I connect everything that happens to me to a grand, cosmic plan.
7 | I often get lost in my own thoughts and contemplation, becoming oblivious to my surroundings.
8 | I am working on a grand philosophical theory and love sharing my ideas.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. My gifts are meant to be shared with all, not used for my own benefit. (Light)
2 | Logic. Emotions must not cloud our sense of what is right and true, or our logical thinking. (Lawful)
3 | Free Thinking. Inquiry and curiosity are the pillars of progress. (Chaotic)
4 | Power. Solitude and contemplation are paths toward mystical power. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Meddling in the affairs of others only causes trouble. (Neutral)
6 | Self-Knowledge. If you know yourself, there's nothing left to know. (Any)

Bond:
1 | Nothing is more important than the other members of my hermitage, order, or association.
2 | I entered seclusion to hide from the ones who might still be hunting me. I must someday confront them.
3 | I'm still seeking the enlightenment I pursued in my seclusion, and it still eludes me.
4 | I entered seclusion because I loved someone I could not have.
5 | Should my discovery come to light, it could bring ruin to the world.
6 | My isolation gave me great insight into a great Dark that only I can destroy.

Flaw:
1 | Now that I've returned to the world, I enjoy its delights a little too much.
2 | I harbor dark, bloodthirsty thoughts that my isolation and meditation failed to quell.
3 | I am dogmatic in my thoughts and philosophy.
4 | I let my need to win arguments overshadow friendships and harmony.
5 | I'd risk too much to uncover a lost bit of knowledge.
6 | I like keeping secrets and won't share them with anyone.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Hermit (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Lore, Medicine, and Nature
Tools: Herbalism kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A diary of your experiences, a winter blanket, a set of common clothes, an herbalism kit, and 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Life of Seclusion</name>
      <text>I was partaking of communal living in accordance with the dictates of a religious order.
I retreated from society after a life-altering event.
I needed a quiet place to work on my art, literature, music, or manifesto.
I needed to commune with nature, far from civilization.
I was the caretaker of an ancient ruin or relic.
I was in search of a place of spiritual significance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Discovery</name>
      <text>The seclusion of your hermitage gave you access to a unique and powerful discovery. The nature of this revelation depends on the nature of your seclusion. You might have discoved a great truth about the cosmos or the Force, a fact that has long been forgotten, a relic of the past that could rewrite history, or a place unseen for ages. It might be information that would be damaging to the people who or consigned you to exile, and hence the reason for your return to society. Work with your GM to determine the details of your discovery and its impact on the campaign.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Loremaster
3 | Medic
4 | Naturalist
5 | Specialist
6 | Alert
7 | Dungeon Delver
8 | Healer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Some hermits are well suited to a life of seclusion, whereas others chafe against it and long for company. Whether they embrace solitude or long to escape it, the solitary life shapes their attitudes and ideals. Some few are driven slightly mad by their isolation.

Personality:
1 | I've been isolated for so long that I rarely speak, preferring gestures and the occasional grunt.
2 | I am utterly serene, even in the face of disaster.
3 | The leader of my community had something wise to say on every topic, and I am eager to share that wisdom.
4 | I feel tremendous empathy for all who suffer.
5 | I'm oblivious to etiquette and social expectations.
6 | I connect everything that happens to me to a grand, cosmic plan.
7 | I often get lost in my own thoughts and contemplation, becoming oblivious to my surroundings.
8 | I am working on a grand philosophical theory and love sharing my ideas.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. My gifts are meant to be shared with all, not used for my own benefit. (Light)
2 | Logic. Emotions must not cloud our sense of what is right and true, or our logical thinking. (Lawful)
3 | Free Thinking. Inquiry and curiosity are the pillars of progress. (Chaotic)
4 | Power. Solitude and contemplation are paths toward mystical power. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Meddling in the affairs of others only causes trouble. (Neutral)
6 | Self-Knowledge. If you know yourself, there's nothing left to know. (Any)

Bond:
1 | Nothing is more important than the other members of my hermitage, order, or association.
2 | I entered seclusion to hide from the ones who might still be hunting me. I must someday confront them.
3 | I'm still seeking the enlightenment I pursued in my seclusion, and it still eludes me.
4 | I entered seclusion because I loved someone I could not have.
5 | Should my discovery come to light, it could bring ruin to the world.
6 | My isolation gave me great insight into a great Dark that only I can destroy.

Flaw:
1 | Now that I've returned to the world, I enjoy its delights a little too much.
2 | I harbor dark, bloodthirsty thoughts that my isolation and meditation failed to quell.
3 | I am dogmatic in my thoughts and philosophy.
4 | I let my need to win arguments overshadow friendships and harmony.
5 | I'd risk too much to uncover a lost bit of knowledge.
6 | I like keeping secrets and won't share them with anyone.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Holonet Technician (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Holonet Technician Proficiencies</name>
      <text>You worked to keep the holonet up and running, whether being employed directly by an institution or indirectly by people across the galaxy. Your work has allowed you to uncover secrets most would never know existed.

Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Stealth, and Technology
Tool Proficiencies: Choose two from Mechanic's Kit, Security Kit, and Slicer's Kit
Equipment: A set of common clothes, an old transceiver antennae, two tools of your choice, and a belt pouch containing 50 cr

d8 | Employment Type
1 | Inter-world Government
2 | Inter-world Corporation
3 | World Government
4 | Crime Syndicate
5 | Independent Contractor
6 | Broadcasting Service
7 | Small Corporation
8 | Darknet Broadcasting

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Holonet Access</name>
      <text>You have the codes to a distributor station which gives you access to all information sent through it. This information comes in the form of useful (and sometimes sensitive) information on a topic you choose each day to tune into; this information isn't always reliable or interesting. Regardless of the quality of the information, it's relevance most likely pertains to your locale.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Stealthy
4 | Techie
5 | Specialist
6 | Keen Mind
7 | Practiced
8 | Tech Dabbler</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Characteristics</name>
      <text>Holonets technicians vary from boring officer worker to criminal information broker.

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | I watch and record people secretly then review it later.
2 | I talk like I'm on a game show or am a holonet broadcaster at all times.
3 | I prefer to be left to my own devices.
4 | I like to record people dying and upload it to the holonet.
5 | There's no such thing as 'real news'.
6 | Information is a weapon that I've mastered.
7 | I am always interested in learning new things.
8 | I prefer interacting indirectly.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Duty. It is my duty to keep all people in contact so that everything will continue working as intended. (Lawful)
2 | Autonomy. Information is meant to confuse and overwhelm. I choose to control my own mind by controlling what information I have access to. (Chaotic)
3 | Happiness. The more hope and joy I spread, the more laughs I bring; that is why I do what I do. (Light)
4 | Popularity. I want to become the most renown being in all the galaxy, and I'll destroy the competition. (Dark)
5 | Knowledge. I don't care who's ideology is right, I care who's ideology will let me learn and document information. (Neutral)
6 | Self-Fulfillment. I'm just here for the fun of it, no matter what happens it'll make a great story one day. (Any)

d6 | Bond
1 | I will do anything to free people from censorship.
2 | I can't let anyone know I work for a crime lord.
3 | I see truth in an ideology, and I must spread that ideal to all.
4 | I got a man killed by giving him a platform to speak, I can't let that happen again.
5 | I'm on the run from a government organization that I spread propaganda against and who's propaganda I destroy.
6 | I have a famous person's private logs, and I don't know what to do with them.

d6 | Flaw
1 | I tend to think any broadcaster is a fraud immediately unless they prove otherwise.
2 | I tend to repeat the same mistake unless it is pointed out to me.
3 | I will ramble endlessly about a random holonet broadcast that I saw which I think was the best ever.
4 | I think everyone who works a normal job is a drone without the ability to think freely.
5 | I describe everything using references to obscure holonet recordings.
6 | I've become completely desensitized to violence and graphic imagery, to the point where I laugh in an off putting way whenever I see it.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Investigator (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Perception, and Survival
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: A uniform in the style of your unit and indicative of your rank, a horn with which to summon help, a set of binders, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Watcher's Eye</name>
      <text>Your experience in enforcing the law, and dealing with lawbreakers, gives you a feel for local laws and criminals. You can easily find the local outpost of the watch or a similar organization, and just as easily pick out the dens of criminal activity in a community, although you're more likely to be welcome in the former locations rather than the latter.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Perceptive
4 | Survivalist
5 | Linguist
6 | Alert
7 | Observant
8 | Keen Mind</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Years of service in the City Watch have led to the rigid discipline most often seen in military service. Working with your comrades has created a strong family bond and pride in your community.

Personality:
1 | I'm always polite and respectful.
2 | I'm haunted by memories of war. I can't get the images of violence out of my mind.
3 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
4 | I'm full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my guard service relevant to almost every combat situation.
5 | I can stare down a hell hound without flinching.
6 | I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.
7 | I have a crude sense of humor.
8 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Light)
2 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
3 | Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)
6 | Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would still lay down my life for the people I served with.
2 | Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | My honor is my life.
4 | I'll never forget the crushing defeat my company suffered or the enemies who dealt it.
5 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
6 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.

Flaw:
1 | The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.
2 | I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven warrior.
3 | I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives— and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.
4 | My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.
5 | I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.
6 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Investigator (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Perception, and Survival
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: A uniform in the style of your unit and indicative of your rank, a horn with which to summon help, a set of binders, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Watcher's Eye</name>
      <text>Your experience in enforcing the law, and dealing with lawbreakers, gives you a feel for local laws and criminals. You can easily find the local outpost of the watch or a similar organization, and just as easily pick out the dens of criminal activity in a community, although you're more likely to be welcome in the former locations rather than the latter.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Perceptive
4 | Survivalist
5 | Linguist
6 | Alert
7 | Observant
8 | Keen Mind</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Years of service in the City Watch have led to the rigid discipline most often seen in military service. Working with your comrades has created a strong family bond and pride in your community.

Personality:
1 | I'm always polite and respectful.
2 | I'm haunted by memories of war. I can't get the images of violence out of my mind.
3 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
4 | I'm full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my guard service relevant to almost every combat situation.
5 | I can stare down a hell hound without flinching.
6 | I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.
7 | I have a crude sense of humor.
8 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Light)
2 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
3 | Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)
6 | Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would still lay down my life for the people I served with.
2 | Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | My honor is my life.
4 | I'll never forget the crushing defeat my company suffered or the enemies who dealt it.
5 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
6 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.

Flaw:
1 | The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.
2 | I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven warrior.
3 | I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives— and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.
4 | My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.
5 | I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.
6 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Jedi (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Lore, and Persuasion
Tools: Artificer's tools
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A copy of the Jedi code, a set of common clothes including a robe, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Shelter of the Faithful</name>
      <text>As a Jedi, you command the respect of those who are loyal to the Jedi Order. You and your adventuring companions can expect to receive free healing and care at any Jedi temple, and those who support your religion will support you (but only you) at a modest lifestyle.

You might also have ties to a specific Jedi temple and have a residence there. This could be the temple where you trained, or a temple where you have found a new home. While near your temple, you can call upon the Jedi for assistance, provided the assistance you ask for is not hazardous and you remain in good standing with your temple.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Loremaster
4 | Charming Persona
5 | Linguist
6 | Crafter
7 | Healer
8 | Force Sensitive</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Jedi are shaped by their experience in their temple. Their study of the history and tenets of the Jedi Order and their relationships to temples, shrines, or hierarchies affect their mannerisms and ideals. Their flaws might be some hidden hypocrisy or heretical idea, or an ideal or bond taken to an extreme.

Personality:
1 | I idolize a particular Jedi, and constantly refer to that person's deeds and example.
2 | I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, empathizing with them and always working towards peace.
3 | I see omens in every event and action. The Force tries to speak to us, we just need to listen
4 | Nothing can shake my optimistic attitude.
5 | I quote (or misquote) sacred Jedi texts and proverbs in almost every situation.
6 | I am tolerant (or intolerant) of those who don't support the Jedi.
7 | I've enjoyed fine food, drink, and high society. Rough living grates on me.
8 | I've spent so long in the Jedi temple that I have little practical experience dealing with people in the  world.

Ideals:
1 | Tradition. The ancient traditions of worship and sacrifice must be preserved and upheld. (Lawful)
2 | Charity. I always try to help those in need, no matter what the personal cost. (Light)
3 | Change. We must help bring about the changes the Force is constantly working in the world. (Chaotic)
4 | Power. I hope to one day rise to the rank of Jedi Master. (Lawful)
5 | Faith. I trust that the Force will guide my actions; I have faith that if I work hard, things will go well. (Lawful)
6 | Aspiration. I seek to prove myself worthy of the Force by matching my actions against the Jedi teachings. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would die to recover an ancient Jedi relic that was lost long ago.
2 | I will someday get revenge on those who razed my temple.
3 | I owe my life to the Jedi who took me in when my parents died.
4 | Everything I do is for the common people.
5 | I will do anything to protect the temple where I served.
6 | I seek to preserve a sacred text that my enemies seek to destroy.

Flaw:
1 | I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.
2 | I put too much trust in those who wield power within my temple's hierarchy.
3 | My piety sometimes leads me to blindly trust those that profess faith in the Force.
4 | I am inflexible in my thinking.
5 | I am suspicious of strangers and expect the worst of them.
6 | Once I pick a goal, I become obsessed with it to the detriment of everything else in my life.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Jensaarai (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Intimidation, Lore, and Perception
Tools: Armormech's Tools
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes including a robe, a sturdy knife, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Depths of Duality</name>
      <text>Due to the corruption of the Jedi training done to the pre-Jensaarai, you have a unique insight into both the Light and Dark side of the Force, as well as its history, applications, and techniques in a scholarly manner.

You fully understand concepts, and can recall key information, The exception being if the research was hidden from the public and you have not had experience working with, in which you may only partially understand. You also recognize well-known Jedi Masters and Sith Lords by their works and marks.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Threatening
3 | Loremaster
4 | Perceptive
5 | Crafter
6 | Linguist
7 | Alert
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Jensaarai are shaped by the unique capacity of their upbringing. Their study of the duality of the Force manifests in their mannerisms and ideals. Their bond might be their family or their armor. Their flaws might be some a hatred of the Jedi or Sith or a desire to become one or the other.

Personality:
1 | I ignore the rhetoric a person spouts when meeting them, preferring to judge them by action.
2 | I'm the first to swing a punch, but the last to draw a weapon.
3 | Danger is my middle name.
4 | Goodwill is in short supply in the galaxy, and I always try to foster a little more wherever I go.
5 | Both the Republic and the Empire have tried to crush us under their bootheels. I refuse to yield.
6 | Defiant to the last isn't good enough. Upon death I will become a force spirit and continue to defy my killer.
7 | Well-behaved people rarely make history.
8 | What gave you the idea that I was going to give you a fair fight?

Ideals:
1 | Respect. Respect will be shown to everyone, disrespect will be shown to those who earn it. (Lawful)
2 | Freedom. People should be free to make their own way without interference. (Chaotic)
3 | Growth. Self-improvement is an unending chore, but one that must be done. (Any)
4 | Escalation. I will immediately end a hostile situation with all means at my disposal. (Neutral)
5 | Power. Given our luck with both Jedi and Sith, I need all I can get. (Dark)
6 | Redemption. There's a spark of good in everyone. (Light)

Bond:
1 | The Jensaarai took me in when nobody else would. I back the order 100%.
2 | I was once a Jedi, but grew disillusioned by their inactivity.
3 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.
4 | I lost my mentor in battle. I will honor their sacrifice by destroying their killer.
5 | I was able to slough off Dark Side corruption, but I couldn't avoid making amends.
6 | The powerful use their strength to raise people up, not keep them down.

Flaw:
1 | I might be a little too enamored with force choking my enemies.
2 | I am my own worst critic, in everything I do.
3 | My armor is precision crafted and has served me faithfully. I never give up a chance to prove how well.
4 | I have a collection of lightsabers from fallen foes, and I love adding to it.
5 | The Jedi and Sith worship the Force as a religion. I do everything I can to remind them they're just worshipping a hammer.
6 | The minute you tell me that someone should not be crossed, I'm already crossing them.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Jensaarai (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Intimidation, Lore, and Perception
Tools: Armormech's Tools
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes including a robe, a sturdy knife, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Depths of Duality</name>
      <text>Due to the corruption of the Jedi training done to the pre-Jensaarai, you have a unique insight into both the Light and Dark side of the Force, as well as its history, applications, and techniques in a scholarly manner.

You fully understand concepts, and can recall key information, The exception being if the research was hidden from the public and you have not had experience working with, in which you may only partially understand. You also recognize well-known Jedi Masters and Sith Lords by their works and marks.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Threatening
3 | Loremaster
4 | Perceptive
5 | Crafter
6 | Linguist
7 | Alert
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Jensaarai are shaped by the unique capacity of their upbringing. Their study of the duality of the Force manifests in their mannerisms and ideals. Their bond might be their family or their armor. Their flaws might be some a hatred of the Jedi or Sith or a desire to become one or the other.

Personality:
1 | I ignore the rhetoric a person spouts when meeting them, preferring to judge them by action.
2 | I'm the first to swing a punch, but the last to draw a weapon.
3 | Danger is my middle name.
4 | Goodwill is in short supply in the galaxy, and I always try to foster a little more wherever I go.
5 | Both the Republic and the Empire have tried to crush us under their bootheels. I refuse to yield.
6 | Defiant to the last isn't good enough. Upon death I will become a force spirit and continue to defy my killer.
7 | Well-behaved people rarely make history.
8 | What gave you the idea that I was going to give you a fair fight?

Ideals:
1 | Respect. Respect will be shown to everyone, disrespect will be shown to those who earn it. (Lawful)
2 | Freedom. People should be free to make their own way without interference. (Chaotic)
3 | Growth. Self-improvement is an unending chore, but one that must be done. (Any)
4 | Escalation. I will immediately end a hostile situation with all means at my disposal. (Neutral)
5 | Power. Given our luck with both Jedi and Sith, I need all I can get. (Dark)
6 | Redemption. There's a spark of good in everyone. (Light)

Bond:
1 | The Jensaarai took me in when nobody else would. I back the order 100%.
2 | I was once a Jedi, but grew disillusioned by their inactivity.
3 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.
4 | I lost my mentor in battle. I will honor their sacrifice by destroying their killer.
5 | I was able to slough off Dark Side corruption, but I couldn't avoid making amends.
6 | The powerful use their strength to raise people up, not keep them down.

Flaw:
1 | I might be a little too enamored with force choking my enemies.
2 | I am my own worst critic, in everything I do.
3 | My armor is precision crafted and has served me faithfully. I never give up a chance to prove how well.
4 | I have a collection of lightsabers from fallen foes, and I love adding to it.
5 | The Jedi and Sith worship the Force as a religion. I do everything I can to remind them they're just worshipping a hammer.
6 | The minute you tell me that someone should not be crossed, I'm already crossing them.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Laborer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Laborer Proficiencies</name>
      <text>You are an experienced laborer and come from a humble social rank. You work with your hands, and anything worth doing is worth doing well. Your life is full of hard work and too little respect for your efforts, but you share a deep camaraderie with your fellow workers.

Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Survival, and Technology
Tool Proficiencies: One type of gaming set and one set of artisan's implements
Equipment: A set of common clothes, a sturdy knife, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Laborer Specialty</name>
      <text>1 | Construction
2 | Droid Repair
3 | Electrician
4 | Facilities Maintenance
5 | Logistics/Shipping
6 | Manufacturing
7 | Mechanic
8 | Plumbing/HVAC</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Working Class</name>
      <text>You have a contact that acts as your liaison to a union or faction. You know how to reach your contact at all times. Your contact can provide you with the means to requisition equipment used in manufacturing or shipping.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Brawny
3 | Survivalist
4 | Techie
5 | Entertainer
6 | Crafter
7 | Athlete
8 | Durable</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Lawyer (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Performance, and Persuasion
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: Documentation of your station, a book of law, a formal uniform you wear to court, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Legal Authority</name>
      <text>You are familiar with the letter of the law and workings of courts, at least on the planet that you were a judge in. If you are in a foreign place where you are not familiar with their exact laws, you often will be able to track down the resources you need to learn them. 

If you or your party gets into legal trouble, your experience may help you get out of it. If you can prove your credentials, you might be able to represent your party in a court of law without admonishment. You may know of legal loopholes that will help your case. If you are in the region where you originally worked, you might have past connections with many legal professionals there.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Performer
4 | Charming Persona
5 | Linguist
6 | Actor
7 | Observant
8 | Keen Mind</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A lawyer's career is centered on issues of right, wrong, and punishment, so they will approach adventuring through a similar lens. They are used to being respected and in control, leading many of them to struggle with wild, Any situations.

Personality:
1 | I quote the law like a religious fanatic quotes scripture.
2 | I bang my weapon like a gavel whenever I want a rowdy group's attention.
3 | I remain impartial when making decisions, even when I should have biases and loyalties.
4 | Evidence is necessary to back up any claim.
5 | I insist on settling all party disagreements through fake court proceedings.
6 | I have to hear all sides of a story, but I secretly hate listening to people whine about how unfairly they're treated.
7 | I am happy to make sacrifices for the sake of fairness.
8 | I will not attack a person unless someone can prove they are doing something wrong.

Ideals:
1 | Law. I will follow the letter of the law always, no matter what I believe. (Lawful)
2 | Justice. My duty is to fight for the disenfranchised underdog. (Light)
3 | Reform. Laws can be corrupt, and I strive to free people from the bad ones. (Chaotic)
4 | Punishment. I will punish all those who have committed great Darks. (Lawful)
5 | Control. I enforce the law only where it benefits myself. (Dark)
6 | Stability. The purpose of the law is to keep civilization from collapsing. That spirit of that goal is more important than the letter of the law. (Neutral)

Bond:
1 | A dangerous criminal is on the loose, and I plan to hunt them down.
2 | All those who strive to uphold the law are my allies.
3 | I have sentenced an innocent man to a horrible punishment, and the guilt still haunts me.
4 | There is an ethical cause that I would give my life for.
5 | I dream of memorizing the laws of every civilization.
6 | I am enamored with the legal system of my own culture, and want to spread its tenets everywhere.

Flaw:
1 | Mercy is a foreign concept to me.
2 | I am unwilling to admit when I am wrong.
3 | I become unreasonably enraged at even the slightest injustice.
4 | I expect others to adhere to the law, but I act like i am above it.
5 | If there isn't a law in the books to handle a moral dilemma, I can't make a decision.
6 | The punishments I deal are cruel and unusual.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Lawyer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Performance, and Persuasion
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: Documentation of your station, a book of law, a formal uniform you wear to court, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Legal Authority</name>
      <text>You are familiar with the letter of the law and workings of courts, at least on the planet that you were a judge in. If you are in a foreign place where you are not familiar with their exact laws, you often will be able to track down the resources you need to learn them. 

If you or your party gets into legal trouble, your experience may help you get out of it. If you can prove your credentials, you might be able to represent your party in a court of law without admonishment. You may know of legal loopholes that will help your case. If you are in the region where you originally worked, you might have past connections with many legal professionals there.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Performer
4 | Charmer
5 | Linguist
6 | Actor
7 | Observant
8 | Keen Mind</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A lawyer's career is centered on issues of right, wrong, and punishment, so they will approach adventuring through a similar lens. They are used to being respected and in control, leading many of them to struggle with wild, Any situations.

Personality:
1 | I quote the law like a religious fanatic quotes scripture.
2 | I bang my weapon like a gavel whenever I want a rowdy group's attention.
3 | I remain impartial when making decisions, even when I should have biases and loyalties.
4 | Evidence is necessary to back up any claim.
5 | I insist on settling all party disagreements through fake court proceedings.
6 | I have to hear all sides of a story, but I secretly hate listening to people whine about how unfairly they're treated.
7 | I am happy to make sacrifices for the sake of fairness.
8 | I will not attack a person unless someone can prove they are doing something wrong.

Ideals:
1 | Law. I will follow the letter of the law always, no matter what I believe. (Lawful)
2 | Justice. My duty is to fight for the disenfranchised underdog. (Light)
3 | Reform. Laws can be corrupt, and I strive to free people from the bad ones. (Chaotic)
4 | Punishment. I will punish all those who have committed great Darks. (Lawful)
5 | Control. I enforce the law only where it benefits myself. (Dark)
6 | Stability. The purpose of the law is to keep civilization from collapsing. That spirit of that goal is more important than the letter of the law. (Neutral)

Bond:
1 | A dangerous criminal is on the loose, and I plan to hunt them down.
2 | All those who strive to uphold the law are my allies.
3 | I have sentenced an innocent man to a horrible punishment, and the guilt still haunts me.
4 | There is an ethical cause that I would give my life for.
5 | I dream of memorizing the laws of every civilization.
6 | I am enamored with the legal system of my own culture, and want to spread its tenets everywhere.

Flaw:
1 | Mercy is a foreign concept to me.
2 | I am unwilling to admit when I am wrong.
3 | I become unreasonably enraged at even the slightest injustice.
4 | I expect others to adhere to the law, but I act like i am above it.
5 | If there isn't a law in the books to handle a moral dilemma, I can't make a decision.
6 | The punishments I deal are cruel and unusual.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Mandalorian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Intimidation, Piloting, and Survival
Tools: -
Language: Mando'a and one of your choice
Equipment: A set of traveler's clothes, a trophy from a previous victory, and a pouch containing 200 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Mandalorian Clan</name>
      <text>Vizsla
Fett
Kryze
Ordo
Wren
Lok
Cadera
Clanless</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Child of Mandalore</name>
      <text>Other Mandalorians know, and will look out for you. If you're ever in need of a place to stay, or a meal to eat, other Mandalorians  will help you as long as your clans aren't feuding. This could be in the form of shelters, meals, even healing. If the Mandalorians are of your clan or a clan friendly to you, they may be willing to help you even at cost to themselves.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Athlete
2 | Threatening
3 | Ace Pilot
4 | Survivalist
5 | Durable
6 | Weapon Expert
7 | Brawny
8 | Fanatic</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Mandalorians are a meritocracy where birthplace, rank, status, and citizenship mean nothing. You are what you do. Mandalorians live by the Resol'nare (the Six Actions). As a true Mandalorian you should strive to live by this code as much as possible by remaining honorable. Your flaw (s) might consist of any dishonor you've committed, or even being too honorable.

Personality:
1 | I try and bring my culture to outsiders.
2 | I always put my clan first.
3 | I follow the Resol'nare to the letter.
4 | I love a good spar.
5 | I enjoy traveling the galaxy.
6 | I keep a small trophy on me to remind me of a past victory.
7 | I view the force as dishonorable in combat.
8 | I've seen the horrors of battle and try to prevent it.

Ideals:
1 | Tradition. I live by my clan's ways, and will continue to do so. (Lawful)
2 | Power. I strive to be the best warrior, no matter who stands in my way. (Dark)
3 | Respect. I have earned the respect of many, and I intend to keep it. (Light)
4 | Freedom. I enjoy having the ability to do whatever I want. (Chaotic)
5 | Comradery. I'll put everything on the line for those dear to me. (Any)
6 | Aspiration. I'll succeed in my goals, it just takes time and effort. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I lost someone dear to me in battle, I will always honor them.
2 | Honor is everything to me.
3 | I will lay down my life for those beside me.
4 | I must keep the traditions of my ancestors alive.
5 | No matter where I go, Mandalore is my home.
6 | In death, I will find glory.

Flaw:
1 | I look down on outsiders.
2 | I have no respect for anyone who flees. Cowardice is unacceptable.
3 | I don't see much use in talking, a blaster is all I need to make my point.
4 | I stick to my traditions no matter what, even at the cost of others.
5 | I retreated once, and I've regretted it ever since.
6 | I value a victory regardless of the ethics behind the victory.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Mercenary (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Investigation, Persuasion, and Piloting
Tools: One type of gaming set
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A uniform of your company (traveler's clothes in quality), an insignia of your rank, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a pouch containing the remainder of your last wages (100 cr)

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Mercenary Life</name>
      <text>You know the mercenary life as only someone who has experienced it can. You are able to identify mercenary companies by their emblems, and you know a little about any such company, including the names and reputations of its commanders and leaders, and who has hired them recently. You can find the cantinas and feasthalls where mercenaries abide in any area, as long as you speak the language, and if you spend at least an hour in such a location you can come across one of the following bits of information: a job offer, significant rumor, referal to a skilled merchant, blacksmith, etc., or a hint towards the pursuit of your current quest. Additionally, you can find mercenary work between adventures sufficient to maintain a comfortable lifestyle (see Practicing a Profession under Downtime Activities in chapter 8 of the Player's Handbook).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Investigator
3 | Charming Persona
4 | Ace Pilot
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Linguist
7 | Weapon Expert
8 | Durable</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Mercenaries are shaped by their lively nature, for the better and the worse. They tend to be driven by either their commitment to money or something more valuable.

Personality:
1 | I do not fear death, but accept it as part of life.
2 | I have a crude sense of humor.
3 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.
4 | I find it good luck to have a flask of ale on me even when the most of my other belongings are gone.
5 | I ask a lot of questions.
6 | I never pass up a friendly wager.
7 | I am always polite and respectful when speaking to those above my station.
8 | I like a job well done, especially if I'm not the one doing it.

Ideals:
1 | Greed. I'm only doing it for the money. (Dark)
2 | Fairness. We all did the work. it is only right that everyone gets a share of the reward. (Lawful)
3 | Live and Let Live. You may not have a family left, but your enemy may. A little compassion goes a long way. (Light)
4 | Measure of Last Resort. Sometimes we have to do things that we REALLY don't want to do, but we must remember that we only do them because we have to. (Chaotic)
5 | Debts. I never leave a favor left undone and nor will I leave those whom owe me favors on the hook. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I have heard a tale of a legendary person of my class. I strive to be more like them. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I have a personal debt that must be paid.
2 | I am with friends whom I trust with my life as they should trust me with theirs.
3 | I come from a family that dislikes weaknesses, so I push myself to know my weaknesses.
4 | My life is my honor. I shall, until death, shape my life to what I want it to be.
5 | Without a purpose in the world, I find myself to be broken which I do not like.
6 | I secretly pursue a love interest that is forbidden by a family whether it is my own or my love's family.

Flaw:
1 | I am always looking for the bigger pay.
2 | I can't tell a lie for the life of me.
3 | I judge too easily by special appearance and pride.
4 | I am almost always carrying some ale in with my gear.
5 | I believe that I am the only skilled person of the group and am even open about it.
6 | I will never let a comrade stand alone, even if it gets me killed.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Noble (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Lore, and Persuasion
Tools: One type of gaming set
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of fine clothes, a signet ring, a letter of pedigree, and a purse containing 250 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Position of Privilege</name>
      <text>Thanks to your noble birth, people are inclined to think the best of you. You are welcome in high society, and people assume you have the right to be wherever you are. The common folk make every effort to accommodate you and avoid your displeasure, and other people of high birth treat you as a member of the same social sphere. You can secure an audience with a local noble if you need to.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Loremaster
4 | Charming Persona
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Linguist
7 | Inspiring Leader
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Nobles are born and raised to a very different lifestyle than most people ever experience, and their personalities reflect that upbringing. A noble title comes with a plethora of bonds—responsibilities to family, to other nobles (including the sovereign), to the people entrusted to the family's care, or even to the title itself. But this responsibility is often a good way to undermine a noble.

Personality:
1 | My eloquent flattery makes everyone I talk to feel like the most wonderful and important person in the world.
2 | The common folk love me for my kindness and generosity.
3 | No one could doubt by looking at my regal bearing that I am a cut above the unwashed masses.
4 | I take great pains to always look my best and follow the latest fashions.
5 | I don't like to get my hands dirty, and I won't be caught dead in unsuitable accommodations.
6 | Despite my noble birth, I do not place myself above other folk. We all have the same blood.
7 | My favor, once lost, is lost forever.
8 | If you do me an injury, I will crush you, ruin your name, and salt your fields.

Ideals:
1 | Respect. Respect is due to me because of my position, but all people regardless of station deserve to be treated with dignity. (Light)
2 | Responsibility. It is my duty to respect the authority of those above me, just as those below me must respect mine. (Lawful)
3 | Independence. I must prove that I can handle myself without the coddling of my family. (Chaotic)
4 | Power. If I can attain more power, no one will tell me what to do. (Dark)
5 | Family. Blood runs thicker than water. (Any)
6 | Noble Obligation. It is my duty to protect and care for the people beneath me. (Light)

Bond:
1 | I will face any challenge to win the approval of my family.
2 | My house's alliance with another noble family must be sustained at all costs.
3 | Nothing is more important than the other members of my family.
4 | I am in love with the heir of a family that my family despises.
5 | My loyalty to my sovereign is unwavering.
6 | The common folk must see me as a hero of the people.

Flaw:
1 | I secretly believe that everyone is beneath me.
2 | I hide a truly scandalous secret that could ruin my family forever.
3 | I too often hear veiled insults and threats in every word addressed to me, and I'm quick to anger.
4 | I have an insatiable desire for carnal pleasures.
5 | In fact, the world does revolve around me.
6 | By my words and actions, I often bring shame to my family.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Nomad (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Medicine, and Survival
Tools: One type of musical instrument
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A walking stick, a hunting trap, a trophy from an animal you killed, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Wanderer</name>
      <text>You have an excellent memory for maps and geography, and you can always recall the general layout of terrain, settlements, and other features around you. In addition, you can find food and fresh water for yourself and up to five other people each day, provided that the land offers berries, small game, water, and so forth.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Brawny
3 | Medic
4 | Survivalist
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Linguist
7 | Gourmand
8 | Dungeon Delver</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Often considered rude and uncouth among civilized folk, nomads have little respect for the niceties of life in the cities. The ties of tribe, clan, family, and the natural world are the most important bonds to nomads.

Personality:
1 | I'm driven by a wanderlust that led me away from home.
2 | I watch over my friends as if they were a litter of newborn pups.
3 | I once ran twenty-five miles without stopping to warn to my clan of an approaching orc horde. I'd do it again if I had to.
4 | I have a lesson for every situation, drawn from observing nature.
5 | I place no stock in wealthy or well-mannered folk. Money and manners won't save you from a hungry owlbear.
6 | I'm always picking things up, absently fiddling with them, and sometimes accidentally breaking them.
7 | I feel far more comfortable around animals than people.
8 | I was, in fact, raised by wolves.

Ideals:
1 | Change. Life is like the seasons, in constant change, and we must change with it. (Chaotic)
2 | Greater Good. It is each person's responsibility to make the most happiness for the whole tribe. (Light)
3 | Honor. If I dishonor myself, I dishonor my whole clan. (Lawful)
4 | Might. The strongest are meant to rule. (Dark)
5 | Nature. The natural world is more important than all the constructs of civilization. (Neutral)
6 | Glory. I must earn glory in battle, for myself and my clan. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My family, clan, or tribe is the most important thing in my life, even when they are far from me.
2 | An injury to the unspoiled wilderness of my home is an injury to me.
3 | I will bring terrible wrath down on the Darkdoers who destroyed my homeland.
4 | I am the last of my tribe, and it is up to me to ensure their names enter legend.
5 | I suffer awful visions of a coming disaster and will do anything to prevent it.
6 | It is my duty to provide children to sustain my tribe.

Flaw:
1 | I am too enamored of ale, wine, and other intoxicants.
2 | There's no room for caution in a life lived to the fullest.
3 | I remember every insult I've received and nurse a silent resentment toward anyone who's ever wronged me.
4 | I am slow to trust members of other species, tribes, and societies.
5 | Violence is my answer to almost any challenge.
6 | Don't expect me to save those who can't save themselves. It is nature's way that the strong thrive and the weak perish.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Nomad (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Medicine, and Survival
Tools: One type of musical instrument
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A walking stick, a hunting trap, a trophy from an animal you killed, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Wanderer</name>
      <text>You have an excellent memory for maps and geography, and you can always recall the general layout of terrain, settlements, and other features around you. In addition, you can find food and fresh water for yourself and up to five other people each day, provided that the land offers berries, small game, water, and so forth.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Brawny
3 | Medic
4 | Survivalist
5 | Entertainer
6 | Linguist
7 | Dungeon Delver
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Often considered rude and uncouth among civilized folk, nomads have little respect for the niceties of life in the cities. The ties of tribe, clan, family, and the natural world are the most important bonds to nomads.

Personality:
1 | I'm driven by a wanderlust that led me away from home.
2 | I watch over my friends as if they were a litter of newborn pups.
3 | I once ran twenty-five miles without stopping to warn to my clan of an approaching orc horde. I'd do it again if I had to.
4 | I have a lesson for every situation, drawn from observing nature.
5 | I place no stock in wealthy or well-mannered folk. Money and manners won't save you from a hungry owlbear.
6 | I'm always picking things up, absently fiddling with them, and sometimes accidentally breaking them.
7 | I feel far more comfortable around animals than people.
8 | I was, in fact, raised by wolves.

Ideals:
1 | Change. Life is like the seasons, in constant change, and we must change with it. (Chaotic)
2 | Greater Good. It is each person's responsibility to make the most happiness for the whole tribe. (Light)
3 | Honor. If I dishonor myself, I dishonor my whole clan. (Lawful)
4 | Might. The strongest are meant to rule. (Dark)
5 | Nature. The natural world is more important than all the constructs of civilization. (Neutral)
6 | Glory. I must earn glory in battle, for myself and my clan. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My family, clan, or tribe is the most important thing in my life, even when they are far from me.
2 | An injury to the unspoiled wilderness of my home is an injury to me.
3 | I will bring terrible wrath down on the Darkdoers who destroyed my homeland.
4 | I am the last of my tribe, and it is up to me to ensure their names enter legend.
5 | I suffer awful visions of a coming disaster and will do anything to prevent it.
6 | It is my duty to provide children to sustain my tribe.

Flaw:
1 | I am too enamored of ale, wine, and other intoxicants.
2 | There's no room for caution in a life lived to the fullest.
3 | I remember every insult I've received and nurse a silent resentment toward anyone who's ever wronged me.
4 | I am slow to trust members of other species, tribes, and societies.
5 | Violence is my answer to almost any challenge.
6 | Don't expect me to save those who can't save themselves. It is nature's way that the strong thrive and the weak perish.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Office Worker (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Lore, and Perception
Tools: One type of gaming set
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes, an expired data cylinder, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Office Specialty</name>
      <text>Accounting
Droid Management
Executive Assistant
Facilities
Information Technology
Procurement
Public Relations
Sentient Resources</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Clerical Auger</name>
      <text>You have an intuitive understanding of how offices work and can readily fit in to an office environment as if you were meant to be there, as long as no one looks too carefully. Additionally, you know where the true power lies in the office: you know who is likely to know the local gossip and you know who to sweet talk into getting things done for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Loremaster
4 | Perceptive
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Linguist
7 | Feigned Confidence
8 | Snappy Interjection</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Office workers run the gamut from loyal and effective team member to lazy and incompetent employee.   
Personality:
1 | I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, empathizing with them and always working towards peace.
2 | I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let me emotions control me.
3 | I have little practical experience dealing with people in the world and prefer to work alone.
4 | I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy.
5 | I am always figuring out how to implement better procedures to prevent mistakes.
6 | There is no \I\ in 	eam.\
7 | I work to live.
8 | I live to work.

Ideals:
1 | Prestige. I hope to one day rise to the top of my field and command the respect of those who work for me. (Lawful)
2 | Superiority. Rules are meant to control the sheep. I'm no sheep. (Chaotic)
3 | Community. It is the duty of all people to strengthen the bonds of community and thereby improve civilization. (Light)
4 | Greed. I will do whatever it takes to climb to the top. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Neutral)
6 | Faith. I trust that my leader will guide my actions, I have faith that if I work hard, things will go well. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I will someday get revenge on the corrupt boss who fired me.
2 | Everything I do is for the common people.
3 | I will do anything to protect my employer.
4 | No one must ever learn that I once stole from my employer.
5 | I'm guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it.
6 | I am committed to my group's goals over my own.

Flaw:
1 | I put too much trust in those who wield power within my employer's hierarchy.
2 | I am inflexible in my thinking.
3 | I like to talk at length about my office job.
4 | I do anything I can to avoid real work.
5 | I am not an independent thinker.  I need detailed instructions and close supervision.
6 | I gossip about others to hide my inadequacies.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Office Worker (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Lore, and Perception
Tools: One type of gaming set
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes, an expired data cylinder, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Office Specialty</name>
      <text>Accounting
Droid Management
Executive Assistant
Facilities
Information Technology
Procurement
Public Relations
Sentient Resources</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Clerical Auger</name>
      <text>You have an intuitive understanding of how offices work and can readily fit in to an office environment as if you were meant to be there, as long as no one looks too carefully. Additionally, you know where the true power lies in the office: you know who is likely to know the local gossip and you know who to sweet talk into getting things done for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Loremaster
4 | Perceptive
5 | Entertainer
6 | Linguist
7 | Feigned Confidence
8 | Snappy Interjection</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Office workers run the gamut from loyal and effective team member to lazy and incompetent employee.   
Personality:
1 | I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, empathizing with them and always working towards peace.
2 | I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let me emotions control me.
3 | I have little practical experience dealing with people in the world and prefer to work alone.
4 | I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy.
5 | I am always figuring out how to implement better procedures to prevent mistakes.
6 | There is no "I" in 	eam."
7 | I work to live.
8 | I live to work.

Ideals:
1 | Prestige. I hope to one day rise to the top of my field and command the respect of those who work for me. (Lawful)
2 | Superiority. Rules are meant to control the sheep. I'm no sheep. (Chaotic)
3 | Community. It is the duty of all people to strengthen the bonds of community and thereby improve civilization. (Light)
4 | Greed. I will do whatever it takes to climb to the top. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Neutral)
6 | Faith. I trust that my leader will guide my actions, I have faith that if I work hard, things will go well. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I will someday get revenge on the corrupt boss who fired me.
2 | Everything I do is for the common people.
3 | I will do anything to protect my employer.
4 | No one must ever learn that I once stole from my employer.
5 | I'm guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it.
6 | I am committed to my group's goals over my own.

Flaw:
1 | I put too much trust in those who wield power within my employer's hierarchy.
2 | I am inflexible in my thinking.
3 | I like to talk at length about my office job.
4 | I do anything I can to avoid real work.
5 | I am not an independent thinker.  I need detailed instructions and close supervision.
6 | I gossip about others to hide my inadequacies.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Outlaw (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, Insight, and Survival
Tools: -
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A hunting trap, an iron pot, a set of traveler's clothes, and a pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Defining Event</name>
      <text>I stood up to a tyrant's agents.
I stole from a corrupt Lord to help the poor.
I broke into a tyrant's castle and stole weapons to arm the people.
I failed to assassinate a tyrant.
I loved a noble, and was caught in bed with them.
I robbed a bank with unfair interest rates.
I murdered a pedophilic priest to save local children.
I received a heroic calling from a mysterious creature.
I was framed for a crime I didn't commit.
Outlaw by choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Notorious</name>
      <text>Since you come from the ranks of the common folk, you fit among them with ease. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other commoners, unless you've shown yourself to be a danger to them. They will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Acrobat
2 | Brawny
3 | Empathic
4 | Survivalist
5 | Master of Disguise
6 | Linguist
7 | Observant
8 | Entertaining Competitor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>An outlaw is a hero for the common people who takes pride in his humble origins and revels in disrupting authority to help those he's close to.

Personality:
1 | I judge people by their actions, not their words.
2 | If someone is in trouble, I'm always ready to lend help.
3 | When I set my mind to something, I follow through no matter what gets in my way.
4 | I have a strong sense of fair play and always try to find the most equitable solution to arguments.
5 | I'm confident in my own abilities and do what I can to instill confidence in others.
6 | Thinking is for other people. I prefer action.
7 | I misuse long words in an attempt to sound smarter.
8 | I get bored easily. When am I going to get on with my destiny?

Ideals:
1 | Respect. People deserve to be treated with dignity and respect. (Light)
2 | Fairness. No one should get preferential treatment before the law, and no one is above the law. (Lawful)
3 | Freedom. Tyrants must not be allowed to oppress the people. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. If I become strong, I can take what I want, what I deserve. (Dark)
5 | Sincerity. There's no good in pretending to be something I'm not. (Neutral)
6 | Destiny. Nothing and no one can steer me away from my higher calling. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I have a family, but I have no idea where they are. One day, I hope to see them again.
2 | I worked the land, I love the land, and I will protect the land.
3 | A proud noble once gave me a horrible beating, and I will take my revenge on any bully I encounter.
4 | My tools are symbols of my past life, and I carry them so that I will never forget my roots.
5 | I protect those who cannot protect themselves.
6 | I wish my childhood sweetheart had come with me to pursue my destiny.

Flaw:
1 | The tyrant who rules my land will stop at nothing to see me killed.
2 | I'm convinced of the significance of my destiny, and blind to my shortcomings and the risk of failure.
3 | The people who knew me when I was young know my shameful secret, so I can never go home again.
4 | I have a weakness for the vices of the city, especially hard drink.
5 | Secretly, I believe that things would be better if I were a tyrant lording over the land.
6 | I have trouble trusting in my allies.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Outlaw (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, Insight, and Survival
Tools: -
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A hunting trap, an iron pot, a set of traveler's clothes, and a pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Defining Event</name>
      <text>I stood up to a tyrant's agents.
I stole from a corrupt Lord to help the poor.
I broke into a tyrant's castle and stole weapons to arm the people.
I failed to assassinate a tyrant.
I loved a noble, and was caught in bed with them.
I robbed a bank with unfair interest rates.
I murdered a pedophilic priest to save local children.
I received a heroic calling from a mysterious creature.
I was framed for a crime I didn't commit.
Outlaw by choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Notorious</name>
      <text>Since you come from the ranks of the common folk, you fit among them with ease. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other commoners, unless you've shown yourself to be a danger to them. They will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Acrobat
2 | Brawny
3 | Empathic
4 | Survivalist
5 | Specialist
6 | Linguist
7 | Alert
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>An outlaw is a hero for the common people who takes pride in his humble origins and revels in disrupting authority to help those he's close to.

Personality:
1 | I judge people by their actions, not their words.
2 | If someone is in trouble, I'm always ready to lend help.
3 | When I set my mind to something, I follow through no matter what gets in my way.
4 | I have a strong sense of fair play and always try to find the most equitable solution to arguments.
5 | I'm confident in my own abilities and do what I can to instill confidence in others.
6 | Thinking is for other people. I prefer action.
7 | I misuse long words in an attempt to sound smarter.
8 | I get bored easily. When am I going to get on with my destiny?

Ideals:
1 | Respect. People deserve to be treated with dignity and respect. (Light)
2 | Fairness. No one should get preferential treatment before the law, and no one is above the law. (Lawful)
3 | Freedom. Tyrants must not be allowed to oppress the people. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. If I become strong, I can take what I want, what I deserve. (Dark)
5 | Sincerity. There's no good in pretending to be something I'm not. (Neutral)
6 | Destiny. Nothing and no one can steer me away from my higher calling. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I have a family, but I have no idea where they are. One day, I hope to see them again.
2 | I worked the land, I love the land, and I will protect the land.
3 | A proud noble once gave me a horrible beating, and I will take my revenge on any bully I encounter.
4 | My tools are symbols of my past life, and I carry them so that I will never forget my roots.
5 | I protect those who cannot protect themselves.
6 | I wish my childhood sweetheart had come with me to pursue my destiny.

Flaw:
1 | The tyrant who rules my land will stop at nothing to see me killed.
2 | I'm convinced of the significance of my destiny, and blind to my shortcomings and the risk of failure.
3 | The people who knew me when I was young know my shameful secret, so I can never go home again.
4 | I have a weakness for the vices of the city, especially hard drink.
5 | Secretly, I believe that things would be better if I were a tyrant lording over the land.
6 | I have trouble trusting in my allies.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Pirate (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Deception, Intimidation, and Piloting
Tools: One type of gaming set, your choice of demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Language: 
Equipment: One set of traveler's clothes, a gaming set you are proficient with, poorly wrought maps of Outer Rim worlds in your territory, a small piece of jewelry worth 100 cr from some exotic planet, and a pouch containing 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Galactic Scourge</name>
      <text>You've been from one end of the galaxy to the other. You know the most lucrative trade routes. You have expert knowledge of the various hyperlanes. In addition to this, you know a large number of the models and designs of common space ships that are found in the galaxy. Further, the bonds you formed with your crew are strong, and you can call on their aid even if you've been away from their side for some time. You can expect your former comrades to offer you passage aboard ship, reasonable aid, or shelter when you are in need. Keep in mind that this bond goes both ways, and they may come to you expecting the same.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Athlete
2 | Silver-Tongued
3 | Threatening
4 | Ace Pilot
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Demolitionist
7 | Bypasser
8 | Slicer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Despite the cutthroat nature of the business, pirates come in all shapes and personalities. Some are bloodthirsty brigands who leave no survivors, others are free spirits who believe in strength over weakness. The hardened warriors of deep space can be implacable foes who often form unshakable bonds with their crewmates. The same circumstances that give them their edge can also grind them down, leaving them vulnerable to greed, shame, and the scars of fear and horror left by battle.

Personality:
1 | I respect my captain and trust my crew. It may be all that saves my life one day.
2 | Whether the credits comes from the split of the spoils or from a side wager, I'll get my hands on it.
3 | When my blood gets up, my swearing could boil the icy tundra of Hoth.
4 | I enjoy spreading the tales of my exploits, no matter who hears.
5 | I never let witnesses escape from a raid.
6 | I take what I need, but I don't kill without reason.
7 | I always have an exit planned.
8 | I assume everyone else wants to take what I have.

Ideals:
1 | Equal Shares. All hands who spend sweat and blood earn their share of the credits. (Lawful)
2 | Adventure. I'm far from home, and everything is strange and wonderful! (Chaotic)
3 | Greater Good. I raid to weaken the Empire that threatens my people, but I don't steal from civilians. (Light)
4 | Strength. The weak exist to feed the strong, and I am strong. (Dark)
5 | Crew. A ship is nothing without her crew. Protect your mates. (Neutral)
6 | Ambition. One day I will be so much more than a captain. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My band and I will be known across the world, and we'll never be forgotten.
2 | My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.
3 | Everything I do is for the good of my people.
4 | My ship and many of her crew were lost to treachery, and I won't rest until I discover who was behind it.
5 | My ship comes first, and all other loyalties simply pale in comparison.
6 | A crew member of a ship we raided saved my life, and I don't know how to resolve that debt.

Flaw:
1 | I never back down from a fight.
2 | When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.
3 | I was drunk on watch when my ship was lost to an ambush. I can't set the shame aside.
4 | I feel I'm entitled to a greater share of the spoils, no matter the circumstances.
5 | I won't let myself be captured. If a raid goes sour, I'm the first to run for cover.
6 | I get lost in the thrill of the raid and can't focus on the details of a plan.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Pirate (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Deception, Intimidation, and Piloting
Tools: One type of gaming set, your choice of demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Language: 
Equipment: One set of traveler's clothes, a gaming set you are proficient with, poorly wrought maps of Outer Rim worlds in your territory, a small piece of jewelry worth 100 cr from some exotic planet, and a pouch containing 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Galactic Scourge</name>
      <text>You've been from one end of the galaxy to the other. You know the most lucrative trade routes. You have expert knowledge of the various hyperlanes. In addition to this, you know a large number of the models and designs of common space ships that are found in the galaxy. Further, the bonds you formed with your crew are strong, and you can call on their aid even if you've been away from their side for some time. You can expect your former comrades to offer you passage aboard ship, reasonable aid, or shelter when you are in need. Keep in mind that this bond goes both ways, and they may come to you expecting the same.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Silver-Tongued
3 | Threatening
4 | Ace Pilot
5 | Entertainer
6 | Specialist
7 | Feigned Confidence
8 | Force of Personality</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Despite the cutthroat nature of the business, pirates come in all shapes and personalities. Some are bloodthirsty brigands who leave no survivors, others are free spirits who believe in strength over weakness. The hardened warriors of deep space can be implacable foes who often form unshakable bonds with their crewmates. The same circumstances that give them their edge can also grind them down, leaving them vulnerable to greed, shame, and the scars of fear and horror left by battle.

Personality:
1 | I respect my captain and trust my crew. It may be all that saves my life one day.
2 | Whether the credits comes from the split of the spoils or from a side wager, I'll get my hands on it.
3 | When my blood gets up, my swearing could boil the icy tundra of Hoth.
4 | I enjoy spreading the tales of my exploits, no matter who hears.
5 | I never let witnesses escape from a raid.
6 | I take what I need, but I don't kill without reason.
7 | I always have an exit planned.
8 | I assume everyone else wants to take what I have.

Ideals:
1 | Equal Shares. All hands who spend sweat and blood earn their share of the credits. (Lawful)
2 | Adventure. I'm far from home, and everything is strange and wonderful! (Chaotic)
3 | Greater Good. I raid to weaken the Empire that threatens my people, but I don't steal from civilians. (Light)
4 | Strength. The weak exist to feed the strong, and I am strong. (Dark)
5 | Crew. A ship is nothing without her crew. Protect your mates. (Neutral)
6 | Ambition. One day I will be so much more than a captain. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My band and I will be known across the world, and we'll never be forgotten.
2 | My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.
3 | Everything I do is for the good of my people.
4 | My ship and many of her crew were lost to treachery, and I won't rest until I discover who was behind it.
5 | My ship comes first, and all other loyalties simply pale in comparison.
6 | A crew member of a ship we raided saved my life, and I don't know how to resolve that debt.

Flaw:
1 | I never back down from a fight.
2 | When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.
3 | I was drunk on watch when my ship was lost to an ambush. I can't set the shame aside.
4 | I feel I'm entitled to a greater share of the spoils, no matter the circumstances.
5 | I won't let myself be captured. If a raid goes sour, I'm the first to run for cover.
6 | I get lost in the thrill of the raid and can't focus on the details of a plan.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Racer (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Nature, Piloting, and Technology
Tools: One type of gaming set or mechanic's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes, a trophy or ribbon from your first-ever win, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Racing Specialty</name>
      <text>Air Speeders
Boonta Speeders
Pod Racers
Speeder Bikes
Starships
Swoop Bikes
Fathiers
Varactyls</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Terrain Mastery</name>
      <text>You have a preternatural instinct for understanding the terrain, interpreting maps, and planning routes.  You and your party can move at three-fourths your speed over difficult terrain during long-distance travel.  Because of these skills, if you know your destination and the intervening terrain--either by reputation, by sight, or by maps you have seen--you are able to identify an effective short-cut, trimming your travel time by up to half.  Your GM may rule that your short-cut entails significant danger or may be temporarily impassable.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Naturalist
3 | Ace Pilot
4 | Techie
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Genius Mechanic
7 | Linguist
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Racers are usually competitive and often fearless. They can lead a whirlwind of a life, and sometimes the adrenaline of the race is no longer enough for them. 
Personality:
1 | Win or lose.  There is no try.
2 | Giving up is never an option for me.
3 | I spit and laugh in the face of danger.
4 | Why do something if there is not the possibility of death?
5 | I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let my emotions control me.
6 | I don't pay attention to the risks in a situation. Never tell me the odds.
7 | The best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can't do it.
8 | I blow up at the slightest insult.

Ideals:
1 | Victory. It's not a victory if you don't follow the rules. (Lawful)
2 | Win. A win is a win, no matter how it's done. (Chaotic)
3 | Charity. I share my winnings with the less fortunate. (Light)
4 | Pride. I will do whatever it takes to be recognized as the best. (Dark)
5 | Excitement. Life is a race worth entering, because you never know how the ships will fly. (Neutral)
6 | Victory. Nothing worth doing is ever a sure thing. (Any)

Bond:
1 | There is nothing more important to me than my vehicle.
2 | I will win the Coruscant Invitational one day.
3 | I'm trying to pay off the debt on my vehicle.
4 | I owe a lot of money to the wrong kind of people.
5 | I do what feels good.  Let's see the authorities catch me.
6 | Someone I loved died because they were too slow.  That will never happen to me.

Flaw:
1 | I think most people in life are content with a participation trophy. They disgust me.
2 | I classify everyone I meet as a winner or a loser.  There's only ever one winner.
3 | There is not a drug I won't try.
4 | Once I start drinking, it's hard for me to stop.
5 | Once someone questions my courage, I never back down no matter how dangerous the situation.
6 | Waiting around makes me antsy. I'd rather do something stupid than do nothing at all.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Racer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Nature, Piloting, and Technology
Tools: One type of gaming set or mechanic's kit
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes, a trophy or ribbon from your first-ever win, a gaming set (one of your choice), and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Racing Specialty</name>
      <text>Air Speeders
Boonta Speeders
Pod Racers
Speeder Bikes
Starships
Swoop Bikes
Fathiers
Varactyls</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Terrain Mastery</name>
      <text>You have a preternatural instinct for understanding the terrain, interpreting maps, and planning routes.  You and your party can move at three-fourths your speed over difficult terrain during long-distance travel.  Because of these skills, if you know your destination and the intervening terrain--either by reputation, by sight, or by maps you have seen--you are able to identify an effective short-cut, trimming your travel time by up to half.  Your GM may rule that your short-cut entails significant danger or may be temporarily impassable.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Animal Handler
2 | Naturalist
3 | Ace Pilot
4 | Techie
5 | Entertainer
6 | Specialist
7 | Linguist
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Racers are usually competitive and often fearless. They can lead a whirlwind of a life, and sometimes the adrenaline of the race is no longer enough for them. 
Personality:
1 | Win or lose.  There is no try.
2 | Giving up is never an option for me.
3 | I spit and laugh in the face of danger.
4 | Why do something if there is not the possibility of death?
5 | I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let my emotions control me.
6 | I don't pay attention to the risks in a situation. Never tell me the odds.
7 | The best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can't do it.
8 | I blow up at the slightest insult.

Ideals:
1 | Victory. It's not a victory if you don't follow the rules. (Lawful)
2 | Win. A win is a win, no matter how it's done. (Chaotic)
3 | Charity. I share my winnings with the less fortunate. (Light)
4 | Pride. I will do whatever it takes to be recognized as the best. (Dark)
5 | Excitement. Life is a race worth entering, because you never know how the ships will fly. (Neutral)
6 | Victory. Nothing worth doing is ever a sure thing. (Any)

Bond:
1 | There is nothing more important to me than my vehicle.
2 | I will win the Coruscant Invitational one day.
3 | I'm trying to pay off the debt on my vehicle.
4 | I owe a lot of money to the wrong kind of people.
5 | I do what feels good.  Let's see the authorities catch me.
6 | Someone I loved died because they were too slow.  That will never happen to me.

Flaw:
1 | I think most people in life are content with a participation trophy. They disgust me.
2 | I classify everyone I meet as a winner or a loser.  There's only ever one winner.
3 | There is not a drug I won't try.
4 | Once I start drinking, it's hard for me to stop.
5 | Once someone questions my courage, I never back down no matter how dangerous the situation.
6 | Waiting around makes me antsy. I'd rather do something stupid than do nothing at all.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Scientist (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Lore, Medicine, Nature, and Technology
Tools: One of your choice
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes, a datapad, a book on your field of research, a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Field of Research</name>
      <text>Biology
Artificial Intelligence
Chemistry
Geology
Physics
The Force
Astrogation
Medicine</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Scientific Method</name>
      <text>You are well acquainted with your field of research from having read numerous journals or having attended scientific conferences. Concepts that are complicated, involving technical jargon that usually goes over most people's heads, are simple to you. You fully understand concepts, can recall key information, and know how to use equipment related to your field, unless the research was hidden from the public, in which you may only partially understand. You also recognize well-known figures in your field.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Loremaster
2 | Medic
3 | Naturalist
4 | Techie
5 | Crafter
6 | Linguist
7 | Tech Dabbler
8 | Keen Mind</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Scientist are interested in things most don't care about. Their research is their life, and drives their personality traits. Their flaws, ideals, and bond are a result of their hours spent researching.

Personality:
1 | I look up to a renowned scientist in my field, and often talk about their work.
2 | I constantly compare my current situation to my past experiments, many of which went terrifyingly wrong.
3 | I believe scientific results always comes first.
4 | I only speak in short incomplete and concise sentences, as they are optimized for efficient communication.
5 | I often get lost in my own thoughts and contemplation, becoming oblivious to my surroundings.
6 | I am unable to think logically under great stress, and begin to shout random scientific words.
7 | I do not believe in etiquette and disregard social expectations.
8 | I was, in fact, grown and raised in a laboratory.

Ideals:
1 | Transparency. All discoveries should be open to everyone. (Light)
2 | Logic. Emotions must not cloud our sense of what is right and true, or our logical thinking. (Lawful)
3 | Greed. I'm only in it for the money and fame. (Dark)
4 | Free Thinking. Inquiry and curiosity are the pillars of progress. (Chaotic)
5 | Live and Let Live. Meddling in the affairs of others only causes trouble. (Balanced)
6 | Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My research is also my best companion.
2 | I will get revenge on the criminals that stole my research.
3 | The school I studied at is the most important place in the world to me.
4 | One day I will return to my home planet and prove that I am the greatest scientist of them all.
5 | I believe my research will be the key to saving the life of a loved one.
6 | I owe my instructor a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.

Flaw:
1 | I believe only other scientists deserve my respect.
2 | I fail to understand why people don't understand my technical jargon.
3 | I experiment on myself without thinking about the long term consequences.
4 | I am paranoid that people are out to steal my research.
5 | I believe I work better when under the influence of intoxicants.
6 | I work on my research to the point where I ignore my own bodily needs.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Scoundrel (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Performance, and Sleight of Hand
Tools: Disguise Kit, Forgery Kit
Language: 
Equipment: A set of fine clothes, a disguise kit, a memento of a former con, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Favorite Schemes</name>
      <text>I cheat at games involving chance.
I shave creds or forge documents.
I insinuate myself into people's lives to prey on their weakness and secure their fortunes.
I put on new identities like clothes.
I run sleight-of-hand cons on street corners.
I convince people that worthless junk is worth their hard-earned money.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: False Identity</name>
      <text>You have created a second identity that includes documentation, established acquaintances, and disguises that allow you to assume that persona.

Additionally, you can forge documents including official papers and personal letters, as long as you have seen an example of the kind of document or the handwriting you are trying to copy.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Performer
4 | Quick-Fingered
5 | Master of Disguise
6 | Force of Personality
7 | Snappy Interjection
8 | Actor</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Scoundrels are colorful characters who conceal their true selves behind the masks they construct. They reflect what people want to see, what they want to believe, and how they see the world. But their true selves are sometimes plagued by an uneasy conscience, an old enemy, or deep-seated trust issues.

Personality:
1 | I fall in and out of love easily, and am always pursuing someone.
2 | I have a joke for every occasion, especially occasions where humor is inappropriate.
3 | Flattery is my preferred trick for getting what I want.
4 | I'm a born gambler who can't resist taking a risk for a potential payoff.
5 | I lie about almost everything, even when there's no good reason to.
6 | Sarcasm and insults are my weapons of choice.
7 | I keep multiple symbols on me and invoke whatever power might come in useful at any given moment.
8 | I pocket anything I see that might have some value.

Ideals:
1 | Independence. I am a free spirit, no one tells me what to do. (Chaotic)
2 | Fairness. I never target people who can't afford to lose a few creds. (Lawful)
3 | Charity. I distribute the money I acquire to the people who really need it. (Light)
4 | Creativity. I never run the same con twice. (Any)
5 | Friendship. Material goods come and go. Bonds of friendship last forever. (Light)
6 | Aspiration. I'm determined to make something of myself. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I fleeced the wrong person and must work to ensure that this individual never crosses paths with me or those I care about.
2 | I owe everything to my mentor—a horrible person who's probably rotting in jail somewhere.
3 | Somewhere out there, I have a child who doesn't know me. I'm making the world better for him or her.
4 | I come from a noble family, and one day I'll reclaim my lands and title from those who stole them from me.
5 | A powerful person killed someone I love. Some day soon, I'll have my revenge.
6 | I swindled and ruined a person who didn't deserve it, and I seek to atone for my misdeeds.

Flaw:
1 | I can't resist a pretty face.
2 | I'm always in debt. I spend my ill-gotten gains on decadent luxuries faster than I bring them in.
3 | I'm convinced that no one could ever fool me the way I fool others.
4 | I'm too greedy for my own good. I can't resist taking a risk if there's money involved.
5 | I can't resist swindling people who are more powerful than me.
6 | I hate to admit it and will hate myself for it, but I'll run and preserve my own hide if the going gets tough.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Servant (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Lore, Performance, and Persuasion
Tools: One of your choice
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A noble symbol representing your employer, a set of artisan's tools (one of your choice), a set of nice clothes, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Decorum</name>
      <text>You know how to carry yourself around the elite and their servants. When in the presence of someone of power, or the servants of such a person, you can easily act as if you belong and, barring any extremely outlandish behavior, you can pass off your companions as belonging, too.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Loremaster
3 | Performer
4 | Charming Persona
5 | Linguist
6 | Crafter
7 | Gourmand
8 | Keen Mind</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A servant, for better or worse, will have their personality affected by their years of servitude. 
Personality:
1 | I am compulsively neat, and clean; I feel uncomfortable if my companions and I are ever dirty or  unpresentable.
2 | I am a bit of a snob, and look down on the common rabble.
3 | I am extremely subservient; I rarely raise my voice or object.
4 | I may be quite calm and polite around those of higher power than I; but I'm harsh towards all my underlings, flexing the little power I have.
5 | I dote over my companions like a concerned mother bird, fixing their clothing and making sure they look nice.
6 | I hated my time as a servant, and go out of my way to enjoy myself and let loose, rarely holding my tongue.
7 | I rarely show any emotions, remaining calm and stoic even in the worst of situations.
8 | I can-or think I can-diffuse the most tense and stressful of situations with the right word or phrase.

Ideals:
1 | Service. Your wish is my desire. (Lawful)
2 | Helpful. I just enjoy making myself useful. (Light)
3 | Free. Noone should be bound in servitude. (Chaotic)
4 | Infiltrate. From the position of a servant, I can worm my way into places of power! (Dark)
5 | Payment. I don't care what my masters do; as long as I get paid. (Neutral)
6 | Live. I only wish to serve in peace. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I am still loyal to my old master.
2 | The Lord I worked for is after my head, and will do anything to capture me.
3 | My family still live as servants; I hope to earn a better life for them.
4 | An older servant taught me the ropes and looked out for me; and I owe them a great debt.
5 | I will exact revenge on the bastards who ruined (or ended) my Master's life.
6 | I have plenty of friends in high places; and they've come in useful from time to time.

Flaw:
1 | I become incredibly nervous around people of power and importance.
2 | Saying that I'm a little bossy is a bit of an understatement.
3 | I can be a sycophant, constantly fawning and flattering others; which can come off as shallow.
4 | I've lived a relatively pampered life; the world of commoners is dull and painful to me.
5 | I never speak for myself, letting others walk all over me.
6 | I often can seem stiff, old fashioned and generally a stick in the mud.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Servant (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Lore, Performance, and Persuasion
Tools: One of your choice
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A noble symbol representing your employer, a set of artisan's tools (one of your choice), a set of nice clothes, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Decorum</name>
      <text>You know how to carry yourself around the elite and their servants. When in the presence of someone of power, or the servants of such a person, you can easily act as if you belong and, barring any extremely outlandish behavior, you can pass off your companions as belonging, too.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Loremaster
3 | Performer
4 | Charmer
5 | Crafter
6 | Entertainer
7 | Specialist
8 | Linguist</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A servant, for better or worse, will have their personality affected by their years of servitude. 
Personality:
1 | I am compulsively neat, and clean; I feel uncomfortable if my companions and I are ever dirty or  unpresentable.
2 | I am a bit of a snob, and look down on the common rabble.
3 | I am extremely subservient; I rarely raise my voice or object.
4 | I may be quite calm and polite around those of higher power than I; but I'm harsh towards all my underlings, flexing the little power I have.
5 | I dote over my companions like a concerned mother bird, fixing their clothing and making sure they look nice.
6 | I hated my time as a servant, and go out of my way to enjoy myself and let loose, rarely holding my tongue.
7 | I rarely show any emotions, remaining calm and stoic even in the worst of situations.
8 | I can-or think I can-diffuse the most tense and stressful of situations with the right word or phrase.

Ideals:
1 | Service. Your wish is my desire. (Lawful)
2 | Helpful. I just enjoy making myself useful. (Light)
3 | Free. Noone should be bound in servitude. (Chaotic)
4 | Infiltrate. From the position of a servant, I can worm my way into places of power! (Dark)
5 | Payment. I don't care what my masters do; as long as I get paid. (Neutral)
6 | Live. I only wish to serve in peace. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I am still loyal to my old master.
2 | The Lord I worked for is after my head, and will do anything to capture me.
3 | My family still live as servants; I hope to earn a better life for them.
4 | An older servant taught me the ropes and looked out for me; and I owe them a great debt.
5 | I will exact revenge on the bastards who ruined (or ended) my Master's life.
6 | I have plenty of friends in high places; and they've come in useful from time to time.

Flaw:
1 | I become incredibly nervous around people of power and importance.
2 | Saying that I'm a little bossy is a bit of an understatement.
3 | I can be a sycophant, constantly fawning and flattering others; which can come off as shallow.
4 | I've lived a relatively pampered life; the world of commoners is dull and painful to me.
5 | I never speak for myself, letting others walk all over me.
6 | I often can seem stiff, old fashioned and generally a stick in the mud.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Sith (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Intimidation, and Lore
Tools: Artificer's tools
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A copy of the Sith code, a set of common clothes including a robe, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Asylum by the Fearful</name>
      <text>As a Sith, you instill fear in those who are aware of your standing. You and your adventuring companions can expect to receive free healing and care at any Sith temple, and those who are aware of your nature will support you (but only you) at a modest lifestyle.

You might also have ties to a specific Sith temple and have a residence there. This could be the temple where you trained, or a temple where you have found a new home. While near your temple, you can call upon the Sith for assistance, provided the assistance you ask for benefits them and you remain in good standing with your temple.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Threatening
4 | Loremaster
5 | Linguist
6 | Crafter
7 | Force of Personality
8 | Force Sensitive</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Sith are shaped by their training. They study the Sith code and use it to oppress the weak and quell resistance. Their study of the Sith code affects their mannerisms and ideals. Their flaws might be some hidden hypocrisy or heretical idea, or an ideal or bond taken to an extreme.

Personality:
1 | I idolize a particular Sith, and constantly refer to that person's deeds and example.
2 | I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, empathizing with them and always working towards peace.
3 | I see omens in every event and action. The Force tries to speak to us, we just need to listen
4 | Nothing can shake my optimistic attitude.
5 | I quote (or misquote) sacred Sith texts and proverbs in almost every situation.
6 | I am tolerant (or intolerant) of those who don't support the Sith.
7 | I've enjoyed fine food, drink, and high society. Rough living grates on me.
8 | I've spent so long in the Sith temple that I have little practical experience dealing with people in the  world.

Ideals:
1 | Tradition. The ancient traditions of worship and sacrifice must be preserved and upheld. (Any)
2 | Disdain. I never try to help those in need, regardless of how simple it would be. (Dark)
3 | Change. We must help bring about the changes the Force is constantly working in the world. (Any)
4 | Power. I hope to one day rise to the rank of Dark Lord of the Sith. (Any)
5 | Faith. I trust that the Force will guide my actions; I have faith that if I work hard, things will go well. (Any)
6 | Aspiration. I seek to prove myself worthy of the Force by matching my actions against the Sith teachings. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would die to recover an ancient Sith relic that was lost long ago.
2 | I will someday get revenge on those who razed my temple.
3 | I owe my life to the Sith who took me in when my parents died.
4 | Everything I do is for the common people.
5 | I will do anything to protect the temple where I served.
6 | I seek to preserve a sacred text that my enemies seek to destroy.

Flaw:
1 | I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.
2 | I put too much trust in those who wield power within my temple's hierarchy.
3 | My piety sometimes leads me to blindly trust those that profess faith in the Force.
4 | I am inflexible in my thinking.
5 | I am suspicious of strangers and expect the worst of them.
6 | Once I pick a goal, I become obsessed with it to the detriment of everything else in my life.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Smuggler (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Piloting, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth
Tools: One type of gaming set and your choice of demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit
Language: 
Equipment: A fusion cutter, a set of dark common clothes including a hood, and a belt pouch containing 150 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Careful Selection</name>
      <text>Some close brushes with the law have taught you that not every city guard can be bribed, and some people are simply too keen to miss minute discrepancies. This feature allows you to study a person and gain insight into whether or not they would accept a bribe, or to pick up on whether they are exceptionally more perceptive than you. It does not reveal how expensive a bribe may be for a given situation, however.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Ace Pilot
3 | Quick-Fingered
4 | Stealthy
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Demolitionist
7 | Bypasser
8 | Slicer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Smugglers might seem like villains on the surface, and many of them are nefarious to the core. But some have an abundance of endearing, if not redeeming, characteristics. There might be honor among thieves, but spies rarely show any respect for law or authority. 
Personality:
1 | I am extremely sociable, especially over a mug of ale.
2 | I always keep my wares close to me, you never know who might stumble across them otherwise.
3 | The best way to hide is out in the open.
4 | I'm a terrible gossip.
5 | Being seen with any unsavory figures is a sure way to undermine my work, which is why I work out of sight.
6 | Deflecting questions has become second nature to me, so I rarely answer straight.
7 | I have dozens of identities and live in constant fear of answering to the wrong name.
8 | I act irrationally confident in the face of danger, nobody suspects anything when you seem like you're in charge.

Ideals:
1 | Morals. I only smuggle things to improve the lives of the common folk. (Light)
2 | Ruthless. I will rise to the top of the heap by any means necessary. (Dark)
3 | Friendship. My associates are dear to me, and I want them to rise with me when I hit it big. (Lawful)
4 | Dauntless. No border crossing or bribe is too difficult- that's just the coward's way of saying exciting! (Chaotic)
5 | Greater. Good I work for a greater cause, and ply my trade only in service to it. (Any)
6 | Unperturbed. I only want to make a living for myself, and smuggling is just an edge I can use to do so. (Neutral)

Bond:
1 | A corrupt official shut me down back in my honest days. I aim to show him a thing or two about recovery.
2 | I never wanted to be a criminal, but it pays the bills.
3 | A bloodthirsty pirate stole a shipment from me and killed a dear friend of mine. I will have my vengeance.
4 | Someone I cared about discovered my profession and has publicly denounced me, and I am caught between protecting my reputation and restoring our relationship.
5 | My love interest is someone who once stole from right under my nose- but they have no idea who I am or how much I admire them for their accomplishment.
6 | My business partners are closer to me than my family.

Flaw:
1 | \Trust nobody, not even yourself.\ I am plagued by paranoia.
2 | I'm so charismatic that sometimes I woo myself. Who am I, Narcissus?
3 | Money is my greatest motivator. I'll do almost anything given enough of it, even if I'll regret it later.
4 | I would betray anyone to save my own skin.
5 | I detach myself from the results of my actions in order to sleep better at night.
6 | Someone who knows me well might call me 	wo-faced\ but those who don't have no idea what hit 'em.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Soldier (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Intimidation, Persuasion, and Piloting
Tools: One type of gaming set
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: An insignia of rank, a trophy taken from a fallen enemy, a gaming set (one of your choice), a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Specialty</name>
      <text>Officer
Scout
Infantry
Medic
Quartermaster
Pilot
Artisan
Support Staff</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Military Rank</name>
      <text>You have a military rank from your career as a soldier. Soldiers loyal to your former military organization still recognize your authority and influence, and they defer to you if they are of a lower rank. You can invoke your rank to exert influence over other soldiers and requisition simple equipment for temporary use. You can also usually gain access to friendly military encampments where your rank is recognized.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Brawny
2 | Threatening
3 | Charming Persona
4 | Ace Pilot
5 | Entertaining Competitor
6 | Linguist
7 | Weapon Expert
8 | Healer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>The horrors of war combined with the rigid discipline of military service leave their mark on all soldiers, shaping their ideals, creating strong bonds, and often leaving them scarred and mentally vulnerable.

Personality:
1 | I'm always polite and respectful.
2 | I'm haunted by memories of war. I can't get the images of violence out of my mind.
3 | I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.
4 | I'm full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my military experience relevant to almost every combat situation.
5 | I can stare down a hell hound without flinching.
6 | I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.
7 | I have a crude sense of humor.
8 | I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.

Ideals:
1 | Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Light)
2 | Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)
3 | Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)
4 | Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Dark)
5 | Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)
6 | Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I would still lay down my life for the people I served with.
2 | Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.
3 | My honor is my life.
4 | I'll never forget the crushing defeat my company suffered or the enemies who dealt it.
5 | Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.
6 | I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.

Flaw:
1 | The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.
2 | I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven warrior.
3 | I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives— and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.
4 | My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.
5 | I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.
6 | I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Spacer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Investigation, Piloting, and Technology
Tools: Your choice of chef's kit, mechanic's kit, or one type of gaming set
Language: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of tools or a gaming set (one of your choice), a set of common clothes, a small souvenir from your travels, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: Specialty</name>
      <text>Pilot
Mechanic
Support Staff
Guard
Ship Medic
Captain
Communications Officer
Ship Cook</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Well-Traveled</name>
      <text>As a spacer, you've been from one end of the galaxy to the other. You've traveled along many of the trade routes, and know the safest routes. You have expert knowledge of the various hyperlanes. In addition to this, you know a large number of the models and designs of common space ships that are found in the galaxy.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Investigator
3 | Ace Pilot
4 | Techie
5 | Gourmand
6 | Genius Mechanic
7 | Entertaining Competitor
8 | Inspiring Leader</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Spacers come from all walks of life, and the responsibilities of life aboard a ship make them generally reliable as well. Spending so much time on their ship shapes their outlook and forms their most important attachments.

Personality:
1 | My crewmates know they can rely on me, no matter what.
2 | I work hard so that I can play hard when the work is done.
3 | I enjoy traveling into new systems and making new friends over a drink.
4 | I stretch the truth for the sake of a good story.
5 | To me, a bar brawl is a nice way to get to know a new city.
6 | I never pass up a friendly wager.
7 | The best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can't do it.
8 | I like a job well done, especially if I can convince someone else to do it.

Ideals:
1 | Respect. The thing that keeps a ship together is mutual respect between captain and crew. (Light)
2 | Fairness. We all do the work, so we all share in the rewards. (Lawful)
3 | Freedom. Space is freedom, the freedom to go anywhere and do anything. (Chaotic)
4 | Mastery. I'm a predator, and the other ships we come across are my prey. (Dark)
5 | People. I'm committed to my crewmates, not to ideals. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. Someday, I'll own my own ship and chart my own destiny. (Any)

Bond:
1 | I'm loyal to my captain first, everything else second.
2 | The ship is most important—crewmates and captains come and go.
3 | I'll always remember my first ship.
4 | I will become the greatest captain that ever lived.
5 | I was cheated out of my fair share of the profits, and I want to get my due.
6 | Ruthless space pirates murdered my captain and crewmates, stole all we owned, and left me lo die. Vengeance will be mine.

Flaw:
1 | I follow orders, even if I think they're wrong.
2 | I'll say anything to avoid having to do extra work.
3 | Once someone questions my courage, I never back down no matter how dangerous the situation.
4 | Once I start drinking, it's hard for me to stop.
5 | I can't help but pocket loose coins and other trinkets I come across.
6 | My pride will probably lead to my destruction.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Student (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Lore, Investigation, and Nature
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: The scholar's robes of your cloister, a writing kit (small pouch with a quill, ink, folded parchment, and a small penknife), a borrowed book on the subject of your current study, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Library Access</name>
      <text>Though others must often endure extensive interviews and significant fees to gain access to even the most common archives in your library, you have free and easy access to the majority of the library, though it might also have repositories of lore that are too valuable, powerful, or secret to permit anyone immediate access.

You have a working knowledge of your cloister's personnel and bureaucracy, and you know how to navigate those connections with some ease.

Additionally, you are likely to gain preferential treatment at other libraries across the galaxy, as professional courtesy shown to a fellow scholar.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Loremaster
3 | Investigator
4 | Naturalist
5 | Linguist
6 | Keen Mind
7 | Observant
8 | Healer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Cloistered scholars are defined by their extensive studies, and their characteristics reflect this life of study. Devoted to scholarly pursuits, they value knowledge highly — as a worthy goal in itself, or as a means to a desirable end.

Personality:
1 | I use polysyllabic words that convey the impression of great erudition.
2 | I've read every book in the world's greatest libraries—or I like to boast that I have.
3 | I'm used to helping out those who aren't as smart as I am, and I patiently explain anything and everything to others.
4 | There's nothing I like more than a good mystery.
5 | I'm willing to listen to every side of an argument before I make my own judgment.
6 | I... speak... slowly... when talking... to idiots,... which... almost... everyone... is... compared... to me.
7 | I am horribly, horribly awkward in social situations.
8 | I'm convinced that people are always trying to steal my secrets.

Ideals:
1 | Knowledge. The path to power and self-improvement is through knowledge. (Neutral)
2 | Beauty. What is beautiful points us beyond itself toward what is true. (Light)
3 | Logic. Emotions must not cloud our logical thinking. (Lawful)
4 | No Limits. Nothing should fetter the infinite possibility inherent in all existence. (Chaotic)
5 | Power. Knowledge is the path to power and domination. (Dark)
6 | Self-Improvement. The goal of a life of study is the betterment of oneself. (Any)

Bond:
1 | It is my duty to protect my students.
2 | I have an ancient text that holds terrible secrets that must not fall into the wrong hands.
3 | I work to preserve a library, university, scriptorium, or monastery.
4 | My life's work is a series of tomes related to a specific field of lore.
5 | I've been searching my whole life for the answer to a certain question.
6 | I sold my soul for knowledge. I hope to do great deeds and win it back.

Flaw:
1 | I am easily distracted by the promise of information.
2 | Most people scream and run when they see a monster. I stop and take notes on its anatomy.
3 | Unlocking an ancient mystery is worth the price of a civilization.
4 | I overlook obvious solutions in favor of complicated ones.
5 | I speak without really thinking through my words, invariably insulting others.
6 | I can't keep a secret to save my life, or anyone else's.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Student (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Lore, Investigation, and Nature
Tools: -
Language: Two of your choice
Equipment: The scholar's robes of your cloister, a writing kit (small pouch with a quill, ink, folded parchment, and a small penknife), a borrowed book on the subject of your current study, and a pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Library Access</name>
      <text>Though others must often endure extensive interviews and significant fees to gain access to even the most common archives in your library, you have free and easy access to the majority of the library, though it might also have repositories of lore that are too valuable, powerful, or secret to permit anyone immediate access.

You have a working knowledge of your cloister's personnel and bureaucracy, and you know how to navigate those connections with some ease.

Additionally, you are likely to gain preferential treatment at other libraries across the galaxy, as professional courtesy shown to a fellow scholar.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Empathic
2 | Loremaster
3 | Investigator
4 | Naturalist
5 | Linguist
6 | Keen Mind
7 | Observant
8 | Healer</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Cloistered scholars are defined by their extensive studies, and their characteristics reflect this life of study. Devoted to scholarly pursuits, they value knowledge highly — as a worthy goal in itself, or as a means to a desirable end.

Personality:
1 | I use polysyllabic words that convey the impression of great erudition.
2 | I've read every book in the world's greatest libraries—or I like to boast that I have.
3 | I'm used to helping out those who aren't as smart as I am, and I patiently explain anything and everything to others.
4 | There's nothing I like more than a good mystery.
5 | I'm willing to listen to every side of an argument before I make my own judgment.
6 | I... speak... slowly... when talking... to idiots,... which... almost... everyone... is... compared... to me.
7 | I am horribly, horribly awkward in social situations.
8 | I'm convinced that people are always trying to steal my secrets.

Ideals:
1 | Knowledge. The path to power and self-improvement is through knowledge. (Neutral)
2 | Beauty. What is beautiful points us beyond itself toward what is true. (Light)
3 | Logic. Emotions must not cloud our logical thinking. (Lawful)
4 | No Limits. Nothing should fetter the infinite possibility inherent in all existence. (Chaotic)
5 | Power. Knowledge is the path to power and domination. (Dark)
6 | Self-Improvement. The goal of a life of study is the betterment of oneself. (Any)

Bond:
1 | It is my duty to protect my students.
2 | I have an ancient text that holds terrible secrets that must not fall into the wrong hands.
3 | I work to preserve a library, university, scriptorium, or monastery.
4 | My life's work is a series of tomes related to a specific field of lore.
5 | I've been searching my whole life for the answer to a certain question.
6 | I sold my soul for knowledge. I hope to do great deeds and win it back.

Flaw:
1 | I am easily distracted by the promise of information.
2 | Most people scream and run when they see a monster. I stop and take notes on its anatomy.
3 | Unlocking an ancient mystery is worth the price of a civilization.
4 | I overlook obvious solutions in favor of complicated ones.
5 | I speak without really thinking through my words, invariably insulting others.
6 | I can't keep a secret to save my life, or anyone else's.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Teacher (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies</name>
      <text>You are an experienced teacher who knows how to best instruct others in an array of disciplines. Although you have a vast amount of knowledge yourself, pedagogy is the most important tool in your toolbox because it allows the rest of your knowledge to spread most efficiently.

Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Lore, Nature, Performance, and Technology
Tool Proficiencies: One instrument or set of artisan's implements of your choice
Languages: One of your choice
Equipment: A set of common clothes, an instrument or set of tools with which you are proficient, a token from a former student, and a belt pouch containing 50 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Knowledge</name>
      <text>If you need information on something, you know if there is a book containing that information and where to find it. Further, when you hear a creature speaking or when you see language written down, you can identify exactly what language is being used even if you are not proficient in the language. Finally, when you hear music, you know which instruments are being used in the performance, even if you are not proficient in their use.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Loremaster
2 | Naturalist
3 | Performer
4 | Techie
5 | Entertainer
6 | Crafter
7 | Linguist
8 | Feigned Confidence</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Characteristics</name>
      <text>As a teacher you are devoted to educating others, as well as learning new information for yourself. It is up to you whether you are preachy or wise, a bookworm or more kinesthetic, a note taker or visual learner. In any case, you are most likely underappreciated.

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | Books are my everything.
2 | Knowledge is the most important thing in the world.
3 | I have quotes for every occasion.
4 | My vocabulary is vast enough I sometimes use words that are larger than necessary.
5 | I love working with kids.
6 | Because I understand why people can make mistakes, I am also patient with them.
7 | Sometimes I start explaining things at a level much to basic for the audience.
8 | I reward hard work and good manners.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Teach. I must spread what I have learned. (Lawful)
2 | Insatiable. When I find something new I must learn everything about it, no matter the cost. (Chaotic)
3 | Discovery. Every single piece of information is waiting to be discovered. (Light)
4 | Greed. Every piece of knowledge will be mine. (Dark)
5 | People. I will teach anybody anything. (Neutral)
6 | Power. Knowledge is power. (Any)

d6 | Bond
1 | I was picked on while growing up for being a bookworm.
2 | The world is such an open place, I feel like there is still so much to learn. I want to compile knowledge from different places.
3 | I like reading books and writing, but I'm no poet yet. It is just a hobby I want to share with others, looking for exotic inspirations.
4 | I will become the power behind the throne by controlling the information the throne receives.
5 | Children are our future, and I will mold them.
6 | I can't teach what I don't know. I will teach everything.

d6 | Flaw
1 | Someone showing bad manners does not exist to me. I will never talk to or acknowledge that person.
2 | I overemphasize the importance of discipline.
3 | I invest so much time into planning that I can't bring myself to deviate from the plan, even when it is needed.
4 | I look down on uneducated adults.
5 | I'd give up my companions for a piece of secret information.
6 | I can't stand not reading at least one page of a book a day.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Urchin (Star Wars 5e EC)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth
Tools: Disguise kit, security kit
Language: 
Equipment: A small knife, a map of the city you grew up in, a pet mouse, a token to remember your parents by, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty: N/A</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: City of Secrets</name>
      <text>You know the secret patterns and flows to cities and can find passages through the urban sprawl that others would miss. When you are not in combat, you (and companions you lead) can travel between any two locations in the city twice as fast as your speed would normally allow.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Quick-Fingered
4 | Stealthy
5 | Master of Disguise
6 | Bypasser
7 | Alert
8 | Athlete</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Urchins are shaped by lives of desperate poverty, for good and for ill. They tend to be driven either by a commitment to the people with whom they shared life on the street or by a burning desire to find a better life— and maybe get some payback on all the rich people who treated them badly.

Personality:
1 | I hide scraps of food and trinkets away in my pockets.
2 | I ask a lot of questions.
3 | I like to squeeze into small places where no one else can get to me.
4 | I sleep with my back to a wall or tree, with everything I own wrapped in a bundle in my arms.
5 | I eat like a pig and have bad manners.
6 | I think anyone who's nice to me is hiding Dark intent.
7 | I don't like to bathe.
8 | I bluntly say what other people are hinting at or hiding.

Ideals:
1 | Respect. All people, rich or poor, deserve respect. (Light)
2 | Community. We have to take care of each other, because no one else is going to do it. (Lawful)
3 | Change. The low are lifted up, and the high and mighty are brought down. Change is the nature of things. (Chaotic)
4 | Retribution. The rich need to be shown what life and death are like in the gutters. (Dark)
5 | People. I help the people who help me, that's what keeps us alive. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I'm going to prove that I'm worthy of a better life. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My town or city is my home, and I'll fight to defend it.
2 | I sponsor an orphanage to keep others from enduring what I was forced to endure.
3 | I owe my survival to another urchin who taught me to live on the streets.
4 | I owe a debt I can never repay to the person who took pity on me.
5 | I escaped my life of poverty by robbing an important person, and I'm wanted for it.
6 | No one else should have to endure the hardships I've been through.

Flaw:
1 | If I'm outnumbered, I will run away from a fight.
2 | Gold seems like a lot of money to me, and I'll do just about anything for more of it.
3 | I will never fully trust anyone other than myself.
4 | I'd rather kill someone in their sleep then fight fair.
5 | It's not stealing if I need it more than someone else.
6 | People who can't take care of themselves get what they deserve.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Urchin (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiencies &amp; Equipment</name>
      <text>Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth
Tools: Disguise kit, security kit
Language: 
Equipment: A small knife, a map of the city you grew up in, a pet mouse, a token to remember your parents by, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 cr

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: City of Secrets</name>
      <text>You know the secret patterns and flows to cities and can find passages through the urban sprawl that others would miss. When you are not in combat, you (and companions you lead) can travel between any two locations in the city twice as fast as your speed would normally allow.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Background Feat</name>
      <text>As a further embodiment of the experience and training of your background, you can choose from the following feats:

d8 | Feat
1 | Silver-Tongued
2 | Empathic
3 | Quick-Fingered
4 | Stealthy
5 | Specialist
6 | Alert
7 | Athlete
8 | Observant</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Urchins are shaped by lives of desperate poverty, for good and for ill. They tend to be driven either by a commitment to the people with whom they shared life on the street or by a burning desire to find a better life— and maybe get some payback on all the rich people who treated them badly.

Personality:
1 | I hide scraps of food and trinkets away in my pockets.
2 | I ask a lot of questions.
3 | I like to squeeze into small places where no one else can get to me.
4 | I sleep with my back to a wall or tree, with everything I own wrapped in a bundle in my arms.
5 | I eat like a pig and have bad manners.
6 | I think anyone who's nice to me is hiding Dark intent.
7 | I don't like to bathe.
8 | I bluntly say what other people are hinting at or hiding.

Ideals:
1 | Respect. All people, rich or poor, deserve respect. (Light)
2 | Community. We have to take care of each other, because no one else is going to do it. (Lawful)
3 | Change. The low are lifted up, and the high and mighty are brought down. Change is the nature of things. (Chaotic)
4 | Retribution. The rich need to be shown what life and death are like in the gutters. (Dark)
5 | People. I help the people who help me, that's what keeps us alive. (Neutral)
6 | Aspiration. I'm going to prove that I'm worthy of a better life. (Any)

Bond:
1 | My town or city is my home, and I'll fight to defend it.
2 | I sponsor an orphanage to keep others from enduring what I was forced to endure.
3 | I owe my survival to another urchin who taught me to live on the streets.
4 | I owe a debt I can never repay to the person who took pity on me.
5 | I escaped my life of poverty by robbing an important person, and I'm wanted for it.
6 | No one else should have to endure the hardships I've been through.

Flaw:
1 | If I'm outnumbered, I will run away from a fight.
2 | Gold seems like a lot of money to me, and I'll do just about anything for more of it.
3 | I will never fully trust anyone other than myself.
4 | I'd rather kill someone in their sleep then fight fair.
5 | It's not stealing if I need it more than someone else.
6 | People who can't take care of themselves get what they deserve.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
