<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <class>
    <name>Scout (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <hd>10</hd>
    <proficiency>Strength Saving Throws, Dexterity Saving Throws, Animal Handling, Arcana, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Perception, Religion, Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
    <numSkills>3</numSkills>
    <armor>Light armor, medium armor</armor>
    <weapons>All blasters, all vibroweapons</weapons>
    <tools>None</tools>
    <wealth>1000+5d4x100</wealth>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <slots>4,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <slots>5,3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4">
      <slots>6,4</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <slots>7,0,5</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <slots>8,0,6</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <slots>9,0,7</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <slots>10,0,8</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <slots>11,0,0,9</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <slots>12,0,0,10</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <slots>13,0,0,11</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12">
      <slots>14,0,0,12</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <slots>15,0,0,0,13</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <slots>16,0,0,0,14</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <slots>16,0,0,0,15</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16">
      <slots>16,0,0,0,16</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <slots>17,0,0,0,0,17</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <slots>17,0,0,0,0,18</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <slots>17,0,0,0,0,19</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <slots>18,0,0,0,0,20</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Starting Scout</name>
        <text>As a 1st-level Scout, you begin play with 10+your Constitution modifier hit points.

You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your background.

	• Armor: Light armor, medium armor
	• Weapons: All blasters, all vibroweapons
	• Tools: None
	• Skills: Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Perception, Piloting* (Religion), Stealth, Survival, and Technology* (Arcana)

Equipment:
You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background

	• (a) light battle armor or (b) combat suit, blaster carbine, and two power cells
	• (a) a simple vibroweapon and a light or medium shield generator or (b) two simple vibroweapons
	• (a) a hold-out and a power cell or (b) two vibrodaggers
	• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack
	• A wristpad

Variant - Starting Wealth:
In lieu of the equipment granted by your class and background, you can elect to purchase your starting gear. If you do so, you receive no equipment from your class and background, and instead roll for your starting wealth using the criteria below:

	Funds = 1,000 + 5d4 x 100 cr

Important Note:
Fight Club 5 only uses standard Fifth Edition Skills, so we have mapped the skills in Star Wars 5e that are different this way.

	• History = Lore
	• Arcana = Technology
	• Religion = Piloting</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Scout</name>
        <text>To multiclass as a Scout, you must meet the following prerequisites:

	• Strength or Dexterity 13, Intelligence 13

You gain the following proficiencies:

	• Light armor, medium armor, all blasters, all vibroweapons, one skill from the class's skill list: Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Perception, Piloting* (Religion), Stealth, Survival, and Technology* (Arcana)

Important Note:
Fight Club 5 only uses standard Fifth Edition Skills, so we have mapped the skills in Star Wars 5e that are different this way.

	• History = Lore
	• Arcana = Technology
	• Religion = Piloting</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Swift Response</name>
        <text>Beginning at 1st level, you learn to react with swift and decisive action in combat. You gain the following benefits:

	• You ignore difficult terrain.
	• You add your proficiency bonus to initiative rolls.
	• On your first turn during combat, you have advantage on attack rolls against creatures that have not yet acted.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger's Quarry</name>
        <text>Also 1st level, you learn how to effectively read and track your prey. On your turn, you can choose a creature you can see within 90 feet and mark it as your quarry (no action required). For the next 10 minutes, you gain the following benefits:

	• Once per round, when you hit the target with a weapon attack, you can deal 1d4 additional damage to it of the same type as the weapon's damage. This die changes as you gain scout levels, as shown in the Ranger's Quarry Damage Die column of the scout class table.
	• You have advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) or Wisdom (Survival) check you make to find it while it's on the same planet as you.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.

Starting at 9th level, you can expend two uses of this feature to extend the duration to 8 hours. At 17th level, you can expend three uses to extend the duration to 24 hours.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Techcasting</name>
        <text>Also at 2nd level, you have derived powers from schematics with the aid of your wristpad. See chapter 10 for the general rules of techcasting and chapter 12 for the tech powers list.

Tech Powers Known:
You learn 4 tech powers of your choice, and you learn more at higher levels, as shown in the Tech Powers Known column of the Scout class table. You may not learn a tech power of a level higher than your Max Power Level.

Tech Points:
You have a number of tech points equal to your scout level, as shown in the Tech Points column of the scout class table, + your Intelligence modifier. You use these tech points to cast tech powers. You regain all expended tech points when you finish a short or long rest.

Max Power Level:
Many tech powers can be overcharged, consuming more tech points to create a greater effect. You can overcharge these powers to a maximum level, which increases at higher levels, as shown in the Max Power Level column of the Scout class table.
	You may only cast tech powers at 4th and 5th-level once. You regain the ability to do so after a long rest.

Techcasting Ability:
Intelligence is your techcasting ability for your tech powers. You use your Intelligence whenever a power refers to your techcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a tech power you cast and when making an attack roll with one.

	Tech save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus +your Intelligence modifier

	Tech attack modifier = your proficiency bonus +your Intelligence modifier

Techcasting Focus:
You use a wristpad (found in chapter 5) as a techcasting focus for your tech powers.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Fighting Style</name>
        <text>Beginning at 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Brawling</name>
        <text>You are skilled at using your weight to your advantage. As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a medium or heavy shield, you gain the following benefits:

	• You are proficient with improvised weapons.
	• Your unarmed strikes use a d4 for damage.
	• When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike or an improvised weapon on your turn, you can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooting</name>
        <text>You are skilled at getting up close and personal with ranged weapons. While you are wielding a ranged weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:
When making a ranged weapon attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll.
	Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover against targets within 15 feet of you.
	You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
        <special>Fighting Style: Defense</special>
        <text>You are skilled at the art of defending yourself. While you are wearing armor with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	• You have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to avoid being moved.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
        <special>Fighting Style: Dueling</special>
        <text>You are skilled in the art of fighting with a single melee weapon. While you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand with which you are proficient and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name>
        <text>You are skilled at putting the weight of a weapon to your advantage. While you are wielding a melee weapon in two hands with which you are proficient, when you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Equilibrium</name>
        <text>You are skilled at fighting while minimally armored. While you are wearing no armor and not wielding a medium or heavy shield, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	• You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with unarmed strikes and weapon attacks.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Sentinel</name>
        <text>You are skilled at techniques that take advantage of every drop in any enemy's guard. While you are wielding a melee weapon with which you are proficient, you can use a bonus action to enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make a number of opportunity attacks equal to your proficiency bonus without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Sharpshooting</name>
        <special>Fighting Style: Archery</special>
        <text>You are skilled with ranged weapons and can make shots that others find difficult. While you are wielding a ranged weapon with which you are proficient, gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Shielding</name>
        <text>You are skilled at using your shield to defend your allies as well as yourself. While you are wielding a medium or heavy shield with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:
When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll.
	If you are wielding a heavy shield, you are no longer required to wield a weapon with the light property in the other hand.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Throwing</name>
        <text>You are skilled with the techniques of throwing weapons. While you are wielding a weapon with the thrown property with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to ranged attack and damage rolls.
	• Whenever you make a ranged attack with a thrown weapon, you can immediately draw another weapon as part of the attack.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name>
        <special>Fighting Style: Dueling</special>
        <text>You are skilled at fighting with two weapons. While you are wielding separate weapons in each hand with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of your two-weapon fighting attack.
	• When you make an opportunity attack, you can attack with both of your weapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Versatile Fighting</name>
        <text>You are skilled at using weapons in different ways. While you are wielding a melee weapon with the versatile property with which you are proficient and no other weapons, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls while wielding a weapon in one hand.
	• You gain a +1 bonus to damage rolls while wielding a weapon in two hands.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Pathfinder</name>
        <text>Beginning at 3rd level, you are skilled at navigating the untamed wilds. You gain the following benefits when traveling for an hour or more:

	• Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel.
	• You can't become lost by unenhanced means.
	• Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.
	• If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.
	• When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.
	• When you make a Wisdom (Survival) check, you gain a bonus to the check equal to your Intelligence modifier.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger's Quarry Damage Die Improvement (1d6)</name>
        <text>You can now deal 1d6 additional damage to the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Extra Attack</name>
        <text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature>
        <name>Expertise</name>
        <text>At 6th level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of skill proficiencies and one of your tool proficiencies, or two of your tool proficiencies. You gain expertise in those skills or tools.

At 14th level, you can choose another two proficiencies (in skills or tools) to gain this benefit.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level, and again at 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger's Quarry Improvement (8 hours)</name>
        <text>Starting at 9th level, you can expend two uses of your Ranger's Quarry feature to extend the duration to 8 hours. At 17th level, you can expend three uses to extend the duration to 24 hours.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger's Quarry Damage Die Improvement (1d8)</name>
        <text>You can now deal 1d8 additional damage to the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
        <text>When you reach 10th level, and again at 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Commando</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, you can take the Dash and Hide actions as a bonus action on each of your turns. Additionally, you can remain perfectly still for long periods of time to set up ambushes.

When you attempt to hide on your turn, you can opt to not move on that turn. If you avoid moving, creatures that attempt to detect you take a -10 penalty to their Wisdom (Perception) checks until the start of your next turn. You lose this benefit if you move or fall prone, either voluntarily or because of some external effect. You are still automatically detected if any effect or action causes you to no longer be hidden.

If you are still hidden on your next turn, you can continue to remain motionless and gain this benefit until you are detected.

Additionally, you can no longer be tracked by unenhanced means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level, and again at 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger's Quarry Damage Die Improvement (1d10)</name>
        <text>You can now deal 1d10 additional damage to the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature>
        <name>Expertise</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you can choose another two proficiencies (in skills or tools). You gain expertise in those skills or tools.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Combat Tech</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you use your action to cast a tech power, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level, and again at 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger's Quarry Improvement (24 hours)</name>
        <text>Starting at 17th level, you can expend three uses to extend the duration to 24 hours.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Ranger's Quarry Damage Die Improvement (1d12)</name>
        <text>You can now deal 1d12 additional damage to the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Supreme Awareness</name>
        <text>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can't see. When you attack a creature you can't see, your inability to see it doesn't impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it.

You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn't hidden from you and you aren't blinded or deafened.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (6th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Foe Slayer</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you become an unparalleled hunter. Your Strength or Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 2. Your maximum for those scores increases by 2.

Additionally, once on each of your turns, you can add your Intelligence modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Intelligence Bonus +2</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Scout Technique: Bulwark Technique -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Scout Technique: Bulwark Technique</name>
        <text>Some scouts find themselves far from civilization not to hunt, gather intelligence, or escape danger, but to venture forth simply to defend those unable to defend themselves. Followers of the Bulwark Technique make use of advanced technology to contain those that threaten the undeserving.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiency: Heavy Armor (Bulwark Technique)</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in heavy armor.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Personal Barrier (Bulwark Technique)</name>
        <text>When you choose this technique at 3rd level, you gain access to a powerful personal barrier. Whenever you complete a short or long rest, you create a barrier on yourself that lasts until you finish a short or long rest. That barrier has hit points equal to twice your scout level + your Intelligence modifier. Your barrier can never have hit points greater than twice your scout level + your Intelligence modifier.

Whenever you take damage, the barrier takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the barrier to 0 hit points, you take any remaining damage.

While the barrier has 0 hit points, it can't absorb damage, but its power remains. Whenever you cast a tech power of 1st level or higher, your barrier regains hit points equal to the number of tech points spent.

Additionally, for as long as your barrier has hit points, you gain the following benefits:

	• You are considered proficient in Constitution saving throws for the purpose of maintaining concentration on tech powers.
	• Hostile creatures that hit you with melee attacks take energy damage equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark Of The Bulwark (Bulwark Technique)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, when the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature makes a melee attack against a friendly creature within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to force the attack to target you instead. If the attack hits, and your Personal Barrier has hit points, the attacking creatures takes bonus damage equal to your Ranger's Quarry Damage Die.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Projected Barrier (Bulwark Technique)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, you've learned how to manipulate your barrier to create new effects. As an action, you can spend three of your barrier's hit points to create a unique effect. You have three such effects: Projected Sphere, Projected Maelstrom, and Projected Wave. When you use your Projected Barrier, you choose which effect to create.

Some Projected Barrier Effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your tech save DC.

If your barrier's hit points are reduced to 0, any Projected Barrier features immediately end.

Projected Sphere:
You create a protective spherical barrier barrier in a 5-foot-radius sphere a point you can see within 30 feet that lasts until the start of your next turn. Creatures within the barrier have three-quarters cover from attacks originating from outside the barrier. You can maintain the barrier by spending an additional barrier hit point at the start of each of your turns (no action required).

Projected Maelstrom:
You create an unstable energy maelstrom in a 5-foot cube at a point you can see within 30 feet that lasts until the start of your next turn. A creature takes 4d4 energy damage when it enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there. You can maintain the barrier by spending an additional barrier hit point at the start of each of your turns (no action required).

This feature's damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 11th level (5d4) and 17th level (6d4).

Projected Wave:
You create a wave of barrier energy in a 15-foot cone. Each creature within the cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 energy damage and is pushed back to the edge of the cone. On a success, they take half damage and aren't pushed.

This feature's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 11th level (3d6) and 17th level (4d6).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Regenerative Shielding (Bulwark Technique)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, when a hostile creature forces you to make a saving throw and you succeed, your personal barrier regains hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Adaptive Barrier (Bulwark Technique)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, when your personal barrier takes damage, you can have it gain resistance to subsequent damage of that type until the start of your next turn (no action required). If it takes damage of more than one type simultaneously, you can choose which type it gains resistance to. Your barrier can only have resistance to one type of damage at a time.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Scout Technique: Deadeye Technique -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Scout Technique: Deadeye Technique</name>
        <text>Some scouts becomes legends written in blaster burns. Followers of the Deadeye Technique the art of the blaster shot and utilize their incredible focus to make shots that most would deem impossible. When everything depends on one shot, you want a Deadeye pulling the trigger.

Due to their uncanny focus, Deadeyes can make shots that other marksmen would never dare to attempt. Deadeyes know how to make the most of ranged weapons and can use them to greater effect than other Scouts.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Focused Superiority (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>When you choose this technique at 3rd level, you learn maneuvers that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.

Maneuvers:
You know two maneuvers of your choice, which are detailed under "Maneuvers" below, and you earn more at higher levels, as shown in the Maneuvers Known column of the Deadeye Technique Focused Superiority table. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack, and you may only use each maneuver once per turn.
	Each time you learn new maneuvers, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.

Superiority Dice:
You have two superiority dice, which are d6s, and you earn more at higher levels, as shown in the Superiority Dice column of the Deadeye Technique Focused Superiority table. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.

Saving Throws:
Some of your maneuvers require your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver's effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:

	Maneuver save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark Of The Deadeye (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, the range of your Ranger's Quarry feature doubles. Additionally, when making ranged weapon attacks against the target of your Ranger's Quarry, the normal and long range of your ranged weapons double.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Focused Superiority Die Improvement (d8/3) (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>Your superiority dice are now d8s.
	You now have three superiority dice, and you earn more at higher levels, as shown in the Superiority Dice column of the Deadeye Technique Focused Superiority table.

You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Maneuvers Known Increase (3) (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>You now know three maneuvers of your choice, which are detailed under "Maneuvers" below, and you earn more at higher levels, as shown in the Maneuvers Known column of the Deadeye Technique Focused Superiority table. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack, and you may only use each maneuver once per turn.

Each time you learn new maneuvers, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cover to Cover (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, attack rolls made against you on your turn are made with disadvantage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Focused Superiority Die Improvement (d10/3) (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>Your superiority dice are now d10s.
	You have three superiority dice, and you earn more at higher levels, as shown in the Superiority Dice column of the Deadeye Technique Focused Superiority table.

You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Maneuvers Known Increase (4) (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>You now know four maneuvers of your choice, which are detailed under "Maneuvers" below, and you earn more at higher levels, as shown in the Maneuvers Known column of the Deadeye Technique Focused Superiority table. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack, and you may only use each maneuver once per turn.

Each time you learn new maneuvers, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shoot First (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, you have learned that the person who shoots first is often the one who walks out alive. When you make a ranged weapon attack against a creature that has not yet acted during your first turn in combat and you have advantage on the roll, you can reroll one of the dice once.

Additionally, on a hit, you deal an extra 1d6 damage of the same type as the weapon.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Maneuvers Known Increase (5) (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>You now know five maneuvers of your choice, which are detailed under "Maneuvers" below, and you earn more at higher levels, as shown in the Maneuvers Known column of the Deadeye Technique Focused Superiority table. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack, and you may only use each maneuver once per turn.

Each time you learn new maneuvers, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Overwatch (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, you have become a master at protecting your allies from afar. When a creature attempts to make an opportunity attack against an allied creature, or forces your ally to make a saving throw, you can use your reaction to make an attack roll against the enemy creature.

If your attack hits, either impose disadvantage on the enemy creature's opportunity attack roll or grant advantage to any allies making the saving throw.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Focused Superiority Die Improvement (d12/4) (Deadeye Technique)</name>
        <text>Your superiority dice are now d12s.
	You now have four superiority dice, and you earn more at higher levels, as shown in the Superiority Dice column of the Deadeye Technique Focused Superiority table.

You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Scout Technique: Hunter Technique -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Scout Technique: Hunter Technique</name>
        <text>Some scouts seek to master weapons to better protect civilization from the terrors of their enemies. Followers of the Hunter Technique learn specialized fighting techniques for use against the most dire threats, from an onslaught of soldiers to towering walkers.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Hunter's Prey (Hunter Technique)</name>
        <text>When you choose this technique at 3rd level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.

Colossus Slayer:
Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it's below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.

Giant Killer:
When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.

Horde Breaker:
Once on each of your turns when you make a weapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon, no action required.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark of the Hunter (Hunter Technique)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, when you use your Ranger's Quarry feature, the first time you make a tech or weapon attack against the target of your Ranger's Quarry each round, roll your Ranger's Quarry Damage Die and add it to the roll.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Defensive Tactics (Hunter Technique)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.

Escape The Horde:
Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.

Multiattack Defense:
When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.

Steel Will:
You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiattack (Hunter Technique)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.

Volley:
You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon's range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.

Whirlwind Attack:
You can use your action to make melee attacks against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Superior Hunter's Defense (Hunter Technique)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.

Evasion:
When you are subjected to an effect, such as a consular's force storm or an engineer's explosion, that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on a saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.

Stand Against the Tide:
When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attac against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.

Uncanny Dodge:
When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Scout Technique: Illusionist Technique -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Scout Technique: Illusionist Technique</name>
        <text>Among the galaxy you may find the various infiltrators and agents who make ample use of holographic technology to get themselves in and out of danger. Followers of the Illusionist Technique make use of this holographic technology to give themselves an illusory edge in combat.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Holographic Decoy (Illusionist Technique)</name>
        <text>When you choose this technique at 3rd level, as an action, you can create a perfect illusion of yourself that lasts for 10 minutes, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a power). The decoy appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. The decoy is purely visual. If anything passes through it, it is revealed to be an illusion. For the duration, you can cast tech powers as though you were in the decoy's space. Both your decoy and the target of your tech power must be within your line of sight.

You can use your bonus action to cause the decoy to move up to 30 feet. As your decoy changes location, you can alter its appearance so that its movements appear natural for the decoy. If your decoy is ever more than 120 feet away from you, it immediately disappears.

Additionally, when both you and your decoy are within 5 feet of a creature that can see the decoy, but is not aware it is an illusion, you have advantage on attack rolls against that creature.

A creature that uses its action to examine your decoy can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your tech save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the creature can see through the image.

Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark of the Illusionist (Illusionist Technique)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature has disadvantage on all checks made to discern the nature of your illusions. Additionally, when the target of your Ranger's Quarry is reduced to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to immediately cause an active illusion, or your Holographic Decoy, to take the form of the creature as long as the creature's dimensions fall within the power's capacity restrictions.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Charged Illusions (Illusionist Technique)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, when a creature discerns the nature of an illusion you have created using a tech power or class feature while within 5 feet of it, you can dispel the illusion (no action required) to have the creature take energy damage equal to 1d10 + half your scout level (rounded down).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Quick Escape (Illusionist Technique)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, whenever you take damage, you can use your reaction to swap places with an illusion of yourself that you have created using a tech power or class feature. The illusion must be within 60 feet of you, and you must be able to see it.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Improved Decoys (Illusionist Technique)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, you can create up to four duplicates of yourself, instead of one, when you use your Holographic Decoy feature. When you use your bonus action to move a decoy, you can move any number of them with the same bonus action.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Scout Technique: Inquisitor Technique -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Scout Technique: Inquisitor Technique</name>
        <text>Across history, there have been those who live to hunt those who wield the Force, be they Jedi or Sith. Followers of the Inquisitor Technique combine technology with force techniques to track down and eliminate force-wielders. For those practitioners of the Force, they are the greatest adversary.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Whispers of the Force (Inquisitor Technique)</name>
        <text>When you choose this technique at 3rd level, you have learned secrets from a subtle attunement to the force. Choose two force powers of no higher level than your Max Power Level, as shown in the scout class table. The chosen powers count as tech powers for you, but are not included in the number in the Powers Known column of the scout class table.

You learn two additional powers at 5th, 9th, and 13th level. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the force powers you know and replace it with another force power of no higher level than your Max Power Level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark of the Inquisitor (Inquisitor Technique)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, when the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature is within 15 feet of you, you gain the following benefits:

	• Whenever the creature casts a force power, it must first succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your tech save DC to maintain concentration. On a failed save, the casting is disrupted, the force power fails, and the force points are wasted.
	• Whenever the creature starts its turn while concentrating on a force power, it must make a Constitution saving throw against your force save DC to maintain concentration. On a failed save, it loses concentration on the power.

At 11th level, the radius of this feature increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sense Force (Inquisitor Technique)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, you can use your action to gain the benefits of the force sight force power until the end of your next turn.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark of the Inquisitor Improvement (Inquisitor Technique)</name>
        <text>At 11th level, the radius of your Mark of the Inquisitor feature increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force Resistance (Inquisitor Technique)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, while the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature is within 30 feet of you, you gain the following benefits:

	• You have advantage on saving throws against force powers they cast.
	• You have resistance to damage dealt by force powers they cast.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Inquisitor's Wrath (Inquisitor Technique)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, you can cast the force suppression and sever force force powers at 3rd level against the target of your Ranger's Quarry without expending tech points. If they are within 30 feet of you, you have advantage on the forcecasting ability check for these powers.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Scout Technique: Predator Technique -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Scout Technique: Predator Technique</name>
        <text>Some scouts work in solitude, while others prefer the strength of a group. Followers of the Predator Technique find power lies with the pack; they distract their prey, while their allies go for the kill.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Predator Technique)</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in heavy armor.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark of the Predator (Predator Technique)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, if the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature can see you, a number of friendly creatures you choose up to your Intelligence modifier have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide from it.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Predator's Resolve (Predator Technique)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:

	• You have advantage on Constitution saving throws.
	• At the start of each of your turns, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of one).
	• When you use your Hunting Party feature and the target of the attack is your Ranger's Quarry, your ally gains a bonus to damage on the attack equal to your Ranger's Quarry Damage Die.

Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Prey on the Weak (Predator Technique)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, and the creature is below its hit point maximum, the next attack roll made against that creature before the end of your next turn by someone other than you has advantage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>On The Hunt (Predator Technique)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, when you use your Predator's Resolve feature, a number of friendly creatures you choose up to your Intelligence modifier that you can see within 30 feet of you also gain the benefits of the feature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Scout Technique: Slayer Technique -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Scout Technique: Slayer Technique</name>
        <text>Some scouts seek to learn the most about their foes and to capitalize on that knowledge. Follower of the Slayer Technique focus on identifying the strengths and weaknesses of their prey, taking advantage of that knowledge to vanquish their foes.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Slayer Technique)</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in heavy armor.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Slayer's Pride (Slayer Technique)</name>
        <text>When you choose this technique at 3rd level, you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark of the Slayer (Slayer Technique)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you immediately learn if the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature has any damage immunities, resistances, or vulnerabilities and what they are. Additionally, the first time you hit the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature with a weapon attack each turn, it takes extra damage equal to your Ranger's Quarry Damage Die. The damage is of the same type as the weapon's damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Supernatural Defense (Slayer Technique)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, whenever the target of your Ranger's Quarry forces you to make a saving throw, or whenever you make an ability check to escape that targets grapple, you can use your reaction and roll your Ranger's Quarry Damage Die, adding it to the roll.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Nemesis (Slayer Technique)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, when you score a critical hit or reduce a creature to 0 hit points on your turn, you can use your bonus action to force one creature of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw against your tech save DC. On a failed save, a creature becomes frightened of you for 1 minute. At the end of each of the creature's turns it repeats this saving throw, ending the effect on a success.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Slayer's Counter (Slayer Technique)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, if the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature forces you to make a saving throw, you can use your reaction to make one weapon attack against it. You make this attack immediately before making the saving throw. If your attack hits, you automatically succeed on the saving throw, in addition to the attack's normal effects.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Scout Technique: Stalker Technique -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Scout Technique: Stalker Technique</name>
        <text>Some Scouts become consumed by the thrill of the hunt. Only heard and never seen they revel in the violence of battle. Followers of the Stalker Technique hone their abilities to track others utilizing a variety of techniques: camouflage, infiltration, surveillance, and target acquisition.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Accomplished Ambusher (Stalker Technique)</name>
        <text>When you choose this technique at 3rd level, when you take the Attack action against a creature that is surprised, you can make one additional attack against that creature as a part of that action.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mark of the Stalker (Stalker Technique)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, while you are hidden from the target of your Ranger's Quarry feature, the first attack roll you make each round against that creature does not automatically reveal your presence to that creature. Make a Dexterity (Stealth) check contested by your target's Wisdom (Perception) check. On a success, you remain hidden. If you are less than 30 feet from your target, the Dexterity (Stealth) check is made with disadvantage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Concealment (Stalker Technique)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, you've become adept at evading creatures that rely on darkvision. While in darkness, you are invisible to any creature that relies on darkvision to see you in that darkness.

Additionally, when you hit a creature with a ranged weapon attack while hidden, you can force that creature to make a Dexterity saving throw against your tech save DC. On a failed save, the creature's speed is reduced to 0 until the end of your next turn. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Stalker's Flurry (Stalker Technique)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, if you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Stalker's Dodge (Stalker Technique)</name>
        <text>At 15th level, whenever a creature attacks you and does not have advantage, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the creature's attack roll against you. You can use this feature before or after the attack roll is made, but it must be used before the outcome of the roll is determined.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
