<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <class>
    <name>Berseker (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <hd>12</hd>
    <proficiency>Strength Saving Throws, Constitution Saving Throws, Animal Handling, Athletics, Intimidation, Nature, Perception, Survival</proficiency>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>
    <armor>Light armor, medium armor</armor>
    <weapons>All vibroweapons, simple blasters</weapons>
    <tools>None</tools>
    <wealth>1000+2d4x100</wealth>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Starting Berserker</name>
        <text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background

	• (a) a martial vibroweapon and a light or medium shield generator or (b) two martial vibroweapons
	• (a) two techaxes or (b) two vibrospears
	• An explorer's pack

Variant - Starting Wealth:
In lieu of the equipment granted by your class and background, you can elect to purchase your starting gear. If you do so, you receive no equipment from your class and background, and instead roll for your starting wealth using the criteria below:

	Berserker = 1,000 + 2d4 x 100 cr

Important Note:
Fight Club 5 only uses standard Fifth Edition Skills, so we have mapped the skills in Star Wars 5e that are different this way.

	• History = Lore
	• Arcana = Technology
	• Religion = Piloting</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Berserker</name>
        <text>To multiclass as a Berserker, you must meet the following prerequisites:
 • Strength 13

You gain the following proficiencies
	• Light armor, all vibroweapons</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Rage</name>
        <text>In battle, you fight with primal ferocity. On your turn, you can enter a rage as a bonus action.
While raging, you gain the following benefits if you aren't wearing heavy armor:

	• You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.
	• When you make a melee weapon attack using Strength, you gain a bonus to the damage roll that increases as you gain levels as a berserker, as shown in the Rage Damage column of the Berserker table.
	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage.

If you are able to cast powers, you can't cast them or concentrate on them while raging. Your rage lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are knocked unconscious or if your turn ends and you haven't attacked a hostile creature since your last turn or taken damage since then. You can also end your rage on your turn as a bonus action.
	Once you have raged the maximum number of times for your berserker level in the Rages column of the Berserker table, you must finish a long rest before you can rage again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Defense</name>
        <special>Unarmored Defense: Constitution, Unarmored Defense: Dexterity</special>
        <text>While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Danger Sense</name>
        <text>At 2nd level, you gain an uncanny sense of when things nearby aren't as they should be, giving you an edge when you dodge away from danger. You have advantage on Dexterity saving throws against effects that you can see, such as traps and spells. To gain this benefit, you can't be blinded, deafened, or incapacitated.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Reckless Attack</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can throw aside all concern for defense to attack with fierce desperation. When you make your first attack on your turn, you can decide to attack recklessly. Doing so gives you advantage on melee weapon attack rolls using Strength during this turn, but attack rolls against you have advantage until your next turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Overdrive Enhancement</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you gain a cybernetic enhancement. Choose one of the following enhancements and gain its feature. You must undergo cybernetic surgery by a person proficient in biotech's tools that incorporates this enhancement into your body. This surgery costs 100 credits and takes 8 hours.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Overdrive Enhancement: Dermal Armor</name>
        <text>While raging you have resistance to all damage except psychic damage.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Overdrive Enhancement: Morbid Protrusions</name>
        <text>While raging, your unarmed strike deals 1d4 + Strength modifier kinetic damage and when you take the Attack action and attack with a melee weapon or unarmed strike, you can use a bonus action to make an unarmed attack.
	This unarmed attack die increases to 1d6 at 5th level, 1d8 at 11th level, and 1d10 at 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Overdrive Enhancement: Pressurized Limbs</name>
        <text>While raging, you can use your bonus action to leap up to 30 feet to an empty space you can see. When you land you deal kinetic damage equal to your Strength modifier to each creature within 5 feet of where you land. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Consitution modifier (minimum of one). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Overdrive Enhancement: Twitchlock Activators</name>
        <text>While you're raging, other creatures have disadvantage on opportunity attack rolls against you, you can also use the Dash action as a bonus action on your turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Berserker Approach</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you choose an approach that shapes the nature of your rage which is detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th levels.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Extra Attack</name>
        <text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Fast Movement</name>
        <text>Starting at 5th level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you aren't wearing heavy armor.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Speed +10</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature>
        <name>Support Enhancement</name>
        <text>At 6th level you gain an additional cybernetic enhancement. Choose one of the following enhancements and gain its feature. You must undergo cybernetic surgery by a person proficient in biotech's tools that incorporates this enhancement into your body. This surgery costs 600 credits and takes 8 hours.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Support Enhancement: Body Sculpting</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in two skills of your choice from Athletics, Acrobatics, Stealth, and Sleight of Hand.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Support Enhancement: Holdout Cavity</name>
        <text>You have a shielded compartment built into your body that can be used to store and hide a light weapon or item of similar size.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Support Enhancement: Krykna Anchors</name>
        <text>You gain a climbing speed equal to your movement speed.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Support Enhancement: Panspectral Optics</name>
        <text>You can see up to 1 mile away with no difficulty. You are able to discern even fine details as though looking at something no more than 100 feet away from you. Additionally, dim light doesn't impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Support Enhancement: Support Structure</name>
        <text>Your carrying capacity (including maximum load and maximum lift) is doubled and you have advantage on Strength checks made to push, pull, lift, or break objects.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature>
        <name>Feral Instinct</name>
        <text>By 7th level, your instincts are so honed that you have advantage on initiative rolls.

Additionally, if you are surprised at the start of combat and aren't incapacitated, you can act normally on your first turn, but only if you enter your rage before doing anything else on that turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature>
        <name>Brutal Critical (1 die)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 9th level, you can roll one additional weapon damage die when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.
	This increases to two additional dice at 13th level and three additional dice at 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Relentless Rage</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, your rage can keep you fighting despite grievous wounds. If you drop to 0 hit points while you're raging and don't die outright, you can make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw. If you succeed, you drop to 1 hit point instead.

Each time you use this feature after the first, the DC increases by 5. When you finish a short or long rest, the DC resets to 10.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Increased Rages</name>
        <text>You may now rage 5 times before a long rest</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature>
        <name>Brutal Critical (2 dice)</name>
        <text>You now roll two additional weapon damage dice when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature>
        <name>Final Enhancement</name>
        <text>At 14th level you gain a final cybernetic enhancement. Choose one of the following enhancements and gain its feature. You must undergo cybernetic surgery by a person proficient in biotech's tools that incorporates this enhancement into your body. This surgery costs 2000 credits and takes 8 hours.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Final Enhancement: Holoskin Emitters</name>
        <text>While you're raging any creature within 5 feet of you that's hostile to you has disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you or another character with this feature. An enemy is immune to this effect if it can't see or hear you or if it can't be frightened.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Final Enhancement: Hydraulic Overrides</name>
        <text>While you're raging you can use a bonus action on your turn to knock a Large or smaller creature prone when you hit it with melee weapon attack.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Final Enhancement: Integrated Boosters</name>
        <text>While raging you have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed. This benefit works only in short bursts; you fall if you end your turn in the air and nothing else is holding you aloft.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Final Enhancement: Ysalamir Capacitor Mesh</name>
        <text>When you are forced to make a saving throw against a force power, you can immediately use your reaction to move up to half your speed towards the source power's caster. If you end this movement within 5 feet of the target, you can immediately make one melee weapon attack against the target as a part of that reaction.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature>
        <name>Persistent Rage</name>
        <text>Beginning at 15th level, your rage is so fierce that it ends early only if you fall unconscious or if you choose to end it.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Increased Rage Damage</name>
        <text>You now have a +4 bonus to melee damage rolls while raging.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature>
        <name>Brutal Critical (3 dice)</name>
        <text>You now roll three additional weapon damage dice when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Increased Rages</name>
        <text>You may now rage 6 times before a long rest</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Indomitable Might</name>
        <text>Beginning at 18th level, if your total for a Strength check is less than your Strength score, you can use that score in place of the total.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Primal Champion</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you embody the power of the wilds. Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 4. Your maximum for those scores is now 24.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Proficiency Bonus +4</modifier>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Proficiency Bonus +4</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Berserker Approach: Augmented Approach -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Berserker Approach: Augmented Approach</name>
        <text>The Augmented Approach is for those who seek to increase their prowess through cybernetic enhancement. Some who take this path go so far they are left with little more than the memory of the body they once owned, all to achieve in combat what they cannot with a body made of flesh and bone.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Basic Cybernetics (Augmented Approach)</name>
        <text>When you choose this approach at 3rd level, you learn the mending and analyse tech powers and can cast them without the use of a wristpad or spending tech points. You can cast analyse this way a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of one). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Overdrive Enhancement (Augmented Approach)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you gain a cybernetic enhancement. Choose one of the following enhancements and gain its feature. You must undergo cybernetic surgery by a person proficient in biotech's tools that incorporates this enhancement into your body. This surgery costs 100 credits and takes 8 hours.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Support Enhancement (Augmented Approach)</name>
        <text>At 6th level you gain an additional cybernetic enhancement. Choose one of the following enhancements and gain its feature. You must undergo cybernetic surgery by a person proficient in biotech's tools that incorporates this enhancement into your body. This surgery costs 600 credits and takes 8 hours.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>More Machine Than Man (Augmented Approach)</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, your cybernetics allow you to become immune to poison and disease. Additionally, you ignore unenhanced difficult terrain.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Final Enhancement (Augmented Approach)</name>
        <text>At 14th level you gain a final cybernetic enhancement. Choose one of the following enhancements and gain its feature. You must undergo cybernetic surgery by a person proficient in biotech's tools that incorporates this enhancement into your body. This surgery costs 2000 credits and takes 8 hours.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Berserker Approach: Ballistic Approach -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Berserker Approach: Ballistic Approach</name>
        <text>For many, rushing an opponent with guns blazing is a last resort. For Berserkers of the Ballistic Approach, this isn't a last resort; it's the primary plan. Leading with a blaster and pure, unbridled rage, the berserker never lets an empty gun diminish their fury.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Firestorm (Ballistic Approach)</name>
        <text>When you choose this approach at 3rd level, you've learned to use ranged weapons with untold fury. While wielding a blaster with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• When making a ranged weapon attack while within 30 feet of your target, you use your choice of Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.
	• When you use a blaster as an improvised weapon, you are considered proficient with it.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Explosive (Ballistic Approach)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, while raging, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack made with a blaster weapon, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.
	• You add your rage damage to damage rolls from ranged weapon attacks while within 30 feet of your target. You may only apply your rage damage to one target when you use the burst feature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Rampage (Ballistic Approach)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, while raging, when you deal damage with a blaster with which you are proficient while within 30 feet of your target, you can use a bonus action to move up to half your speed towards your target. You must end this movement closer to your target than you started. If you end this movement within 5 feet of your target, you can make one melee weapon attack with your blaster as a part of this bonus action.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Down, Not Out (Ballistic Approach)</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, when you are hit with an attack by a creature within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to make a single attack against that creature with a blaster with which you are proficient.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Brawn (Ballistic Approach)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you use the burst feature of a blaster with which are you proficient, you can apply your rage damage bonus to every target that takes damage. Additionally, when a creature fails the saving throw, it is knocked prone.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Berserker Approach: Bloodstorm Approach -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Berserker Approach: Bloodstorm Approach</name>
        <text>For some Bloodstorm Approach is said to have originated from the ancient wookiee Hroufrasnooohn clan (which loosely translates to Bloodstorm in Galactic Basic), whose warriors performed gravity-defying feats with their flying vibroaxes through a combination of unorthodox techniques and a mystical belief in their own abilities. A berserker who follows this approach can hurl their devastating weapons at enemies with such power and skill that it completely blurs the line between melee and ranged combat.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Furious Throw (Bloodstorm Approach)</name>
        <text>When you choose this approach at 3rd level, your throwing techniques have become a perfect extension of your melee prowess. You may count your thrown weapon attacks as if they were melee weapon attacks for the purposes of your class abilities and feats, such as your Berserker Rage and Reckless Attack abilities.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Returning Attacks (Bloodstorm Approach)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, any weapon you throw can ricochet back to you at your command. When you make a thrown weapon attack, you may have the weapon fly back to your hand immediately after the attack.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Throw Anything (Bloodstorm Approach)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, your strength and mastery of throwing techniques has allowed you to throw vibroaxes as easily as others hurl vibrodaggers. When you are wielding a melee weapon that you have proficiency with, it gains the thrown property (range 20/60).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fling People (Bloodstorm Approach)</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, you learn to throw creatures as easily as you throw your weapons. When you successfully grapple a creature, you may immediately throw the creature:

Throw Friend:
If the creature is a willing ally and volunteers to be grappled, you throw the target into any unoccupied space within 60 feet. That creature may immediately use its reaction to make one melee weapon attack, adding your Strength modifier to the attack's damage roll.

Throw Foe:
If the creature is an opponent, you throw the target into any unoccupied space within 30 feet, where it takes damage equal to your Strength modifier and falls prone.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Raging Whirlwind (Bloodstorm Approach)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you can send your weapon spinning into a gravity-defying whirlwind of pain. Once per rage as an action, you may throw a weapon with the thrown property to a point you choose within 60 feet. The weapon fills the air as a cyclone in a 10 foot radius sphere centered on that point. A creature takes damage equal to the thrown weapon's damage + your Strength modifier + your Rage Damage when it enter's the whirlwind's area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there. This effect ends when you command the weapon to return to you as a free action or your rage ends.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Berserker Approach: Cyclone Approach -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Berserker Approach: Cyclone Approach</name>
        <text>The Cyclone Approach empowers the berserker's ability to fight with weapons in each hand. Followers of this approach learn to move quickly to avoid attacks and can become a whirlwind of fury and steel, cleaving through hordes of enemies.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style (Cyclone Approach)</name>
        <text>When you choose this approach at 3rd level, you learn the Two-Weapon Fighting Fighting Style option, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Double Swing (Cyclone Approach)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, once on each of your turns when you miss with an attack while raging, you can immediately make a melee attack with the weapon in your other hand. You do not add your ability modifier to the damage of this attack.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Twisting Winds (Cyclone Approach)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, your unpredictable movement makes you harder to hit and pin down. When you make a saving throw or ability checks to avoid being knocked prone, pushed, grappled, or restrained, it gains a bonus equal to your Strength modifier.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mighty Leap (Cyclone Approach)</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, the distance you can jump is doubled, and you do not provoke attacks of opportunity if you leave a hostile creature's reach while jumping.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Tornado (Cyclone Approach)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you can become a tornado of attacks. When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your regular attacks to make a melee attack against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target. If you are wielding a separate melee weapon in each hand, each successful hit against a target deals damage equal to the damage dice of both weapons + your ability modifier + any other modifiers.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Strength modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Berserker Approach: Frenzied Approach -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Berserker Approach: Frenzied Approach</name>
        <text>TEXT</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Frenzy (Frenzied Approach)</name>
        <text>When you choose this approach at 3rd level, you can go into a frenzy when you rage. If you do so, for the duration of your rage you can make a single melee weapon attack as a bonus action on each of your turns after this one. When your rage ends, you suffer one level of exhaustion (as described in appendix A).
	When you finish a long rest, you reduce your exhaustion level by 2 rather than 1. Additionally, any effect that removes exhaustion reduces your exhaustion by 1 additional level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mindless Rage (Frenzied Approach)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you can't be charmed or frightened while raging. If you are charmed or frightened when you enter your rage, the effect is suspended for the duration of the rage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Intimidating Presence (Frenzied Approach)</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, you can use your action to frighten someone with your menacing presence. When you do so, choose one creature that you can see within 30 feet of you. If the creature can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn. On sub-sequent turns, you can use your action to extend the duration of this effect on the frightened creature until the end of your next turn. This effect ends if the creature ends its turn out of line of sight or more than 60 feet away from you.

			If the creature succeeds on its saving throw, you can't use this feature on that creature again for 24 hours.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Retaliation (Frenzied Approach)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you take damage from a creature that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Berserker Approach: Marauder Approach -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Berserker Approach: Marauder Approach</name>
        <text>Few things are more terrifying than being in the path of a Berserker who has learned the ways of the Force. Those who follow this path unlock something deep within them, a well of untamed power from the depths of their fury. When a marauder unleashes their rage, they channel their brute strength into primal might, and uses it to devastate his foes in a hail of fire, blades, and blood. Due to the uncontrolled nature of their powers, marauders have a dangerous predilection for the strength and raw power offered by the dark side, and many fall into it's clutches. Even those who do not are always temped by the voices of fury barely contained within.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Forcecasting (Marauder Approach)</name>
        <text>When you choose this approach at 3rd level, you have derived powers from your primal connection to the Force. See chapter 10 for the general rules of forcecasting and chapter 11 for the force powers list.
Force Powers Known:
You learn 4 force powers of your choice, and you learn more at higher levels, as shown in the Force Powers Known column of the Marauder Approach Forcecasting table. You may not learn a force power of a level higher than your Max Power Level, and you may learn a force power at the same time you learn its prerequisite.

Force Points:
You have a number of force points equal to your berserker level, as shown in the Force Points column of the Marauder Approach Forcecasting table, + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice). You use these force points to cast force powers. You regain all expended force points when you finish a long rest.

Max Power Level:
Many force powers can be overpowered, consuming more force points to create a greater effect. You can overpower these abilities to a maximum level, which increases at higher levels, as shown in the Max Power Level column of the Marauder Approach Forcecasting table.
	You may only cast force powers at 4th-level once. You regain the ability to do so after a long rest.

Forcecasting Ability:
Your forcecasting ability varies based on the alignment of the powers you cast. You use your Wisdom for light side powers, Charisma for dark side powers, and Wisdom or Charisma for universal powers (your choice). You use this ability score modifier whenever a power refers to your forcecasting ability. In addition, you use this ability score modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a force power you cast and when making an attack roll with one.

	Force save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus +your forcecasting ability modifier

	Force attack modifier = your proficiency bonus +your forcecasting ability modifier</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Furious Force (Marauder Approach)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you can cast force powers while raging as long as the power's casting time is no more than 1 action, the power does not require concentration, and you are not wearing heavy armor or wielding a medium or heavy shield. While raging, you add your rage damage to damage rolls from force powers you cast. If a force power damages more than one target, you may only apply your rage damage to one of the targets.

Casting force powers during rage counts as attacking for the purposes of maintaining rage.

See Player's Handbook or Star Wars 5e.com for Marauder Approach Forcecasting Table.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Reckless Power (Marauder Approach)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, weapons and the force are equally an extension of your rage. While you are raging and you use your action to cast a force power, you can make a single melee weapon attack as a bonus action.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Powerful Presence (Marauder Approach)</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, as a bonus action, you unleash a battle cry infused with force energy. Choose up to ten other creatures of within 60 feet of you that can hear you. Friendly creatures have advantage on attack rolls and saving throws until the start of your next turn, and hostile creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls and saving throws until the end of your next turn.
	Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force Storm (Marauder Approach)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you can expel the might of your rage all at once to unleash a devastating storm of force energy. As an action, you can end your rage early, forcing each creature within 15 feet of you to make a Dexterity saving throw against your universal force save DC. On a failed save, a creature takes 1d12 force damage for each round you've spent in rage, or half as much on a successful one.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Berserker Approach: Warchief Approach -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Berserker Approach: Warchief Approach</name>
        <text>For some berserkers, it is their duty or birthright to lead their tribe and kin to battle and victory. The Warchief Approach is one forged from alliances, bonds, and strategy. In combat, your rages are less mindless, and more focused. Ignoring the distractions of unimportant events, your attention hones in on the battlefield and how best to direct and control it. You guide your allies' strikes, and your presence is enough to wash away their fatigue.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Savage Diplomat (Warchief Approach)</name>
        <text>Your path necessitates that you build relationships with others, for the betterment of your tribe or yourself.

When you choose this approach at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Persuasion or Intimidation. You can choose to learn one language in place of the skill proficiency.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Inspiring Presence (Warchief Approach)</name>
        <text>At 6th level your mere presence on the battlefield rallies your allies. When you rage, choose up to 3 allies that you can see within 30 feet of you. Each creature gains temporary hit points equal to half your berserker level (rounded down) + your Charisma modifier (minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Raid Planning (Warchief Approach)</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, you learn to flare up your allies' drive for combat, urging them to follow you into the fray. During a long rest, you tell sagas, sing battle songs, and give inspiring speeches. At the end of the long rest choose up to 5 creatures that can hear and understand you (which can include yourself) to add your Charisma modifier (minimum of one) to their next initiative roll, and a 10 foot bonus to their speed on their first turn of combat.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>War Chant (Warchief Approach)</name>
        <text>By 14th level you have memorized the litanies, songs, and chants of your people and their dedication to war. When you enter a rage you can take a commanding stance. If you do so, for the duration of your rage you have a special reaction you can take on a number of allies' turns equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). You can only use this special reaction to use your Commanding Rage feature.

Additionally, during this rage, when an enemy within 10 feet of you makes an attack roll against an ally, you can use your reaction to reduce that roll by an amount equal to your Charisma modifier.

Once you've used this feature, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
