<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <class>
    <name>Consular (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <hd>6</hd>
    <proficiency>Wisdom Saving Throws, Charisma Saving Throws, Deception, History, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Medicine, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>
    <armor>None</armor>
    <weapons>Simple vibroweapons, simple lightweapons</weapons>
    <tools>None</tools>
    <wealth>1000+2d4x100</wealth>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <slots>1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <slots>1,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <slots>11,0,12</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4">
      <slots>12,0,16</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <slots>14,0,0,20</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <slots>15,0,0,24</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <slots>17,0,0,0,28</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <slots>18,0,0,0,32</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <slots>20,0,0,0,0,36</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <slots>21,0,0,0,0,40</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <slots>23,0,0,0,0,0,44</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12">
      <slots>24,0,0,0,0,0,48</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <slots>26,0,0,0,0,0,0,52</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <slots>27,0,0,0,0,0,0,56</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <slots>29,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,60</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16">
      <slots>30,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,64</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <slots>32,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,68</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <slots>33,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,72</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <slots>34,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,76</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <slots>35,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,80</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Starting Consular</name>
        <text>As a 1st-level Consular, you begin play with 6+your Constitution modifier hit points.
 
You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
	• Armor: none
	• Weapons: Simple vibroweapons, simple lightweapons
	• Tools: none
	• Skills: Choose two from Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Lore* (History), Medicine, and Persuasion.
 
You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background

	• (a) a simple lightweapon or (b) a simple vibroweapon
	• (a) a scholar's pack, (b) an explorer's pack, or © a diplomat's pack
 
Variant - Starting Wealth:
In lieu of the equipment granted by your class and background, you can elect to purchase your starting gear. If you do so, you receive no equipment from your class and background, and instead roll for your starting wealth using the criteria below:

	Funds = 1,000 + 2d4 x 100 cr

Important Note:
Fight Club 5 only uses standard Fifth Edition Skills, so we have mapped the skills in Star Wars 5e that are different this way.

	• History = Lore
	• Arcana = Technology
	• Religion = Piloting</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Consular</name>
        <text>To multiclass as a Consular, you must meet the following prerequisites:
 • Wisdom or Charisma 13

You gain the following proficiencies
	• Simple lightweapons</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Forcecasting</name>
        <text>In your meditations on the force, you have learned powers, fragments of knowledge that imbue you with an abiding force ability. See 

chapter 10 for the general rules of forcecasting and chapter 11 for the force powers list.Force Powers Known
You learn 8 force powers of your choice, and you learn more at higher levels, as shown in the Force Powers Known column of the consular class table. You may not learn a force power of a level higher than your Max Power Level, and you may learn a force power at the same time you learn its prerequisite.

Force Points
You have a number of force points equal to your consular level x 4, as shown in the Force Points column of the consular class table, + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice). You use these force points to cast force powers. You regain all expended force points when you finish a long rest.

Max Power Level
Many force powers can be overpowered, consuming more force points to create a greater effect. You can overpower these abilities to a maximum level, which increases at higher levels, as shown in the Max Power Level column of the consular class table.

You may only cast force powers at 6th, 7th, 8th, and 9th-level once. You regain the ability to do so after a long rest.

Forcecasting Ability
Your forcecasting ability varies based on the alignment of the powers you cast. You use your Wisdom for light side powers, Charisma for dark side powers, and Wisdom or Charisma for universal powers (your choice). You use this ability score modifier whenever a power refers to your forcecasting ability. In addition, you use this ability score modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a force power you cast and when making an attack roll with one.

Force save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus +your forcecasting ability modifier

Force attack modifier = your proficiency bonus +your forcecasting ability modifier</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Force Recovery</name>
        <text>Also at 1st level, you have learned to regain some of your energy by briefly meditating. When you finish a short rest, you can regain a number of force points equal to half your consular level (rounded down) + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one). Once you've used this feature, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting</name>
        <text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to twist your powers to suit your needs. When you cast a force power, you can expend additional force points to modify the power. You gain two of the following Empowerment options of your choice. You gain another one at 10th and 17th level.

You can use only one Empowerment option on a power when you cast it, unless otherwise noted.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Careful Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the power's full force. To do so, you spend 1 additional force point and choose a number of those creatures up to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the power.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Distant Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 additional force point to double the range of the power.
	When you cast a power that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 additional force point to make the range of the power 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Extended Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 additional force point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Extended Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 additional force point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Heightened Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that forces a creature to make a saving throw to resist its effects, you can spend 3 additional force points to give one target of the power disadvantage on its first saving throw made against the power.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Improved Power</name>
        <text>When you roll damage for a power, you can spend 1 additional force point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one). You must use the new rolls.
	You can use Improved Power even if you have already used a different Empowerment option during the casting of the power.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Lingering Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that requires concentration to maintain you can choose to spend 3 additional force points. If you do, when you lose concentration on the power, the power will not end until the end of your next turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Pinpoint Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that allows you to force creatures in an area to make a saving throw you can instead spend 1 force point and make a ranged force attack against a single target that would be in the range. On a hit the target suffers the effects as though they failed their saving throw.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Quickened Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 2 additional force points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Refocused Power</name>
        <text>When you are forced to make a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration on a power you can use your reaction and spend 2 force points to automatically succeed on the saving throw. You can use this option even if you have already used a different Empowerment option during the casting of the power.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Twinned Power</name>
        <text>When you cast a power that targets only one creature and doesn't have a range of self, you can spend a number of additional force points equal to the power's level to target a second creature in range with the same power (1 force point if the power is at-will).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Empowered Casting: Force Shield</name>
        <text>Also at 2nd level, you learn how to defend yourself purely through your strength with the Force. When you are hit by an attack, you can use your reaction to shroud yourself in Force energy. Until the start of your next turn, you have a bonus to AC equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of +1). This includes the triggering attack.
	You can use this feature twice. You gain an additional use at 5th, 11th, and 17th level in this class. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Consular Tradition</name>
        <text>When you reach 3rd level, you choose a consular tradition, which is detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 10th, 14th, and 18th level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Hidden Force</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn how to conceal the casting of your force powers. When you cast a force power, you can choose to conceal the presence of that casting from others. A creature that sees you cast the force power can make an Investigation (Intelligence) check against your universal force save DC. On a success, they can determine that you used the Force in some way. If a creature has the force sight force power active, they automatically succeed on this check. A creature that can not see you automatically fails this check.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level, and again at 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
        <text>When you reach 10th level, and again at 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level, and again at 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level, and again at 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (6th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>One With The Force</name>
        <text>At 20th level, your attunement to the Force is absolute. Your Wisdom or Charisma score increases by 4, and your maximum for this score increases by 4. Additionally, you gain mastery over a single force power, and can cast it with little effort. Choose one 3rd-level force power that you know as your signature power. You can cast it once at 3rd level without expending force points. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.
	If you want to cast it at a higher level, you must expend force points as normal.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of Balance -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of Balance</name>
        <text>There is serenity in balance, and no one knows this better than the consular. Those consulars who follow the Way of Balance focus on utilizing the Force to equalize the battlefield. They bend the Force to shield their allies and expose their foes.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force Barrier (Way of Balance)</name>
        <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can weave the Force around yourself for protection. When you cast a universal power of 1st level or higher, you can simultaneously manipulate the Force to create a barrier on yourself that lasts until you finish a long rest. The barrier has hit points equal to twice your consular level + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice). Your barrier can never have hit points greater than twice your consular level + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice).
	Whenever you take damage, the barrier takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the barrier to 0 hit points, you take any remaining damage.
	While the barrier has 0 hit points, it can't absorb damage, but its power remains. Whenever you cast a universal power of 1st level or higher, the barrier regains a number of hit points equal to twice the level of the power.
	Once you create the barrier, you can't create it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Projected Barrier (Way of Balance)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to cause your Force Barrier to absorb that damage. If this damage reduces the barrier to 0 hit points, the warded creature takes any remaining damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>At-Will Barrier (Way of Balance)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 10th level, your at-will universal powers grant a small boost to your Force Barrier. When you cast an at-will universal power, the barrier regains 1 hit point.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Improved Suppression (Way of Balance)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you cast a force power that requires you to make an ability check as a part of casting that power (as in sever force and force suppression), you add your proficiency bonus to that ability check.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force Resistance (Way of Balance)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, you have advantage on saving throws against force powers. Additionally, you have resistance against the damage of force powers.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of Confluence -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of Confluence</name>
        <text>The Force binds us, creating an intangible bridge connecting all living things. Those consulars who follow the Way of Confluence master this power, manipulating those connections to both sustain and torment.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Manipulate Life Force (Way of Confluence)</name>
        <text>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, when you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points with a force power, or restore hit points to a creature with 0 hit points with a foce power, you gain temporary hit points equal to half your consular level (rounded down) + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Empowered Connection (Way of Confluence)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, while you have temporary hit points, you can add half your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, rounded up, minimum of one) to any damage or healing you do with force powers that doesn't already include that modifier.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Life Eternal (Way of Confluence)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 10th level, you can use your powerful connection to the Force to keep fighting when others would fall. When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can spend 5 force points to drop to 1 hit point instead.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Interconnectedness (Way of Confluence)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you cast a 5th level or lower force power that deals damage or restores hit points and targets only one creature, the power can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Dynamic Attachment (Way of Confluence)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, while you have temporary hit points, you have resistance against the damage of force powers, and your force powers ignore resistance.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of Endurance -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of Endurance</name>
        <text>The Force manifests in myriad ways; while some use the Force to manipulate the world around them, others use it to enhance themselves. Those consulars who follow the Way of Endurance channel the Force to allow them to overcome and reflect the most grievous of injuries.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Upheld by The Force (Way of Endurance)</name>
        <text>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, the Force flowing through your body strengthens you, granting the following benefits:
	• Your hit point maximum increases by 3, and it increases by 1 again whenever you gain a level in this class.
	• Your base AC becomes 13 + your Constitution modifier.
	• When you make a melee weapon attack as a part of a force power you cast, you can use Wisdom or Charisma (your choice) instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls.
	Additionally, as an action, you can gain resistance to kinetic and energy damage for 1 minute. This effect lasts until you end it as a bonus action, you are incapacitated, or you don armor other than a shield. You can use this feature twice. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Retaliation Strike (1d6) (Way of Endurance)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you learn to turn an opponent's aggression back on them. When you deal damage with a force power or a melee weapon attack, if you took damage since the start of your last turn, you deal an extra 1d6 damage. The damage is the same type as the power or weapon's damage.
	This die increases when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d8 at 10th level, to 1d10 at 14th level, and to 1d12 at 18th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Retaliation Strike Improvement (1d8) (Way of Endurance)</name>
        <text>Your Retaliation Strike damage increases to 1d8.
	This die increases when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d10 at 14th level, and to 1d12 at 18th level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Boundless Vitality (Way of Endurance)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 10th level, when you take damage, you can use your reaction and expend a force point to regain health equal to 1d8 + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one) as long as the damage would not reduce your hit points to 0.
	This die increases when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d10 at 14th level, and to 1d12 at 18th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Retaliation Strike Improvement (1d10) (Way of Endurance)</name>
        <text>Your Retaliation Strike damage increases to 1d10.
	This die increases when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d12 at 18th level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Unrelenting Resilience (Way of Endurance)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you use your Boundless Vitality feature while concentrating on a force power, you can add the result of the roll to the Constitution saving throw made to maintain concentration.
	Additionally, when you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright while Upheld by the Force is active, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Retaliation Strike Improvement (1d10) (Way of Endurance)</name>
        <text>Your Retaliation Strike damage increases to 1d10.
	This die increases when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d12 at 18th level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>The Force Unleashed (Way of Endurance)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, as an action, you can choose a point within 60 feet. Each creature of your choice within 30 feet of that point must make a Constitution saving throw against your universal force save DC. On a failed save, a creature takes 5d10 force damage and suffers 1 level of exhaustion. On a successful save, a creature takes half damage does not suffer exhaustion.
	For each creature that fails this saving throw, a friendly creature within 30 feet of them can regain hit points equal to the amount of damage dealt. A friendly creature can only gain this benefit once per turn.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of Lightning -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of Lightning</name>
        <text>Of all of the dark arts of the Force, little can match the spectacle and devastation of Force lightning. Those consulars who follow the Way of Lightning summon intense discharges of pure Force energy, overwhelming enemies with punishing damage from a distance, leaving them shaken and vulnerable – if not dead.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shocking Affinity (Way of Lightning)</name>
        <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, when you cast a force power that deals lightning damage, you can use Wisdom or Charisma as your forcecasting ability for it.
	Additionally, when you cast a damage dealing force power that requires an attack roll or saving throw, you can cause that power to instead deal lightning damage. If the power would call for a saving throw other than Dexterity, it instead calls for a Dexterity saving throw. If you hit with the power, or the target fails the power's saving throw, affected creatures become shocked until the start of your next turn. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Potent Lighting (Way of Lightning)</name>
        <text>At 6th level you add your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of +1) to any damage you deal with force powers that deal lightning damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Potent Lighting (Way of Lightning)</name>
        <text>At 6th level you add your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of +1) to any damage you deal with force powers that deal lightning damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Electric Attunement (Way of Lightning)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you gain resistance to lightning damage. Additionally, force powers you cast ignore resistance to lightning damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Unlimited Power (Way of Lightning)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, you can increase the power of your simpler lightning force powers. When you cast a force power of 6th-level or lower that deals lightning damage, you can deal maximum damage with that power.
	You can use this feature with no adverse effects a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). If you use this feature beyond this before you finish a long rest, you take 2d12 necrotic damage for each level of the power, immediately after you cast it. Each time you use this feature again before finishing a long rest, the necrotic damage per power level increases by 1d12. This damage can not be reduced in any way.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of Manipulation -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of Manipulation</name>
        <text>The power of the Force is both vast and diverse, with uses varying drastically based on their wielder. Those consulars who follow the Way of Manipulation learn to control their weapons with the Force, maneuvering them across the battlefield.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Saber Storm (Way of Manipulation)</name>
        <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you learn to deftly control your weapons utilizing the Force. As an action, you can initiate your Saber Storm. When you do so, select a melee weapon you wield, or one melee weapon within 5 feet that is not worn or carried by a conscious creature, and use the Force to cause it to levitate, acting as an extension of your will for 1 minute. When you activate this feature, you can cause the weapon to move up to 10 feet and make a melee force attack against a creature within 5 feet of it. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 + your forcecasting ability modifier damage. The type is of the normal damage dealt by the weapon. The weapon then returns to your side.
	Your weapon moves with you, and while Saber Storm is active and you have a weapon animated, on each of your turns you can use an action to move a weapon up to 10 feet and repeat the attack against a creature within 5 feet of it. The weapon then returns to your side. Your Saber Storm ends early if you are incapacitated. At any time, you can end this feature and return the animated weapon to your hand.
	Additionally, while your Saber Storm is active, and at least one animated weapon is within 5 feet of you, you gain the following benefits:
	• You gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of +1).
	• You gain a bonus to any Constitution saving throw you make to maintain your concentration on a power. The bonus equals your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of +l).
	This feature can animate more than one weapon when you reach higher levels: two weapons at 5th level, three weapons at 11th level, and four weapons at 17th level. When you use your action to attack with your weapons, you can direct them at the same target or at different ones. Make a separate attack roll for each weapon.
	At 5th level, the distance your weapon can travel increases to 20 feet. This distance increases to 30 feet at 11th level, and 40 feet at 17th level.
	You can use this feature twice. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Saber Storm Improvement (1st) (Way of Manipulation)</name>
        <text>At 5th level, the distance your weapon can travel increases to 20 feet. This distance increases to 30 feet at 11th level, and 40 feet at 17th level.
	You can use this feature twice. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Deceptive Strike (Way of Manipulation)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, when you cast a force power with a range of touch while Saber Storm is active, your animated weapon can move up to its range and deliver the power as if it had cast it.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Guarding Weapon (Way of Manipulation)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 10th level, you can direct your animated weapons to absorb damage while your Saber Storm is activate. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to expend one force slot to have your animated weapon intercept it, and reduce that damage to you by an amount equal to five times the force slot's level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Saber Storm Improvement (2nd) (Way of Manipulation)</name>
        <text>At 11th level, the distance your weapon can travel increases to 30 feet at, and 40 feet at 17th level.
	You can use this feature twice. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Isolate (Way of Manipulation)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you deal damage to a creature while Saber Storm is active, and that creature fails a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration on a force power, you can steal and redirect the power. Until the end of your next turn, either you or the creature who failed the Constitution saving throw gain the effects of the power (your choice).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Saber Storm Improvement (3rd) (Way of Manipulation)</name>
        <text>At 17th level, the distance your weapon can travel increases to 40 feet.
	You can use this feature twice. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sapping Storm (Way of Manipulation)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, when you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points while Saber Storm is active, you gain temporary force points equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one). These temporary force points can not exceed your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice), and when you would spend a force point while you have temporary force points, the temporary force points are spent first. When Saber Storm ends, you lose any remaining temporary force points.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of Negation -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of Negation</name>
        <text>Some force users seek mastery over the fundamentals of energy manipulation, known as tutaminis. Those consulars who follow the Way of Negation harness this power to limit the havoc that other force-wielders might wreak.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force Deflection (Way of Negation)</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, when you fail a saving throw, you can use your reaction to gain a +4 bonus to that saving throw.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Power Surge (Way of Negation)</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, you learn to simultaneously limit a creature's force powers and store that power within yourself to later strengthen your damaging force powers.
	You can store a maximum number of power surges equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one). Whenever you successfully end a force power with a power such as force suppression or sever force, or use your Force Shield or Force Deflection features to successfully avoid an attack or succeed on a saving throw, you gain one power surge, as you redirect the flow of the Force into yourself.
	Once per turn, when you deal damage to a creature or object with a force power, you can spend one power surge to deal extra damage to that target. The extra damage is of the same type as the power's damage, and it equals half your consular level (rounded down).
	Whenever you finish a long rest, your number of power surges resets to one. If you end a short rest with no power surges, you gain one power surge.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Enduring Focus (Way of Negation)</name>
        <text>At 10th level, you can casually deflect attacks while channeling your power. While you are concentrating on a Force power, you have a +2 bonus to your AC and all saving throws.
	Additionally, you can extend your Force Deflection to a creature within 5 feet of you when they fail a saving throw.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Conflux (Way of Negation)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you use your Force Deflection feature, you can cause a ripple in the Force to expand from you. Up to three creatures of your choice that you can see within 60 feet of you each take force damage equal to half your consular level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Tutaminis Mastery (Way of Negation)</name>
        <text>At 18th level, when you use a Force-Empowered Casting option, you can spend a power surge to use it without spending additional force points.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of Telekenetics -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of Telekenetics</name>
        <text>The consular knows how to manipulate the essence of the surrounding elements with the power of the Force. Those consulars who follow the Way of Telekinetics create torrential gusts of telekinetic energy, forming a potent combination that can pummel even the toughest adversaries into submission.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Staggering Stratagem (Way of Telekenetics)</name>
        <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, your potency with the telekinetic power of the Force heightens. Once per turn, when you deal force damage to a Large or smaller creature, you can choose to either push it up to 10 feet away from you or pull it up to 10 feet closer to you.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mighty Blast (Way of Telekenetics)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, your force powers batter and blast your enemies with the strength of a hurricane. When you cast a force power of 1st level or higher that deals force damage, one creature of your choice damaged by that power must make a Strength saving throw against your universal force save DC or be knocked prone.
	This feature can affect additional creatures when you reach higher levels: two creatures at 11th level and three creatures at 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mighty Blast Improvement (1st) (Way of Telekenetics)</name>
        <text>This feature can affect two creatures.
	This feature can affect additional creatures when you reach higher levels: three creatures at 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Size Matters Not (Way of Telekenetics)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 10th level, you can manipulate creatures of Huge size or smaller with your force powers and Way of Telekinetics features.

Additionally, when you use your action to cast a force power, you can use a bonus action to leap up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Repulsing Wave (Way of Telekenetics)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you are dealt damage by a creature within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to deal force damage to the creature equal to your consular level + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of +1). If the attacker is Huge or smaller, it must also make a Strength saving throw against your universal force save DC. On a failed save, the attacker is pushed in a straight line up to 20 feet away from you.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mighty Blast Improvement (2nd) (Way of Telekenetics)</name>
        <text>This feature can affect three creatures.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>My Ally is The Force (Way of Telekenetics)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, you can manipulate creatures of Gargantuan size or smaller with your force powers and Way of Telekinetics features.
	Additionally, whenever a force power you cast pushes or pulls a creature, you can increase the distance of that push or pull by an additional 20 feet.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of the Sage -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of the Sage</name>
        <text>The rejuvenating power of the Force is incredible, and the consular is the master of this usage. Those consulars who follow the Way of the Sage assist with an array of healing powers that grant allies the strength to continue through even the harshest of encounters. Separated from the heart of the fray, the sage can be an unfailing warden to those in need.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Disciple of Life (Way of the Sage)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, as an action, you can channel the Force and evoke healing energy that restores a number of hit points equal to five times your consular level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. This feature has no effect on droids or constructs.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Preserve Life (Way of the Sage)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, as an action, you can channel the Force and evoke healing energy that restores a number of hit points equal to five times your consular level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. This feature has no effect on droids or constructs.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Preserve Life (Way of the Sage)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, as an action, you can channel the Force and evoke healing energy that restores a number of hit points equal to five times your consular level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. This feature has no effect on droids or constructs.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Blessed by The Force (Way of the Sage)</name>
        <text>At 14th level you gain the ability to overcome grievous injuries. As a bonus action when you have fewer than half of your hit points remaining, you can regain a number of hit points equal to half your hit point maximum.
	Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Supreme Healing (Way of the Sage)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, when you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a power, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hit points to a creature, you restore 12.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Consular Tradition: Way of the Seer -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Consular Tradition: Way of the Seer</name>
        <text>The Force guides us in innumerable ways, often manifesting as visions. Those consulars who follow the Way of Seer attempt to harness these visions in an attempt to work towards the best possible future, as they see it.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force Visions (Way of the Seer)</name>
        <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, glimpses of the future begin to press in on your awareness. When you finish a long rest, roll two d20s and record the numbers rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of these foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn. Each foretelling roll can be used only once. When you finish a long rest, you lose any unused foretelling rolls.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Powerful Mind (Way of the Seer)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you can use your force abilities to read a creature's thoughts. You can then use your access to the creature's mind to command it.
	As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your universal force save DC. If the creature succeeds on the saving throw, you can't use this feature on it again until you finish a long rest. If the creature fails its save, you can read its surface thoughts (those foremost in its mind, reflecting its current emotions and what it is actively thinking about.) when it is within 60 feet of you. This effect lasts for 1 minute. During that time, you can use your action to end this effect and use the coerce mind force power on the creature without expending force points. The target automatically fails its saving throw against the power.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Visions of the Past (Way of the Seer)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 10th level, you can call up visions of the past that relate to an object you hold or your immediate surroundings. You spend at least 1 minute in meditation, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of recent events. You can meditate in this way for a number of minutes equal to your Wisdom score and must maintain concentration during that time, as if you were casting a force power. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
	Object Reading: Holding an object as you meditate, you can see visions of the object's previous owner. After meditating for 1 minute, you learn how the owner acquired and lost the object, as well as the most recent significant event involving the object and that owner. If the object was owned by another creature in the recent past (within a number of days equal to your Wisdom score), you can spend 1 additional minute for each owner to learn the same information about that creature.
	Area Reading: As you meditate, you see visions of recent events in your immediate vicinity (a room, street, tunnel, clearing, or the like, up to a 50-foot cube), going back a number of days equal to your Wisdom score. For each minute you meditate, you learn about one significant event, beginning with the most recent. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as battles and betrayals, marriages and murders, births and funerals. However, they might also include more mundane events that are nevertheless important in your current situation.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shielded Thoughts (Way of the Seer)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, your thoughts can't be read by telepathy or other means unless you allow it. You also have resistance to psychic damage, and whenever a creature deals psychic damage to you, that creature takes the same amount of damage that you do.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Clarity of Vision (Way of the Seer)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, the visions in your dreams intensify and paint a more accurate picture in your mind of what is to come. You roll three d20s for your Force Visions feature, rather than two.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
