<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <class>
    <name>Engineer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <hd>8</hd>
    <proficiency>Constitution Saving Throws, Intelligence Saving Throws, Arcana, History, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Religion</proficiency>
    <numSkills>3</numSkills>
    <armor>Light armor</armor>
    <weapons>Simple blasters, simple vibroweapons</weapons>
    <tools>Tinker's tools and one of your choice</tools>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <slots>14,0,0,0,16</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
        <text>Armor: Light armor
Weapons: Simple blasters, simple vibroweapons
Tools: Tinker's tools and one of your choice
Saving Throws: Constitution, Intelligence
Skills: Choose three from Investigation, Lore (Arcana), Medicine, Nature, Piloting (History), and Technology (Religion)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Starting Equipment</name>
        <text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background

	• (a) a simple vibroweapon or (b) a simple blaster and two power cells
	• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack
	• Combat suit, a set of tinker's tools, a vibrodagger, and a wristpad

Variant - Starting Wealth:
In lieu of the equipment granted by your class and background, you can elect to purchase your starting gear. If you do so, you receive no equipment from your class and background, and instead roll for your starting wealth using the criteria below:

	Funds = 1,000 + 3d4 x 100 cr

Important Note:
Fight Club 5 only uses standard Fifth Edition Skills, so we have mapped the skills in Star Wars 5e that are different this way.

	• History = Lore
	• Arcana = Technology
	• Religion = Piloting</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Techcasting</name>
        <text>During your training you have derived powers from schematics with the aid of your wristpad. See chapter 10 for the general rules of techcasting and chapter 12 for the tech powers list.

Tech Powers Known:
You learn 6 tech powers of your choice, and you learn more at higher levels, as shown in the Tech Powers Known column of the engineer class table. You may not learn a tech power of a level higher than your Max Power Level.

Tech Points:
You have a number of tech points equal to your engineer level x 2, as shown in the Tech Points column of the engineer class table, + your Intelligence modifier. You use these tech points to cast tech powers. You regain all expended tech points when you finish a short or long rest.

Max Power Level:
Many tech powers can be overcharged, consuming more tech points to create a greater effect. You can overcharge these powers to a maximum level, which increases at higher levels, as shown in the Max Power Level column of the engineer class table.
	You may only cast tech powers at 6th, 7th, 8th, and 9th-level once. You regain the ability to do so after a long rest.

Techcasting Ability:
Intelligence is your techcasting ability for your tech powers. You use your Intelligence whenever a power refers to your techcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a tech power you cast and when making an attack roll with one.

	Tech save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus +your Intelligence modifier

	Tech attack modifier = your proficiency bonus +your Intelligence modifier

Techcasting Focus:
You use a wristpad (found in chapter 5) or your tool proficiencies granted by this class as a techcasting focus for your tech powers.

See The Player's Handbook or Star Wars 5e.com for The Engineer Class Tech Powers Known Table.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Potent Aptitude (d6)</name>
        <text>Your technological experience lends you an uncommon insight that you can use to bolster your allies. To do so, you use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than yourself within 60 feet of you who can hear you. That creature gains one Potent Aptitude die, a d6.

Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Potent Aptitude die, but must decide before the GM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once the Potent Aptitude die is rolled, it is lost.

A creature can have only one Potent Aptitude die at a time.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Your Potent Aptitude die changes when you reach certain levels in this class. The die becomes a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Infuse Item</name>
        <text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to temporarily enhance a weapon or armor. At the end of a long rest, you can touch one unenhanced object that is a suit of armor or a simple or martial weapon. Until the end of your next long rest or until you die, the object becomes an enhanced item, granting a +1 bonus to AC if it's armor or a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls if it's a weapon.
	Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Tool Understanding</name>
        <text>Also at 2nd level, you have advantage on any ability check you make that uses any of the tool proficiencies you gain from this class.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Engineering Discipline</name>
        <text>Also at 2nd level, you have advantage on any ability check you make that uses any of the tool proficiencies you gain from this class.

The wide range of tool applications gives birth to well defined distinctions between different engineering disciplines. Each discipline focuses on maximizing the personal use of a certain tool.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Modification Slots Increase (5)</name>
        <text>Your modified item now has 5 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Quick Thinking</name>
        <text>Beginning when you reach 5th level, you regain all of your expended uses of Potent Aptitude when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level, and again at 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Modification Slots Increase (6)</name>
        <text>Your modified item now has 6 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Modification Slots Increase (7)</name>
        <text>Your modified item now has 7 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level, and again at 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature>
        <name>Modification Slots Increase (8)</name>
        <text>Your modified item now has 8 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level, and again at 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature>
        <name>Modification Slots Increase (9)</name>
        <text>Your modified item now has 9 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Tech Mastery</name>
        <text>At 20th level, your mastery of technology is unrivaled. Your Constitution and Intelligence scores increase by 2. Your maximum for those scores increases by 2.

Additionally, when you roll initiative and have no uses of Potent Aptitude left, you regain one use.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Constitution Bonus +2</modifier>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Intelligence Bonus +2</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Engineering Discipline: Armormech Engineering -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Discipline: Armormech Engineering</name>
        <text>Those engineers who choose the Armormech Engineering discipline focus on the ability to work with hard metals and electronic shielding to construct and enhance all types of personal armor.

See The Player's Handbook or Star Wars 5e.com for Armormech Modifications.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Armormech Engineering)</name>
        <text>When you choose this discipline at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in armormech's tools, medium armor, and heavy armor. Additionally, when you engage in crafting with armormech's tools, the rate at which you craft doubles.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Armor (Armormech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to modify one unenhanced suit of armor or shield utilizing your armormech knowledge. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of the armor in order to modify it. You must have the armor, materials, and armormech's tools in order to perform this modification.

Your modified armor requires attunement, can only be used by you, and counts as a tech focus for your tech powers while you are attuned to it. Your modified armor has 4 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).

Some modification effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your tech save DC.

At 9th level, you can maintain both a modified suit of armor and shield. The total modification slots are split across the two items.

See the Player's Handbook or Star Wars 5e.com for the list of Armormech Modifications.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Damage Absorbtion (Armormech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, when you take damage, you can use your reaction and expend one use of your Potent Aptitude to absorb some of that damage. When you do so, the damage you take from the attack is reduced by the amount rolled on the die + your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armormech's Celerity (Armormech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, when you take the Attack action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Shield (Armormech Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 9th level, you can maintain both a modified suit of armor and shield. The total modification slots are split across the two items.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Casting Celerity (Armormech Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you use your action to a cast a tech power, you can use your Armormech's Celerity feature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Suit Reliability (Armormech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, your suit is like a second skin. Whenever you make an ability check or saving throw that uses Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10. You must be wearing your modified armor to gain this benefit.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Engineering Discipline: Armstech Engineering -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Discipline: Armstech Engineering</name>
        <text>Those engineers who choose the Armstech Engineeering discipline focus on the skill of constructing and modifying blasters and vibroweapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>When you choose this discipline at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in armstech's tools, medium armor, martial blasters, and martial vibroweapons. Additionally, when you engage in crafting with armstech's tools, the rate at which you craft doubles.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Weaponry (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to modify one unenhanced weapon with which you are proficient utilizing your armstech experience. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of a weapon in order to modify it. You must have the weapon, materials, and armstech's tools in order to perform this modification.

Your modified weapon requires attunement, can only be used by you, and counts as a tech focus for your tech powers while you are attuned to it. Your modified weapon has 4 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).

Some modification effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your tech save DC.

At 9th level, you can maintain two modified weapons. The total modification slots are split across the two weapons.

See the Player's Handbook or Star Wars 5e.com for the list of Armstech Modifications.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Close Call (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, when you make an attack roll with your modified weapon and miss, you can expend one use of your Potent Aptitude to attempt to turn that miss into a hit. Roll the die and add it to the attack roll.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armstech's Strike (1d6) (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, once per round, when you deal damage to a creature with your modified weapon, you can increase the damage by 1d6. The damage is of the same type as the weapon's damage.

The damage increases to 2d6 at 11th level and 3d6 at 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Weaponry (2) (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 9th level, you can maintain two modified weapons. The total modification slots are split across the two weapons.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armstech's Strike (2d6) (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Once per round, when you deal damage to a creature with your modified weapon, you can now increase the damage by 2d6. The damage is of the same type as the weapon's damage.

The damage increases to 3d6 at 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Targeting Matrix (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you cast a tech power that allows you to force creatures in an area to make a saving throw, you can instead make an attack roll with your modified weapon against a single target that would be in the range of the power. On a hit, the target suffers the effects as though they failed their saving throw. If the power would affect more than one creature, it instead affects only one.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armstech's Strike (3d6) (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Once per round, when you deal damage to a creature with your modified weapon, you can now increase the damage by 3d6. The damage is of the same type as the weapon's damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armstech Salvo (Armstech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, when you use your Targeting Matrix feature, and the tech power would affect more than one creature, you can instead attack each affected creature that would be in the range of the power. Make a separate attack roll for each target. On a hit, each target suffers the effects as though they failed their saving throw.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Engineering Discipline: Artificer Engineering -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Discipline: Artificer Engineering</name>
        <text>Those engineers who choose the Artificer Engineering discipline focus on building and modifying lightsabers, while tapping into the latent presence of the Force in these lightsaber crystals.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Artificer Engineering)</name>
        <text>When you choose this discipline at 3rd level you gain proficiency in artificer's tools, and with the lightsaber simple lightweapon. additionally, when you engage in crafting with artificer's tools, the rate at which you craft doubles.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Lightsaber (Artificer Engineering)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to modify an unenhanced lightsaber utilizing your artificer knowledge. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of the lightsaber in order to modify it. You must have the lightsaber, materials, and artificer's tools in order to perform this modification.

Your modified lightsaber requires attunement, can only be used by you, and counts as a tech focus for your tech powers while you are attuned to it. Your modified lightsaber has 4 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).

Some modification effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your tech save DC.

At 9th level, you can maintain two different modified lightsabers. The total modification slots are split across the two items.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force Resonance (Artificer Engineering)</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, once per round, when you hit a creature with your modified lightsaber, you can expend one use of your Potent Aptitude to deal an extra 2d6 damage to that target. The damage is the same type as your modified lightsaber's damage.

The damage increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to 3d6 at 5th level, 5d6 at 10th level, and 8d6 at 15th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Kyber Knowledge (Artificer Engineering)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, you're study of kyber crystals has awakened a latent force sensitivity. Choose two force powers of 1st level. The chose powers count as tech powers for you, but are not included in the number in the Powers Known column of the engineer class table.

At 10th level, you learn two additional force powers of 1st or 2nd level. At 14th level, you learn two force powers of 1st-3rd level, and at 18th level, you learn two force powers of 1st-4th level. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the force powers you know and replace it with another force power of the same level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Lightsaber (2) (Artificer Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 9th level, you can maintain two different modified lightsabers. The total modification slots are split across the two items.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Disruptive Resonance (Artificer Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you hit a creature that is concentrating on a power with your modified lightsaber, the creature has disadvantage on the Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration. Additionally, on a failed save, the creature immediately takes psychic damage equal to your engineer level + your Intelligence modifier.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Resonating Recovery (Artificer Engineering)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, once per turn, when you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points, you regain a use of your Potent Aptitude. Your number of Potent Aptitude uses can not exceed your Intelligence modifier.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Engineering Discipline: Astrotech Engineering -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Discipline: Astrotech Engineering</name>
        <text>Those engineers who choose the Astrotech Engineering discipline focus on crafting and upgrading their droid companions.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Astrotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>When you choose this discipline at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in astrotech's tools. Additionally, when you engage in crafting with astrotech's tools, the rate at which you craft doubles.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Droid Companion (Astrotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to employ all the knowledge you've accumulated to create and customize your own personalized droid companion.

Choose your droid, which is detailed at the end of this discipline. Over the course of 8 hours, which can be done during a long rest, you can expend 500 cr worth of materials to finally finish your droid.

If your droid is irreparable destroyed, or you want to interface with a different droid, you can spend an additional 250 credits and 1 hour to change the target of this feature. You may only have one droid companion at a time.

Your droid gains a variety of benefits while it is interfaced with you:

	• The droid obeys your commands as best it can. It rolls for initiative like any other creature, but you determine its actions, decisions, attitudes, and so on. If you are incapacitated or absent, your droid acts on its own.
	• Your droid's level equals your engineer level, and for each engineer level you gain after 3rd, your droid companion gains an additional Hit Die and increases its hit points accordingly.
	• Your droid has the proficiency bonus of a player character of the same level.
	• Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement class feature, your droid's abilities also improve. Your droid can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or it can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, your droid can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature unless its description specifies otherwise.
	• Your droid can not wear armor, but you can have the armor professionally integrated into its chassis. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of the armor in order to integrate it into your droid. Your droid must be proficient in armor in order to have it integrated.
	• Your droid is a valid target of the tracker droid interface tech power.

Additionally, you can modify your droid. Your droid companion has 4 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).

See the Player's Handbook or Star Wars 5e.com for Generating Your Droid instructions and Astrotech Modifications list.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Potent Integration (Astrotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, when your droid makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to expend one use of your Potent Aptitude to give it a boost. Roll the die and add it to both the attack and damage rolls, if the attack hits.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Coordinated Attack (Astrotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, when you take the Attack action, if your companion can see you, it can use its reaction to make a weapon attack against the same creature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Droid Defense (Astrotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, while your droid can see you, it has advantage on all saving throws.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Superior Droid Defense (Astrotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, whenever an attacker that your droid can see hits it with an attack, it can use its reaction to halve the attack's damage against it.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Engineering Discipline: Audiotech Engineering -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Discipline: Audiotech Engineering</name>
        <text>Those engineers who choose the Audiotech Engineering focus on using a specially modified instrument to use music to assist their allies and disrupt their enemies.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Audiotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>When you choose this discipline at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in three musical instruments of your choice, as well as the Performance skill. Additionally, you can use Intelligence instead of Charisma when you make a Performance check while wielding your modified instrument.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Instrument (Audiotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to modify an instrument utilizing your audiotech knowledge. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend 500 cr worth of materials to modify a single instrument. You must have the instrument, materials, and tinker's tools in order to perform this modification.

Your modified instrument requires attunement, can only be used by you, and counts as a tech focus for your tech powers while you are attuned to it. Your modified instrument has 4 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).

Some modification effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your tech save DC.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Potent Amplitude (Audiotech Engineering)</name>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>(Audiotech Engineering) (Audiotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>text</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Concussive Blast (Audiotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, you add your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of +1) to any damage you deal with tech powers and class features that deal sonic damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Smooth Rhythm (Audiotech Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, whenever you use your Potent Aptitude while your playing an enhanced song, you can roll a d6 and use it instead of expending a Potent Aptitude Dice.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Legendary Coda (Audiotech Engineering)</name>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Engineering Discipline: Biochem Engineering -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Discipline: Biochem Engineering</name>
        <text>Those engineers who choose the Biochem Engineering discipline focus on utilizing their vast knowledge of medicine and chemistry to supply allies with potent healing and enemies with debilitating poisons and acids.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Biochem Engineering)</name>
        <text>When you choose this discipline at 3rd level you gain proficiency in the Medicine skill, biochemist's kits, and poisoner�s kits. additionally, when you engage in crafting with biochemist's kits and poisoner's kits, the rate at which you craft doubles.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Biochemist's Pack (Biochem Engineering)</name>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Biochemist's Touch (Biochem Engineering)</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, whenever you grant temporary hit points, or deal acid or poison damage using a tech power or class feature, you may expend one use of your Potent Aptitude to increase the pote</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Potent Mixtures (Biochem Engineering)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, when you cast a tech power of 1st-level or higher that grants temporary hit points, or deals acid or poison damage, you add your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of +1) to the roll.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Epicenter (Biochem Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, as a reaction when you take damage from a creature within 15 feet of you that you can see, you can use one of your mixtures. The effects of the mixture release in a 15-foot-radius sphere centered on you, and if the mixture requires a saving throw, you automatically succeed on it. Additionally, the affected area is difficult terrain to creatures other than you until the end of your next turn.

Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Masterful Mixtures (Biochem Engineering)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, when you deal acid or poison damage using a tech power or class feature, you ignore resistance and treat immunity as resistance.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Engineering Discipline: Cybertech Engineering -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Discipline: Cybertech Engineering</name>
        <text>Those engineers who choose the Cybertech Engineering discipline focus on the ability to craft reusable consumables and items that augment and complement their techcasting abilities.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Cybertech Engineering)</name>
        <text>When you choose this discipline at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in cybertech's tools. additionally, when you engage in crafting with cybertech's tools, the rate at which you craft doubles.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cybertech Contraptions (Cybertech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn modify gadgets and wristpads utilizing your cybertech knowledge. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend 500 cr worth of materials to modify your wristpad. You must have a wristpad, materials, and cybertech's tools in order to perform this modification.

Your wristpad requires attunement, can only be used by you, and counts as a tech focus for your tech powers while you are attuned to it. Your modified wristpad has 4 modification slots, and it gains more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. For each modification installed, your tech point maximum is reduced by 1. Over the course of a long rest, you can replace or remove a number of modifications up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).

Some modification effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your tech save DC.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Potent Techcasting (Cybertech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, when you miss with a tech attack roll, or a creature succeeds on a saving throw against a tech power you cast, you can expend one use of your Potent Aptitude to overwhelm them. Roll the die, and either add it to the attack roll or subtract it from their saving throw.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Adaptable Applications (Cybertech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, when you cast a tech power of 1st level or higher, you can choose to deal additional damage or provide additional healing with that power. The additional damage or healing equals half your engineer level (rounded down).

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Combat Contrivances (Cybertech Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, when you use your action to a cast a 1st-level or higher tech power, you can use your bonus action to gain temporary hit points equal to the level of the tech power + your Intelligence modifier.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Perfected Purposing (Cybertech Engineering)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, when you cast a tech power, you can choose to deal maximum damage or provide maximum healing with that power.

Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Engineering Discipline: Experimental Engineering -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Discipline: Experimental Engineering</name>
        <text>Those engineers who choose the Experimental Engineering discipline create and use untested combinations, resulting in powerful and often unpredictable effects.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>When you choose this discipline at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in a set of tools of your choice. Additionally, when you engage in crafting with tinker's tools, the rate at which you craft doubles.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Modified Tinkercannon (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to enhance your tinker's tools with unproven science, modifying them into a backpack with a cannon. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend 500 cr worth of materials to modify your tinker's tools. You must have materials and tinker's tools in order to perform this modification.

Whenever you cast a tech power of 1st level or higher while wielding your tinker's tools, you risk unexpected complications. Your GM can have you roll a d20. If you roll a 1, roll on the Experimental Engineering Surge table to create a random effect.

Additionally, your tinker's tools come equipped with 4 overrides, and they gain more at higher levels, as shown in the Modification Slots column of the engineer class table. Each time you trigger an Experimental Engineering Surge, you can use an override to reroll the percentile dice. You must use the new result, you can only do this once per surge, and your maximum tech points is reduced by 1 until you complete a long rest. You regain all expended overrides when you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Unstable Volley (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, as a bonus action you can expend one use of your Potent Aptitude to launch a volley of unstable energy at a surface located with-in 30 feet of you that you can see. This energy adheres to the surface for 1 minute, after which it erupts. As a part of this bonus action, or as a bonus action on each of your turns, you can cause the energy to erupt early. Each creature within 5 feet of it must make a Dext-erity saving throw against your tech save DC. A creature takes 1d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.

This damage increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to 2d6 at 5th level, 3d6 at 10th level, and 4d6 at 15th level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>(Experimental Engineering) (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>text</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Unstable Volley Increase (2d6) (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>The damage from your Unstable Volley feature increases to to 2d6 at 5th level, and again when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing 3d6 at 10th level, and 4d6 at 15th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Creative Destruction (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, you can add your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of +1) to any damage you deal with tech powers and class features. If the tech power or class feature would damage multiple creatures, you can only deal this additional damage to one of them.

If you choose to deal this additional damage, your GM can have you roll on the Experimental Engineering Surge table.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Unstable Volley Increase (3d6) (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>The damage from your Unstable Volley feature increases to 3d6 at 10th level, and again to 4d6 at 15th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Experimental Overrides (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you gain a modicum of control over your surges. Whenever you roll on the Experimental Engineering Surge table and use one of your overrides, you can choose either total.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Unstable Volley Increase (4d6) (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>The damage from your Unstable Volley feature increases to 4d6 at 15th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Engineering Bombardment (Experimental Engineering)</name>
        <text>Starting at 18th level, the harmful energies of your tech powers and class features intensify. When you roll damage for a tech power or class feature and roll the highest number possible on any of the dice, you can roll it again and use both results. You can only use this ability once per tech power or class feature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
