<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <class>
    <name>Guardian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <hd>10</hd>
    <proficiency>Constitution Saving Throws, Charisma Saving Throws, Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, Persuasion, Religion</proficiency>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>
    <armor>Light armor, medium armor</armor>
    <weapons>All lightweapons, all vibroweapons</weapons>
    <tools>None</tools>
    <wealth>1000+5d4x100</wealth>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <slots>4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Starting Guardian</name>
        <text>You start with proficiency in two skills. Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Lore* (History), Perception, Persuasion, and Piloting* (Religion).

You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background

	• (a) a martial lightweapon or vibroweapon and a light or medium shield or (b) two martial lightweaponss or vibroweapons
	• (a) combat suit and light shield or (b) light battle armor
	• (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack

Variant - Starting Wealth:
In lieu of the equipment granted by your class and background, you can elect to purchase your starting gear. If you do so, you receive no equipment from your class and background, and instead roll for your starting wealth using the criteria below:

	Funds = 1,000 + 5d4 x 100 cr

Important Note:
Fight Club 5 only uses standard Fifth Edition Skills, so we have mapped the skills in Star Wars 5e that are different this way.

	• History = Lore
	• Arcana = Technology
	• Religion = Piloting</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Guardian</name>
        <text>To multiclass as a Guardian, you must meet the following prerequisites:
 • Strength 13

You gain the following proficiencies
	• Light armor, all vibroweapons</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Forcecasting</name>
        <text>In your meditations on the force, you have learned powers, fragments of knowledge that imbue you with an abiding force ability. See chapter 10 for the general rules of forcecasting and chapter 11 for the force powers list.

Force Powers Known
You learn 4 force powers of your choice, and you learn more at higher levels, as shown in the Force Powers Known column of the guardian class table. You may not learn a force power of a level higher than your Max Power Level, and you may learn a force power at the same time you learn its prerequisite.

Force Points
You have a number of force points equal to your guardian level x 2, as shown in the Force Points column of the guardian class table, + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice). You use these force points to cast force powers. You regain all expended force points when you finish a long rest.

Max Power Level
Many force powers can be overpowered, consuming more force points to create a greater effect. You can overpower these abilities to a maximum level, which increases at higher levels, as shown in the Max Power Level column of the guardian class table.

You may only cast force powers at 5th-level once. You regain the ability to do so after a long rest.

Forcecasting Ability
Your forcecasting ability varies based on the alignment of the powers you cast. You use your Wisdom for light side powers, Charisma for dark side powers, and Wisdom or Charisma for universal powers (your choice). You use this ability score modifier whenever a power refers to your forcecasting ability. In addition, you use this ability score modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a force power you cast and when making an attack roll with one.

Force save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus +your forcecasting ability modifier

Force attack modifier = your proficiency bonus +your forcecasting ability modifier</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Channel the Force</name>
        <text>You know how to channel the Force to create a unique effect. You start with your choice from two such effects: Cause Harm and Lend Aid. At 3rd level, your Guardian Focus grants you an additional effect. When you use your Channel the Force, you choose which effect to create.
	Some Channel the Force effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your universal force save DC.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of once). You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Channel the Force: Cause Harm</name>
        <text>As an action, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force to sap the life from a hostile creature you can see within 30 feet. That creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes necrotic damage equal to your guardian level + your Charisma modifier (minimum of one), or half as much on a successful one.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Channel the Force: Lend Aid</name>
        <text>As a bonus action, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force and touch a creature within 5 feet of you. That creature regains hit points equal to your guardian level + your Wisdom modifier (minimum of one). Alternatively, if the creature is poisoned or diseased, you neutralize the poison or disease. If more than one poison or disease afflicts the target, you neutralize one poison or disease that you know is present, or you neutralize one at random.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <slots>5,4,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Force-Empowered Strikes</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend force points to deal additional damage to the target. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level force slot, plus 1d8 for each slot level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage is the same type as the weapon's damage.
	You can't use a higher level force slot than your Max Power Level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Guardian Aura</name>
        <text>Additionally at 2nd level, you gain an aura of your choice, as described at the end of the class description. When you reach 10th level you can select a second aura.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Conquest</name>
        <text>Whenever a creature who is frightened of you starts its turn within 5 feet of you, its speed is reduced to 0 and that creature takes psychic damage equal to half your guardian level.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Conviction</name>
        <text>You and friendly creatures within 5 feet of you can't be frightened.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Devotion</name>
        <text>You and friendly creatures within 5 feet of you can't be charmed.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Hatred</name>
        <text>You and friendly creatures within 5 feet of you gain a bonus to the first melee weapon damage rolls you make each round equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1).
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Presence</name>
        <text>Whenever you or a friendly creature within 5 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of +1).
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Protection</name>
        <text>Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to take that damage instead of that creature taking it. This feature doesn't transfer any other effects that might accompany the damage, and this damage can't be reduced in any way.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Vigor</name>
        <text>Whenever a friendly creature starts its turn within 5 feet of you, that creature gains temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one).
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Warding</name>
        <text>You and friendly creatures within 5 feet of you have resistance to damage from force powers.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <slots>6,6,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Guardian Foci</name>
        <text>Different guardians focus on different lightsaber fighting styles, called Forms, as they hone their powers.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form I: Shii-Cho</name>
        <text>Form I, also known as Determination Form, uses wild, unpredictable attacks designed to distract and disarm their foes. Those guardians who focus on Shii-Cho Form make seemingly random, yet deliberate, attacks to knock their opponents off-balance.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form I: Shii-Cho: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Dueling, Equilibrium, or Two-Weapon Fighting Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form I: Shii-Cho: The Way of the Sarlaac</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can enter a frenetic stance for one minute. While in this stance, the first time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, it has disadvantage on the next melee attack roll it makes against you before the start of your next turn. Additionally, if that creature is within 5 feet of you, it must make a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier). On a failed save, it is pushed back 5 feet, and you can immediately move into the space it just vacated without provoking opportunity attacks.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form I: Shii-Cho: Disarming Slash</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force (no action required) to attempt to disarm the target, forcing it to drop one item of your choice that it's holding. The creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, it drops the object you choose. If you are within 5 feet of the target, and you have a free hand, you can catch the item. Otherwise, the object lands at its feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form II: Makashi</name>
        <text>Form II, also known as Contention Form, encourages precision and efficiency over power, using jabs, parries and light cuts over slashes, blocks and chops. Those guardians who focus on Makashi Form utilize calculated blade manipulation, intense focus, and expert timing to confuse and trap their opponents.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form II: Makashi: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Dueling, Equilibrium, or Two-Weapon Fighting Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form II: Makashi: The Way of the Ysalamiri</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can enter an offensive stance for one minute. While in this stance, you add your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice) to the first melee weapon attack and damage rolls you make each turn.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form II: Makashi: Makashi Riposte</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	When another creature damages you with a melee attack, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force and use your reaction to attempt to deflect the attack. When you do so, the damage you take from the attack is reduced by 1d10 + your Dexterity modifier + your guardian level.
	If you reduce the damage to 0, you can immediately make a single melee weapon attack against that creature as a part of the reaction.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form III: Soresu</name>
        <text>Form III, also known as Resilience Form, relies on tight bladework and subtle dodges to provide maximum defensive coverage, minimizing exposure to ranged weaponry. Those guardians who focus on Soresu Form use broad footwork to move around the playing field, making broad, short sweeping motions that protect the body.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form III: Soresu: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in heavy armor.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form III: Soresu: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Defense, Shielding, or Sentinel Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form III: Soresu: The Way of the Mynock</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance for one minute. As a part of this bonus action, and as a bonus action on each of your turns, you can cast the saber ward power. When you do so, you have a number of special reactions equal to your proficiency bonus that you can only use to cast the saber reflect force power. You can only take one reaction per turn.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form III: Soresu: Advancing Defender</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
   When you cast the saber reflect power, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force to move up to 10 feet as a part of that same reaction. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IV: Ataru: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Great Weapon Fighting, Two-Weapon Fighting, or Versatile Fighting Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IV: Ataru: The Way of the Hawk-Bat</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you you can take an aggressive stance, leaping around the battlefield for 1 minute. As a part of this bonus action, and as a bonus action on each of your turns, you can cast the force jump power at 1st-level without expending force points. Additionally, when you cast force jump, you have advantage on the first attack roll you make against each creature within 5 feet of where you land.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IV: Ataru: Retreating Leap</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	When a creature makes a melee attack roll against you, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force and your reaction to jump 10 feet in a direction of your choice, imposing disadvantage on the roll. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks. You can wait until after the attack roll is made, but before the DM determines whether the attack hits.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form V: Djem So</name>
        <text>Form V, also known as Perseverance Form, utilizes a force-enhanced strength to overwhelm opponents. Those guardians who focus on Djem So Form actively attempt to force an opening rather than waiting for the opportunity to present itself.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form V: Djem So: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in heavy armor.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form V: Djem So: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Great Weapon Fighting, Sentinel, or Versatile Fighting Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form V: Djem So: The Way of the Krayt Dragon</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can take a threatening stance for one minute. While in this stance, the first time you hit with a melee weapon attack using Strength each turn, you can attempt to damage another creature with the same attack. Choose another creature within 5 feet of the original target and within your reach. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes damage equal to your Strength modifier. The damage is of the same type dealt by the original attack.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form V: Djem So: Falling Avalanche</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	On your turn, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force (no action required) and reduce your speed by half to gain advantage on the next ability check or attack roll you make using Strength before the end of your next turn. You can not use this feature if you have moved more than half your speed this turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VI: Niman</name>
        <text>Form VI, also known as Moderation Form, strikes a balance between bladework and force powers. Those guardians who focus on Niman Form weave Force manipulation with their melee weapon strikes, pushing their opponents off-balance to create an opening.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VI: Niman: The Way of the Rancor</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can enter a balanced stance for one minute. As a part of this bonus action, and as a bonus action on each of your turns, when you use your action to cast a force power, you can make one melee weapon attack.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VI: Niman: Telekinetic Slash</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	When you deal damage with an at-will force power, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force and expend force points to deal additional damage to the target. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level force slot, plus 1d8 for each slot level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage is the same type as the power's damage.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VII: Juyo</name>
        <text>Form VII, also known as Ferocity Form, revels in the satisfaction of battle and victory. Those guardians who focus on Juyo Form channel their emotions into their fighting, making heavy, sweeping strikes.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VII: Juyo: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in heavy armor.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VII: Juyo: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Great Weapon Fighting, Two-Weapon Fighting, or Versatile Fighting Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VII: Juyo: The Way of the Vornskr</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can take a savage stance, designating one creature you can see within 10 feet of you as your prey for 1 minute. You have advantage on attack rolls against the creature. If the target drops to 0 hit points, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn to mark a new creature.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VII: Juyo: Snap Aggression</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	If you are surprised at the start of combat and aren't incapacitated, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force to act normally on your first turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VIII: Sokan</name>
        <text>Form VIII, also known as Persistence Form, uses determined movements followed by swift strokes to keep their opponents' footing unsteady. Those guardians who focus on Persistence Form make use of thee terrain, trying to maneuver their opponents into vulnerable areas before dispatching them.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VIII: Sokan: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in heavy armor.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VIII: Sokan: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Defense, Equilibrium, or Shielding Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VIII: Sokan: The Way of the Varactyl</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can enter an unyielding stance for one minute. While in this stance, you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to shove or to avoid being moved, and you ignore difficult terrain. Additionally, once per turn, when you hit with a melee weapon attack, you can attempt to shove the target up to 10 feet away from you (no action required).
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VIII: Sokan: High Ground Defense</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	When an opponent within 5 feet of you makes a melee attack against you, you can use your reaction and expend a use of your Channel the Force to move to another space within 5 feet of that opponent without provoking opportunity attacks, imposing disadvantage on the roll. If the attack misses, you can attempt to shove the creature up to 10 feet away from you as a part of that same reaction.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IX: Trakata</name>
        <text>Form IX, also known as Deception Form, capitalizes on a lightweapon's ability to quickly be toggled on and off. Those guardians who focus on Trakata Form perform dazzling tricks with their lightweapon, confusing their opponents before dispatching them.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IX: Trakata: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Dueling, Two-Weapon Fighting, or Versatile Fighting Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IX: Trakata: The Way of the Monkey-Lizard</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can enter a confusing stance for one minute. As a part of this bonus action, and as a bonus action on each of your turns, when you take the Dodge action, you can make one melee weapon attack against a creature within range. Additionally, when you make this melee weapon attack, you can flourish your weapon to attempt to distract your target. Make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check contested by a Wisdom (Perception) check of the target of your attack. On a success, you make this attack roll with advantage.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IX: Trakata: Unbalancing Block</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	When you are hit with a melee weapon attack, and you are wielding a lightweapon with which you are proficient, you can use your reaction and expend a use of your Channel the Force to add your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of +1) to your AC for that attack, potentially causing the attack to miss you.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form X: Jar'Kai</name>
        <text>Form X, also known as Domination Form, utilizes two weapons to overwhelm their foes. Those guardians who focus on Jar'Kai Form know that two weapons offer greater versatility than one, and capitalize on the twin angles from which they attack to subdue their enemies.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form X: Jar'Kai: Fighting Style</name>
        <text>When you choose this form as your focus at 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one from the Equilibrium, Sentinel, or Two-Weapon Fighting Fighting Style options, detailed in Chapter 6. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form X: Jar'Kai: The Way of the Acklay</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can enter a destructive stance for one minute. While in this stance, you can add half your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice, minimum of one) to any melee weapon damage roll you make that doesn't already include that modifier. Additionally, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can move up to 5 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form X: Jar'Kai: Twin Strike</name>
        <text>Lastly at 3rd level, you gain the following Channel the Force option.
	Once per turn, when you miss with a melee weapon attack, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force to immediately make another melee weapon attack against the same target (no action required).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Brawling</name>
        <text>You are skilled at using your weight to your advantage. As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a medium or heavy shield, you gain the following benefits:
	• You are proficient with improvised weapons.
	• Your unarmed strikes use a d4 for damage.
	• When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike or an improvised weapon on your turn, you can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooting</name>
        <text>You are skilled at getting up close and personal with ranged weapons. While you are wielding a ranged weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:
When making a ranged weapon attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll.
	Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover against targets within 15 feet of you.
	You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
        <special>Fighting Style: Defense</special>
        <text>You are skilled at the art of defending yourself. While you are wearing armor with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:
	• You gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	• You have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to avoid being moved.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
        <special>Fighting Style: Dueling</special>
        <text>You are skilled in the art of fighting with a single melee weapon. While you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand with which you are proficient and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name>
        <text>You are skilled at putting the weight of a weapon to your advantage. While you are wielding a melee weapon in two hands with which you are proficient, when you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Equilibrium</name>
        <text>You are skilled at fighting while minimally armored. While you are wearing no armor and not wielding a medium or heavy shield, you gain the following benefits:
	• You gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	• You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with unarmed strikes and weapon attacks.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Sentinel</name>
        <text>You are skilled at techniques that take advantage of every drop in any enemy's guard. While you are wielding a melee weapon with which you are proficient, you can use a bonus action to enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make a number of opportunity attacks equal to your proficiency bonus without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Sharpshooting</name>
        <special>Fighting Style: Archery</special>
        <text>You are skilled with ranged weapons and can make shots that others find difficult. While you are wielding a ranged weapon with which you are proficient, gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Shielding</name>
        <text>You are skilled at using your shield to defend your allies as well as yourself. While you are wielding a medium or heavy shield with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:
When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll.
	If you are wielding a heavy shield, you are no longer required to wield a weapon with the light property in the other hand.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Throwing</name>
        <text>You are skilled with the techniques of throwing weapons. While you are wielding a weapon with the thrown property with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:
	• You gain a +1 bonus to ranged attack and damage rolls.
	• Whenever you make a ranged attack with a thrown weapon, you can immediately draw another weapon as part of the attack.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name>
        <special>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</special>
        <text>You are skilled at fighting with two weapons. While you are wielding separate weapons in each hand with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:
	• When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of your two-weapon fighting attack.
	• When you make an opportunity attack, you can attack with both of your weapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Fighting Style: Versatile Fighting</name>
        <text>You are skilled at using weapons in different ways. While you are wielding a melee weapon with the versatile property with which you are proficient and no other weapons, you gain the following benefits:
	• You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls while wielding a weapon in one hand.
	• You gain a +1 bonus to damage rolls while wielding a weapon in two hands.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <slots>7,8,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <slots>9,0,10,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Extra Attack</name>
        <text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <slots>10,0,12,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Force Purity</name>
        <text>By 6th level, the Force flowing through you makes you immune to poison and disease.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <slots>11,0,14,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form I: Shii-Cho: Unpredictable Motion</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, while you are wielding a melee weapon, opportunity attacks against you are made at disadvantage.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form II: Makashi: Shatterpoint</name>
        <text>Starting at 7th level, if you spend at least 1 minute observing or interacting with another creature outside combat, you can use your connection to the Force to sense their strengths and weak-nesses, and learn certain informat-ion about its capabilities compared to your own. The GM tells you if the creature is your equal, superior, or inferior in regard to two of the following characteristics of your choice:

	• Strength score
	• Dexterity score
	• Wisdom score
	• Charisma score
	• Armor Class
	• Current hit points
	• Total class levels (if any)
	• Total Forcecaster levels (if any)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form III: Soresu: Circle of Shelter</name>
        <text>At 7th level, you learn to fend off strikes directed at you, your mount, or other creatures nearby. If you or a creature you can see within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack, you can use your reaction to ward the creature if you're wielding a melee weapon or a shield. Roll 1d8 and add the number rolled to the target's AC against that attack. If the attack still hits, the target has resistance against the attack's damage.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (a minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IV: Ataru: Hawk-Bat Swoop</name>
        <text>At 7th level, you gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces without falIing during the move. If you end your turn in the air, you fall immediately to the ground.
	Additionally, you no longer take damage when falling from a distance no greater than your walking speed.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form V: Djem So: Vigor</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, if your total for a Strength check or saving throw is less than your Guardian level, you can use that value in place of the total.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VI: Niman: Enlightenment</name>
        <text>Starting at 7th level, you can add half your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one) to any saving throw you make that doesn't already include that modifier.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VII: Juyo: Relentless</name>
        <text>At 7th level, you have advantage on initiative rolls and gain a 10 foot bonus to your speed on your first turn of combat.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VIII: Sokan: Unwavering Self</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, if you fail a Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution saving throw, you can reroll the die. You must use the new roll.
	Once you've used this feature, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again. At 15th level you can use this feature twice between long rests.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IX: Trakata: Duplicitous Force</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, when you make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, you gain a bonus to that check equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form X: Jar'Kai: Eye of the Storm</name>
        <text>Beginning at 7th level, when you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you regain a use of your Channel the Force, to a maximum of your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <slots>12,0,16,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level, and again at 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <slots>14,0,0,18,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <slots>15,0,0,20,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
        <text>When you reach 10th level, and again at 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Second Guardian Aura</name>
        <text>When you reach 10th level you can select a second aura.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Conquest</name>
        <text>Whenever a creature who is frightened of you starts its turn within 5 feet of you, its speed is reduced to 0 and that creature takes psychic damage equal to half your guardian level.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Conviction</name>
        <text>You and friendly creatures within 5 feet of you can't be frightened.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Devotion</name>
        <text>You and friendly creatures within 5 feet of you can't be charmed.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Hatred</name>
        <text>You and friendly creatures within 5 feet of you gain a bonus to the first melee weapon damage rolls you make each round equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1).
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Presence</name>
        <text>Whenever you or a friendly creature within 5 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of +1).
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Protection</name>
        <text>Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to take that damage instead of that creature taking it. This feature doesn't transfer any other effects that might accompany the damage, and this damage can't be reduced in any way.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Vigor</name>
        <text>Whenever a friendly creature starts its turn within 5 feet of you, that creature gains temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one).
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Warding</name>
        <text>You and friendly creatures within 5 feet of you have resistance to damage from force powers.
	At 10th level, the range of this aura increases to 15 feet, and at 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <slots>16,0,0,22,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Improved Force-Empowered Strikes</name>
        <text>By 11th level, you are so suffused with righteous might that all your melee weapon strikes carry the power of the Force with them. Whenever you hit a creature with a melee weapon, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage. If you also use your Force-Empowered Strikes with an attack, you add this damage to the extra damage of your Force-Empowered Strikes. The damage is the same type as the weapon's damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <slots>17,0,0,24,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level, and again at 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <slots>19,0,0,0,26,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <slots>20,0,0,0,28,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Cleansing Touch</name>
        <text>Beginning at 14th level, you can use your action and expend a use of your Channel the Force ability to end one force power on yourself or on one willing creature that you touch.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <slots>21,0,0,0,30,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form I: Shii-Cho: Sarlaac Sweep</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, when a creature moves to within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature. If the attack hits, you can attempt to damage another creature within 5 feet of the original target and within your reach. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes damage equal to your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice). The damage is of the same type dealt by the original attack.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form II: Makashi: Glancing Blow</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form III: Soresu: Stand Against the Tide</name>
        <text>Beginning at 15th level, when a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IV: Ataru: Whirlwind Attack</name>
        <text>At 15th level, you can use your action to make melee attacks against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form V: Djem So: Brutal Strikes</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, the Force flowing through you grants you incredible strength. When you roll a 1 or 2 on a Force-Empowered Strikes or Improved Force-Empowered Strikes damage die, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.
	Additionally, when you spend force points to use your Force-Empowered Strikes feature, you gain temporary hit points equal to twice the number of points spent.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VI: Niman: Redirect</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, when you would be affected by a force power that requires a Dexterity saving throw or attack roll and would effect only you, you may redirect that power to another target within 30 feet. If the power required an attack roll, make an appropriate attack roll against the new target. If it required a Dexterity saving throw, the new target must make a Dexterity saving throw against your force save DC.
	Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VII: Juyo: Devastating Critical</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, when you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you gain a bonus to that weapon's damage roll equal to your guardian level.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VIII: Sokan: Unhindered Charge</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, when you move at least 10 feet before making a melee weapon attack, you deal additional damage equal to your Strength modifier.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IX: Trakata: Pass the Blade</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, when a creature misses you with an attack, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one), and you add your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one) to the first melee weapon attack and damage rolls you make against that creature before the end of your next turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form X: Jar'Kai: Rising Whirlwind</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, as an action, you can rush forward up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see without provoking opportunity attacks. Each creature within 5 feet of your path must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes normal weapon damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one. If you are wielding two melee weapons, or a weapon with the double property, a creature makes this save with disadvantage, and takes additional damage equal to your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice, minimum of one) on a failed save.
	Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <slots>22,0,0,0,32,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level, and again at 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <slots>24,0,0,0,0,34,0,0,0,0,</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <slots>25,0,0,0,0,36,0,0,0,0,</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <slots>26,0,0,0,0,38,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (6th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <slots>27,0,0,0,0,40,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form I: Shii-Cho: Master of Determination</name>
        <text>At 20th level, the erratic fluidity of your movement confounds even the most determined of foes. Your Strength or Dexterity and Wisdom or Charisma scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for these scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:
	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage from unenhanced weapons.
	• Attack rolls made against you can't have advantage.
	• When more than one creature is within 5 feet of you, you gain a bonus to your Armor Class equal to the number of creatures within 5 feet of you, up to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, minimum of one).
	• When you use your Sarlaac Sweep feature, you have advantage on the attack roll, and you can apply the bonus damage to every creature within 5 feet of you.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form II: Makashi: Master of Contention</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you are a duelist of the highest caliber. Your Dexterity and Wisdom or Charisma scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for those scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:
	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage, and you ignore resistance to kinetic and energy damage.
	• All melee attacks have disadvantage against you.
	• Your melee weapon attacks inflict an additional damage die.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form III: Soresu: Master of Resilience</name>
        <text>At 20th level, your presence on the field of battle is an inspiration to your allies. Your Constitution and Wisdom or Charisma scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for those scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:
	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage from unenhanced weapons.
	• When you use the saber reflect force power, you can make a single melee attack on an enemy within 5ft of you as a part of that same reaction.
	• You have advantage on Dexterity saving throws, as do your allies within 30 feet of you.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IV: Ataru: Master of Aggression</name>
        <text>At 20th level, your presence on the field of battle is as a graceful blur of deadly blades and daring acrobatics. Your Dexterity and Wisdom or Charisma scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for those scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:
	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage from unenhanced weapons.
	• When an ally within 30 feet of you takes the Attack action, they can make one additional attack as a part of that same action.
	• When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can move up to 10 feet. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form V: Djem So: Master of Perseverance</name>
        <text>At 20th level, your might overwhelms even the most implacable of foes. Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 2. Your maximum for these scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:
	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage from unenhanced weapons.
	• Once per turn, when you hit with a melee weapon attack using Strength, you can use your Force-Empowered Strikes feature at 1st-level without expending force points. You gain temporary hit points equal to the extra damage dealt.
	• When a creature within 5 feet of you makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to make a single weapon attack with advantage against that creature. If the attack hits, impose disadvantage on the triggering attack roll.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VI: Niman: Master of Moderation</name>
        <text>At 20th level, the Force flows in perfect concert with your weapon attacks. Your Dexterity and Wisdom or Charisma scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for these scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:
	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage from unenhanced weapons.
	• You have advantage on saving throws against force powers. Additionally, you have resistance against the damage of force powers.
	• When you use your action to cast an at-will force power that targets only one creature, you can target an additional creature within 5 feet of the original target and within the power's range.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VII: Juyo: Master of Ferocity</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you are a paragon of extraordinary martial prowess. Your Strength and Dexterity scores increase by 2. Your maximum for those scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:
	• You have resistance to all damage.
	• When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack as part of that action.
	• Your melee weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.
	This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form VIII: Sokan: Master of Persistence</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you are an unrelenting force on the field of battle. Your Strength and Wisdom or Charisma scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for these scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:
	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage from unenhanced weapons.
	• You ignore effects that would reduce your speed.
	• Once per turn, when you push a creature, you can move up to 10 feet as a part of this push without provoking opportunity attacks. If you end this movement within 5 feet of that creature, you can make one melee weapon attack (no action required).
	This effect ends early if you are incap-acitated or die. Once you've used this feature, you can't use it again until you complete a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form IX: Trakata: Master of Deception</name>
        <text>At 20th level, your skill with a lightweapon is both mesmerizing and confounding. Your Dexterity and Wisdom or Charisma scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for these scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:

	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage from unenhanced weapons.
	• Your attack rolls can't suffer from disadvantage.
	• Whenever a creature misses you with a melee attack, it takes 5 energy damage.
	• Whenever a creature hits you with a melee attack, it takes damage equal to half of the damage you take from the attack.

This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Form X: Jar'Kai: Master of Domination</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you are a whirlwind of strikes, eviscerating all who step within your reach. Your Strength and Dexterity scores increase by 2. Your maximum for these scores increases by 2. Additionally, you can use your action to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:

	• You have resistance to kinetic and energy damage from unenhanced weapons.
	• When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you have advantage on the next melee weapon attack roll you make against that creature, and that creature provokes an opportunity attack from you even if they take the Disengage action before leaving your reach until the end of your next turn.
	• Creatures provoke an opportunity attack from you when they enter your reach.

  This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or die. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
