<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <class>
    <name>Monk (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <hd>8</hd>
    <proficiency>Strength Saving Throws, Dexterity Saving Throws, Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Insight, Perception, Stealth</proficiency>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>
    <armor>None</armor>
    <weapons>Simple Blasters, Simple Vibroweapons, Chakrams, Techblades</weapons>
    <tools>None</tools>
    <wealth>1000+1d4x100</wealth>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Starting Monk</name>
        <text>You start with proficiency in two skills. Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, Insight, Lore* (History), Perception, and Stealth

You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background

	• (a) a chakram, (b) a techblade, © a simple vibroweapon, or (d) a simple blaster and a power cell
	• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack
	• 10 vibrodarts

Variant - Starting Wealth:
In lieu of the equipment granted by your class and background, you can elect to purchase your starting gear. If you do so, you receive no equipment from your class and background, and instead roll for your starting wealth using the criteria below:

	Funds = 1,000 + 2d4 x 100 cr

Important Note:
Fight Club 5 only uses standard Fifth Edition Skills, so we have mapped the skills in Star Wars 5e that are different this way.

	• History = Lore
	• Arcana = Technology
	• Religion = Piloting</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Monk</name>
        <text>To multiclass as a Monk, you must meet the following prerequisites:
 • Dexterity 13 and Wisdom 13

You gain the following proficiencies
	• Simple vibroweapons, techblades</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Defense</name>
        <text>Beginning at 1st level, while you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Martial Arts</name>
        <text>At 1st level, your practice of martial arts gives you mastery of combat styles that use unarmed strikes and monk weapons, which are chakrams, techblades, and any simple vibroweapons that don't have the two-handed or heavy property.
You gain the following benefits while you are unarmed or wielding only monk weapons and you aren't wearing armor or wielding a shield:

	• You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes and monk weapons.
	• You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon. This die changes as you gain monk levels, as shown in the Martial Arts column of the Monk table.
	• When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike or a monk weapon on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action. For example, if you take the Attack action and attack with a quarterstaff, you can also make an unarmed strike as a bonus action, assuming you haven't already taken a bonus action this turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Focus</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, your training allows you to harness the mystic energy of focus. Your access to this energy is represented by a number of focus points. Your monk level determines the number of points you have, as shown in the Focus Points column of the Monk table.
	You can spend these points to fuel various focus features. You start knowing three such features: Flurry of Blows, Patient Defense, and Step of the Wind. You learn more focus features as you gain levels in this class.
	When you spend a focus point, it is unavailable until you finish a short or long rest, at the end of which you draw all of your expended focus back into yourself. You must spend at least 30 minutes of the rest meditating to regain your focus points.
Some of your focus features require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature's effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:

	Focus save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice)

Flurry Of Blows:
Immediately after you take the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 focus point to make two unarmed strikes as a bonus action.

Patient Defense:
You can spend 1 focus point to take the Dodge action as a bonus action on your turn.

Step Of The Wind:
You can spend 1 focus point to take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action on your turn, and your jump distance is doubled for the turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Movement</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels, as shown in the Monk table.
	At 9th level, you gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids on your turn without falling during the move.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Deflect Missiles</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your reaction to deflect a projectile when you are hit by a ranged weapon attack. When you do so, the damage you take from the attack is reduced by 1d 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your monk level.
	If you reduce the damage to 0, and the damage is energy or ion, you can redirect it at another target if you have a weapon capable of doing so. You can spend 1 focus point to make a ranged attack as you deflect the projectile, as part of the same reaction. You make this attack with proficiency, regardless of your weapon proficiencies, and the projectile counts as a monk weapon for the attack.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Order</name>
        <text>When you reach 3rd level, you commit yourself to one a monastic order, which is detailed at the end of the class description. Your order grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Slow Fall</name>
        <text>Beginning at 4th level, you can use your reaction when you fall to reduce any falling damage you take by an amount equal to five times your monk level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Martial Arts Damage Die Increase (d6)</name>
        <text>Your martial arts damage die is now a d6.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Extra Attack</name>
        <text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Stunning Strike</name>
        <text>Starting at 5th level, you can interfere with an opponent's body. When you hit another creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 1 focus point to attempt a stunning strike. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of your next turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature>
        <name>Focused Strikes</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, your unarmed strikes count as enhanced for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to unenhanced attacks and damage.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Movement Improvement (+15)</name>
        <text>Your speed now increases by 15 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels, as shown in the Monk table.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Speed +15</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature>
        <name>Evasion</name>
        <text>At 7th level, your instinctive agility lets you dodge out of the way of certain area effects. When you are subjected to an effect, such as a consular's force storm or an engineer's explosion, that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on a saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Stillness Of Mind</name>
        <text>Starting at 7th level, you can use your action to end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level, and again at 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Movement Improvement</name>
        <text>At 9th level, you gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids on your turn without falling during the move.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
        <text>When you reach 10th level, and again at 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Movement Improvement (+20)</name>
        <text>Your speed now increases by 20 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels, as shown in the Monk table.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Speed +20</modifier>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Purity Of Body</name>
        <text>At 10th level, your mastery of the focus flowing through you makes you immune to disease and poison.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Martial Arts Damage Die Increase (d8)</name>
        <text>Your martial arts damage die is now a d8.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level, and again at 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature>
        <name>Tongue of the Sun And Moon</name>
        <text>Starting at 13th level, you learn to touch the focus of other minds so that you understand all spoken languages. Moreover, any creature that can understand a language can understand what you say.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature>
        <name>Diamond Soul</name>
        <text>Beginning at 14th level, your mastery of focus grants you proficiency in all saving throws.
	Additionally, whenever you make a saving throw and fail, you can spend 1 focus point to reroll it and take the second result.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Movement Improvement (+25)</name>
        <text>Your speed now increases by 25 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels, as shown in the Monk table.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Speed +25</modifier>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Timeless Body</name>
        <text>At 15th level, your focus sustains you so that you suffer none of the frailty of old age, and you can't be aged abnormally. You can still die of old age, however. In addition, you no longer need food or water.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level, and again at 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature>
        <name>Martial Arts Damage Die Increase (d10)</name>
        <text>Your martial arts damage die is now a d10.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Movement Improvement (+30)</name>
        <text>Your speed now increases by 30 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels, as shown in the Monk table.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Speed +30</modifier>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Empty Body</name>
        <text>Beginning at 18th level, you can use your action to spend 4 focus points to become invisible for 1 minute. During that time, you also have resistance to all damage but force damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement (6th)</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Alternatively, you can choose a feat (see Chapter 6 for a list of feats).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Perfect Self</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you've gained perfect control over your body. Your Dexterity and Wisdom or Charisma scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for those scores increases by 2. Additionally, when you roll for initiative and have no focus points remaining, you regain 2 focus points.</text>
        <modifier category="Bonus">Dexterity Bonus +2</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Monastic Order: Aing-Tii Order -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Order: Aing-Tii Order</name>
        <text>Monks of the Aing-Tii Order blend an attunement to the Force with their supreme focus to become a blur of motion in the heat of battle.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Forcecasting (Aing-Tii Order)</name>
        <text>When you choose this Order at 3rd level, you have learned powers, fragments of knowledge that imbue you with an abiding force ability. See chapter 10 for the general rules of forcecasting and chapter 11 for the force powers list.

Force Powers Known:
You learn 4 force powers of your choice, and you learn more at higher levels, as shown in the Force Powers Known column of the Aing-Tii Order Forcecasting table. You may not learn a force power of a level higher than your Max Power Level, and you may learn a force power at the same time you learn its prerequisite.

Force Points:
You have a number of force points equal to your monk level, as shown in the Force Points column of the Aing-Tii Order Forcecasting table, + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice). You use these force points to cast force powers. You regain all expended force points when you finish a long rest.

Max Power Level:
Many force powers can be overpowered, consuming more force points to create a greater effect. You can overpower these abilities to a maximum level, which increases at higher levels, as shown in the Max Power Level column of the Aing-Tii Order Forcecasting table.
	You may only cast force powers at 4th-level once. You regain the ability to do so after a long rest.

Forcecasting Ability:
Your forcecasting ability varies based on the alignment of the powers you cast. You use your Wisdom for light side powers, Charisma for dark side powers, and Wisdom or Charisma for universal powers (your choice). You use this ability score modifier whenever a power refers to your forcecasting ability. In addition, you use this ability score modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a force power you cast and when making an attack roll with one.

	Force save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus +your forcecasting ability modifier

	Force attack modifier = your proficiency bonus +your forcecasting ability modifier</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Flow-Walking (Aing-Tii Order)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you can cast the phasestrike force power without expending force points. When you reach 11th level, the damage bonus of the special attack made during phasestrike increases to 2d8, and at 17th level it increases to 3d8.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Focused Flurry (Aing-Tii Order)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, when you use your action to cast an at-will force power, you can use your Martial Arts and Focus features.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Prismatic Step (Aing-Tii Order)</name>
        <text>At 11th level, when you take the Attack action, you can teleport up to 10 feet before each attack to an unoccupied space you can see.
	If you attack at least two different creatures with the action, you can make one additional attack against a third creature (no action required).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Iridescent Strikes (Aing-Tii Order)</name>
        <text>Starting at 17th level, when you use your action to cast a force power, you can spend 2 focus points to teleport to a space within 5 feet of a creature affected by the power and make two unarmed attacks against that creature as a bonus action.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Monastic Order: Echani Order -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Order: Echani Order</name>
        <text>Monks of the Echani Order train relentlessly both with and without their weapons, to the point where the weapon becomes an extension of the body. Founded on a mastery of sword fighting, the tradition has expanded to include many different weapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Path Of The Echani (Echani Order)</name>
        <text>Beginning when you choose this order at 3rd level, your special martial arts training leads you to master the use of certain weapons. You gain the following benefits.

          Echani Weapons:
Choose two types of weapons to be your Echani weapons: one vibroweapon and one blaster. Each of these weapons can be any simple or martial weapon that lacks the heavy and special properties. You gain proficiency with these weapons if you don't already have it. Weapons of the chosen types are monk weapons for you. Many of this tradition's features work only with your Echani weapons. When you reach 6th, 11th, and 17th level in this class, you can choose another type of weapon to be an Echani weapon for you, following the criteria above.

Agile Parry:
If you make an unarmed strike as part of the Attack action on your turn and are holding a Echani weapon, you can use it to defend yourself if it is a melee weapon. You gain a +2 bonus to AC until the start of your next turn, while the weapon is in your hand and you aren't incapacitated.

Echani's Shot:
You can use a bonus action on your turn to make your ranged attacks with an Echani weapon more deadly. When you do so, any target you hit with a ranged attack using an Echani weapon takes an extra 1d4 damage of the weapon's type. You retain this benefit until the end of the current turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>One With the Blade (Echani Order)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you extend your focus into your Echani weapons, granting you the following benefits.
	Enhanced Echani Weapons:
Your attacks with your Echani weapons count as enhanced for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to unenhanced attacks and damage.
	Deft Strike:
When you hit a target with a Echani weapon, you can spend 1 focus point to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target equal to your Martial Arts die. You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sharpen The Blade (Echani Order)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, you gain the ability to augment your weapons further with your focus. As a bonus action, you can expend up to 3 focus points to grant one Echani weapon you touch a bonus to attack and damage rolls when you attack with it. The bonus equals the number of points you spent. This bonus lasts for 1 minute or until you use this feature again. This feature has no effect on an enhanced weapon that already has a bonus to attack and damage rolls.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Unerring Accuracy (Echani Order)</name>
        <text>At 17th level, your mastery of weapons grants you extraordinary accuracy. If you miss with an attack roll using a monk weapon on your turn, you can reroll it. You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Monastic Order: Jal Shey Order -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Order: Jal Shey Order</name>
        <text>Monks of the Jal Shey order, driven by the pursuit of knowledge, maintain one of the most well-respected and heavily guarded repositories of history and knowledge across the galaxy: the Archives of the Jal Shey. Here, young folk of all species seeking the clarity of truth and the strength of knowledge pledge to learn the arts of seeking enlightenment by understanding the world around them, and mastering the techniques to defend it. To become a Jal Shey monk is to give one's self to the quest for unveiling the deepest mysteries of the galaxy, to bring light to the secrets of the dark, and guard the most powerful and dangerous of truths.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mystical Erudition (Jal Shey Order)</name>
        <text>Beginning when you choose this order at 3rd level, you've undergone extensive training in lore from the Jal Shey's collected knowledge. You learn one language of your choice, and you gain proficiency in your choice of Lore* (History), Medicine, Nature, or Technology* (Arcana).
	You learn an additional language and an additional skill proficiency from the above list at 11th and 17th level.
Important Note:

*Fight Club 5 only uses standard Fifth Edition Skills, so we have mapped the skills in Star Wars 5e that are different this way.
	• History = Lore
	• Arcana = Technology
	• Religion = Piloting</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Extract Aspects (Jal Shey Order)</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you can strike multiple pressure points to extract crucial details about your foe. Whenever you hit a creature with one of the attacks granted by your Flurry of Blows, you can learn learn certain information about its capabilities. The GM tells you if the creature has two of the following characteristics of your choice:

	• Condition immunities
	• Damage vulnerabilities
	• Damage resistances
	• Damage immunities</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Extort Truth (Jal Shey Order)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you can hit a series of hidden nerves on a creature with precision, temporarily causing them to be unable to mask their true thoughts and intent. When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can have the attack deal no damage and spend 1 focus point to force them to make a Charisma saving throw against your focus save DC. On a failed save, the creature is unable to speak a deliberate lie for 1 minute and all Charisma checks directed at the creature are made with advantage for the duration.
	On a success or failure, a creature is aware that you attempted to influence them. They can choose to avoid answering questions to which they would normally respond with a lie.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Preternatural Counter (Jal Shey Order)</name>
        <text>Also at 6th level, your quick mind and study of your foe allows you to use their failure to your advantage. When a creature within 5 feet of you misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to make an unarmed strike against that creature.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mind Of Mercury (Jal Shey Order)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, you've honed your awareness and reflexes through mental aptitude and pattern recognition. Once per turn, if you've already used your reaction, you can spend 1 focus point to take an additional reaction. You can only take one reaction per turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Debilitating Barrage (Jal Shey Order)</name>
        <text>At 17th level, you've gained the knowledge to temporarily inhibit a creature's fortitude by striking a series of pressure points. Whenever you hit a creature with one of the attacks granted by your Flurry of Blows, you can spend 3 focus points to cause the creature to become vulnerable to a damage type of your choice. This effect lasts for 1 minute or until they take damage of the chosen type.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Monastic Order: Matukai Order -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Order: Matukai Order</name>
        <text>Monks of the Matukai Order center their philosophy around a balance and harmony between the spiritual Force and the physical body, using exercise as a form of meditation. They channel the Force through their bodies, turning themselves into exceptional warriors.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Force-Enhanced Strikes (Matukai Order)</name>
        <text>Beginning when you choose this order at 3rd level, you learn to channel the Force into your unarmed strikes and monk weapons, further enhancing your melee strikes. When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike or monk weapon, you can spend 1 focus point to deal it an additional 1d6 force damage.
	The force damage increases to 2d6 when you reach 11th level in this class.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Instinctive Leap (Matukai Order)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, when a hostile creatures moves to within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to disengage and leap up to half your speed. If you end this movement in the air, you immediately fall to the ground.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Absorb Damage (Matukai Order)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, you learn to channel the Force into your skin and bones, greatly enhancing your durability. You can use a bonus action to channel the Force throughout your body. Until the start of your next turn, you have resistance to kinetic and energy damage.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Control The Field (Matukai Order)</name>
        <text>At 17th level, whenever you use your Instinctive Leap feature, you can leap your entire movement speed instead of only half. Additionally, when you land, you can make an unarmed strike with advantage against a creature within 5 feet of you as part of the same reaction. On a hit, this attack deals an additional 2d6 force damage.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Monastic Order: Nightsister Order -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Order: Nightsister Order</name>
        <text>Monks of the Nightsister Order utilize an innate Force-sensitivity to commune with death. They learn to channel this power to drain the life of their foes to prolong their own existence. Males who join this order are called Nightbrothers.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ichor Lightning (Nightsister Order)</name>
        <text>Beginning when you choose this order at 3rd level, you gain a new attack option that you can use with the Attack action. This special attack is a ranged force attack with a range of 30 feet. You are proficient with it, and you add your Dexterity modifier to its attack and damage rolls. Its damage is necrotic, and its damage die is a d4. This die changes as you gain monk levels, as shown in the Martial Arts column of the Monk table.

When you take the Attack action on your turn and use this special attack as part of it, you can spend 1 focus point to make the special attack twice as a bonus action.

When you gain the Extra Attack feature, this special attack can be used for any of the attacks you make as part of the Attack action.

When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with this attack, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier + your monk level (your choice, minimum of one).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Dark Magick (Nightsister Order)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, when you take this action, each creature within 30 feet of you that can see you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your focus save DC or be charmed or frightened (your choice) of you until the end of your next turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mastery Of Death (Nightsister Order)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, when you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can expend 1 focus point (no action required) to have 1 hit point instead.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Spirit Blade Assault (Nightsister Order)</name>
        <text>At 17th level, as an action, you conjure a blade of negative energy and strike one creature within 5 feet of you with it, expending 1 to 10 focus points. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 2d10 necrotic damage per focus point spent, or half as much on a successful one.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Monastic Order: Teras Kasi Order -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Order: Teras Kasi Order</name>
        <text>Monks of the Teras Kasi Order are the ultimate masters of martial arts combat, whether armed or unarmed. They learn techniques to push and trip their opponents, manipulate focus to heal damage to their bodies, and practice advanced meditation that can protect them from harm.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Open Hand Technique (Teras Kasi Order)</name>
        <text>Beginning when you choose this order at 3rd level, you can manipulate your enemy's focus when you harness your own. Whenever you hit a creature with one of the attacks granted by your Flurry of Blows, you can impose one of the following effects on that target:

	• It must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be knocked prone.
	• It must make a Strength saving throw. If it fails, you can push it up to 15 feet away from you.
	• It can't take reactions until the end of your next turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wholeness of Body (Teras Kasi Order)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to heal yourself. As an action, you can regain hit points equal to three times your monk level.

Once you've used this feature, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Tranquility (Teras Kasi Order)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, you can enter a special meditation that surrounds you with an aura of peace. At the end of a long rest, you gain the effect of a sanctuary force power that lasts until the start of your next long rest (the power can end early as normal). The saving throw DC for the power equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Quivering Palm (Teras Kasi Order)</name>
        <text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to set up lethal vibrations in someone's body. When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can spend 3 focus points to start these imperceptible vibrations, which last for a number of days equal to your monk level. The vibrations are harmless unless you use your action to end them. To do so, you and the target must be on the same planet. When you use this action, the creature must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, it is reduced to 0 hit points. If it succeeds, it takes 10d10 necrotic damage.

You can have only one creature under the effect of this feature at a time. You can choose to end the vibrations harmlessly (no action required).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Monastic Order: Whills Order -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Order: Whills Order</name>
        <text>Monks of the Whills Order hold the secrets of the Force sacred, and dedicate their lives to defending ancient knowledge of the Force and its artifacts. They master the use of ranged weapons, often crafting their own weapons in respectful admiration of the Jedi tradition of crafting lightweapons.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Flurry Of Light (Whills Order)</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you gain proficiency in blaster pistole, blaster rifle, ion blaster, ion rifle, and the lightbow, which are your Whills weapons and are monk weapons for you. When you are wielding a Whills weapon, you gain the following benefits:

	• Your Whills weapons count as melee weapons for you, and when you make a melee weapon attack with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to your Martial Arts Damage Die.
	• When you take the Attack action on your turn and attack with a Whills weapon, you can make one additional attack with that weapon as a bonus action, or you can spend 1 focus point to make two attacks with that weapon as a bonus action. You roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your Whills weapon when attacking as a bonus action. This die changes as you gain monk levels, as shown in the Martial Arts column of the Monk table.
	• When you would make a ranged weapon attack with a Whills weapon, you can instead reload the weapon.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>The Force Is With You (Whills Order)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, as you channel the Force through you, you gain the following benefits:

	• You can use your Stunning Strike feature when you hit with a ranged weapon attack while you are wielding a Whills weapon.
	• You can spend 1 focus point to ignore half cover with your Whills weapons. At 11th level, you can spend 2 focus points to ignore three quarters cover. At 17th level, you can spend 3 focus points to ignore total cover, as long as your target is not hidden from you.
	• When you hit a creature with a Whills weapon, that creature has disadvantage on opportunity attacks against you until the start of your next turn.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>One With The Force (Whills Order)</name>
        <text>At 11th level, you learn how to enter a trance, preparing to unleash yourself upon your enemy. While in this trance, you can still talk and move. If you stay in the trance for at least one minute, when you roll initiative, you can make a ranged weapon attack on a number of creatures up to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of one) within 30 feet of you when you were in this trance.

Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Guided Strikes (Whills Order)</name>
        <text>At 17th level, your first ranged weapon attack and your first melee weapon attack each turn deal additional damage equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of +1).</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
