<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <feat>
    <name>(Conditions)</name>
    <text>Blinded:
	• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

Charmed:
	• A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or enhanced effects.
	• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

Deafened:
	• A deafened creature can't hear and automatically fails any ability check that requires hearing.

Diseased:
	• A diseased creature suffers effects that vary based on the disease.

Exhaustion:
	• Some special abilities and environmental hazards, and the long-term effects of freezing or scorching temperatures, can lead to a special condition called exhaustion. Exhaustion is measured in six levels. An effect can give a creature one or more levels of exhaustion, as specified in the effect's description.

Exhaustion Level:
Level | Effect
1 | Disadvantage on ability checks
2 | 1 slowed level
3 | Disadvantage on attack rolls and saving throws
4 | Hit point maximum halved
5 | 4 slowed levels
6 | Death

	• If an already exhausted creature suffers another effect that causes exhaustion, its current exhaustion level increases by the amount specified in the effect's description.

	• A creature suffers the effect of its current exhaustion level as well as all lower levels. For example, a creature suffering level 2 exhaustion has 1 slowed level and has disadvantage on ability checks.

	• An effect that removes exhaustion reduces its level as specified in the effect's description, with all exhaustion effects ending if a creature's exhaustion level is reduced below 1.

	• Finishing a long rest reduces a creature's exhaustion level by 1, provided that the creature has also ingested some food and drink.

Frightened:
	• A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.
	• The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.

Grappled:
	• A grappled creature has 4 slowed levels.
	• The condition ends if the grappler is incapacitated (see the condition).
	• The condition also ends if an effect removes the grappled creature from the reach of the grappler or grappling effect.

Incapacitated:
	• An incapacitated creature can't take actions or reactions.

Invisible:
	• An invisible creature is impossible to see without the aid of powers or a special sense. For the purpose of hiding, the creature is heavily obscured. The creature's location can be detected by any noise it makes or any tracks it leaves.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have disadvantage, and the creature's attack rolls have advantage.

Paralyzed:
	• A paralyzed creature is incapacitated (see the condition) and can't move or speak.
	• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws. Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.
	• Any attack that hits the creature is a critical hit if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature.

Petrified:
	• A petrified creature is transformed, along with any object it is wearing or carrying, into a solid inanimate substance (usually stone). Its weight increases by a factor of ten, and it ceases aging.
	• The creature is incapacitated (see the condition), can't move or speak, and is unaware of its surroundings.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.
	• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	• The creature has resistance to all damage.
	• The creature is immune to poison and disease, although a poison or disease already in its system is suspended, not neutralized.

Poisoned:
	• A poisoned creature has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks.

Prone:
	• A prone creature's only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.
	• The creature has disadvantage on melee attack rolls.
	• The creature has disadvantage on ranged attack rolls against targets within 30 feet.
	• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.

Restrained:
	• A restrained creature has 4 slowed levels.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.
	• The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws.

Shocked:
	• A shocked creature can't take reactions	• On its turn, a shocked creature can take either an action or a bonus action, but not both.

Slowed:
	• Some abilities, effects, and hazards can lead to a special condition called slowed. Slowed is measured in four levels. An effect can give a creature one or more levels of slowed, as specified in the effect's description.

Slowed Level:
Level | Effect
1 | Speed reduced by 15 feet
2 | Speed reduced by 25 feet
3 | Speed reduced by 30 feet
4 | Speed reduced to 0, and can't benefit from any bonus to speed

	• If an already slowed creature suffers another effect that causes it to be slowed, its current slowed level increases by the amount specified in the effect's description.

	• An effect that removes slowed reduces its level as specified in the effect's description, with all slowed effects ending if a creature's slowed level is reduced below 1.

Stunned:
	• A stunned creature is incapacitated (see the condition), can't move, and can speak only falteringly.
	• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.

Unconscious:
	• An unconscious creature is incapacitated (see the condition), can't move or speak, and is unaware of its surroundings	• The creature drops whatever it's holding and falls prone.
	• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.
	• Any attack that hits the creature is a critical hit if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>(Fighting Styles)</name>
    <text>Akimbo Mastery:

	• You've mastered fighting with two blasters, unleashing a volley of shots. While you are wielding separate weapons in each hand with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you roll the maximum on a weapon damage die against a creature, that creature suffers a -1 penalty on the first attack roll it makes before the start of your next turn.

	• You can engage in Two-Weapon Fighting even when the weapons you are wielding lack the light property.

	• You can reload two weapons when you would normally only be able to reload only one.

	• When you take the Attack action, you can choose to attack swiftly at the expense of accuracy. Your weapon attack is made without the aid of your proficiency bonus, but you can use your reaction to attack with a different weapon that you're holding in the other hand, also without your proficiency bonus. If you would make more than one attack when you take the Attack action, only one attack is made without your proficiency bonus.

Berserk Mastery:
	• You've mastered returning pain to those who deliver it, becoming a scourge on the battlefield. You gain the following benefits:

	• When a creature within 5 feet of you deals damage to you with a weapon or unarmed strike, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack or unarmed strike against that creature. On a hit, you deal additional damage equal to your proficiency bonus.

	• When a creature scores a critical hit against you, you have advantage on the first attack you make against that creature before the end of your next turn. If you would already have advantage, you can instead reroll one of the dice once.

	• You have advantage on saving throws that would force you to act against your will, be frightened, or prevent you from attacking a creature.

Brawler Mastery:
	• You've mastered using your weight to your advantage, easily wrangling targets around. You gain the following benefits:

	• Your improvised weapons use a d6 for damage and gain the versatile (2d4) property.

	• Your damage die for your unarmed strikes and natural weapons increases by one step (from 1 to d4, d4 to d6, or d6 to d8).

	• Your speed isn't halved by carrying a grappled creature who is the same size category as you or smaller.

	• Once per turn, when you hit a creature with an unarmed strike or a weapon wielded in one hand on your turn, you can make an additional unarmed strike against the same target without the aid of your proficiency bonus (no action required).

Covert Mastery:
	• You've mastered fighting from unseen angles, gaining an advantage over your foes. You gain the following benefits:

	• You can try to hide when you are lightly obscured from the creature from which you are hiding.

	• Dim light doesn't impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.

	• When you are hidden from a creature and miss it with an unarmed strike or weapon attack, making the attack doesn't automatically reveal your position.

	• Once per turn, when you deal damage to a creature with an unarmed strike or weapon attack while hidden from it, you deal additional damage equal to your proficiency bonus.

Defense Mastery:
	• You've mastered the art of defending yourself, treating your armor as a second skin. While you are wearing medium or heavy armor with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Damage that you take from weapons is reduced by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus. If this would reduce the damage to 0, the damage is instead reduced to 1.

	• When a creature makes a melee attack against you while within your reach, whether the attack hits or misses, you can use your reaction to attempt to shove that creature up to 10 feet directly away from you.

	• The time it takes for you to don and doff armor is reduced by half.

Disruption Mastery:
	• Choose one from force- or tech-casting. You've mastered fighting and interfering with casters of the chosen type, confounding their concentration. You gain the following benefits:

	• When a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see casts a power, they provoke an opportunity attack from you.

	• Whenever you force a creature to make a saving throw to maintain concentration, the DC for the saving throw increases by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus.

	• You have advantage on saving throws against powers cast by creatures you can see if you've dealt damage to them since the start of your last turn.

Dual Wield Mastery:
	• You've mastered fighting with two weapons, becoming a flurry of motion. While you are wielding separate weapons in each hand with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you use your bonus action to engage in Two-Weapon Fighting, you can choose to forgo one or more attacks. For each attack you forgo, you gain a +1 bonus to AC until the start of your next turn.

	• You can engage in Two-Weapon Fighting even when the weapons you are wielding lack the light property.

	• You can draw or stow two weapons when you would normally be able to draw or stow only one.

	• When you use your bonus action to engage in Two-Weapon Fighting, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If you do so, you can make an additional attack with that weapon, also without your proficiency bonus. If you would normally make more than one attack with your bonus action, only one attack is made without your proficiency bonus.

Duelist Mastery:
	• You've mastered the art of fighting with a single weapon, making one weapon feel like many. While you are wielding a weapon in one hand with which you are proficient and no other weapons, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you take the Attack action, you can choose to attack with haste at the expense of accuracy. Your weapon attack is made without the aid of your proficiency bonus, but you can use your reaction to make an additional weapon attack, also without your proficiency bonus. If you would make more than one attack when you take the Attack action, only one attack is made without your proficiency bonus.

	• When a creature hits you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to add your proficiency bonus to your AC for that attack, potentially causing the attack to miss you.

	• You have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to avoid being disarmed.

Equilibrium Mastery:
	• You've mastered fighting without the confines of armor, treating combat as an elegant dance. While you are wearing light or no armor and not wielding a shield, you gain the following benefits:

	• When a creature misses you with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to make an unarmed strike or weapon attack against that creature without your proficiency bonus.

	• When a creature hits you with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to impose a penalty to the attack roll equal to your proficiency bonus, potentially causing the attack to miss.

	• If you are disarmed, you can use your reaction to immediately catch the weapon.

Explosives Mastery:
	• You've mastered fighting with explosives, causing untold destruction. You gain the following benefits:

	• When determining the save DC of an ammunition or explosive you control, you can use 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier, if it would be higher than the item's DC.

	• When using an ammunition or explosive that requires a saving throw and deals damage, you can take a penalty to the save DC equal to your proficiency bonus. If you do so, the item's damage increases by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus.

	• You have advantage on saving throws against ammunition and explosive you control.

Formation Mastery:
	• You've mastered fighting with a partner, learning to move and act as a single unit. While an ally is within 5 feet of you, you gain the following benefits:

	• When a creature misses an ally within 5 feet of you with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to make a weapon attack against that creature without your proficiency bonus.

	• When a creature hits an ally within 5 feet of you with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to impose a penalty to the attack roll equal to your proficiency bonus, potentially causing the attack to miss.

	• When you take the Guard action, the guarded ally has advantage on Dexterity saving throws that would affect only them while guarded.

Formfighting Mastery:
	• Prerequisite: The ability to cast force powers	• You've mastered the basics of the known forms of lightsaber combat, wielding your weapon with unparalleled grace. You gain the following benefits:

	• You learn three lightsaber forms, detailed later in this chapter. If you already know at least three lightsaber forms, you instead learn the remaining forms.

	• Once on each of your turns, before you make a melee weapon attack, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If you do so, you can engage in one of your lightsaber forms without using your bonus action. If that form lets you make an attack, that attack is also made without your proficiency bonus.

	• Once on each of your turns, before you make a melee weapon attack, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If you do so, and the attack hits, you can choose another creature within 5 feet of it. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes damage equal to twice your proficiency bonus.

Great Weapon Mastery:
	• You've mastered putting the weight of a weapon to your advantage, letting its momentum empower your strikes. While you are wielding a light- or vibro-weapon with the two-handed property with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• On your turn, when you score a critical hit or reduce a creature to 0 hit points with a melee weapon attack, you can make one melee weapon attack as a bonus action.

	• When you miss with a melee weapon attack, you can use your bonus action to repeat the attack against the same target. Any modifications to the original attack roll, such as advantage, disadvantage, or without your proficiency bonus, also affect this attack roll. On a hit, this attack deals kinetic damage equal to your Strength modifier.

	• Before you make a melee weapon attack, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If the attack hits, you add twice your proficiency bonus to the attack's damage.

	• While wielding the weapon in two hands, you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to avoid being disarmed.

Guerrilla Mastery:
	• You've mastered maneuvering across the battlefield, sliding through openings that others might not see. You gain the following benefits:

	• You can move through a hostile creature's space regardless of that creature's size.

	• When you hit a creature with an opportunity attack, you can move up to half your speed (no action required) without provoking opportunity attacks from that creature.

	• Once per turn, when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, another enemy of the creature is within 5 feet of it, and that enemy isn't incapacitated, you can deal additional damage equal to twice your proficiency bonus.

	• When a hostile creature moves to within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to Disengage and move up to half your speed. If you could already use your reaction to Disengage and move up to half your speed, you can instead move up to your full speed.

Gunning Mastery:
	• You've mastered using blasters in unique ways, controlling the battlefield. While you are wielding a blaster weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• When a creature succeeds on the saving throw against the burst or rapid property of your weapon, they take damage equal to your Dexterity modifier.

	• When you use the burst property of a weapon, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus to the save DC. If you do so, each creature that fails the save takes additional damage equal to your proficiency bonus.

	• When you use the rapid property of a weapon, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus to the save DC. If you do so, and the target fails the save, they take additional damage equal to twice your proficiency bonus.

	• You treat the strength number of weapons as one step lower (19 to 17, 17 to 15, 15 to 13, or 13 to 11). If the strength number is 11, you ignore it entirely.

Mounted Mastery:
	• You've mastered the art of fighting while mounted, moving seamlessly with your companion. While you are mounted on a vehicle or controlled beast, you gain the following benefits:

	• Once per turn, you can choose to have advantage on a melee weapon attack roll against an unmounted creature that is smaller than your mount. If the attack hits, you deal additional damage equal to your proficiency bonus.

	• If your mount is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you can use your reaction to have it instead take no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw, and only half damage if it fails.

	• While mounted on a vehicle, you can use your bonus action instead of your action to take one of the vehicle's actions available to you. You can't take the same action twice in one turn.

	• While mounted on a controlled beast, you can use your bonus action to have your mount make a single attack against a creature within its range.

Onslaught Mastery:
	• You've mastered using your momentum to your advantage, effectively pummeling creatures into submission and keeping them down once they fall. You gain the following benefits:

	• When a creature falls prone within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack or an unarmed strike.

	• When you would have advantage on a melee weapon attack due to a creature being prone, you can reroll one of the dice once.

	• When a prone creature within 5 feet of you attempts to stand, they provoke an opportunity attack from you.

	• Once on each of your turns, if you move at least 10 feet in a straight line towards a creature before hitting it with a melee weapon attack, you deal additional damage equal to your proficiency bonus.

Sentinel Mastery:
	• You've mastered techniques to take advantage of every drop in any enemy's guard; in tight spaces you are indomitable. While you are wielding a light- or vibro-weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Creatures within your reach provoke opportunity attacks from you even if they take the Disengage action.

	• You can use a bonus action to enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you have a number of special reactions equal to your proficiency bonus that you can only use to make opportunity attacks. You can only take one reaction per turn.

	• When you take the Dodge action, once per round, you can take two reactions on the same turn, instead of only one.

Sharpshooter Mastery:
	• You've mastered blaster weapons and can easily make shots that others find impossible. While you are wielding a blaster weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Attacking at long range doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.

	• Your ranged weapon attacks ignore one-quarter and half cover against targets 30 feet or greater from you. If your ranged weapon attacks would already ignore one-quarter and half cover against targets 30 feet or greater from you, they now also ignore three-quarters cover.

	• Before you make an attack with a blaster weapon against a target 30 feet or greater from you, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If the attack hits, you add twice your proficiency bonus to the attack's damage.

Shield Mastery:
	• You've mastered using a shield to defend your allies as well as yourself, strategically imposing your shield to capitalize on its protection. While you are wielding a shield with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• If you aren't incapacitated, you can add your shield's AC bonus to any Dexterity saving throw you make against a power or other harmful effect.

	• When a creature you can see damages you, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus.

	• When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, and you succeed on the saving throw, you can use your reaction to take no damage.

Snapshot Mastery:
	• You've mastered getting up close and personal with blaster weapons, maintaining both rate of fire and accuracy. While you are wielding a blaster weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you take the Attack action targeting a creature within 30 feet, you can choose to attack rapidly at the expense of accuracy. Your ranged weapon attack is made without the aid of your proficiency bonus, but you can use your bonus action to make an additional ranged weapon attack, also without your proficiency bonus. If you would make more than one attack when you take the Attack action, only one attack is made without your proficiency bonus.

	• Your ranged weapon attacks ignore one-quarter and half cover against targets within 30 feet of you. If your ranged weapon attacks would already ignore one-quarter and half cover against targets within 30 feet of you, they now also ignore three-quarters cover.

	• Other creatures provoke an opportunity attack from you when they move to within 30 feet of you, and you can use blaster weapons when making opportunity attacks.

Throwing Mastery:
	• You've mastered the techniques of throwing weapons, readily blending the weapons with your movements. While you are wielding a weapon with the thrown property with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Attacking at long range doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls with thrown weapons.

	• Once on each of your turns, you can make a ranged weapon attack with a thrown weapon against a target within the weapon's normal range without the aid of your proficiency bonus (no action required).

	• When you hit a creature with a ranged attack with a thrown weapon, you have advantage on your next melee weapon attack against that creature before the end of your next turn.

	• Once per turn, you can draw a weapon with the thrown property without using your object interaction.

Twin-Blade Mastery:
	• You've mastered fighting with double-bladed weapons, using both ends to devastating effect. While you are wielding a weapon with the double property with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Whenever you roll the maximum on a weapon damage die against a creature, you gain a +1 bonus to the next attack roll you make against that creature before the end of your next turn.

	• You can engage in Double-Weapon Fighting even when the weapon you are wielding lacks the light property.

	• Grasping a double weapon you are wielding in only one hand with your other hand no longer requires your object interaction.

	• Before you make a melee weapon attack, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If the attack hits, you add your proficiency bonus to the attack's damage.

Versatile Mastery:
	• You've mastered using weapons in different ways, altering your attack patterns mid-swing. While you are wielding a light- or vibro-weapon with the versatile property with which you are proficient and no other weapons, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you are the target of a melee weapon attack, you can immediately use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against the target without your proficiency bonus. On a hit, the target suffers the attack's normal effects, and you impose disadvantage on the triggering roll.

	• Once per turn, when you make an attack roll while wielding a weapon in two hands, you can attempt to follow up on the attack. If the attack hits, the creature must make a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your bonus to attacks with the weapon). On a failed save, the creature is pushed back 5 feet, and you can immediately move into the space it just vacated without provoking opportunity attacks.

	• Once per turn, when you make an attack roll while wielding a weapon in one hand, the target is wielding a shield, and your other hand is empty, you can use your other hand to pull down the shield (no action required). If you do so, the creature gains no benefit to armor class from its shield for that attack.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>(Lightsaber Forms)</name>
    <text>Ataru Form:
	• You can leap up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space you can see.

Jar'Kai Form:
	• As a part of the bonus action to adopt this form, if you took the Attack action, you can engage in Double- or Two-Weapon Fighting.
	• Each time you hit with an attack on this turn, you can move up to 5 feet without provoking opportunity attacks from the creature you hit.

Juyo/Vapaad Form:
	• Until the start of your next turn, your critical hit range with weapons increases by 1.

Makashi Form:
	• Until the start of your next turn, when a creature makes a melee weapon attack against you and misses, you can use your reaction to make one melee weapon attack against that creature.

Niman Form:
	• As a part of the bonus action to adopt this form, if you took the Attack action, you can engage in Double- or Two-Weapon Fighting.
	• Until the end of your next turn, you can use Wisdom or Charisma instead of Strength or Dexterity for the attack and damage rolls of your melee weapon attacks. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Shien/Djem So Form:
	• Before the end of your next turn, you can add half your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, rounded down, minimum of +1) to one ability check or attack roll you make using Strength.

Shii-Cho Form:
	• As a part of the bonus action to adopt this form, if you took the Attack action, you can engage in Double- or Two-Weapon Fighting.
	• Additionally, the first time you hit a creature within 5 feet of you with a weapon attack before the end of your next turn, you can force the target to make a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your bonus to attacks with the weapon). On a failed save, it is pushed back 5 feet, and you can immediately move into the space it just vacated without provoking opportunity attacks.

Sokan Form:
	• Until the start of your next turn, you ignore difficult terrain. Additionally, when an opponent makes a melee weapon attack against you, you can use your reaction to move to another space within 5 feet of that opponent without provoking opportunity attacks, imposing disadvantage on the triggering roll.

Soresu Form:
	• The first time you take kinetic, energy, or ion damage from a weapon before the end of your next turn, that damage is reduced by half.

Trakata Form:
	• As a part of the bonus action to adopt this form, you can flourish your weapon to attempt to distract an enemy you can see. Make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check contested by a Wisdom (Perception) check of one creature that you can see within 5 feet of you. On a success, that creature has disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes against you.

Vonil/Ishu Form: (EC)
	• If you took the Attack action before adopting this form, you can direct one of your companions to strike a creature you hit with an attack. Choose a friendly creature within 5 feet of the creature you hit with an attack that can see or hear you. That creature can immediately use its reaction to make one weapon attack against the same creature you hit with an attack.
	• If you did not take the Attack action before adopting this form, and there is a friendly creature within 15 feet of you, you can move up to 10 feet. You must end this movement within 5 feet of the friendly creature.

Ysannanite Form: (EC)
	• As a part of the bonus action to adopt this form, if you took the Attack action, you can engage in Double- or Two-Weapon Fighting.
	• Additionally, until the end of your next turn, when making a ranged weapon attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>(Scout Routines)</name>
    <prerequisite>Scout</prerequisite>
    <text>The routines are presented in alphabetical order. If multiple scouts grant the same routine, affected creatures can only benefit from it once. You must be conscious to grant the benefit of your routines.

Adaptability Routine:
At the start of each of your turns, you can choose an ability score with a saving throw in which you are not proficient. Until the start of your next turn, you add half your proficiency bonus to saving throws you make with the chosen ability. Alternatively, you can choose to extend this benefit to friendly creatures within 5 feet of you, except for you.

Maven's Routine:
At the start of each of your turns, you can choose to gain resistance to damage from tech powers until the start of your next turn. Alternatively, you can choose to extend this benefit to friendly creatures within 5 feet of you, except for you.

Mesmer's Routine:
At the start of each of your turns, you can choose to have advantage on saving throws against effects that would incapacitate you or put you to sleep until the start of your next turn. Alternatively, you can choose to extend this benefit to friendly creatures within 5 feet of you, except for you.

Nomad's Routine:
At the start of each of your turns, you can choose to gain advantage on Constitution saving throws to avoid exhaustion from unenhanced sources, as well as being naturally adapted to both hot and cold climates. Alternatively, you can choose to extend this benefit to friendly creatures within 5 feet of you, except for you.

Responder's Routine:
When you roll initiative, you can choose to add your proficiency bonus to the initiative roll and have advantage on attack rolls against creatures that have not yet acted. Alternatively, you can choose to allow each creature within 5 feet of you, including you, to add half your proficiency bonus to the initiative roll and have advantage on the first attack roll they make against a creature that has not yet acted.

Sharpshooter's Routine:
At the start of each of your turns, you can choose to gain a bonus to the first weapon attack roll you make before the start of your next turn equal to your Intelligence modifier. Alternatively, you can choose to allow each creature within 5 feet of you, including you, to add half your Intelligence modifier to the first weapon attack roll they make before the start of your next turn.

Strider's Routine:
At the start of each of your turns, you can choose to have each slowed level only reduce your speed by 5 feet, unless it would reduce your speed to 0 until the start of your next turn. Alternatively, you can choose to extend this benefit to friendly creatures within 5 feet of you, except for you.

Warden's Routine:
At the start of each of your turns, you can choose to gain a climbing and swimming speed equal to your walking speed until the start of your next turn. Alternatively, you can choose to extend this benefit to friendly creatures within 5 feet of you, except for you.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>(Starship Conditions)</name>
    <text>Blinded:
	• A blinded ship can't see and automatically fails any ability check that relies on sight or the ship's sensors.
	• Attack rolls against the ship have advantage, and the ship's attack rolls have disadvantage.

Disabled:
	• A disabled ship can't communicate with external sources more than 1,000 feet away.
	• A disabled ship can't take actions or reactions.
	• A disabled ship's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.

Ionized:
	• An ionized starship has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks.

Invisible:
	• An invisible starship is impossible to see without the aid of powers or a special sense. For the purpose of hiding, the starship is heavily obscured. The starship's location can be detected by any noise it makes or any tracks it leaves.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have disadvantage, and the creature's attack rolls have advantage.

Shocked:
	• A shocked starship's speed is reduced by half.
	• The starship can't take reactions.

Stalled:
	• A stalled ship is disabled (see the condition).
	• Any active features controlled by the ship, such as a Tractor Beam or Gravity Well Projector, automatically end.
	• The ship automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	• Attack rolls against the ship have advantage.

Stunned:
	• A stunned ship's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.
	• The ship automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	• Attack rolls against the ship have advantage.

System Damage:
	• Some special abilities, or when certain conditions are met, cause a ship to sustain a special condition called System Damage. such as and the long-term effects of freezing or scorching temperatures, can lead to a special condition called System Damage. System Damage is measured in six levels. An effect can give a starship one or more levels of System Damage, as specified in the effect's description.

System Damage Effects:
Level | Effect
1 | Disadvantage on ability checks
2 | Flying speed halved and turning speed doubled
3 | Disadvantage on attack rolls and saving throws
4 | Hit point maximum, shield point maximum, and shield regeneration rate halved
5 | Ship becomes permanently "used" (see the condition)
6 | Ship suffers catastrophic power failure. All primary systems fail.

	• If a ship with System Damage suffers another effect that causes System Damage, its current level of System Damage increases by the amount specified in the effect's description.
	• A ship suffers the effect of its current level of System Damage as well as all lower levels. For example, a ship suffering level 2 System Damage has its flying speed halved, turning speed doubled, and has disadvantage on ability checks.
	• An effect that removes System Damage reduces its level as specified in the effect's description, with all System Damage effects (except for "used") ending if a ship's System Damage level is reduced below 1.
	• Finishing maintenance reduces a ship's System Damage level by 1.

Tractored:
	• A tractored ship's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.
	• The condition ends if the tractoring ship is disabled (see the condition).
	• The condition also ends if an effect removes the tractored ship from the reach of the tractoring ship or effect.

Used:
	• A used starship's value is reduced by half.
	• When a deployed crew member on a used starship rolls a 1 on an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, they must make a destruction saving throw. If the roll is 10 or higher, they succeed. On a failure, the ship suffers 1 level of System Damage.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ace Pilot</name>
    <text>You're quite experienced both on land and in the air, be it from time in a navy, as a mercenary, or perhaps even piracy. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Piloting skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• Whenever you make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Perception) check related to vehicles or ships, you are considered to have expertise in the Investigation or Perception skill.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ace Pilot (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Religion</proficiency>
    <text>You're quite experienced both on land and in the air, be it from time in a navy, as a mercenary, or perhaps even piracy. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Piloting skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• Whenever you make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Perception) check related to vehicles or ships, you are considered to have expertise in the Investigation or Perception skill.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Acrobat</name>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics</proficiency>
    <text>You become more nimble, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Acrobatics skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• As a bonus action, you can make a DC 15 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. If you succeed, difficult terrain doesn't cost you extra movement until the end of the current turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Acrobat (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics</proficiency>
    <text>You become more nimble, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Acrobatics skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• As a bonus action, you can make a DC 15 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. If you succeed, difficult terrain doesn't cost you extra movement until the end of the current turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Actor</name>
    <text>Skilled at mimicry and dramatics, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You have advantage on Charisma (Deception) and Charisma (Performance) checks when trying to pass yourself off as a different person.

	• You can mimic the speech of another person or the sounds made by other creatures. You must have heard the person speaking, or heard the creature make the sound, for at least 1 minute. A successful Wisdom (Insight) check contested by your Charisma (Deception) check allows a listener to determine that the effect is faked.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Actor (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Skilled at mimicry and dramatics, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You have advantage on Charisma (Deception) and Charisma (Performance) checks when trying to pass yourself off as a different person.

	• You can mimic the speech of another person or the sounds made by other creatures. You must have heard the person speaking, or heard the creature make the sound, for at least 1 minute. A successful Wisdom (Insight) check contested by your Charisma (Deception) check allows a listener to determine that the effect is faked.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Adaptive Training</name>
    <prerequisite>at least 3 levels in fighter</prerequisite>
    <text>You've developed a new fluidity to your training and practice, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you complete a long rest, you can replace a fighting style you know with another style available. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Alert</name>
    <text>Always on the lookout for danger, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +5 bonus to initiative.

	• You can't be surprised while you are conscious.

	• Other creatures don't gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being unseen by you.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">initiative +5</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Alert (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Always on the lookout for danger, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +5 bonus to initiative.

	• You can't be surprised while you are conscious.

	• Other creatures don't gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being hidden from you.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">initiative +5</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Animal Handler</name>
    <proficiency>Animal Handling</proficiency>
    <text>You master the techniques needed to train and handle animals. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Animal Handling skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You can use a bonus action on your turn to command one friendly beast within 60 feet of you that can hear you and that isn't currently following the command of someone else. You decide now what action the beast will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you issue a general command that lasts for 1 minute, such as to guard a particular area.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Animal Handler (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Animal Handling</proficiency>
    <text>You master the techniques needed to train and handle animals. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Animal Handling skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You can use a bonus action on your turn to command one friendly beast within 60 feet of you that can hear you and that isn't currently following the command of someone else. You decide now what action the beast will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you issue a general command that lasts for 1 minute, such as to guard a particular area.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ashla Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force powers</prerequisite>
    <text>Your calmness in the face of adversity allow you to more adeptly channel the light side of the Force. You gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to your force save DC and force attack modifier of your light side force powers.

	• You can add one light side power of your max power level or below to the list of powers you can cast. This does not count against your powers known.

	• When you successfully cast a light side power, either your or the target's (your choice) hit point maximum and current hit points increase by an amount equal to the power's level. This effect lasts for 1 minute. You can only have one instance of this effect active at a time.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell attack +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell dc +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Athlete (Strength)</name>
    <text>You have undergone extensive physical training to gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you are prone, standing up uses only 5 feet of your movement.

	• Climbing doesn't halve your speed.

	• You can make a running long jump or a running high jump after moving only 5 feet on foot, rather than 10 feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Athlete (Dexterity)</name>
    <text>You have undergone extensive physical training to gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you are prone, standing up uses only 5 feet of your movement.

	• Climbing doesn't halve your speed.

	• You can make a running long jump or a running high jump after moving only 5 feet on foot, rather than 10 feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Athlete (Strength) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have undergone extensive physical training to gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you are prone, standing up uses only 5 feet of your movement.

	• Climbing doesn't halve your speed.

	• You can make a running long jump or a running high jump after moving only 5 feet on foot, rather than 10 feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Athlete (Dexterity) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have undergone extensive physical training to gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you are prone, standing up uses only 5 feet of your movement.

	• Climbing doesn't halve your speed.

	• You can make a running long jump or a running high jump after moving only 5 feet on foot, rather than 10 feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Augmented Cyborg</name>
    <text>You've experimented with cybernetic augmentations, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one cybernetic augmentation of standard rarity from Appendix A. That augmentation is installed and doesn't count against the maximum cybernetic augmentations you can support, but it does count towards your total cybernetics augmentations as shown in the Cybernetic Augmentations Side Effects table in Chapter 7.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Battle Scarred</name>
    <text>You've spent a lifetime fighting, with the scars to prove it. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you roll a 19 or a 20 on the d20 for a death saving throw, you regain 1 hit point.

	• When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. Once you've used this ability, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Battle Scarred (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've spent a lifetime fighting, with the scars to prove it. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you roll a 19 or a 20 on the d20 for a death saving throw, you regain 1 hit point.

	• When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. Once you've used this ability, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Bendu Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You stride the line between the light side and the dark, lending a strength to your universal powers. You gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to your force save DC and force attack modifier of your universal force powers.

	• You can add one universal power of your max power level or below to the list of powers you can cast. This does not count against your powers known.

	• A creature affected by a universal power you cast gains disadvantage on the next saving throw or ability check made to resist a power you cast.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell attack +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell dc +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Biochemist (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have studied the secrets of chemistry and are an expert in its practice, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the biochemist's kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• As an action, you can identify one medpac, stimpac, or adrenal within 5 feet of you, as if you had tasted it. You must see the liquid for this benefit to work.

	• Over the course of a short or long rest, you can temporarily improve the potency of one medpac. To use this benefit, you must have a biochemist's kit with you, and the medpac must be within reach. If the medpac is consumed before the end of your next short or long rest, when a creature uses this medpac, they take the maximum instead of rolling.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Blade Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master the doubleblade, doublesaber, doubleshoto, doublesword, dual-phase lightsaber, hidden blade, lightdagger, lightfoil, lightsaber, shotosaber, techblade, vibroblade, vibrodagger, and vibrorapier. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• As a bonus action, you can take a parrying stance. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +1 bonus to AC unless you are disarmed.

	• When you make an opportunity attack with the weapon, you have advantage on the attack roll.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Blade Specialist</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You master the doubleblade, doublesaber, doubleshoto, doublesword, hidden blade, lightdagger, lightfoil, lightsaber, martial lightsaber, shotosaber, techblade, vibroblade, vibrodagger, and vibrorapier. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• As a bonus action, you can take a parrying stance. While you are in this stance and you aren't wielding a shield, you gain a bonus to AC equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded up) until the start of your next turn.

	• Your critical hit range increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Blinding Agility</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity 20, 12th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the reflexes one who can see things before they happen, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Dexterity saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Dexterity saving throws you make.

	• Weapons that lack the two-handed or special properties are considered to have the finesse property for you.

	• Opportunity attacks made against you have disadvantage.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">dexterity save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Blinding Agility (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity 20, character level 12</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the reflexes one who can see things before they happen, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Dexterity saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Dexterity saving throws you make.

	• Weapons that lack the *two-handed*, *heavy*, or *special* properties are considered to have the finesse property for you.

	• Opportunity attacks made against you have disadvantage.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">dexterity save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Bloodthirsty (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You fight with reckless abandon, caring not of your own safety. You use your pain to fuel your attacks, causing your enemies even greater pain. You may die one day • but that day will come earlier for your enemies. You gain the following benefits:

	• When a creature within 5 feet of you misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to cause the attack to hit you. If the attack hits and deals damage, you can immediately make a melee weapon attack with advantage against that creature.

	• When a creature scores a critical hit against you, you have advantage on the next attack you make against that creature, until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Bogan Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force powers</prerequisite>
    <text>Your use of intense, raw emotion has improved your ability to harness the dark side of the Force. You gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to your force save DC and force attack modifier of your dark side force powers.

	• You can add one dark side power of your max power level or below to the list of powers you can cast. This does not count against your powers known.

	• When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for a dark side power, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell attack +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell dc +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Bountiful Luck</name>
    <prerequisite>Lucky feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Your people have extraordinary luck, which you have learned to lend to your companions when you see them falter. You're not sure how you do it; you just wish it, and it happens. Surely a sign of fortune's favor!

	• When an ally you can see within 30 feet of you rolls a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can use your reaction and expend 1 luck point to let the ally reroll the die. The ally must use the new roll.

	• When you use this ability, you can't use luck points before the end of your next turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Bountiful Luck (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Lucky feat</prerequisite>
    <text>Your people have extraordinary luck, which you have learned to lend to your companions when you see them falter. You're not sure how you do it; you just wish it, and it happens. Surely a sign of fortune's favor!

	• When an ally you can see within 30 feet of you rolls a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can use your reaction and expend 1 luck point to let the ally reroll the die. The ally must use the new roll.

	• When you use this ability, you can't use luck points before the end of your next turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Brawling Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered using your weight to your advantage, easily wrangling targets around. As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a medium or heavy shield, you gain the following benefits:

	• Your unarmed strikes use a d6 for damage.

	• Your improvised weapons use a d6 for damage and gain the versatile (1d8) property.

	• Your speed isn't halved by carrying a grappled creature who is the same size category as you or smaller.

	• When you take the Attack action and make an attack against a creature grappled by you, you can use a bonus action to make another attack against that creature.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Brawny</name>
    <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
    <text>You become stronger, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Athletics skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You count as if you were one size larger for the purpose of determining your carrying capacity.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Brawny (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
    <text>You become stronger, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Athletics skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You count as if you were one size larger for the purpose of determining your carrying capacity.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Bypasser (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You pride yourself on your quickness and your close study of certain clandestine activities. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the security kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• Whenever you make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Perception) check to detect the nature of a lock, you are considered to have expertise in the Investigation or Perception skill.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Casting Specialist</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>Choose one from force- or tech-casting. You've mastered your chosen casting type, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to your force or tech save DC and your force or tech attack modifier.

	• Once per turn, when you cast a power that requires an attack roll or saving throw, you can have advantage on one attack roll, or you can force one creature affected by the power to have advantage or disadvantage on the saving throw (your choice). Once you've used this feature on a power, you can't affect that power again until you complete a short or long rest. Once you've used this feature on a creature, you can't do so again until you complete a short or long rest.

	• Once per turn, when you cast a power that doesn't require an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, but requires a die roll, you can choose the maximum or minimum on the die (your choice). If the power requires rolling multiple dice, you can only affect a number of them equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded up) in this way. Once you've used this feature on a power, you can't affect that power again until you complete a short or long rest.

	• You can select this feat twice. Each time you do so, you must choose a different casting type.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell attack +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell dc +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Charger (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You can take the Dash action as a bonus action.

	• If you move at least 10 feet in a straight line immediately after taking this bonus action, you either gain a +5 bonus to your next melee attack's damage roll (if you chose to make a melee attack and hit) or push the target up to 10 feet away from you (if you chose to shove and you succeed).

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Charmer</name>
    <proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
    <text>You've master the art of charming those around you, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• If you spend 1 minute talking to someone who can understand what you say, you can make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by the creature's Wisdom (Insight) check. If you or your companions are fighting the creature, your check automatically fails. If your check succeeds, the target is charmed by you as long as it remains within 60 feet of you and for 1 minute thereafter.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Charming Persona (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
    <text>You've master the art of charming those around you, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• If you spend 1 minute talking to someone who can understand what you say, you can make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by the creature's Wisdom (Insight) check. If you or your companions are fighting the creature, your check automatically fails. If your check succeeds, the target is charmed by you as long as it remains within 60 feet of you and for 1 minute thereafter.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Climber</name>
    <text>You excel at scaling cliffsides, hills, trees, and general climbing. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain a climbing speed equal to your movement speed.

	• You have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to avoid falling off or down while climbing.

	• You can spend 5 minutes instructing, pointing out handholds, and guiding other creatures before making a climb. When you do so, choose up to six friendly creatures (which can include yourself) within 30 feet of you. Each creature can add a 1d6 to any ability check or saving throw they make for that climb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Climber (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You excel at scaling cliffsides, hills, trees, and general climbing. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain a climbing speed equal to your movement speed.

	• You have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to avoid falling off or down while climbing.

	• You can spend 5 minutes instructing, pointing out handholds, and guiding other creatures before making a climb. When you do so, choose up to six friendly creatures (which can include yourself) within 30 feet of you. Each creature can add a 1d6 to any ability check or saving throw they make for that climb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Close Quarters Caster (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced utilizing powers in close quarters, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• When making a ranged force or tech attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll.

	• Your ranged force and tech attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you.

	• You learn one at-will power that requires an attack roll. Your casting ability for this at-will power depends on the power list you chose from: Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment) for force powers or Intelligence for tech powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Close Quarters Shooting Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered getting up close and personal with ranged weapons, maintain both rate of fire and accuracy. While you are wielding a ranged weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you take the Attack action, you can choose to fire rapidly at the expense of accuracy. Your ranged weapon attacks are made without the aid of your proficiency bonus, but you use your bonus action to make an additional ranged weapon attack, also without your proficiency bonus.

	• Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover against targets within 30 feet of you.

	• Other creatures provoke an opportunity attack from you when they move to within 15 feet of you, and you can used ranged weapons when making opportunity attacks.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Close-Quarters Caster</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced utilizing powers in close quarters, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• When making a ranged force or tech attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll.

	• Your ranged force and tech attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you.

	• You learn one at-will power that requires an attack roll. Your casting ability for this at-will power depends on the power list you chose from: Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment) for force powers or Intelligence for tech powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Combat Caster</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level, The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced making your powers more difficult to avoid, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• When a creature rolls a 1 on the d20 roll of a saving throw against a power you cast that deals damage, they instead take the highest number possible for the damage die.

	• You learn one at-will power that requires a saving throw. Your casting ability for this at-will power depends on the power list you chose from: Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment) for force powers or Intelligence for tech powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Combat Caster (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced making your powers more difficult to avoid, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• When a creature rolls a 1 on the d20 roll of a saving throw against a power you cast that deals damage, they instead take the highest number possible for the damage die.

	• You learn one at-will power that requires a saving throw. Your casting ability for this at-will power depends on the power list you chose from: Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment) for force powers or Intelligence for tech powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Companion Keeper</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain the services of a companion. Choose one of the companion nature options, detailed later in this chapter.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Crafter</name>
    <text>You have a knack for crafting; you work with greater efficiency and produce goods of higher quality. Select one type of artisan's implements. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the chosen tool. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• When you craft something with the chosen tool, the total market value you can craft increases 50 cr per day. If you have expertise with it, the market value instead increases by 100 cr per day.

	• If you use the tool you've selected to practice a profession during downtime, you can support a lifestyle one higher than you would normally be able to.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different set of artisan's implements

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Crafter (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have a knack for crafting; you work with greater efficiency and produce goods of higher quality. Select one type of artisan's tools. You gain the following benefits whilst using it:

	• Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the chosen tool. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• When you craft something with the tool you've selected, the total market value you can craft increases 50 cr per day. If you have expertise with them, the market value instead increases by 100 cr per day.

	• If you use the tool you've selected to practice a profession during downtime, you can support a lifestyle one higher than you would normally be able to.

You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different set of artisan's tools.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Crushing Weapon Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master the electrostaff, greatsaber, techaxe, vibroaxe, vibroclub, vibromace, and vibrosword. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll and hit, and the lower of the two d20 rolls would also hit, you can attempt to knock the target prone. If the target is no more than one size larger than you (your size or smaller if your weapon has the light property), make a Strength (Athletics) check contested by the target's Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check (the target chooses the ability). If you win the contest, the target is knocked prone.

	• You can ready your weapon to deliver a punishing blow against a foe that tries to advance on you. When you take the Ready action on your turn and make a melee attack as your reaction, you have advantage on your attack roll.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Crushing Weapon Specialist</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You master the greatsaber, techaxe, techstaff, vibroaxe, vibroknuckler, vibromace, and vibrosword. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll and hit, and the lower of the two d20 rolls would also hit, you can attempt to knock the target prone. If the target is no more than one size larger than you (your size or smaller if your weapon has the light property), make a Strength (Athletics) check contested by the target's Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check (the target chooses the ability). If you win the contest, the target is knocked prone.

	• Once per round, when you use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack, you have advantage on the attack roll.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Cunning Intellect</name>
    <prerequisite>Intelligence 20, 12th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You've been customized beyond other droids of the same model, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one droid customization of standard rarity from Appendix A. That customization is installed and doesn't count against the maximum droid customizations you can support, but it does count towards your maximum parts as shown in the Droid Size Maximum Parts table in Chapter 7.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Cunning Intellect (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Intelligence 20, character level 12</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the cunning of the most prolific scholars, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Intelligence saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Intelligence saving throws you make.

	• You can learn new languages and tools over the course of 30 days of training, rather than the 250 normally required.

	• Whenever you make an ability check that uses your Intelligence, you can add half your proficiency bonus (rounded down) if it doesn't already include your proficiency bonus. Additionally, if you roll lower than half your level (rounded down) on an Intelligence check, you can instead use your level for the d20 roll.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">wisdom save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Customized Droid</name>
    <prerequisite>Type droid</prerequisite>
    <text>You've been customized beyond other droids of the same model, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one droid customization of standard rarity from Appendix A. That customization is installed and doesn't count against the maximum droid customizations you can support, but it does count towards your maximum parts as shown in the Droid Size Maximum Parts table in Chapter 7.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Defense Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered the art of defending yourself, treating your armor as a second skin. While you are wearing armor with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Critical hits made against you are treated as normal hits.

	• When a creature makes a melee attack against you and misses, you can use your reaction to attempt to shove that creature up to 10 feet directly away from you.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Demolitionist (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have extensive experience with explosives, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the demolitions kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• Whenever you make an Intelligence (Demolitions Kit) check to disarm an explosive, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10, as long as you spend at least one minute disarming it.

	• Over the course of a short rest, you can temporarily improve the potency of one grenade or mine. To use this benefit, you must have a demolitions kit, and the explosive must be within reach.  If the explosive is detonated before the end of your next short or long rest, its DC becomes 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier, and it deals extra damage equal to your Intelligence modifier of the same type it would normally deal.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dual Focused Caster</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level, the ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You have learned to bifurcate your attention while concentrating on powers, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• If you attempt to cast a power that requires concentration while already concentrating on an existing power, you can maintain concentration on both powers simultaneously. You must spend your action each subsequent round on maintaining this concentration, or lose concentration for both powers.

	• At the end of each of your turns where you have two powers you are concentrating on, you must make a Constitution saving throw (DC equals 10 + the number of complete rounds you've been concentrating on two powers). On a failure, you lose concentration for both powers. You can drop concentration on one of your powers during your turn as a free action to avoid this saving throw.

	• Any time you would be forced to make a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration due to taking damage, the DC equals 10 + both powers' levels combined, or half the damage you take, whichever number is higher. On a failure, you lose concentration on both powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dual Focused Caster (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You have learned to bifurcate your attention while concentrating on powers, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• If you attempt to cast a power that requires concentration while already concentrating on an existing power, you can maintain concentration on both powers simultaneously. You must spend your action each subsequent round on maintaining this concentration, or lose concentration for both powers.
                
	• At the end of each of your turns where you have two powers you are concentrating on, you must make a Constitution saving throw (DC equals 10 + the number of complete rounds you've been concentrating on two powers). On a failure, you lose concentration for both powers. You can drop concentration on one of your powers during your turn as a free action to avoid this saving throw.

	• Any time you would be forced to make a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration due to taking damage, the DC equals 10 + both powers' levels combined, or half the damage you take, whichever number is higher. On a failure, you lose concentration on both powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dueling Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Your mastery of fighting with a single melee weapon is unsurpassed; you make one weapon feel like many. While you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand with which you are proficient and no other weapons, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you take the Attack action, you can decide to attack with haste at the expense of accuracy. Your melee weapon attacks are made without the aid of your proficiency bonus, but you use your reaction to make an additional melee weapon attack, also without your proficiency bonus.

	• When a creature hits you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to add your proficiency bonus to your AC for that attack, potentially causing the attack to miss you.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dungeon Delver (Intelligence)</name>
    <text>Alert to the hidden traps and secret doors found in many dungeons, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks made to detect the presence of secret doors.

	• You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid or resist traps.

	• You have resistance to the damage dealt by traps.

	• You can search for traps while traveling at a normal pace, instead of only at a slow pace.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dungeon Delver (Wisdom)</name>
    <text>Alert to the hidden traps and secret doors found in many dungeons, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks made to detect the presence of secret doors.

	• You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid or resist traps.

	• You have resistance to the damage dealt by traps.

	• You can search for traps while traveling at a normal pace, instead of only at a slow pace.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dungeon Delver (Intelligence) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Alert to the hidden traps and secret doors found in many dungeons, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks made to detect the presence of secret doors.

	• You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid or resist traps.

	• You have resistance to the damage dealt by traps.

	• You can search for traps while traveling at a normal pace, instead of only at a slow pace.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Dungeon Delver (Wisdom) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Alert to the hidden traps and secret doors found in many dungeons, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks made to detect the presence of secret doors.

	• You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid or resist traps.

	• You have resistance to the damage dealt by traps.

	• You can search for traps while traveling at a normal pace, instead of only at a slow pace.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Durable</name>
    <text>Hardy and resilient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you roll a Hit Die to regain hit points, the minimum number of hit points you can regain from the roll equals twice your Constitution modifier (minimum of 2).

	• Your hit point maximum increases by an amount equal to twice your level when you gain this feat. Whenever you gain a level thereafter, your hit point maximum increases by an additional 2 hit points.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Durable (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Hardy and resilient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you roll a Hit Die to regain hit points, the minimum number of hit points you can regain from the roll equals twice your Constitution modifier (minimum of 2).

	• Your hit point maximum increases by an amount equal to twice your level when you gain this feat. Whenever you gain a level thereafter, your hit point maximum increases by an additional 2 hit points.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Empathic</name>
    <proficiency>Insight</proficiency>
    <text>You possess keen insight into how other people think and feel. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Insight skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You can use your action to try to get uncanny insight about one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you. Make a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by the target's Charisma (Deception) check. On a success, you have advantage on attack rolls and ability checks against the target until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Empathic (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Insight</proficiency>
    <text>You possess keen insight into how other people think and feel. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Insight skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You can use your action to try to get uncanny insight about one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you. Make a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by the target's Charisma (Deception) check. On a success, you have advantage on attack rolls and ability checks against the target until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Entertainer</name>
    <text>You have a natural gift for performing and competing. Select one gaming set or musical instrument. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the chosen gaming set or musical instrument. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• While playing your chosen instrument or game, you can always readily read the emotions of those paying attention to you. During this time, and for up to one minute after completing, you have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to read the emotions of those you performed for or competed against.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different gaming set or musical instrument.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Entertaining Competitor (Dexterity) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have a natural gift for performing and competing. Select one gaming set or musical instrument. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the chosen gaming set or musical instrument. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• While playing your chosen instrument or game, you can always readily read the emotions of those paying attention to you. During this time, and for up to one minute after completing, you have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to read the emotions of those you performed for or competed against.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different gaming set or musical instrument.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Entertaining Competitor (Wisdom) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have a natural gift for performing and competing. Select one gaming set or musical instrument. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the chosen gaming set or musical instrument. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• While playing your chosen instrument or game, you can always readily read the emotions of those paying attention to you. During this time, and for up to one minute after completing, you have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to read the emotions of those you performed for or competed against.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different gaming set or musical instrument.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Entertaining Competitor (Charisma) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have a natural gift for performing and competing. Select one gaming set or musical instrument. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the chosen gaming set or musical instrument. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• While playing your chosen instrument or game, you can always readily read the emotions of those paying attention to you. During this time, and for up to one minute after completing, you have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to read the emotions of those you performed for or competed against.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different gaming set or musical instrument.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Equilibrium Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered the art of fighting while minimally armored, treating combat as an elegant dance. While you are wearing no armor and not wielding a medium or heavy shield, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to damage rolls you make with unarmed strikes and weapon attacks.

	• When a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the roll. You can choose to use this feature after the creature makes its attack roll, but before the GM determines whether the attack hits.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Exalted Awareness</name>
    <prerequisite>Wisdom 20, 12th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the wisdom associated with the most renowned masters of the Force, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Wisdom saving throws you make.

	• Creatures within 60 feet of you have disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide from you.

	• As an action, you can sense the presence of illusions and other effects designed to deceive the senses within 30 feet of you, provided that you aren't blinded or deafened. You sense that an effect is trying to trick you, but you gain no insight into what is hidden or its true nature. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">wisdom save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Exalted Awareness (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Wisdom 20, character level 12</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the wisdom associated with the most renowned masters of the Force, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Wisdom saving throws you make.

	• Creatures within 60 feet of you have disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide from you.

	• As an action, you can sense the presence of illusions and other effects designed to deceive the senses within 30 feet of you, provided that you aren't blinded or deafened. You sense that an effect is trying to trick you, but you gain no insight into what is hidden or its true nature. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">wisdom save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Expert Potency</name>
    <prerequisite>at least 3 levels in engineer</prerequisite>
    <text>You've obtained new ways to assist your allies, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When a creature has a Potent Aptitude die from you and casts a power, they can roll the die and add the number rolled to one damage or healing roll of the power. If the power would damage or heal multiple targets, this bonus only applies to one of them. The Potent Aptitude die is then lost.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fanatic</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>Every blow that hits your enemies make you feel closer to victory, making you shake in excitement. You gain the following benefits:

	• When you score a critical hit with an attack roll or reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.

	• Whenever a creature you can see within 30 feet is reduced to 0 hit points, you go into a fervor gaining temporary hit points equal to 1d4 + your Constitution modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fanatic (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Every blow that hits your enemies make you feel closer to victory, making you shake in excitement. You gain the following benefits:

	• When you score a critical hit with an attack roll or reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.

	• Whenever a creature you can see within 30 feet is reduce to 0 hit points, you go into a fervor gaining temporary hit points equal to 1d4 + your Constitution modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Feigned Confidence</name>
    <text>You've spent years pretending you know what you're doing, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you would make an ability check with a skill or tool that doesn't add your proficiency bonus, you can first make a DC 15 Charisma (Deception) check. On a success, you can add your proficiency bonus to the initial ability check. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Feigned Confidence (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've spent years pretending you know what you're doing, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you would make an ability check that doesn't add your proficiency bonus, you can first make a DC 15 (Charisma) Deception check. On a success, you can add your proficiency bonus to the check. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Master</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You've mastered a particular style of fighting. Choose one of the fighting mastery options, detailed later in this chapter. You can select this feat multiple times. You can't take a fighting mastery option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Stylist (Strength)</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one of the fighting style options, detailed later in this chapter.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. You can't take a fighting style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Stylist (Dexterity)</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one of the fighting style options, detailed later in this chapter.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. You can't take a fighting style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Stylist (Constitution)</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one of the fighting style options, detailed later in this chapter.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. You can't take a fighting style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Stylist (Strength) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one of the Fighting Style options, detailed above.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Stylist (Dexterity) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one of the Fighting Style options, detailed above.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Stylist (Constitution) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose one of the Fighting Style options, detailed above.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Focused Vitality</name>
    <prerequisite>at least 3 levels in monk</prerequisite>
    <text>You've learned to harness you focus to restore yourself, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• As an action, you can spend 2 focus points and a roll a Martial Arts die. You regain a number of hit points equal to the amount rolled + your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of one).

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Force Guidance (Wisdom)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've learned to utilize your gift with the Force in a specific, unique way. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose a skill or tool in which you are proficient. When you make an ability check with the chosen skill or tool, you can add half your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, rounded down, minimum of one) to the check if it doesn't already include that modifier. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different skill or tool.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Force Guidance (Charisma)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've learned to utilize your gift with the Force in a specific, unique way. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose a skill or tool in which you are proficient. When you make an ability check with the chosen skill or tool, you can add half your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, rounded down, minimum of one) to the check if it doesn't already include that modifier. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different skill or tool.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Force Guidance (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've learned to utilize your gift with the Force in a specific, unique way. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Choose a skill in which you are proficient. When you make an ability check with the chosen skill, you can add half your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, rounded down, minimum of one) to the check if it doesn't already include that modifier. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom or Charisma modifier (your choice, a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Force of Personality</name>
    <text>Rooms never go unalerted to your presence, and the strength of your personality make others lose focus on their own social game. Powers and other effects infrequently override your force of will. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You can use your Charisma modifier instead of your Wisdom modifier when making Insight checks.

	• When you would make a Wisdom saving throw, you can instead make a Charisma saving throw. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier. You regain all expended uses of this feature when you complete a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Force of Personality (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Rooms never go unalerted to your presence, and the strength of your personality makes others lose focus on their own social game. Powers and other effects infrequently override your force of will.

	• Your Charisma score increase by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You can use your Charisma modifier instead of your Wisdom modifier when making Insight checks.

	• When you would make a Wisdom saving throw, you can instead make a Charisma saving throw. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier. You regain all expended uses of this feature when you complete a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Force Sensitive (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You learn two at-will force powers, and one 1st-level force power, which you cast it at its lowest level. Once you cast it, you must finish a long rest before you can cast it again. Your forcecasting ability is Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment).

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Force-Sensitive</name>
    <prerequisite>Type humanoid</prerequisite>
    <text>You know two at-will force powers. When you reach 3rd level, you learn one 1st-level force power, which you can cast once per long rest. When you reach 5th level, you learn one 2nd-level force power, which you can once per long rest. Your forcecasting ability is Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment). Additionally, you lose the Force-Insensitive special trait if you have it.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Forceful Vigor</name>
    <text>Your strength and virility rarely go unnoticed, often to the point of distraction. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You can use your Strength modifier instead of your Constitution modifier when making Constitution checks.

	• When you would make a Constitution saving throw, you can instead make a Strength saving throw. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Strength modifier. You regain all expended uses of this feature when you complete a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Galvanizing Presence</name>
    <text>Your presence on the battlefield is a source of inspiration. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• As a bonus action, you let out a rallying war cry, ending the frightened or charmed condition on yourself and a number of allies that can hear you equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Once you've used this ability, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Galvanizing Presence (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Your presence on the battlefield is a source of inspiration. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• As a bonus action, you let out a rallying war cry, ending the frightened or charmed condition on yourself and a number of allies that can hear you equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Once you've used this ability, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Genius Mechanic (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have spent prolonged use with a mechanic's kit, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the mechanic's kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• Whenever you make an Intelligence (Mechanic's Kit) check to make a repair, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10, as long as you spend at least ten minutes repairing it.

	• Whenever you make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Perception) check to find a construct's weakness, you are considered to have expertise in the Investigation or Perception skill.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Gourmand (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have mastered a variety of special recipes, allowing you to prepare exotic dishes with useful effects. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the chef's kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• As an action, you can inspect a drink or plate of food within 5 feet of you and determine whether it is poisoned, provided that you can see and smell it.

	• During a long rest, you can prepare and serve a meal that helps you and your allies recover from the rigors of adventuring, provided you have suitable food, chef's kit, and other supplies on hand. The meal serves up to six people, and each person who eats it regains two additional Hit Dice at the end of the long rest. In addition, those who partake of the meal have advantage on Constitution saving throws against disease for the next 24 hours.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Great Weapon Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered putting the weight of a weapon to your advantage, letting its momentum empower your strikes. While you are wielding a melee weapon in two hands with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• On your turn, when you score a critical hit with a melee weapon or reduce a creature to 0 hit points with one, you can make one melee weapon attack as a bonus action.

	• Before you make a melee attack with a weapon that you are wielding in two-hands with which you are proficient with, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If the attack hits, you add double your proficiency bonus to the attack's damage.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Haggler</name>
    <text>Your skills at bartering have granted you the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1 up to a maximum of 20.

	• You have advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) and Charisma (Deception) checks when attempting to barter or trade.

	• You are always aware of the current monetary value for any unenhanced or common enhanced item. Whenever you identify an item, you gain a rough estimate of its current monetary value.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Haggler (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Your skills at bartering have granted you the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1 up to a maximum of 20.

	• You have advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) and Charisma (Deception) checks when attempting to barter or trade.

	• You are always aware of the current monetary value for any unenhanced or common enhanced item. Whenever you identify an item, you gain a rough estimate of its current monetary value.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Healer (Intelligence)</name>
    <text>You are an able medic, allowing you to mend wounds quickly and get your allies back in the fight. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you use a traumakit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains 1 hit point.

	• As an action, you can spend one use of a traumakit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + 4 hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice. The creature can't regain hit points again in this way until it finishes a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Healer (Wisdom)</name>
    <text>You are an able medic, allowing you to mend wounds quickly and get your allies back in the fight. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you use a traumakit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains 1 hit point.

	• As an action, you can spend one use of a traumakit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + 4 hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice. The creature can't regain hit points again in this way until it finishes a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Healer (Intelligence) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You are an able medic, allowing you to mend wounds quickly and get your allies back in the fight. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you use a medkit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains 1 hit point.

	• As an action, you can spend one use of a medkit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + 4 hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice. The creature can't regain hit points again in this way until it finishes a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Healer (Wisdom) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You are an able medic, allowing you to mend wounds quickly and get your allies back in the fight. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you use a medkit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains 1 hit point.

	• As an action, you can spend one use of a medkit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + 4 hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice. The creature can't regain hit points again in this way until it finishes a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Heavily Armored (Strength)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with medium armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of heavy armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with heavy armor. If you are already proficient with heavy armor, instead while you are wearing heavy armor, critical hits made against you are treated as normal hits.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Heavily Armored (Dexterity)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with medium armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of heavy armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with heavy armor. If you are already proficient with heavy armor, instead while you are wearing heavy armor, critical hits made against you are treated as normal hits.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Heavily Armored (Constitution)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with medium armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of heavy armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with heavy armor. If you are already proficient with heavy armor, instead while you are wearing heavy armor, critical hits made against you are treated as normal hits.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Heavily Armored (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with medium armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of heavy armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with heavy armor. If you are already proficient with heavy armor, instead increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• While you are wearing heavy armor, kinetic and energy damage that you take from unenhanced weapons is reduced by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Heavily Armored (Proficienct) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with medium armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of heavy armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with heavy armor. If you are already proficient with heavy armor, instead increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• While you are wearing heavy armor, kinetic and energy damage that you take from unenhanced weapons is reduced by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Heavy Weapon Specialist</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You master the assault cannon, bowcaster, scattergun, and shotgun. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• When a creature rolls a 1 on the saving throw against one of these weapons, they treat the effect's damage as if it had rolled the maximum. If a creature would already treat the effect's damage as if it had rolled the maximum when it rolls a 1 on this weapon's saving throw, it instead does so on a roll of 1 or 2.

	• Whenever you score a critical hit against a creature that is holding an object, you can attempt to disarm the target. If the target is no more than one size larger than you (your size or smaller if your weapon has the light property), it must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier) or it drops an object of your choice at its feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Heavy Weapons Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master the assault cannon, bowcaster, scattergun, and shotgun. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• When a creature rolls a 1 on the saving throw against one of these weapons, it takes damage as if suffering a critical hit.

	• Whenever you score a critical hit against a creature that is holding a weapon, you can attempt to disarm the target. If the target is no more than one size larger than you (your size or smaller if your weapon has the *light* property), it must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier) or it drops an object of your choice at its feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Herbalist (Intelligence) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You are adept at harnessing the useful properties of herbs and other plants. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the herbalism kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• As an action, you can inspect a plant within 5 feet of you and determine whether it is edible or poisonous, provided that you can see and smell it.

	• You can apply herbal remedies to help yourself or your allies recover from maladies. Over the course of a short rest, you can remove one poison or disease from a friendly creature within reach. You must have an herbalism kit and access to local herbs to use this benefit.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Herbalist (Wisdom) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You are adept at harnessing the useful properties of herbs and other plants. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the herbalism kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• As an action, you can inspect a plant within 5 feet of you and determine whether it is edible or poisonous, provided that you can see and smell it.

	• You can apply herbal remedies to help yourself or your allies recover from maladies. Over the course of a short rest, you can remove one poison or disease from a friendly creature within reach. You must have an herbalism kit and access to local herbs to use this benefit.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Inspiring Leader</name>
    <prerequisite>Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You can spend 10 minutes inspiring your companions, shoring up their resolve to fight. When you do so, choose up to six friendly creatures (which can include yourself) within 30 feet of you who can see or hear you and who can understand you. Each creature can gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Charisma modifier. A creature can't gain temporary hit points from this feat again until it has finished a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Inspiring Leader (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You can spend 10 minutes inspiring your companions, shoring up their resolve to fight. When you do so, choose up to six friendly creatures (which can include yourself) within 30 feet of you who can see or hear you and who can understand you. Each creature can gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Charisma modifier. A creature can't gain temporary hit points from this feat again until it has finished a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Investigative Attunement</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You've spent a significant amount of time appraising and testing enhanced items. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Your maximum attunement increases by 1.

	• You have advantage on ability checks made to identify items.

	• Once per long rest, you can choose one object that you must touch for 10 minutes. If it is an enhanced or modified item, you learn its properties and how to use them, whether it requires attunement to use, and how many charges it has, if any. You learn whether any powers are affecting the item and what they are. If the item was created by a power, you learn which power created it.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Investigator</name>
    <proficiency>Investigation</proficiency>
    <text>You have an eye for detail and can pick out the smallest clues. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Investigation skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You can take the Search action as a bonus action.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Investigator (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Investigation</proficiency>
    <text>You have an eye for detail and can pick out the smallest clues. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Investigation skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You can take the Search action as a bonus action.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Jedi Slayer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have practiced techniques useful in melee combat against forcewielders, gaining the following benefits:

	• When a creature within 5 feet of you casts a force power, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature.

	• When you damage a creature that is concentrating on a power, that creature has disadvantage on the saving throw it makes to maintain its concentration.

	• You have advantage on saving throws against force powers cast by creatures within 5 feet of you.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Keen Mind</name>
    <text>You have a mind that can track time, direction, and detail with uncanny precision. You gain the following benefits.

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You always know which way is north.

	• You always know the number of hours left before the next sunrise or sunset.

	• You can accurately recall anything you have seen or heard within the past month.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Keen Mind (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have a mind that can track time, direction, and detail with uncanny precision. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You always know which way is north.

	• You always know the number of hours left before the next sunrise or sunset.

	• You can accurately recall anything you have seen or heard within the past month.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Kinetic Stoicism</name>
    <prerequisite>at least 3 levels in sentinel</prerequisite>
    <text>You've developed a preternatural focus, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Once per turn, whenever you roll a Kinetic Combat die, you can roll the die twice and take either result.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lightly Armored (Strength)</name>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of light armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with light armor. If you are already proficient with light armor, instead while you are wearing light armor, your speed increases by 5 feet.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lightly Armored (Dexterity)</name>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of light armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with light armor. If you are already proficient with light armor, instead while you are wearing light armor, your speed increases by 5 feet.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lightly Armored (Constitution)</name>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of light armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with light armor. If you are already proficient with light armor, instead while you are wearing light armor, your speed increases by 5 feet.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lightly Armored (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of light armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with light armor. If you are already proficient with light armor, instead increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• While you are wearing light armor, your speed increases by 5 feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lightly Armored (Proficient) (Strength) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of light armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with light armor. If you are already proficient with light armor, instead increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• While you are wearing light armor, your speed increases by 5 feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lightly Armored (Proficient) (Strength) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of light armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with light armor. If you are already proficient with light armor, instead increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• While you are wearing light armor, your speed increases by 5 feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Linguist</name>
    <text>You have studied languages and codes, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You learn three languages of your choice.

	• You can ably create written ciphers. Others can't decipher a code you create unless you teach them, they succeed on an Intelligence check (DC = your Intelligence score + your proficiency bonus), or they use a power to decipher it.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Linguist (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have studied languages and codes, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You learn three languages of your choice.

	• You can ably create written ciphers. Others can't decipher a code you create unless you teach them, they succeed on an Intelligence check (DC equal to your Intelligence score + your proficiency bonus), or they use a power to decipher it.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Loremaster</name>
    <proficiency>History</proficiency>
    <text>Your study of history rewards you with the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Lore skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• When you take the Help action to aid another creature's ability check, you can make a DC 15 Intelligence (Lore) check. On a success, that creature's check gains a bonus equal to your proficiency bonus, as you share pertinent advice and historical examples. To receive this bonus, the creature must be able to understand what you're saying.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Loremaster (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>History</proficiency>
    <text>Your study of history rewards you with the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Lore (History) skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• When you take the Help action to aid another creature's ability check, you can make a DC 15 Intelligence (Lore* (History)) check. On a success, that creature's check gains a bonus equal to your proficiency bonus, as you share pertinent advice and historical examples. To receive this bonus, the creature must be able to understand what you're saying.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lucky</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You have inexplicable luck that seems to kick in at just the right moment.

	• You have 3 luck points. Whenever you make an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can spend one luck point to roll an additional d20. You can choose to spend one of your luck points after you roll the die, but before the outcome is determined. You choose which of the d20s is used for the attack roll, ability check, or saving throw.

	• You can also spend one luck point when an attack roll is made against you. Roll a d20, and then choose whether the attack uses the attacker's roll or yours. If more than one creature spends a luck point to influence the outcome o f a roll, the points cancel each other out; no additional dice are rolled.

	• You regain your expended luck points when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Lucky (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have inexplicable luck that seems to kick in at just the right moment.

	• You have 3 luck points. Whenever you make an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can spend one luck point to roll an additional d20. You can choose to spend one of your luck points after you roll the die, but before the outcome is determined. You choose which of the d20s is used for the attack roll, ability check, or saving throw.

	• You can also spend one luck point when an attack roll is made against you. Roll a d20, and then choose whether the attack uses the attacker's roll or yours. If more than one creature spends a luck point to influence the outcome o f a roll, the points cancel each other out; no additional dice are rolled.

	• You regain your expended luck points when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Maneuverable (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've learned that you are at your best when you're on the move. You gain the following benefits:

	• Your speed increases by 5 feet.

	• When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can move 5 feet at no movement cost as part of the attack.

	• When you hit a creature with a melee attack that you have not already attacked on your current turn, you gain a +2 bonus to the damage roll.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mariner</name>
    <text>You've spent an exorbitant amount of time in water. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain a swimming speed equal to your movement speed.

	• You have advantage on a ability checks and saving throws related to swimming.

	• You can hold your breath for a number of minutes equal to 1 + twice your Constitution modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mariner (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've spent an exorbitant amount of time in water. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain a swimming speed equal to your movement speed.

	• You have advantage on a ability checks and saving throws related to swimming.

	• You can hold your breath for a number of minutes equal to 1 + twice your Constitution modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Martial Adept</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You have martial training that allows you to perform special combat maneuvers. You gain the following benefits:

	• You learn two maneuvers of your choice from among those available to the fighter class. If a maneuver you use requires your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver's effects, the saving throw DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).

	• If you already have superiority dice, you gain one more; otherwise, you have two superiority dice, which are d4s. These dice are used to fuel your maneuvers. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Martial Adept (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have martial training that allows you to perform special combat maneuvers. You gain the following benefits:

	• You learn two maneuvers of your choice from among those available to the fighter class. If a maneuver you use requires your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver's effects, the saving throw DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).

	• If you already have superiority dice, you gain one more; otherwise, you have two superiority dice, which are d4s. These dice are used to fuel your maneuvers. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Master of Disguise (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have honed your ability to shape your personality and to read the personalities of others. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the disguise kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• If you spend 1 hour observing a creature, you can then spend 8 hours crafting a disguise you can quickly don to mimic that creature. Making the disguise requires a disguise kit. You must make checks as normal to disguise yourself, but you can assume the disguise as an action.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Medic</name>
    <proficiency>Medicine</proficiency>
    <text>You master the physician's arts, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• During a short rest, you can clean and bind the wounds of up to six willing beasts and humanoids. Make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check for each creature. On a success, if a creature spends a Hit Die during this rest, that creature can forgo the roll and instead regain the maximum number of hit points the die can restore. A creature can do so only once per rest, regardless of how many Hit Dice it spends.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Medic (Proficient)</name>
    <text>You master the physician's arts, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• During a short rest, you can clean and bind the wounds of up to six willing beasts and humanoids. Make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check for each creature. On a success, if a creature spends a Hit Die during this rest, that creature can forgo the roll and instead regain the maximum number of hit points the die can restore. A creature can do so only once per rest, regardless of how many Hit Dice it spends.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">medicine +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Medic (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Medicine</proficiency>
    <text>You master the physician's arts, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• During a short rest, you can clean and bind the wounds of up to six willing beasts and humanoids. Make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check for each creature. On a success, if a creature spends a Hit Die during this rest, that creature can forgo the roll and instead regain the maximum number of hit points the die can restore. A creature can do so only once per rest, regardless of how many Hit Dice it spends.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Medic (Proficient) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master the physician's arts, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• During a short rest, you can clean and bind the wounds of up to six willing beasts and humanoids. Make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check for each creature. On a success, if a creature spends a Hit Die during this rest, that creature can forgo the roll and instead regain the maximum number of hit points the die can restore. A creature can do so only once per rest, regardless of how many Hit Dice it spends.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">medicine +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Meditative Mindfulness</name>
    <prerequisite>At least 3 levels in consular</prerequisite>
    <text>You've delved to new depths during your meditation, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you complete a long rest, you can choose one of the force powers you know and replace it with another force power, as long as that power is not of a higher level than your Max Power Level.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mobile</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You are exceptionally speedy and agile. You gain the following benefits:

	• Your speed increases by 10 feet.

	• When you use the Dash action, difficult terrain doesn't cost you extra movement on that turn.

	• When you make a melee attack against a creature, you don't provoke opportunity attacks from that creature for the rest of the turn, whether you hit or not.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +10</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mobile (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You are exceptionally speedy and agile. You gain the following benefits:

	• Your speed increases by 10 feet.

	• When you use the Dash action, difficult terrain doesn't cost you extra movement on that turn.

	• When you make a melee attack against a creature, you don't provoke opportunity attacks from that creature for the rest of the turn, whether you hit or not.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +10</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Moderately Armored (Strength)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with light armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of medium armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with medium armor. If you are already proficient with medium armor, instead while you are wearing medium armor, you can add 3, rather than 2, to your AC if you have a Dexterity of 16 or higher, and you ignore the bulky property of medium armor.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Moderately Armored (Dexterity)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with light armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of medium armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with medium armor. If you are already proficient with medium armor, instead while you are wearing medium armor, you can add 3, rather than 2, to your AC if you have a Dexterity of 16 or higher, and you ignore the bulky property of medium armor.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Moderately Armored (Constitution)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with light armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of medium armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with medium armor. If you are already proficient with medium armor, instead while you are wearing medium armor, you can add 3, rather than 2, to your AC if you have a Dexterity of 16 or higher, and you ignore the bulky property of medium armor.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Moderately Armored (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with light armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of medium armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with medium armor. If you are already proficient with medium armor, instead increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• While you are wearing medium armor, you can add 3, rather than 2, to your AC if you have a Dexterity of 16 or higher.

	• Wearing medium armor doesn't impose disadvantage on your Dexterity (Stealth) checks.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Moderately Armored (Proficient) (Strength) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with light armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of medium armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with medium armor. If you are already proficient with medium armor, instead increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• While you are wearing medium armor, you can add 3, rather than 2, to your AC if you have a Dexterity of 16 or higher.

	• Wearing medium armor doesn't impose disadvantage on your Dexterity (Stealth) checks.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Moderately Armored (Proficient) (Dexterity) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with light armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have trained to master the use of medium armor, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with medium armor. If you are already proficient with medium armor, instead increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• While you are wearing medium armor, you can add 3, rather than 2, to your AC if you have a Dexterity of 16 or higher.

	• Wearing medium armor doesn't impose disadvantage on your Dexterity (Stealth) checks.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mounted Caster</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level, the ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You are trained in the use of powers while mounted. While you are mounted and aren't incapacitated, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you cast a power targeting yourself, you can also affect your mount with the power.

	• You have advantage on melee force or tech attack rolls against any unmounted creature that is smaller than your mount.

	• If your mount is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, it instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw, and only half damage if it fails.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mounted Caster (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You are trained in the use of powers while mounted. While you are mounted and aren't incapacitated, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you cast a power targeting yourself, you can also affect your mount with the power.

	• You have advantage on melee force or tech attack rolls against any unmounted creature that is smaller than your mount.

	• If your mount is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, it instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw, and only half damage if it fails.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Mounted Combatant (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You are a dangerous foe to face while mounted. While you are mounted and aren't incapacitated, you gain the following benefits:

	• You have advantage on melee attack rolls against any unmounted creature that is smaller than your mount.

	• You can force an attack targeted at your mount to target you instead.

	• If your mount is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, it instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw, and only half damage if it fails.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Naturalist</name>
    <proficiency>Nature</proficiency>
    <text>Your extensive study of nature rewards you with the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Nature skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You learn the toxin scan tech power. You can cast it once, using supplies scavenged around you, without the use of a wristpad and without spending tech points, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Naturalist (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Nature</proficiency>
    <text>Your extensive study of nature rewards you with the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Nature skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You learn the *toxin scan* tech power. You can cast it once, using supplies scavenged around you, without the use of a wristpad and without spending tech points, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Observant (Intelligence)</name>
    <text>Quick to notice details of your environment, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• If you can see a creature's mouth while it is speaking a language you understand, you can interpret what it's saying by reading its lips.

	• You are considered to have advantage when determining your passive Wisdom (Perception) and passive Intelligence (Investigation) scores.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Observant (Wisdom)</name>
    <text>Quick to notice details of your environment, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• If you can see a creature's mouth while it is speaking a language you understand, you can interpret what it's saying by reading its lips.

	• You are considered to have advantage when determining your passive Wisdom (Perception) and passive Intelligence (Investigation) scores.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Observant (Intelligence) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Quick to notice details of your environment, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• If you can see a creature's mouth while it is speaking a language you understand, you can interpret what it's saying by reading its lips.

	• You have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Perception) and passive Intelligence (Investigation) scores.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Observant (Wisdom) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Quick to notice details of your environment, you gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• If you can see a creature's mouth while it is speaking a language you understand, you can interpret what it's saying by reading its lips.

	• You have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Perception) and passive Intelligence (Investigation) scores.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Overwhelming Presence</name>
    <prerequisite>Charisma 20, 12th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the presence of the most affluent of leaders, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Charisma saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Charisma saving throws you make.

	• While you are conscious, up to five friendly creatures within 30 feet of you who can see or hear you and who can understand you can gain a bonus to one Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw they make equal to your Charisma modifier. Once they've done so, they can't do so again until they finish a short or long rest.

	• As an action, you can attempt to distract up to five creatures you can see within 30 feet of you. Each creature must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier). Any creature immune to being charmed is unaffected. If you or your companions are fighting a creature, it has advantage on the saving throw. On a failed save, for the next minute, a creature has disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to perceive any creature other than you until the effect ends or until the target can no longer see or hear you. The feature ends early if you are incapacitated.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">charisma save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Overwhelming Presence (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Charisma 20, character level 12</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the presence of the most affluent of leaders, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Charisma saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Charisma saving throws you make.

	• While you are conscious, up to five friendly creatures within 30 feet of you who can see or hear you and who can understand you can gain a bonus to one Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw they make equal to your Charisma modifier. Once they've done so, they can't do so again until they finish a short or long rest.

	• As an action, you can attempt to distract up to five creatures you can see within 30 feet of you. Each creature must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier). Any creature immune to being charmed is unaffected. If you or your companions are fighting a creature, it has advantage on the saving throw. On a failed save, for the next minute, a creature has disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to perceive any creature other than you until the effect ends or until the target can no longer see or hear you. The feature ends early if you are incapacitated.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">charisma save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Perceptive</name>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <text>You hone your senses until they become razor sharp. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Perception skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• Being in a lightly obscured area doesn't impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks if you can both see and hear.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Perceptive (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <text>You hone your senses until they become razor sharp. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Perception skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• Being in a lightly obscured area doesn't impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks if you can both see and hear.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Performer</name>
    <proficiency>Performance</proficiency>
    <text>You master performance so that you can command any stage. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Performance skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• While performing, you can try to distract one humanoid you can see who can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Performance) check contested by the humanoid's Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, you grab the humanoid's attention enough that it makes Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks with disadvantage until you stop performing.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Performer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Performance</proficiency>
    <text>You master performance so that you can command any stage. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Performance skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• While performing, you can try to distract one humanoid you can see who can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Performance) check contested by the humanoid's Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, you grab the humanoid's attention enough that it makes Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks with disadvantage until you stop performing.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Poisoner (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have studied the secrets of poisons and toxins, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the poisoner's kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• As an action, you can identify one poison within 5 feet of you. You must see the poison for this benefit to work.

	• Over the course of a short rest, you can temporarily improve the potency of one dose of poison. To use this benefit, you must have a poisoner's kit, and the poison must be within reach. If the poison is applied before the end of your next short or long rest, its DC becomes 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier, and it deals extra poison damage equal to your Intelligence modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Polearm Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master the lightsaber pike, saberspear, vibrolance, vibropike, and vibrospear. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• When you take the Attack action, you can use a bonus action to make a melee attack with the opposite end of the weapon. The weapon's damage die for this attack is a d4, and the attack deals kinetic damage. If the weapon has the reach property, the bonus action attack does not benefit from this property.

	• Other creatures provoke an opportunity attack from you when they enter your reach.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Polearm Specialist</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You master the lightsaber pike, saberspear, vibrolance, vibropike, and vibrospear. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• When you take the Attack action, you can use a bonus action to make a melee attack with the opposite end of the weapon. The weapon's damage die for this attack is a d4, and the attack deals kinetic damage. If the weapon has the reach property, the bonus action attack does not benefit from this property.

	• When you take the Attack action, you can choose to forgo one of your attacks. If you do so, your reach increases by 5 feet until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Power Adept</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level, the ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>When you gain this feat, choose one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, force, lightning, or necrotic. Powers you cast ignore resistance to damage of the chosen type. In addition, when you roll damage for a power you cast that deals damage of that type, you can treat any 1 on a damage die as a 2.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different damage type.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Power Adept (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>When you gain this feat, choose one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, force, lightning, or necrotic. Powers you cast ignore resistance to damage of the chosen type. In addition, when you roll damage for a power you cast that deals damage of that type, you can treat any 1 on a damage die as a 2.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different damage type.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Practiced</name>
    <text>You have acquired skills over your career, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in any combination of two skills or tools of your choice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Practiced (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have acquired skills over your career, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in any combination of two skills or tools of your choice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Precision Applications</name>
    <prerequisite>At least 3 levels in operative</prerequisite>
    <text>You've honed your skills to fine edge, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to carefully aim your next attack. You gain advantage on your next attack roll before the end of your current turn. You can't use this feature if you have moved during this turn, and using this feature reduces your speed to 0 until the end of your current turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Promising Commander</name>
    <text>You've trained relentless to lead your allies on the field of battle, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• As an action, you can gain tactical insight. For one minute, once per turn you can utter a special command or warning whenever an ally you can see within 30 feet makes an attack roll or saving throw. This creature can add a d4 to the roll provided it can hear and understand you. A creature can only benefit from one such die at a time. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Promising Commander (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've trained relentless to lead your allies on the field of battle, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• As an action, you can gain tactical insight. For one minute, once per turn you can utter a special command or warning whenever an ally you can see within 30 feet makes an attack roll or saving throw. This creature can add a d4 to the roll provided it can hear and understand you. A creature can only benefit from one such die at a time. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Prone Combatant</name>
    <text>You've practiced fighting while prone, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain a crawling speed equal to your movement speed.

	• You no longer have disadvantage on ranged attack rolls against targets within 30 feet.

	• When you attempt to hide on your turn while prone, you can opt to not move on that turn. If you avoid moving, you are considered lightly obscured. You lose this benefit if you move or stand up, either voluntarily or because of some external effect. You are still automatically detected if any effect or action causes you to no longer be hidden. If you are still hidden on your next turn, you can continue to remain motionless and gain this benefit until you are detected.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Prone Combatant (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've practiced fighting while prone, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain a crawling speed equal to your movement speed.

	• You no longer have disadvantage on ranged attack rolls against targets within 30 feet.

	• When you attempt to hide on your turn while prone, you can opt to not move on that turn. If you avoid moving, you are considered lightly obscured. You lose this benefit if you move or stand up, either voluntarily or because of some external effect. You are still automatically detected if any effect or action causes you to no longer be hidden. If you are still hidden on your next turn, you can continue to remain motionless and gain this benefit until you are detected.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Quick Caster</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level, the ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced casting powers in quick succession, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• When you cast a power with a casting time of a bonus action, you may use your action to cast a power with a power level no higher than half your proficiency bonus (rounded down).

	• When you cast a power with a casting time of a bonus action, you can cast it without expending force or tech points as long as it is no higher level than your proficiency bonus. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Quick Caster (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced casting powers in quick succession, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• When you cast a power with a casting time of a bonus action, you may use your action to cast a power with a power level no higher than half your proficiency bonus (rounded down).

	• When you cast a power with a casting time of a bonus action, you can cast it without expending force or tech points as long as it is no higher level than your proficiency bonus. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Quick-fingered</name>
    <proficiency>Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
    <text>Your nimble fingers and agility let you perform sleight of hand. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Sleight of Hand skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• As a bonus action, you can make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check to plant something on someone else, conceal an object on a creature, lift a purse, or take something from a pocket.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Quick-Fingered (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
    <text>Your nimble fingers and agility let you perform sleight of hand. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Sleight of Hand skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• As a bonus action, you can make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check to plant something on someone else, conceal an object on a creature, lift a purse, or take something from a pocket.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Quick-Witted</name>
    <text>Great ideas come to you naturally, often when your life depends on it. You always have a plan, or at least parts of it. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You can use your Intelligence modifier instead of your Dexterity modifier when making initiative checks.

	• When you would make a Dexterity saving throw, you can instead make an Intelligence saving throw. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. You regain all expended uses of this feature when you complete a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Quick-Witted (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Great ideas come to you naturally, often when your life depends on it. You always have a plan, or at least parts of it. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You can use your Intelligence modifier instead of your Dexterity modifier when making Initiative checks.

	• When you would make a Dexterity saving throw, you can instead make an Intelligence saving throw. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. You regain all expended uses of this feature when you complete a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Relentless Pursuer</name>
    <prerequisite>At least 3 levels in berserker</prerequisite>
    <text>You've harnessed a new level of persistence, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When a creature ends its turn within 15 feet of you, you can use your reaction to move up to half your speed to a space closer to the creature. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Resilient</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>Choose one ability score. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase the chosen ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in saving throws using the chosen ability.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Resilient (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Choose one ability score. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase the chosen ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in saving throws using the chosen ability.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Rifle Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master the use of blaster carbine, blaster rifle, ion rifle, lightbow, sniper rifle, and slugthrower. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll and hit, and the lower of the two d20 rolls would also hit, you can attempt to snare the target. If the target is no more than one size larger than you (your size or smaller if your weapon has the *light* property), it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier) or its movement speed is halved until the end of your next turn.

	• When a creature you can see misses you with an attack roll, you can use your reaction to Disengage and move up to half your speed. You must end this movement further away from the creature than you started.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Rifle Specialist</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You master the use of blaster carbine, blaster rifle, ion rifle, sniper rifle, and slugthrower. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll and hit, and the lower of the two d20 rolls would also hit, you can attempt to snare the target. If the target is no more than one size larger than you (your size or smaller if your weapon has the light property), it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier) or gains 1 slowed level until the end of it's next turn.

	• When a creature you can see misses you with an attack roll, you can use your reaction to Disengage and move up to half your speed. You must end this movement further away from the creature than you started.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Savage Shorty</name>
    <prerequisite>Strength 13, size Small</prerequisite>
    <text>Despite being short of stature, your size has no impact on your strength and virility. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Your speed increases by 5 feet.

	• You lose the Undersized special trait.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Savage Shorty (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Strength 13, size Small</prerequisite>
    <text>Despite being short of stature, your size has no impact on your strength and virility. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Your speed increases by 5 feet.

	• You no longer have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons due to being Small.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Sentinel Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered techniques to take advantage of every drop in any enemy's guard; in tight spaces you are indomitable. While you are wielding a melee weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you hit a creature with an opportunity attack, the creature's speed becomes 0 for the rest of the turn.

	• Creatures within 5 feet of you provoke opportunity attacks from you even if they take the Disengage action before leaving your reach.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Serene Resolve</name>
    <prerequisite>At least 3 levels in guardian</prerequisite>
    <text>You've learned to adapt the Force in new ways, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• As a bonus action, you can expend a use of your Channel the Force to regain 2 force points. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, as shown in the guardian table. You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Shard Modification</name>
    <prerequisite>Type droid</prerequisite>
    <text>You are specially modified droid used to house a shard. Shards are sentient crystals native to the planet Orax, roughly a foot in length, that communicate with each other through pulses of light. While inhabiting a specialized droid host, shards are able to overcome the droid's inability to wield the Force, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You lose the Force Insensitive special trait.

	• You can cast the sense force power once per day. Wisdom or Charisma (your choice) is your forcecasting ability for this power.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Sharpshooting Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have mastered ranged weapons and can easily make shots that others find impossible. While you are wielding a ranged weapon with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• Attacking at long range doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.

	• Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.

	• Before you make an attack with a ranged weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If the attack hits, you add double your proficiency bonus to the attack's damage.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Shielding Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered using a shield to defend your allies as well as yourself, and you understand that shields are not just for protection but also for offense. While you are wielding a medium or heavy shield with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• If you take the Attack action on your turn, you can use a bonus action to try to shove a creature within 5 feet of you with your shield.

	• If you aren't incapacitated, you can add your shield's AC bonus to any Dexterity saving throw you make against a power or other harmful effect.

	• If you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you can use your reaction to take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, interposing your shield between yourself and the source of the effect.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Sidearm Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master the blaster pistol, heavy pistol, hold out, ion blaster, light pistol, and wrist launcher. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• You learn to load and fire your weapon more efficiently. You can now reload these weapons using your reaction. You must have one free hand to reload.

	• Whenever you score a critical hit against a living creature that has a head, you can attempt to daze the target. If the target is no more than one size larger than you (your size or smaller if your weapon has the *light* property), it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier) or be stunned until the end of its next turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Sidearm Specialist</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You master the blaster pistol, heavy pistol, hold out, ion pistol, light pistol, and wrist launcher. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• You learn to load and fire your weapon more efficiently. You can now reload these weapons using your object interaction. You must have one free hand to reload.

	• Whenever you score a critical hit against a living creature that has a head, you can attempt to daze the target. If the target is no more than one size larger than you (your size or smaller if your weapon has the light property), it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier) or be stunned until the end of its next turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Silver-Tongued</name>
    <proficiency>Deception</proficiency>
    <text>You develop your conversational skill to better deceive others. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Deception skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• When you take the Attack action, you can replace one attack with an attempt to deceive one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Deception) check contested by the target's Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, your movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks from the target and your attack rolls against it have advantage; both benefits last until the end of your next turn or until you use this ability on a different target. If your check fails, the target can't be deceived by you in this way for 1 hour.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Silver-Tongued (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Deception</proficiency>
    <text>You develop your conversational skill to better deceive others. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Deception skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• When you take the Attack action, you can replace one attack with an attempt to deceive one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Deception) check contested by the target's Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, your movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks from the target and your attack rolls against it have advantage; both benefits last until the end of your next turn or until you use this ability on a different target. If your check fails, the target can't be deceived by you in this way for 1 hour.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Skulker (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You are expert at slinking through shadows. You gain the following benefits:

	• You can try to hide when you are lightly obscured from the creature from which you are hiding.

	• When you are hidden from a creature and miss it with a ranged weapon attack, making the attack doesn't reveal your position.

	• Dim light doesn't impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks relying on sight.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Slicer (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You are an expert at finding things in computers you shouldn't. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the slicer's kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• Whenever you make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Perception) check to detect the nature of computer software, you are considered to have expertise in the Investigation or Perception skill.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Snappy Interjection</name>
    <text>You've mastered a quick tongue to aid your allies. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Once per short or long rest, when an ally makes an attack roll, an ability check or a saving throw, you can spend your reaction to give them advantage on the roll.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Snappy Interjection (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered a quick tongue to aid your allies. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When an ally makes an attack roll, an ability check or a saving throw, you may spend your reaction to give them advantage on the roll. Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Sniping Caster</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level, The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced casting powers more accurately from long range, learning techniques that give you the following benefits:

	• When you cast a power that requires you to make an attack roll, the power's range is doubled.

	• Your ranged force and tech attacks ignore one-quarter, half, and three-quarters cover.

	• You learn one at-will power that requires an attack roll. Your casting ability for this at-will power depends on the power list you chose from: Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment) for force powers or Intelligence for tech powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Sniping Caster (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced casting powers more accurately from long range, learning techniques that give you the following benefits:

	• When you cast a power that requires you to make an attack roll, the power's range is doubled.

	• Your ranged force and tech attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.

	• You learn one at-will power that requires an attack roll. Your casting ability for this at-will power depends on the power list you chose from: Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment) for force powers or Intelligence for tech powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Specialist</name>
    <text>You have focused training with a specific tool. Select one type of specialist's kit. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with the chosen kit. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain expertise with it.

	• You can attempt ability checks with the chosen kit without the kit present, but you have disadvantage on the check when you do so.

	• Whenever you make an ability check with the chosen kit and you don't have disadvantage on the check, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10, as long as you spend at least 1 minute on the check.

	• You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different specialist's kit.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Stealthy</name>
    <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
    <text>You know how best to hide, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Stealth skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• If you are hidden, you can move up to 10 feet in the open without revealing yourself if you end the move in a position where you're not clearly visible.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Stealthy (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
    <text>You know how best to hide. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Stealth skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• If you are hidden, you can move up to 10 feet in the open without revealing yourself if you end the move in a position where you're not clearly visible.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Supreme Accuracy (Dexterity)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You have uncanny aim with attacks that rely on precision. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll using Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma you can reroll one of the dice once.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Supreme Accuracy (Intelligence)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You have uncanny aim with attacks that rely on precision. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll using Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma you can reroll one of the dice once.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Supreme Accuracy (Wisdom)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You have uncanny aim with attacks that rely on precision. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll using Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma you can reroll one of the dice once.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Supreme Accuracy (Charisma)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You have uncanny aim with attacks that rely on precision. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll using Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma you can reroll one of the dice once.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Supreme Accuracy (Dexterity) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You have uncanny aim with attacks that rely on precision rather than brute force. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll using Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma you can reroll one of the dice once.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Supreme Accuracy (Intelligence) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You have uncanny aim with attacks that rely on precision rather than brute force. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll using Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma you can reroll one of the dice once.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Supreme Accuracy (Wisdom) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You have uncanny aim with attacks that rely on precision rather than brute force. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll using Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma you can reroll one of the dice once.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Supreme Accuracy (Charisma) (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma 13</prerequisite>
    <text>You have uncanny aim with attacks that rely on precision rather than brute force. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll using Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma you can reroll one of the dice once.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Survivalist</name>
    <text>You master wilderness lore, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Survival skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You learn the alarm tech power. You can cast it once, using supplies scavenged around you, without the use of a wristpad and without spending tech points, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Survivalist (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master wilderness lore, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Survival skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You learn the *alarm* tech power. You can cast it once, using supplies scavenged around you, without the use of a wristpad and without spending tech points, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Tech Dabbler</name>
    <text>You know two at-will tech powers. When you reach 3rd level, you learn and can cast one 1st-level tech power once per long rest. When you reach 5th level, you learn and can cast one 2nd-level tech power once per long rest. Your techcasting ability is Intelligence. You require use of a wristpad for these powers. Additionally, you lose the Tech-Impaired special trait if you have it.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Tech Dabbler (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You learn two at-will tech powers, and one 1st-level tech power, which you cast it at its lowest level. Once you cast it, you must finish a long rest before you can cast it again. Intelligence is your techcasting ability for these powers. You do not require use of a wristpad for these powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Techie</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana</proficiency>
    <text>You master the theory and practice of technology, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Technology skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You learn the repair droid tech power. You can cast it once, using supplies scavenged around you, without the use of a wristpad and without spending tech points, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Techie (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana</proficiency>
    <text>You master the theory and practice of technology, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Technology skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• You learn the *repair droid* tech power. You can cast it once, using supplies scavenged around you, without the use of a wristpad and without spending tech points, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Threatening</name>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <text>You become fearsome to others, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• When you take the Attack action, you can replace one attack with an attempt to demoralize one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Intimidation) check contested by the target's Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, the target is frightened until the end of your next turn. If your check fails, the target can't be frightened by you in this way for 1 hour.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Threatening (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <text>You become fearsome to others, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill. If you are already proficient in it, you instead gain expertise in it.

	• When you take the Attack action, you can replace one attack with an attempt to demoralize one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Intimidation) check contested by the target's Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, the target is frightened until the end of your next turn. If your check fails, the target can't be frightened by you in this way for 1 hour.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Throwing Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered the techniques of throwing weapons, readily blending the weapons with your movements. While you are wielding a weapon with the *thrown* property with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to ranged attack rolls you make with thrown weapons.

	• Attacking at long range doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls with thrown weapons.

	• When you hit a creature with a ranged weapon attack with a thrown weapon, you have advantage on your next melee weapon attack against that creature before the end of your next turn.

	• You can use two-weapon fighting even when the melee weapons you are wielding in one hand aren't light, if at least one of them has the *thrown* property.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Tiny Terror</name>
    <prerequisite>Strength 13, size Tiny</prerequisite>
    <text>Despite falling below knee height of other species, your size has less impact on your strength and virility. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Your speed increases by 5 feet.

	• You lose the Pintsized special trait, and you are no longer limited to +3 when determing your bonus to attack and damasge rolls for weapon attacks using Strength due to the Puny special trait.

	• You gain the Undersized special trait: Undersized. Your small stature makes it hard for you to wield bigger weapons. You can't use heavy shields or martial weapons with the two-handed property unless it has the light property, and if a martial weapon has the versatile property, you can only wield it in two-hands.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Tireless Outrider</name>
    <prerequisite>At least 3 levels in scout</prerequisite>
    <text>You've pushed yourself past the limits of your endurance, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• As an action, you can reduce your exhaustion level by 1 and give yourself a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d10 + your Intelligence modifier. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Titan's Power</name>
    <prerequisite>Strength 20, 12th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the strength that legends tell of, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Strength saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Strength saving throws you make.

	• You ignore the two-handed property of weapons with which you are proficient.

	• When you miss with a melee weapon attack, the creature takes damage equal to your Strength modifier. This damage is of the same type as the weapon's damage.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">strength save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Titan's Power (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Strength 20, character level 12</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the strength that legends tell of, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Strength saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to Strength saving throws you make.

	• You ignore the *two-handed* property of weapons with which you are proficient.

	• When you miss with a melee weapon attack, the creature takes damage equal to your Strength modifier. This damage is of the same type as the weapon's damage.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">strength save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Tough</name>
    <prerequisite>Durable feat, 4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the blood of heroes flowing through your veins. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you take the Dodge action in combat, you can spend one Hit Die to heal yourself. Roll the die, add your Constitution modifier, and regain a number of hit points equal to the total (minimum of one).

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Tough (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Durable feat</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the blood of heroes flowing through your veins. You gain the following benefits:

	• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Whenever you take the Dodge action in combat, you can spend one Hit Die to heal yourself. Roll the die, add your Constitution modifier, and regain a number of hit points equal to the total (minimum of one).

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Trip Weapon Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You master the chakram, light ring, net, saberwhip, vibrobaton, vibrostaff, and vibrowhip. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• As a bonus action on your turn, you can extend your weapon to sweep around and pull down an opponent's shield. Until the end of that creature's next turn, it gains no benefit to armor class from its shield.

	• When you score a critical hit with the weapon or hit with an opportunity attack using the weapon, you can attempt to trip the opponent as well. If the target is no more than one size larger (your size or smaller if your weapon has the light property), it must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your choice of either your Strength or Dexterity modifier) or be knocked prone.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Trip Weapon Specialist</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You master the chakram, light ring, net, saberwhip, vibrobaton, vibrostaff, and vibrowhip. You gain the following benefits while wielding any of these weapons, if you are proficient with it:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to the weapon's attack rolls.

	• As a bonus action on your turn, you can extend your weapon to sweep around and pull down an opponent's shield. Until the end of that creature's next turn, it gains no benefit to armor class from its shield.

	• When you score a critical hit with the weapon or hit with an opportunity attack using the weapon, you can attempt to trip the opponent as well. If the target is no more than one size larger (your size or smaller if your weapon has the light property), it must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your choice of either your Strength or Dexterity modifier) or be knocked prone.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Two-Weapon Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered fighting with two weapons, becoming a flurry of motion. While you are wielding separate weapons in each hand with which you are proficient, you gain the following benefits:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to AC while you are wielding a separate weapon in each hand.

	• You can use two-weapon fighting even when the weapons you are wielding aren't light.

	• You can draw or stow two weapons when you would normally be able to draw or stow only one.

	• When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can choose to forgo your proficiency bonus. If you do so, you can make an additional two-weapon fighting attack, also without your proficiency bonus.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Unnatural Resilience</name>
    <prerequisite>Constitution 20, 12th level</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the fortitude often attributed to gods, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Constitution saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to saving throws you make.

	• Enhanced effects, such as powers or medpacs, that would restore hit points to you can't restore an amount less than half your level + your Constitution modifier. If this amount would exceed that maximum amount of hit points that effect could restore, you instead take that effect's maximum.

	• You can add your Constitution modifier to death saving throws you make.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">constitution save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Unnatural Resilience (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>Constitution 20, character level 12</prerequisite>
    <text>You have the fortitude often attributed to gods, granting the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency in Constitution saving throws. If you are already proficient in them, you add double your proficiency bonus to saving throws you make.

	• Enhanced effects, such as powers or medpacs, that would restore hit points to you can't restore an amount less than half your level + your Constitution modifier. If this amount would exceed that maximum amount of hit points that effect could restore, you instead take that effect's maximum.

	• You can add your Constitution modifier to death saving throws you make.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="saving throw">constitution save +%0</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Versatile Design</name>
    <prerequisite>At least 3 levels in scholar</prerequisite>
    <text>You've learned to approach problems from new angles, granting the following benefits:

	• Increase an ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• When you complete a long rest, you can choose one of the maneuvers you know and replace it with another one.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Versatile Mastery (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You've mastered the art of using weapons in different ways, altering your attack patterns mid-swing. While you are wielding a melee weapon with the versatile property with which you are proficient and no other weapons, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you are the target of a melee weapon attack, you can immediately use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against the target with disadvantage. On a hit, you impose disadvantage on the attack roll made against you.

	• If you miss an attack while wielding a weapon in two hands, you can immediately make an attack roll against the same target using one hand. You can only make this attack once per turn.

	• If you miss an attack while wielding a weapon in one hand, you can immediately attempt to shove that creature up to 5 feet directly away from you. You can only make this attempt once per turn.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>War Caster</name>
    <prerequisite>4th level, the ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced casting powers in the midst of combat, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a power when you take damage.

	• Once per round, when a hostile creature provokes an opportunity attack from you, you can use your reaction to cast a power at the creature, rather than making an opportunity attack. The power must have a casting time of 1 action and must target only that creature.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>War Caster (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast force or tech powers</prerequisite>
    <text>You've practiced casting powers in the midst of combat, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:

	• You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a power when you take damage.

	• When a hostile creature's movement provokes an opportunity attack from you, you can use your reaction to cast a power at the creature, rather than making an opportunity attack. The power must have a casting time of 1 action and must target only that creature.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Weapon Expert (Strength)</name>
    <text>You have practiced extensively with a variety of weapons, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with all blasters, lightweapons, and vibroweapons. If you are already proficient with all blasters, lightweapons or vibroweapons, instead once per turn when you roll damage for a weapon attack using a weapon from a category in which you are proficient with all weapons, you can reroll the weapon's damage dice and use either total.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Weapon Expert (Dexterity)</name>
    <text>You have practiced extensively with a variety of weapons, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with all blasters, lightweapons, and vibroweapons. If you are already proficient with all blasters, lightweapons or vibroweapons, instead once per turn when you roll damage for a weapon attack using a weapon from a category in which you are proficient with all weapons, you can reroll the weapon's damage dice and use either total.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Weapon Expert (Constitution)</name>
    <text>You have practiced extensively with a variety of weapons, gaining the following benefits:

	• Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• You gain proficiency with all blasters, lightweapons, and vibroweapons. If you are already proficient with all blasters, lightweapons or vibroweapons, instead once per turn when you roll damage for a weapon attack using a weapon from a category in which you are proficient with all weapons, you can reroll the weapon's damage dice and use either total.

	• You can take this feat twice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Weapon Expert (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>You have practiced extensively with a variety of weapons, gaining the following benefits:

	• You gain proficiency with all blasters, lightweapons, and vibroweapons. If you are already proficient with them, instead increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.

	• Once per turn when you roll damage for a weapon attack using a weapon with which you are proficient, you can reroll the weapon's damage dice and use either total.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
  </feat>
</compendium>
