<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
   <feat>
      <name>Deployment-Coordinator 1 - Inspiring Display (Star Wars 5e)</name>
      <text>Also at 1st rank, you can inspire others through stirring words. To do so, you use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than yourself within 60 feet of you who can hear you. That creature gains one Inspiring Display die, a d4. Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Inspiring Display die, but must decide before the GM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once the Inspiring Display die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one Inspiring Display die at a time.

You can use this feature twice. You gain another use of this feature at 2nd, 3rd, 4th, and 5th rank in this deployment. You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Your Inspiring Display die changes when you reach certain ranks in this deployment. The die becomes a d6 at 2nd rank, a d8 at 3rd rank, a d10 at 4th rank, and a d12 at 5th rank.</text>
   </feat>
  <feat>
      <name>Deployment-Coordinator 1st - Inspiring Display (Star Wars 5e)</name>
      <text></text>
   </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Deployment-Coordinator 2nd - Uplifiting Directive (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>At 2nd rank, while aboard your ship, you can use the Direct action with a range of 60 feet, as long as the target can hear and understand you.

Additionally, when you take the Direct action, roll a d20. Note the number on the d20. This becomes your uplifting directive number.

While you have an uplifting directive number, when an ally makes an ability check or attack roll affected by your Direct action, you can replace the result of a d20 roll with the value of the uplifting directive roll. You can use this feature before or after making the roll, but before any effects of the roll are determined. You can only have one uplifting directive roll at a time, and you lose any unused uplifting directive rolls when you complete a short or long rest.</text>
</feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Deployment-Coordinator 2nd - Call To Arms (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Also at 2nd rank, while aboard your ship, if you are surprised at the start of combat and aren't incapacitated, you and a creature who can see or hear you may act normally on their first turn.</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Deployment-Coordinator 3rd - Versatile Coordinator (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Starting at 3rd rank, when you would expend an Inspiring Display die, you can use a d4 instead of expending a die. You can only use this feature once per round.</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Deployment-Coordinator 3rd - Commanding Presence (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>Also at 3rd rank, you learn a new way to use your Inspiring Display. While aboard your ship, when a creature that can see or hear you fails an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, you can use use your reaction and expend a use of your Inspiring Display to aid that creature provided it did not already have or use an Inspiring Display die this turn. The creature can then roll the die and add it to the result.</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Deployment-Coordinator 4th - Masterful Directive (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <text>At 4th rank, when you roll your uplifting directive number as a part of the Direct action, you can use your bonus action to increase your uplifting directive number by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus. If this would increase the value of your uplifting directive number to more than 20, it instead becomes 20.</text>
  </feat>
</compendium>
