<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <race>
    <name>Abyssin (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Rapidly Regenerating</name>
      <text>You heal quickly, both at will and in response to danger. As a bonus action, you can choose to spend one of your Hit Dice to recover hit points. Additionally, when you take damage, you can use your reaction and expend a Hit Die to regain hit points as long as the damage would not reduce your hit points to 0.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rugged Survivalist</name>
      <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Survival skill. Additionally, you are naturally adapted to hot climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tech-Impaired</name>
      <text>While abyssin can figure out basic technology, they experience difficulty using more complex equipment like wristpads. You can not use tech powers or take levels in techcasting classes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Savage Attacks</name>
      <text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon's damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Abyssin. Abyssin uses mainly growls and grunts that many species consider primitive. The written form of language uses only a small number of simple hieroglyphs.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Aing-Tii (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Sensitive</name>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'7"	+2d10"
Weight	145 lb.	x (2d4) lb.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in one skill, one tool, and one weapon of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Armored Plates</name>
      <text>You have thick armored plates. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Attunement</name>
      <text>Aing-tii have a natural attunement for the Force, which makes them resistant to its powers. You have advantage on saving throws against force powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Sensitive</name>
      <text>You know the force push/pull at-will force power. Wisdom or Charisma (your choice) is your forcecasting ability for this power.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Prehensile Tail</name>
      <text>You have supreme control over your tail and can use it to manipulate objects as well as your hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can understand, read, and write Galactic Basic, and the non-verbal communication of the aing-tii. However, you cannot speak or make noise verbally.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Aleena (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Your sharp teeth are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier. Additionally, as a bonus action, you can perform a special bite attack. On a hit, the target suffers the attack's normal effects, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1), and you can't use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cosmopolitan</name>
      <proficiency>History</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Lore.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Nimble Escape</name>
      <text>You can take the Disengage or Hide action as a bonus action on each of its turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Nimbleness</name>
      <text>You can move through the space of any creature that is of a size larger than yours.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Racer's Reflexes</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Dexterity ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, you can choose to add 1d4 to the result. You can choose to do this after the check is rolled, but before the DM determines if you've passed or failed the check. You cannot do so again until you complete a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Undersized</name>
      <text>Your small stature makes it hard for you to wield bigger weapons. You cannot use heavy shields. Additionally, you cannot use martial weapons with the two-handed property unless it also has the light property, and if a martial weapon has the versatile property, you can only wield it in two hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Aleena. Aleena is characterized by its use of short syllables and energetic movements to convey urgency and emotion.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Anzellan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <speed>20</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and two other ability scores of your choice increase by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Crafter</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one tool of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Detail Oriented</name>
      <text>You are practiced at scouring for details. You have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) checks that rely on sight within 5 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pintsized</name>
      <text>Your tiny stature makes it hard for you to wield bigger weapons. You can't use medium or heavy shields. Additionally, you can't wield weapons with the two-handed or versatile property, and you can only wield one-handed weapons in two hands unless they have the light property.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Puny</name>
      <text>Anzellans are too small to pack much of a punch. You have disadvantage on Strength saving throws, and when determining your bonus to attack and damage rolls for weapon attacks using Strength, you can't add more than +3.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Small and Nimble</name>
      <text>You are too small and fast to effectively target. You have a +1 bonus to AC, and you have advantage on Dexterity saving throws.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tanned</name>
      <text>You are naturally adapted to hot climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Technician</name>
      <proficiency>Arcana</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Technology skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tinker</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with tinker's implements. You can use these and spend 1 hour and 100 cr worth of materials to construct a Tiny Device (AC 5, 1 hp). You can take the Use an Object action to have your device cause one of the following effects: create a small explosion, create a repeating loud noise for 1 minute, create smoke for 1 minute, create a soothing melody for 1 minute. You can maintain a number of these devices up to your proficiency bonus at once, and a device stops functioning after 24 hours away from you. You can dismantle the device to reclaim the materials used to create it.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Anzellan. Anzellan is characterized by its bouncy sound and emphasis on alternating syllables.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Aqualish (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d10"
Weight	140 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Arms Dealers</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check related to buying or selling weapons, you are considered to have expertise in the Persuasion skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aggressive</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Aqualish. Aqualish is a harsh, guttural language. It's rare that other species bother to learn it unless they regularly interact with Aqualish.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Arcona (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Your sharp talons are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Clever</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one Intelligence skill of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Easily Addicted</name>
      <text>Arcona are susceptible to spice addiction, and as a result you are taught to identify it from an early age. Additionally, consuming salt can cause them to hallucinate, potentially replicating the effects of spice. Whenever you make an ability check related to identifying salt or spice or seeing whether something contains salt or spice, you have advantage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>You have a thick hide. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. Additionally, your thick hide is naturally adapted to hot climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that involve smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Reptilian Senses</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Wisdom (Perception) check related to sensing heat, you are considered to have expertise in the Perception skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Arconese. Arconese is spoken through complex, guttural squeaks from the back of the throat. However, arcona born and raised in colonies outside of Cona often did not learn Arconese, but the local language instead.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Ardennian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	3'2"	+2d8"
Weight	50 lb.	x1 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Four-Armed</name>
      <text>Ardennians have four arms which they can use independently of one another. You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your arms at any given time, and once per round you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Jungle Dweller</name>
      <text>Growing up in the tree-villages of Ardennia has left an impact. You don't treat jungle terrain as difficult terrain.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
      <text>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Prehensile Feet</name>
      <text>You have supreme control over your feet and can use them to manipulate objects as well as your hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Strong-Legged</name>
      <text>When you make a long jump, you can cover a number of feet up to twice your Strength score. When you make a high jump, you can leap a number of feet up into the air equal to 3 + twice your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Treeclimber</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 25 feet. You have advantage on Strength saving throws and Strength (Athletics) checks that involve climbing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Ardennian. Ardennian has a bubbly, energizing tone to it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Arkanian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Arkanian Brilliance</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an Intelligence ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, you can choose to add 1d4 to the result. You can choose to do this after the check is rolled, but before the DM determines if you've passed or failed the check. You cannot do so again until you complete a short or long rest.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Honed Mind</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Infrared Sight</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Wisdom (Perception) check related to sight, you are considered to have expertise in the Perception skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
      <text>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Arkanian. Arkanian, when spoken, has an airy tone, and is regarded as one of the most difficult written languages to learn.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Balosar (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing</name>
      <text>Your antennapalps give you advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks based on hearing.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Snap Senses</name>
      <text>Through your antennapalps, you can sense incoming danger and react accordingly. When you roll for initiative, you can choose to gain advantage on the roll. Alternatively, if you are surprised, you may act normally on your first turn. Once you've used this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spicer</name>
      <text>You are proficient in spicer's kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Toxin Resistance</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage (explained in chapter 9).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Balosur. Balosur is known by its throaty rasps and deep vocalizations, and is considered crude as a written language.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Barabel (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'7"	+2d10"
Weight	140 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can make a special bite attack. If the attack hits, it deals 1d4 kinetic damage, and you gain temporary hit points (minimum of 1) equal to your Constitution modifier, and you can't use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Barabel have retractable claws. You are proficient with your claws, which deal 1d4 kinetic damage on a hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>You have a thick hide. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. Additionally, your thick hide is naturally adapted to cold climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hunter</name>
      <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in Survival.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Prehensile Tail</name>
      <text>You have supreme control over your tail and can use it to manipulate objects as well as your hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Barabel. The Barabel language is characterized by its barks and hisses.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Besalisk (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	6'0"	+2d12"
Weight	175 lb.	x (2d6) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Four-Armed</name>
      <text>Besalisks have four arms which they can use independently of one another. You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your arms at any given time, and once per round you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Long-Limbed</name>
      <text>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <special>Powerful Build</special>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Besalisk.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Bith (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'9"	+2d6"
Weight	100 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Detail Oriented</name>
      <text>You are practiced at scouring for details. You have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) checks within 5 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that involve hearing or smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Musician</name>
      <text>You are proficient in one musical instrument of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Programmer</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (Technology) check related to computers, you are considered to have expertise in the Technology skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic, Bith, and one more language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Bothan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'3"	+2d4"
Weight	60 lb.	x (2d4) lb..

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Naturally Stealthy</name>
      <text>You can attempt to hide even when you are obscured only by a creature that is your size or larger than you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Nimble Escape</name>
      <text>You can take the Disengage or Hide action as a bonus action on each of its turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shrewd</name>
      <proficiency>Deception, Insight</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Insight and Deception skills.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Bothese. Bothese had a great influence on the forming of Galactic Basic; the two languages share many cognates.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Cathar (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'9"	+2d12"
Weight	130 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a cat's keen senses, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Leonin Agility</name>
      <text>Your reflexes and agility allow you to move with a burst of speed. When you move on your turn in combat, you can double your speed until the end of the tum. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you move 0 feet on one of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cat's Claws</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 20 feet. Additionally, your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cat's Talent</name>
      <proficiency>Perception, Stealth</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Perception and Stealth skills.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Catharese.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Cerean (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'8"	+2d8"
Weight	120 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Intuitive Initiative</name>
      <text>You can choose to reroll Initiative checks, but you must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Mind</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom saving throws.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Perceptive</name>
      <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Perception.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Strong-Legged</name>
      <text>When you make a long jump, you can cover a number of feet up to twice your Strength score. When you make a high jump, you can leap a number of feet up into the air equal to 3 + twice your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>Cereans don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Cerean.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Chadra-Fan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	2'8"	+2d8"
Weight	35 lb.	x1 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Climb</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 25 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that involve hearing or smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Second Heart</name>
      <text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tinker</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with tinker's tools. You can use these and spend 1 hour and 100 cr worth of materials to construct a Tiny Device (AC 5, 1 hp). You can take the Use an Object action to have your device cause one of the following effects: create a small explosion, create a repeating loud noise for 1 minute, create smoke for 1 minute, emit an onerous smell for 1 minute.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>Chadra-Fan only require 2 hours of sleep a day. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Chadra-Fan. The Chadra-Fan language is characterized as being nasally and squeaky.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Chagrian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d8"
Weight	120 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Resistance</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage (explained in chapter 9).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Chagri.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Chevin (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'9"	+2d12"
Weight	170 lb.	x (2d6) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>You have a thick hide. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. Additionally, your thick hide is naturally adapted to both hot and cold climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Nomadic</name>
      <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in Survival.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Thick Skull</name>
      <text>Your skull is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal 1d6 + your Strength modifier kinetic damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Chevin. The Chevin language is characterized by grunts and low-pitched rumblings. Chevin typically have deep voices, even when speaking Basic.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Chironian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>40</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Cultured</name>
      <proficiency>History</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Lore skill.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Equine Build</name>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push or drag. Additionally, any climb that requires hands and feet is especially difficult for you because of your hooves. When you make such a climb, each foot of movement costs you 4 extra feet, instead of the normal 1 extra foot. Finally, a Medium or smaller creature can ride on your equine back if you allow it. In such a situation, you continue to act independently, not as a controlled mount.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hooves and Horns</name>
      <text>Your hooves (and depending on your age, horns) are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Charge</name>
      <text>If you move at least 10 feet in a straight line before hitting with a melee weapon attack, you can attempt to trip the target prone as part of the same attack. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Chironan. Chironan is characterized by its soft, melodic sounds.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Chiss (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'11"	+2d10"
Weight	110 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tech Resistance</name>
      <text>Growing up around technology leaves an impact on chiss. You have advantage on saving throws against tech powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Martial Proficiency</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with light and medium armor as well as the blaster pistol and sniper rifle.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Cheunh. Cheunh is a complex language that is difficult for non-chiss to learn. Chiss take pride in this difficulty.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Clawdite (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and one other ability score of your choice increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Changeling Instincts</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Deception, Intimidation, Insight, and Persuasion.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shapechanger</name>
      <text>As an action, you can change your appearance and your voice. You determine the specifics of the changes, including your coloration, hair length, and sex. You can also adjust your height and weight, but not so much that your size changes. You can make yourself appear as a member of another species, though none of your game statistics change. You can't duplicate the appearance of a creature you've never seen, and you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs that you have. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this trait. You stay in the new form until you use an action to revert to your true form or until you die.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unsettling Visage</name>
      <text>When a creature you can see makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the roll. You must use this feature before knowing whether the attack hits or misses. Using this trait reveals your shapeshifting nature to any creature within 30 feet that can see you. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic, Clawdite, and one more language of your choice. Clawdite is characterized by its rolling sounds paired with hissing sibilants.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Codru-Ji (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'6"	+2d8"
Weight	90 lb.	x (2d6) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Four-Armed</name>
      <text>Codru-Ji have four arms which they can use independently of one another. You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your arms at any given time, and once per round you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>You have a thick hide. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 12 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Grappler</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Strength (Athletics) check to grapple you are considered to have expertise in the Athletics skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>Codru-Ji sleep lightly, standing and semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Codruese, which has a solemn and stately cadence to it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Colicoid (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Strength or Constitution score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Acute Senses</name>
      <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cannibalize</name>
      <text>If you spend at least 1 minute devouring the corpse of a beast or humanoid, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of one). Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Closed Mind</name>
      <text>Colicoid brains have an unusual composition which gives them a natural defense against the Force. You have advantage on Wisdom and Charisma saving throws against force powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Defensive Ball</name>
      <text>You are able to curl into a rolling ball for extra protection. When you take the Dash action while you aren't wielding a shield, you gain a bonus to AC equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded up) until the start of your next turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Armor</name>
      <text>You are able to curl into a rolling ball for extra protection. When you take the Dash action while you aren't wielding a shield, you gain a bonus to AC equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded up) until the start of your next turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stinger</name>
      <text>Your stinger is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Colicoid. The Colicoid language uses sounds produced by the antennae and jointed legs of the colicoids, including humming sounds and clicks, which makes it difficult for other species to speak.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Dashade (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Your claws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Contention</name>
      <text>Due to their unique physiology, dashade hardiness allows them to overcome use of the Force. You have advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws against force powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Heat Dissipation</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check to avoid detection by electronic sensors and cameras, you are considered to have expertise in the Stealth skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Radiation Resistant</name>
      <text>Dashade are naturally able to resist radiation. You have resistance to necrotic damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Language</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Dashadi. Dashadi is characterized by its low pitch and elongated growls.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Defel (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Your claws are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hidden Step</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can turn invisible until the start of your next turn or until you attack, make a damage roll, or force someone to make a saving throw. Once you've used this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Miners</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in scavenging kits.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
      <text>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sneaky</name>
      <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Stealth skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Surprise Attack</name>
      <text>If you surprise a creature and hit it with an attack on your first turn in combat, the attack deals an extra 2d6 damage to it. You can use this trait only once per combat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Undersized</name>
      <text>Your small stature makes it hard for you to wield bigger weapons. You can't use heavy shields. Additionally, you can't use martial weapons with the two-handed property unless it also has the light property, and if a martial weapon has the versatile property, you can only wield it in two hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Defel. Most defel refuse to speak Galactic Basic while on their home planet of Af'El unless they have a specific need for it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Devaronian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'10"	+2d8"
Weight	120 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Jungle Dweller</name>
      <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
      <text>Growing up in the jungles of Devaron has left an impact. You are proficient in Survival. Additionally, you don't treat jungle terrain as difficult terrain.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tech Resistance</name>
      <text>Devaronians have a history of using technology as a weapon. You have advantage on saving throws against tech powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Two Livered</name>
      <text>Devaronians have two livers, which makes them adept at filtering toxins. You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage (explained in chapter 9).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Devaronese. Devaronese is characterized by grunts and grumbles. It is rare to hear a Devaronian speak it any where other than their homeworld of Devaron.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Draethos (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d12"
Weight	130 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Way of the Warrior</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with light and medium armor as well as vibroblades and vibroswords.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Telepathy</name>
      <text>You can communicate telepathically with creatures within 30 feet of you. You must share a language with the target in order to communicate in this way.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>ou can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Draethos. Draethos is characterized by its flurry of cacophonous sighs and clicks.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Droid, Class I (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Wisdom or Charisma score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Type</name>
      <text>Your creature type is droid.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Integration</name>
      <text>You can not wear armor, but you can have the armor professionally integrated into your chassis. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of the armor in order to have it integrated. This work must be done by someone proficient with astrotech's tools. You must be proficient in armor in order to have it integrated.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Resistances</name>
      <text>You are resistant to necrotic, poison, and psychic damage, and are immune to poison and disease.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Vulnerabilities</name>
      <text>You are vulnerable to ion damage. Additionally, you have disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Systems</name>
      <text>You do not need to eat or drink.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Insensitive</name>
      <text>While droids can be manipulated by many force powers, they can not sense the Force. You can not use force powers or take levels in forcecasting classes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Maintenance Mode</name>
      <text>Rather than sleep, you enter an inactive state to perform routine maintenance for 4 hours each day. You have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks while performing maintenance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rapid Reconstruction</name>
      <text>You are built with internal repair mechanisms. As a bonus action, you can choose to spend one of your Hit Dice to recover hit points.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and one language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Droid, Class II (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	2'5"	+2d8"
Weight	60 lb.	x1 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and one other ability score of your choice increase by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Type</name>
      <text>Your creature type is droid.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Integration</name>
      <text>You can not wear armor, but you can have the armor professionally integrated into your chassis. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of the armor in order to have it integrated. This work must be done by someone proficient with astrotech's tools. You must be proficient in armor in order to have it integrated.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Resistances</name>
      <text>You are resistant to necrotic, poison, and psychic damage, and are immune to poison and disease.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Vulnerabilities</name>
      <text>You are vulnerable to ion damage. Additionally, you have disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Systems</name>
      <text>You do not need to eat or drink.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Insensitive</name>
      <text>While droids can be manipulated by many force powers, they can not sense the Force. You can not use force powers or take levels in forcecasting classes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Integrated Engineering</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in your choice of demolitions kit, security kit, or slicer's kit. The chosen kit is integrated into your chassis, and can not be removed while you are conscious.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Maintenance Mode</name>
      <text>Rather than sleep, you enter an inactive state to perform routine maintenance for 4 hours each day. You have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks while performing maintenance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rapid Reconstruction</name>
      <text>You are built with internal repair mechanisms. As a bonus action, you can choose to spend one of your Hit Dice to recover hit points.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Retractible Arms</name>
      <text>You have two retractible arms: one grasper and one manipulator. The manipulator arm can only wield weapons and shield generators with the *light* property.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Protocol</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in two skills of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Binary. You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic and one language of your choice, but you can not speak it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Droid, Class III (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>20</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'6"	+2d4"
Weight	120 lb.	x (2d6) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and one other ability score of your choice increase by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Type</name>
      <text>Your creature type is droid.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Integration</name>
      <text>You can not wear armor, but you can have the armor professionally integrated into your chassis. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of the armor in order to have it integrated. This work must be done by someone proficient with astrotech's tools. You must be proficient in armor in order to have it integrated.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Resistances</name>
      <text>You are resistant to necrotic, poison, and psychic damage, and are immune to poison and disease.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Vulnerabilities</name>
      <text>You are vulnerable to ion damage. Additionally, you have disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Systems</name>
      <text>You do not need to eat or drink.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Insensitive</name>
      <text>While droids can be manipulated by many force powers, they can not sense the Force. You can not use force powers or take levels in forcecasting classes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Knowledge Protocol</name>
      <proficiency>History</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Lore* (History) skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Maintenance Mode</name>
      <text>Rather than sleep, you enter an inactive state to perform routine maintenance for 4 hours each day. You have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks while performing maintenance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rapid Reconstruction</name>
      <text>You are built with internal repair mechanisms. As a bonus action, you can choose to spend one of your Hit Dice to recover hit points.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write all registered languages.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Droid, Class IV (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'2"	+2d8"
Weight	110 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and one other ability score of your choice increase by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Type</name>
      <text>Your creature type is droid.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Integration</name>
      <text>You can not wear armor, but you can have the armor professionally integrated into your chassis. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of the armor in order to have it integrated. This work must be done by someone proficient with astrotech's tools. You must be proficient in armor in order to have it integrated.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Resistances</name>
      <text>You are resistant to necrotic, poison, and psychic damage, and are immune to poison and disease.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Vulnerabilities</name>
      <text>You are vulnerable to ion damage. Additionally, you have disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Systems</name>
      <text>You do not need to eat or drink.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Insensitive</name>
      <text>While droids can be manipulated by many force powers, they can not sense the Force. You can not use force powers or take levels in forcecasting classes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Maintenance Mode</name>
      <text>Rather than sleep, you enter an inactive state to perform routine maintenance for 4 hours each day. You have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks while performing maintenance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Martial Protocol</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with light and medium armor as well as two simple or martial blasters or vibroweapons of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rapid Reconstruction</name>
      <text>You are built with internal repair mechanisms. As a bonus action, you can choose to spend one of your Hit Dice to recover hit points.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and one language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Droid, Class V (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Dexterity or Constitution score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Type</name>
      <text>Your creature type is droid.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Integration</name>
      <text>You can not wear armor, but you can have the armor professionally integrated into your chassis. Over the course of a long rest, you can expend materials equal to half the cost of the armor in order to have it integrated. This work must be done by someone proficient with astrotech's tools. You must be proficient in armor in order to have it integrated.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Resistances</name>
      <text>You are resistant to necrotic, poison, and psychic damage, and are immune to poison and disease.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Vulnerabilities</name>
      <text>You are vulnerable to ion damage. Additionally, you have disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Droid Systems</name>
      <text>You do not need to eat or drink.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Insensitive</name>
      <text>While droids can be manipulated by many force powers, they can not sense the Force. You can not use force powers or take levels in forcecasting classes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Maintenance Mode</name>
      <text>Rather than sleep, you enter an inactive state to perform routine maintenance for 4 hours each day. You have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks while performing maintenance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Manual Laborer</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in Athletics and one set of artisan's implements of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <text>Your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift doubles. If it would already double, it instead triples.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rapid Reconstruction</name>
      <text>You are built with internal repair mechanisms. As a bonus action, you can choose to spend one of your Hit Dice to recover hit points.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and one language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Dug (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	3'2"	+2d6"
Weight	50 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Courageous</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fury of the Small</name>
      <text>When you damage a creature with an attack or a power and the creature's size is larger than yours, you can cause the attack or power to deal extra damage to the creature. The extra damage equals your level. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Strong and Small</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 25 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <text>You count as two sizes larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Dug.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Duros (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d10"
Weight	115 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Galactic Traveler</name>
      <proficiency>History</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Lore* (History).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pilot</name>
      <proficiency>Religion</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Piloting* (Religion).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tech Resistance</name>
      <text>Duros grow up around technology, and while they may not all use it they all have experience with it. You have advantage on saving throws against tech powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Durese. Durese is a common interstellar tongue used by prominent spacers and traders.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Echani (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'1"	+1d10"
Weight	105 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Allies of the Force</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Wisdom (Insight) check against someone you know to wield the Force, you are considered to have expertise in the Insight skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unarmed Combatant</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d6 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Echani Art</name>
      <text>If a humanoid you can see makes a melee weapon attack, you can use your reaction to make a Wisdom (Insight) check against the target's Charisma (Deception). On a success you learn one of the following traits about that creature: it's Strength, Dexterity or Constitution score; bonus to Strength, Dexterity or Constitution saving throws; armor class; or current hit points. On a failure, the target becomes immune to this feature for one day. You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses on a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Combative Culture</name>
      <proficiency>Acrobatics, History</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Lore (History) and Acrobatics.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Martial Upbringing</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in light armor, and gain proficiency with two martial vibroweapons of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and one extra language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Esh-Kha (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength or Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force-Sensitive</name>
      <text>You know your choice of the turbulence, force disarm, or slow at-will force powers. Your forcecasting ability is Wisdom or Charisma (depending on power alignment).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Inquisitive</name>
      <proficiency>Investigation</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Investigation skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Savage Attacks</name>
      <text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon's damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Versatility</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in one skill of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Weapon Training</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in two vibroweapons or blasters of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Kharan. Kharan contains many metaphorical expressions when translated to Galactic Basic. The language has many comparisons to music and singing, such as a galactic government being compared to a chorus.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Ewok (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	2'9"	+2d6"
Weight	40 lb.	x1 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Crude Weapon Specialists</name>
      <text>Ewoks are used to making do with less. You can spend 1 hour, which you can do over the course of a short rest, crafting a weapon out of loose materials. You can craft any simple kinetic weapon, but the weapon's damage suffers a -1 penalty.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Musical Culture</name>
      <text>Ewoks incorporate music in their celebrations and rituals. You have proficiency in an instrument of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Survivalist</name>
      <proficiency>Nature, Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Nature and Survival.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
      <text>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Treeclimber</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 25 feet. You have advantage on Strength saving throws and Strength (Athletics) checks that involve climbing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Ewokese. You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic, but your vocal cords do not allow you to speak it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Ex-Republic Clone (Advanced Player)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait>
      <name>Clone Characteristics</name>
      <text>The basic Republic Clone is bred for obedience and military discipline.

Though often viewed as the "Flesh and blood" equivalent of Battle Droids, most Clones possess a limited capacity for individuality. They were bred for no other purpose than combat, but nevertheless they developed as individuals under the guidance of their Jedi officers. The Jedi's unique abilities and leadership prowess earned them the admiration and respect of the Clones who served under them, and as such allowed Clones to develop a more individual mindset.

Republic Clones are genetic replicas of the Human Species. Specifically, they are based off of the bounty hunter Jango Fett, and as a result they are almost indistinguishable from one another.

Homeworld: The vast majority of Republic Clones are created on Kamino by the Kaminoans.

Languages: Republic Clones all learn Basic.

Example Names: When a Republic Clone is created, they are assigned a two letter and four digit identification tag, although those that survive multiple deployments tend to take up a moniker to better identify themselves.

Adventurers: All Republic Clones received basic training in core military skills, such as weapons handling, marksmanship, drill, and other essentials. As such, the vast majority of Republic Clones become Soldiers, with a rare few becoming Scouts and Technicians.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores Aberration </name>
      <text>Republic Clones begin play with the following Ability Score array: Strength 15, Dexterity 13, Constitution 10, Intelligence 12, Wisdom 10, and Charisma 8. Additionally, a Republic Clone player can choose one Ability Score to increase by 2 at the time of Character Creation.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bonus Feat</name>
      <text>Republic Clones gain one bonus Feat at 1st level.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bonus Proficiency </name>
      <text>Republic Clones are versatile and accomplished at many tasks. A Republic Clone character chooses one additional proficiency at 1st level.

The Skill must be chosen from the character's list of Class Skills.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Echoes of The Original </name>
      <text>Your mind isn't completely your own or, at least, it wasn't always yours. As you are a clone of another living being typically the life experiences of the original host have been suppressed or wiped. Do to the brain wash program of order 66, you experience echoes from another life.

Intrusive Echoes. Immediately after you make an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw and roll a 1 on the d20, your minds memories emerge and overtake your perceptions and experiences. You might see people around you as someone other than who they are, or you become disoriented by a double-experience of the world around you.

These echoes grant you knowledge, talents, or even languages you can't always explain, but they also intrude on your perceptions and beliefs unexpectedly. They will last for 1d12 rounds in combat or hours of provoked out of combat.
	Roll on or choose an option from the Echoes table to determine the nature of this Gift.

Additionally, you gain the traits that follow.

Echo Table:
d6 | Echo
1 | My mind is with that of another clone elsewhere, perhaps on another world.
2 | I have lived many times before, my mind compiling experiences each time a clone from the same host dies creating an amalgam of thoughts and personality.
3 | My consciousness is an exact replica of the original being I believe I am he/she.
4 | I was physically and mentally merged with two separate body and minds. As such I am a unique combination. (Imperial or Sith experimentation)
5 | I share my body with an intangible, otherworldly mind, a non corporeal being.
6 | Time fractures around me, and I sometimes collide with my originals past or future.

Roll on the Intrusive Echoes table to determine the effect of these vivid memories and perceptions. Once one of effects occur, these intrusive echoes can't manifest again until you finish a short or long rest.

Intrusive Echoes Table:
d6 | Effect
1 | You are charmed by a creature you can see (of the DM's choice) for 1 minute or until the creature damages you.
2 | You are frightened by a creature you can see (of the DM's choice) for 1 minute, or until the creature damages you.
3 | You perceive another time or place around you until the end of your next turn. During this time, you are blinded to your actual surroundings.
4 | You perceive a different time or place overlapping your surroundings. Your speed is halved until the end of your next turn.
5 | Memories and sensations overwhelm you. You are incapacitated until the start of your next turn.
6 | Your memory is one of triumph. You can reroll the ability check, attack roll, or saving throw that you just made. You must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Falleen (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'7"	+2d10"
Weight	110 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Closed Mind</name>
      <text>Falleen brains have an unusual composition which make them resistant to influence from the Force. You have advantage on saving throws against force powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Enthralling Pheromones</name>
      <text>You can use your pheromones to influence individuals of both sexes. Whenever you roll a 1 on a Charisma (Persuasion) check, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll. Additionally, once per short or long rest, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower on a Charisma check as a 10. This feature has no effect on droids or constructs.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hold Breath</name>
      <text>You can hold your breath for up to 1 hour at a time.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
      <text>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Falleen. Falleen is characterized by its common use of the Z and X sounds, of which the Falleen are fond.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Felucian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'8"	+2d6"
Weight	165 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Sensitive</name>
      <text>You know the *burst* at-will force power. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the Beast Trick (Light Force) force power once per day. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the Plant Surge (Light Force) force power once per day. Wisdom is your forcecasting ability for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stealthy</name>
      <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Stealth skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
      <text>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic, Felucianese, and one more language of your choice. Felucianese is characterized by guttural, whisper-like vowels, interspersed with hard clicks.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Flesh Raider (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Wisdom or Charisma score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aggressive</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cannabalize</name>
      <text>If you spend at least 1 minute devouring the corpse of a beast or humanoid, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of one). Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Contention</name>
      <text>Due to their unique physiology, flesh raider hardiness allows them to overcome use of the Force. You have advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws against force powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hunters</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Wisdom (Survival) check to hunt for food, you are considered to have expertise in the Survival skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Rakata. Rakata is characterized by its deep tones and simplistic nature, using mainly consonants and long vowels. It's script seems to be a very ancient form of Galactic Basic.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Gamorrean (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'10"	+2d8"
Weight	150 lb.	x (2d6) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gamorrean Toughness</name>
      <text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level. Additionally, you have advantage on Constitution saving throws.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gamorrean Weaponry</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with the vibroaxe, vibroclub, and vibrosword.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Savage Attacks</name>
      <text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon's damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Gamorrese. You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic, but your vocal cords do not allow you to speak it. Gamorrese is characterized by its grunts and squeals, and its writing is a crude, pictographic style.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Gand (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'1"	+2d10"
Weight	75 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Exoskeleton</name>
      <text>You have a thick exoskeleton. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 12 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gand Resilience</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage (explained in chapter 9).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Lungless</name>
      <text>Gand do not have lungs, and therefore do not need to breathe.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regenerative</name>
      <text>When you take damage, you can use your reaction and expend a Hit Die to regain health as long as the damage would not reduce your hit points to 0.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Gand. The Gand language does not use pronouns as Gand refer to themselves in the third person, so often Gand who speak Galactic Basic are difficult to understand.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Geonosian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d4"
Weight	60 lb.	x (2d4) lb..

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>You Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Constitution or Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Crafter</name>
      <text>Geonosian culture promotes artisanry. You have proficiency in one tool of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Exoskeleton</name>
      <text>You have a thick exoskeleton. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 12 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Flight</name>
      <text>You have a flying speed of 30 feet. To use this speed, you can't be wearing medium or heavy armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Geonosian Weaponry</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in simple blasters.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Geonosian. The Geonosian language conists of click consonants through use of a Geonosians' dual mandibles. This makes it difficult for other species to learn to speak it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Givin (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d8"
Weight	105 lb.	x2d4 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hardened Exterior</name>
      <text>You have a tough, bony exterior. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mathematical Savants</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (Technology) check involving mathematics, you are considered to have expertise in the Technology skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stargazer</name>
      <proficiency>Arcana, Religion</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Piloting* (Religion) and Technology* (Arcana).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Vacuum Sealed</name>
      <text>You can survive for one day within the vacuum of space. You still require oxygen to breathe. You have resistance to cold damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Givin. Givin is characterized by its use of mathematical jargon and symbols, making it nigh incomprehensible to the less mathematically inclined.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Gotal (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d10"
Weight	120 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and one other ability score of your choice increase by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Energy Sensors</name>
      <text>Gotals perceive the environment around them through use of electromagnetic sensors held in their cranial horns. You have blindsight out to 30 feet. If another trait would grant you blindsight, the range is increased by half as many feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hunter</name>
      <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in Survival.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Empathy</name>
      <text>Gotal's electromagnetic sensors allow them to sense the emotions in those around them. You have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to determine emotions against humanoids and beasts within 10 feet of you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Antarian. The Antarian language is characterized by growls and clicking noises at various volumes.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Gran (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'10"	+2d10"
Weight	115 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Slow Metabolism</name>
      <text>You are able to go a number of days without food equal to 3 + twice your Constitution modifier before suffering exhaustion.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Sight</name>
      <text>Through use of infrared vision, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Reader of Hearts</name>
      <proficiency>Insight</proficiency>
      <text>Through identifying subtle variations in a target's body heat, the Gran are able to better understand their emotions and intentions. You are proficient in the Insight skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Toughness</name>
      <text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Gran. It is rare to hear Gran spoken on any world other than Kinyen.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Gungan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d10"
Weight	115 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Martial Proficiency</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with light and medium armor as well as the vibrospear and vibropike.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Strong-Legged</name>
      <text>When you make a long jump, you can cover a number of feet up to twice your Strength score. When you make a high jump, you can leap a number of feet up into the air equal to 3 + twice your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Gungan. When speaking Galactic Basic, you often have trouble with word tenses and infinitives; this usually has a comical effect.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Half-Human (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Half-humans stand and weigh around the average of the two species' height and weight. Regardless of your position in that range, your size is the size of your non-human half.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is that of your non-human half.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Half-humans gain the ability score increases of their non-human half, but they can choose any ability score for one of the options, instead of the given option. Half-humans can not increase the same ability score twice during character creation using this feature.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Defiant</name>
      <text>Half-humans are known to be stubborn and often refuse to give up, even against the worst odds. When you or a creature you can see that can see and understand you makes an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, you can roll a d4 and add it to their roll (no action required). You can use this before or after the roll, but before the GM determines the roll's outcome. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Additional Trait</name>
      <text>Half-humans also gain the special traits from their non-human half, except for those trait (s) mentioned in the Half-Human table below.

(There was too much to put here, you can find the table at Star Wars 5e.com/characters/species/Half-human )</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic, regardless of whether or not the non-human half can speak it, and the language (s) associated with your non-human half.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Harch (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +1, Intelligence +1, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'5"	+2d8"
Weight	150 lbs.	x (2d4) lbs.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength, Intelligence, and Constitution scores increase by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Your fangs are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal 1d4 + your Strength modifier kinetic damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Six-Armed</name>
      <text>Harch have six arms which they can use independently of one another. You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your arms at any given time, and once per round you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spider Climb</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 30 feet. You have advantage on Strength saving throws and Strength (Athletics) checks that involve climbing, and while climbing you always have two hands free.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Venomous Fangs</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can make a special attack with your bite. If the attack hits, it deals its normal damage, and the target must make a Constitution saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save, the target is poisoned until the end of its next turn, and you can't use this feature again until you complete a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Harchese. Harchese is discernible from other insectoid languages by a noticeable emphasis on consonants, especially the "ch" sound.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Herglic (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	6'	+2d12"
Weight	200 lbs	x (2d8) lbs.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hold Breath</name>
      <text>You can hold your breath for up to 1 hour at a time.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <special>Powerful Build</special>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Technician</name>
      <proficiency>Arcana</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Technology* (Arcana) skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Toughness</name>
      <text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Herglese. Herglese has a clear and commanding cadence, drawing the attention of those who hear it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Human (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait>
      <name>Highly Adaptable </name>
      <text>Humans gain one bonus Feat at 1st level. To represent their highly adaptable nature.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Language - Galactic Basic</name>
      <text>Galactic Basic, is the common trade language, and the language used by all humans. It is also the official language of the empire.  As such some individuals go a whole lifetime without having to learn another language.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bonus Trained Skill</name>
      <text>Humans are versatile and accomplished at many tasks. A Human character chooses one additional Trained Skill at 1st level. The Skill must be chosen from the character's list of Class Skills.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Human Info</name>
      <text>Humans dominate the Core Worlds and can be found in virtually every corner of the galaxy. They are the ancestors of early spacefaring pioneers, conquerors, traders, travelers, and refugees. Humans have always been people on the move. As a result, they can be found on almost every inhabited planet. As a Species, Humans are physically, culturally, and politically diverse. Hardy or fine, light-skinned or dark, Humans remain one of the most dominant Species throughout all eras of play.

Human Characteristics

Personality: Human personality runs the gamut of possibilities, though members of this Species tend to be highly adaptable, tenacious, and willing to keep striving no matter the odds. They are flexible and ambitious, diverse in their tastes, morals, customs, and habits.

Average Height/Weight: A typical Human male stands at 5', 10" tall and weighs 165 lbs, while a typical Human female stands at 5', 2" tall and weighs 121 lbs.

Homeworlds: Various, including Coruscant, Corellia, Naboo, Tatooine, and Alderaan.

Example Names: Anakin, Arani, Bail, Ben, Biggs, Boba, Corran, Dack, Dan, Galak, Garm, Han, Jango, Jodo, Lando, Leia, Luke, Mace, Mara, Obi-Wan, Owen, Padm, Qui-Gon, Sia-Lan, Rann, Talon, Vor'en, Wedge, Winter.

Adventurers: Humans aren't afraid to try anything, and Human adventurers are the most audacious, daring, and ambitious members of an audacious, daring, and ambitious Species. A Human can earn glory by amassing power, wealth, and fame. More than any other Species, Humans champion causes rather than territories or groups.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Human (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'8"	+2d10"
Weight	110 lb.	x (2d4) lb..

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>One ability score of your choice increases by 2, and two different abilities of your choice increase by 1. Alternatively, four ability scores of of your choice each increase by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Defiant</name>
      <text>Humans are known to be stubborn and often refuse to give up, even against the worst odds. You can add a d4 to a skill check or saving throw, after rolling but before you know the outcome. You must then finish a short or long rest before you can use this feature again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in one skill, one tool, and one weapon of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and one extra language of your choice. Humans typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects. They are fond of sprinkling their speech with words borrowed from other tongues: trandoshan curses, twi'lek musical expressions, chiss military phrases, and so on.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Hutt, Adolescent (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and two other ability scores of your choice increase by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Closed Mind</name>
      <text>Hutt brains have an unusual composition which made them resistant to influence from the Force. You have advantage on Wisdom and Charisma saving throws against force powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Resistance</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage (explained in chapter 9).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <special>Powerful Build</special>
      <text>Your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift doubles. If it would already double, it instead triples.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Prehensile Tail</name>
      <text>Your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift doubles. If it would already double, it instead triples.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shrewd Demeanor</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in two Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma skills of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Slow and Lethargic</name>
      <text>Hutts are slow and generally incapable of moving quickly. You have disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws, and when determining your bonus to AC from your Dexterity, you can't add more than +3.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Wealthy</name>
      <text>During character creation, you start with additional credits equal to your level x your proficiency bonus x 1,000 cr.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Huttese. Hutts rarely speak Galactic Basic, even though they are perfectly able; if the person with whom they are speaking doesn't understand Huttese, they are more likely to use an interpretor than deign to speak the language of lesser species.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Iktotchi (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'11"	+2d10"
Weight	120 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Precognition</name>
      <text>You can see brief fragments of the future, that allow you to turn failures into successes. When you roll a 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Telepathy</name>
      <text>You can communicate telepathically with creatures within 30 feet of you. You must share a language with the target in order to communicate in this way.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Horns</name>
      <text>Your horns are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pilot</name>
      <proficiency>Religion</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Piloting* (Religion) skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>ou can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Iktotchese.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Ithorian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <spellAbility>Constitution</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'9"	+2d12"
Weight	135 lb.	x (2d4) lb..

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hold Breath</name>
      <text>Ithorians have a great lung capacity and can hold their breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sonic Resistance</name>
      <text>Ithorians have resistance to sonic damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sonic Scream</name>
      <text>You can use your action to violently expell air in a 15-foot cone. When you do so, each creature in the area of the exhalation must make a Wisdom saving throw. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier. A creature takes 2d6 sonic damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one. The damage increases to 4d6 at 5th level, 6d6 at 11th level, and 8d6 at 17th level. This ability has no effect on constructs.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and Ithorese . You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic, but your vocal cords do not allow you to speak it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Jawa (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	2'9"	+2d4"
Weight	35 lb.	x1 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Grovel, Cower, and Beg</name>
      <text>As an action on your turn, you can cower pathetically to distract nearby foes. Until the end of your next turn, your allies gain advantage on attack rolls against enemies within 10 feet of you that can see you. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tech Dabbler</name>
      <text>You know the ion blast at-will tech power. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the repair droid tech power once per day. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the hold droid tech power once per day. Intelligence is your techcasting ability for these powers. You do not require use of a wristpad for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Thieves</name>
      <proficiency>Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Sleight of Hand.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tinker</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with tinker's tools. You can use these and spend 1 hour and 100 cr worth of materials to construct a Tiny Device (AC 5, 1 hp). You can take the Use an Object action to have your device cause one of the following effects: create a small explosion, create a repeating loud noise for 1 minute, create smoke for 1 minute, cause a small electrical fire.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Jawaese. You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic, but your vocal cords do not allow you to speak it. Jawaese blends quickly spoken, semi-meaningless syllables with scents to be understood.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kage (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Animal Handler</name>
      <proficiency>Animal Handling</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in Animal Handling.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Athletic</name>
      <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Athletics skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Strong-legged</name>
      <text>When you make a long jump, you can cover a number of feet up to twice your Strength score. When you make a high jump, you can leap a number of feet up into the air equal to 3 + twice your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
      <text>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Superior Darkvision</name>
      <text>You've lived most of your life without direct sunlight. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unarmed Combatant</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Weapon Training</name>
      <text>Kage are adept warriors. You are proficient with the electroprod and electrostaff.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and one language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kaleesh (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'1"	+2d6"
Weight	105 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>The thermal pits under a Kaleesh's eyes grant darkvision. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Weapon Training</name>
      <text>Kaleesh are adept hunters. You are proficient with the blaster carbine, vibroblade, vibropike, and, vibrospear.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tracker</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Survival skill. Additionally, you are considered to have expertise in Wisdom (Survival) checks made to track a creature if that creature has a scent.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Kaleesh.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kaminoan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	6'4"	+2d10"
Weight	150 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2 and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Master Geneticists</name>
      <proficiency>Medicine</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Medicine skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ultraviolet Sight</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Wisdom (Perception) check related to sight, you are considered to have expertise in the Perception skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Long-Limbed</name>
      <text>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tech Dabbler</name>
      <text>You know the temporary boost at-will tech power. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the kolto pack tech power once per day. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the toxin purge tech power once per day. Intelligence is your techcasting ability for these powers. You do not require use of a wristpad for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Kaminoan. Kaminoan has a sound like flowing water to it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Karkarodon (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'8"	+2d10"
Weight	130 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aggressive</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Your fanged maw is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hungry Jaws</name>
      <text>In battle, you can throw yourself into a vicious feeding frenzy. As a bonus action, you can make a special attack with your bite. If the attack hits, it deals its normal damage, and you gain temporary hit points (minimum of 1) equal to your Constitution modifier, and you can't use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Karkaran. Karkaran is characterized by its fierce sounds.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kel Dor (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'6"	+2d12"
Weight	80 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your natural evolution allows you to see what others do not in dim and dark conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Foreign Biology</name>
      <text>You cannot breathe oxygen. The kel dors have created a breathing apparatus to negate the negative effects of living in an oxygen rich environment, but if your mask is removed while you are in such an environment, you lose consciousness.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Life in the Void</name>
      <text>You can survive for one hour within the vacuum of space. You have resistance to Necrotic damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Telepathy</name>
      <text>You can communicate telepathically with creatures within 30 feet of you. You must share a language with the target in order to communicate in this way.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Kel Dor.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Killik (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'9"	+2d10"
Weight	110 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Four-Armed</name>
      <text>Killiks have four arms which they can use independently of one another. You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your arms at any given time, and once per round you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hardened Carapace</name>
      <text>When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Strong-Legged</name>
      <text>When you make a long jump, you can cover a number of feet up to twice your Strength score. When you make a high jump, you can leap a number of feet up into the air equal to 3 + twice your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Telepathy</name>
      <text>You can communicate telepathically with creatures within 30 feet of you. You must share a language with the target in order to communicate in this way.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Killik. You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic, but your vocal cords do not allow you to speak it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Klatooinian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +1, Constitution +1, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Enforcer</name>
      <text>You are proficient in the Intimidation skill. When you take the Help action to give an ally advantage on an Intimidation check, they gain a bonus to the roll equal to your proficiency bonus.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Toughness</name>
      <text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Weapon Training</name>
      <text>Klatooinians are trained to fight from a young age. You have proficiency in two martial vibroweapons of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Wisdom of the Elders</name>
      <proficiency>History</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Lore skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic, Klatooinian, and Huttese. Klatooinian is a gutteral, barking language, with many loanwords adopted from Huttese over the centuries.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kubaz (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'7"	+2d10"
Weight	140 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Art Obsession</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an ability check related to the acquisition or location of art or valuables, you are considered proficient in the check. If you would already be proficient, you instead have expertise.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Deft Hand</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one of the following skills: Deception, Sleight of Hand, or Stealth.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Slicer</name>
      <proficiency>Arcana</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency with the Technology* (Arcana) skill and the slicer's kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
      <text>You wear protective eyewear, and if your goggles are removed while you are in an area of bright light, you have disadvantage on attack rolls and Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Kubazian. Kubazian is comprised of a unique series of whirring, nasally syllables, causing Kubaz to have a high-pitched accent when speaking other languages.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kushiban (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	2'11"	+2d4"
Weight	35 lb.	x1 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Grovel, Cower, and Beg</name>
      <text>As an action on your turn, you can cower pathetically to distract nearby foes. Until the end of your next turn, your allies gain advantage on attack rolls against enemies within 10 feet of you that can see you. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>You have a thick hide. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 12 + your Dexterity modifier. Additionally, your thick hide is naturally adapted to cold climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
      <text>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Nimble Agility</name>
      <text>Your reflexes and agility allow you to move with a burst of speed. When you move on your turn in combat, you can double your speed until the end of the tum. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you move 0 feet on one of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stealthy</name>
      <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Stealth skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Kushiban. Kushiban has a bubbly, joyful tone to it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kyuzo (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'9"	+2d8"
Weight	140 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your natural evolution allows you to see what others do not in dim and dark conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Foreign Biology</name>
      <text>Kyuzo struggle in atmospheres other than those of Phatrong. You wear a filter mask, and if your mask is removed while you are in such an environment, you lose consciousness.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Long-Limbed</name>
      <text>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Strong-Legged</name>
      <text>When you make a long jump, you can cover a number of feet up to twice your Strength score. When you make a high jump, you can leap a number of feet up into the air equal to 3 + twice your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Kyuzo. Kyuzo is characterized by short words and quick phrases. Kyuzo struggle with Galactic Basic as it is grammatically dissimilar to Kyuzo.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Lannik (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	3'0"	+2d8"
Weight	40 lb.	x1 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Attunement</name>
      <text>Lanniks have a natural attunement for the Force, which makes them resistant to its powers. You have advantage on saving throws against force powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Sensitive</name>
      <text>You know the *guidance* at-will force power. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the *valor* force power once per day. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the *force enlightenment* force power once per day. Wisdom is your forcecasting ability for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
      <text/>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Lasat (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	6'0"	+2d12"
Weight	160 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bo-rifle Training</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with blaster rifles and vibrostaffs.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Climbing</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Sight</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or sight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <special>Powerful Build</special>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Lasat, a language whose *r*'s are difficult to replicate by most other species.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Lurmen (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Healer</name>
      <proficiency>Medicine, Nature</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Medicine and Nature skills, and the bioanalysis kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Prehensile Tail and Feet</name>
      <text>You have supreme control over your tail and feet and can use them to manipulate objects as well as your hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rolling Agility</name>
      <text>As a lurmen, you can run on all fours, or curl into a ball, to move quickly along the ground. When you move on your turn in combat, you can double your speed until the end of the tum. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you move 0 feet on one of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Treeclimber</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 25 feet. You have advantage on Strength saving throws and Strength (Athletics) checks that involve climbing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Undersized</name>
      <text>Your small stature makes it hard for you to wield bigger weapons. You can't use heavy shields. Additionally, you can't use martial weapons with the two-handed property unless it also has the light property, and if a martial weapon has the versatile property, you can only wield it in two hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Lurmese. Lurmese is a name collectively given to the various tribal languages spoken by the lurmen people. While each language is distinct, shared phrases allow translation between dialects.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Miraluka (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'8"	+2d10"
Weight	110 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Sensitive</name>
      <text>You know the *mind trick* at-will force power. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the *sanctuary* force power once per day. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the *force confusion* power once per day. Wisdom or Charisma (your choice) is your forcecasting ability for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force Sight</name>
      <text>Miraluka perceive the environment around them through use of the Force. You are constantly under the effects of the force power *force sight*, though the power does not require concentration for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Miralukese.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Mirialan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'6"	+2d10"
Weight	100 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spiritual</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in Lore. Additionally, you are considered to have expertise in Intelligence (Lore* (History)) checks made to learn or recall something about a culture's religion.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Surprise Attack</name>
      <text>If you surprise a creature and hit it with an attack on your first turn in combat, the attack deals an extra 2d6 damage to it. You can use this trait only once per combat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unarmed Combatant</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Mirialan.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Mon Calamari (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'9"	+2d8"
Weight	100 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Intelligence or Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to life underwater, you have superior vision in low light conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mon Calamari Resistance</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against slow effects and you have resistance against cold damage (explained in chapter 9).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Musical</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one musical instrument of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic, Mon Cal, and one language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Mustafarian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Strength or Dexterity score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>As an originally cave-dwelling species, your eyes are adapted to the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>You have a thick hide. While you are unarmored or wearing light armor, your AC is 12 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Lava Dweller</name>
      <text>Your body is well accustomed to extreme heat, giving you resistance to fire damage. Additionally, your thick hide is naturally adapted to hot climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Refinery Specialist</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in your choice of constructor's implements, scavenging kit, or surveyor's implements. Additionally, whenever you make an Intelligence (Nature) check to identify a metal or mineral, you are considered to have expertise in the Nature skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Mustafarian. Mustafarian consists of choppy clicks and emphatic groans.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Muun (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'8"	+2d10"
Weight	145 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Finance Savvy</name>
      <text>Muun share a keen business sense and an ability to find value where others don't. Whenever you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check involving finances you are considered to have expertise in the Persuasion skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Long-Limbed</name>
      <text>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Three Hearts</name>
      <text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Muun. The Muuns' admiration of mathematics carries over into their language, which bares a striking resemblance to Binary.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Nautolan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	5'1"	+2d8"
Weight	120 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to life underwater, you have superior vision in low light conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Insightful</name>
      <text>Nautolan head tentacles are adept at determining moods. You have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to determine emotions.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Nautila. Nautila is unique in that it can only be properly pronounced underwater due to its use of pheromones in addition to spoken sounds. In any other environment, the language loses a great amount of detail; that Nautolans find this annoying.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Neimoidian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Grovel, Cower, and Beg</name>
      <text>As an action on your turn, you can cower pathetically to distract nearby foes. Until the end of your next turn, your allies gain advantage on attack rolls against enemies within 10 feet of you that can see you. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Smooth Talker</name>
      <proficiency>Deception, Persuasion</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Deception and Persuasion.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Wealthy</name>
      <text>During character creation, you start with additional credits equal to your level x your proficiency bonus x 1,000 cr.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Pak Pak. Pak Pak is often considered an elegant-sounding language by those who hear it. It consists of husky sighs and guttural ululations.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Noghri (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'5"	+2d6"
Weight	115 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hunter</name>
      <proficiency>Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in Survival and Stealth.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Leap</name>
      <text>If you jump at least 10 feet in a straight line before hitting with a melee weapon attack, you can attempt to shove the target prone as part of the same attack. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Strong-Legged</name>
      <text>When you make a long jump, you can cover a number of feet up to twice your Strength score. When you make a high jump, you can leap a number of feet up into the air equal to 3 + twice your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unarmed Combatant</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Honorghran. Honorghran is characterized by its scratchy, gutteral sounds.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Ortolan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	2'10"	+2d4"
Weight	50 lb.	x1 lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Foragers</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Wisdom (Survival) check to forage for food you are considered to have expertise in the Survival skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Grovel, Cower, and Beg</name>
      <text>As an action on your turn, you can cower pathetically to distract nearby foes. Until the end of your next turn, your allies gain advantage on attack rolls against enemies within 10 feet of you that can see you. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>Your thick hide is naturally adapted to cold climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that involve hearing or smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Musical</name>
      <proficiency>Performance</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Performance and one musical instrument of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Ortolan. Ortolan is characterized by its grunts and hoots.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Pa'lowick (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait>
      <name>Hold Breath</name>
      <text>Pa'lowick have a great lung capacity and can hold their breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Proud Performer</name>
      <text>Pa'lowick are best known for the energy they can bring to a singing performance. Whenever you make a Charisma (Performance) check involving singing, you are considered to have expertise in the Performance skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Snout</name>
      <text>You have supreme control over your snout and can use it to manipulate objects as well as your hands. Additionally, your snout is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal 1d4 + your Strength modifier kinetic damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sonic Scream</name>
      <text>As an action, you can violently expel air in a 15-foot cone. When you do so, each creature in the area of the exhalation must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). A creature takes 2d6 sonic damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one. The damage increases to 4d6 at 5th level, 6d6 at 11th level, and 8d6 at 17th level. This ability has no effect on constructs. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (a minimum of once). You regain one use of this feature when you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Lowickese. Lowickese requires the user to purse their lips and blow air, and is considered amusing by other species.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Pau'an (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Authoritative</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in Persuasion or Intimidation (your choice).

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cultured</name>
      <proficiency>History</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Lore skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hypersensitive Hearing</name>
      <text>Pau'ans possess incredibly receptive hearing, often to their detriment, so you wear special covers on your ears. Whenever you make a Wisdom (Perception) check involving hearing, you are considered to have expertise in the Perception skill, but if your hearing aids are removed, you have disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal sonic damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Vigilant</name>
      <text>You can choose to have advantage on your next Initiative check. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Utapese. Utapese is characterized by its rigid, yet melodic sound.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Pyke (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Long-Limbed</name>
      <text>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mercantile</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Deception, Persuasion, or Intimidation.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Notorious Slavers</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an ability check related to the buying, selling, or controlling of slaves, you are considered proficient in the check. If you would already be proficient, you instead have expertise.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spicer</name>
      <text>You are proficient in spicer's kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Pyke. The Pyke language is characterized by its multisyllable grunts.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Quarren (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'9"	+2d10"
Weight	105 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Climb</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ink Cloud</name>
      <text>You can use your action to expel ink in a 10-foot cone. When you do so, each creature in the area of the exhalation must make a Constitution saving throw. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier. On a failed save, a creature is blinded until the end of its next turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Quarrenese. The Quarrenese language is characterized by its garbled nature that evokes an image of speaking underwater.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Rakata (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Adaptive Resilience</name>
      <text>Prolongued use of technology allows rakata to readily adapt to its effects. You have advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws against tech powers.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cannibalize</name>
      <text>If you spend at least 1 minute devouring the corpse of a beast or humanoid, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Constitution modifier. Once you've used this feature, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Your claws are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a keen eyesight, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force-Insensitive</name>
      <text>While rakata can be manipulated by many force powers, they can not sense the Force. You can not use force powers or take levels in forcecasting classes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Technician</name>
      <proficiency>Arcana</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in the Technology skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Rakata. Rakata is characterized by its deep tones and simplistic nature, using mainly consonants and long vowels. It's script seems to be a very ancient form of Galactic Basic.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Rattataki (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Physical Characteristics</name>
      <text>Height	4'4"	+2d10"
Weight	90 lb.	x (2d4) lb.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Dexterity or Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Acrobatic</name>
      <proficiency>Acrobatics</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Acrobatics.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Intimidating</name>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Intimidation.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Surprise Attack</name>
      <text>If you surprise a creature and hit it with an attack on your first turn in combat, the attack deals an extra 2d6 damage to it. You can use this trait only once per combat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unarmed Combatant</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
      <text/>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Rattataki. Rattataki is known for have an inordinate amount of curses.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Rishii (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait>
      <name>Flight</name>
      <text>You have a flying speed of 30 feet. To use this speed, you can't be wearing medium or heavy armor.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Sight</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or sight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mimicry</name>
      <text>You can mimic sounds you have heard, including voices. A creature that hears the sounds you make can tell they are imitations with a successful Wisdom (Insight) check opposed by your Charisma (Deception) check.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Rishii. Rishii's clicks, trills, and whistles are difficult for outsiders to learn without the aid of a protocol droid, and so Rishii often feel comfortable speaking to eachother in the language in front of others.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Rodian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Adept Climbers</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 30 feet.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hunter</name>
      <proficiency>Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in Survival and Stealth.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that involve hearing or smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Rodese. Rodians can communicate with eachother using pheromones. Force-sensitives can detect this communication, though they can't understand it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Ryn (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence or Charisma score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Con Artist</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one gaming set of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Divination</name>
      <text>Whether through mystical divination or sheer luck, you can turn failures into successes. When you roll a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Eternal Nomads</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in Lore or Survival (your choice).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Musical</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in Performance and one musical instrument of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Prehensile Tail</name>
      <text>You have supreme control over your tail and can use it to manipulate objects as well as your hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Language</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Ryn. Ryn uses tones and inflections and is easily described as melodious by anyone who hears it. You can communicate with droids and other ryn without using words through the use of your beak.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Selkath (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Your claws are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls. Additionally, as a bonus action, you can perform a special claw attack. On a hit, the target suffers the attack's normal effects, and it must make a Constitution saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save, the target is poisoned until the end of its next turn, and you can't use this feature again until you complete a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gift of the Progenitor</name>
      <text>You know the temporary boost at-will tech power. When you reach 3rd level, you learn and can cast the kolto pack tech power once per day. When you reach 5th level, you learn and can cast the kolto cloud tech power once per day. Your techcasting ability is Intelligence. You do not require use of a wristpad for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Selkatha. Selkatha has a very moist and gurgling tone to it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Shistavanen (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Forced March</name>
      <text>Shistavanen are able to maintain a fast pace longer than other species. Shistavanen have advantage on Constitution saving throws made to avoid Exhaustion due to prolongued travel, as described in Chapter 8.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that involve hearing or smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regenerative</name>
      <text>When you take damage, you can use your reaction and expend a Hit Die to regain hit points as long as the damage would not reduce your hit points to 0.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tooth and Nail</name>
      <text>Your fangs and claws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Shistavanen. The Shistavanen language is characterized by its barks and growls.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Sith Pureblood (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Strength or Dexterity score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force-Sensitive</name>
      <text>You know the denounce at-will force power. When you reach 3rd level, you learn and can cast the curse force power once per long rest. When you reach 5th level, you learn and can cast the darkness force power once per long rest. Your forcecasting ability is Charisma for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sadistic</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with saberwhips, vibrowhips, and nets.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Sith. Sith is an agglutinative language, in which words or even phrases were made up of linears sequences of distinct meaningful units.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Squib (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Your sharp teeth are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Business Savvy</name>
      <text>A common trait of all Squibs is their desire and love of haggling. Squibs believe a deal is done when both sides believe they got the better of the other. Whenever you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check involving haggling you are considered to have expertise in the Persuasion skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Flexible Cheeks</name>
      <text>Squibs have flexible cheeks in which they can store small goods. You can store up to two items that weigh a combined total of no more than 2 lb. in your cheeks, and you have advantage on Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) checks made to conceal them.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>Your thick hide is naturally adapted to cold climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sensitive Fur</name>
      <text>Squibs' fur is exceptionally sensitive to physical details. You have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) checks that rely on touch.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Undersized</name>
      <text>Your small stature makes it hard for you to wield bigger weapons. You can't use heavy shields. Additionally, you can't use martial weapons with the two-handed property unless it also has the light property, and if a martial weapon has the versatile property, you can only wield it in two hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Squibbian. The Squibbian language originated as a secret form of communication for Squibs to convey information without being understood.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Ssi-Ruu (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>35</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Type</name>
      <text>Your creature type is both beast and humanoid.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Force-Insensitive</name>
      <text>While Ssi-ruuk can be manipulated by many force powers, they can not sense the Force. You can not use force powers or take levels in forcecasting classes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hunter</name>
      <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in Survival.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Empathy</name>
      <text>Ssi-ruuk have scent-tongues that let them read the emotions of individuals. You have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to determine emotions against humanoids and beasts within 10 feet of you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
      <text>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Thick Skin</name>
      <text>You have tough, scaly skin and prefer not to wear clothes. While you are unarmored or wearing light armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tooth and Nail</name>
      <text>Your fangs and claws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Ssi-ruuvi. Ssi-ruuvi is a language of musical whistles, honks and clicks, and is nigh impossible for humans and similar species to speak.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Sullustan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mercantile</name>
      <text>Whenever you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check related to conducting business, you are considered to have expertise in the Persuasion skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pilot</name>
      <proficiency>Religion</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Piloting.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic, Sullestese, and one more language of your choice. Sullestese is characterized as a robust language in business, and as such is commonly learned by professional merchants.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Talz (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>You have a thick hide. While you are unarmored or wearing light armor, your AC is 12 + your Dexterity modifier. Additionally, your thick hide is naturally adapted to cold climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Long-Limbed</name>
      <text>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Talzzi. You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic, but your vocal cords do not allow you to speak it. Talzzi is characterized by its high-pitched chirps and buzzes.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Tarasin (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +1, Intelligence +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Chameleon Skin</name>
      <text>Your scales are translucent, allowing your color-shifting skin to help you blend into your surroundings. You have proficiency in the Stealth skill. Additionally, you can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Jungle Dweller</name>
      <text>Growing up in the jungles of Cularin has left an impact. You don't treat jungle terrain as difficult terrain.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Naturalist</name>
      <proficiency>Nature</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Nature skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sa'tosin Sense</name>
      <text>Tarasins have short spines called sa'tosin that allow them to sense the use of the Force. You are constantly under the effects of the force power sense force, though the power does not require concentration for you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Tarasinese. You can communicate non-verbally with other tarasins through use of a complex system of skin color changes.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Tevetha (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Aggressive</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Arm Blades</name>
      <text>Your retractable dewclaws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Toughness</name>
      <text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mechanical Memory</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (Technology) check related to memorizing or duplicating mechanical readouts, you are considered to have expertise in the Technology skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Yevethan. Yevetha are able to speak other languages, but their isolationist nature makes them tend to reject the languages of other species. Only rarely would a Yevethan speak Galactic Basic, as this would often decrease their social standing.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Thisspiasian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Your claws are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cultured</name>
      <proficiency>History</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Lore skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Four-Armed</name>
      <text>Thisspiasians have four arms which they can use independently of one another. You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your arms at any given time, and once per round you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Inscrutable</name>
      <text>Your calm demeanor and control make you hard to read. Wisdom (Insight) checks made against you have disadvantage, and you have advantage on any saving throw against an effect that would read your thoughts.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Prehensile Tail</name>
      <text>You have supreme control over your tail and can use it to manipulate objects as well as your hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>Thisspiasians only require 2 hours of sleep a day. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Thisspiasian. Thisspiasian is a complex language characterized by its interlocking sentences and heavy use of sibilants.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Togorian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Dexterity or Constitution score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Togorians have retractable claws. You are proficient with your claws, which deal 1d6 kinetic damage on a hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Savage Attacks</name>
      <text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon's damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stealthy Hunter</name>
      <proficiency>Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Survival and Stealth skills.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Toughness</name>
      <text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Togorese. Togorese is characterized by its deep, resonating growls.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Togruta (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Strength or Dexterity score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Montral Reception</name>
      <text>You have tremorsense out to 30 feet. You can detect and pinpoint the origin of vibrations within a specific radius, provided that monster and the source of the vibrations are in contact with the same ground or substance. Tremorsense can't be used to detect flying or incorporeal creatures.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Wild Hunters</name>
      <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency with the Survival skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Togruti. Togruti is an ornate language characterized by trills and long vowel sounds which are modified by subtle tremors in the togruta's head-tails. This language is heavily influenced by Basic, but also incorporates some native idioms, which caused Basic-speaking togruta to use seemingly strange expressions.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Toydarian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Business Savvy</name>
      <text>A common trait of all Toydarians is their shrewd business sense and their ability to haggle any deal. A loyal and proud people, these traits could be off-putting to outsiders, as many Toydarians in the galaxy were seen as crooks or slimy businessmen, but this was not always the case. Whenever you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check involving haggling you are considered to have expertise in the Persuasion skill.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Closed Mind</name>
      <text>Toydarian brains have an unusual composition which made them resistant to influence from the Force. You have advantage on Wisdom and Charisma saving throws against force powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Flight</name>
      <text>You have a flying speed of 25 feet. To use this speed, you can't be wearing medium or heavy armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shrewd Demeanor</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in two Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma skills of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Undersized</name>
      <text>Your small stature makes it hard for you to wield bigger weapons. You can't use heavy shields. Additionally, you can't use martial weapons with the two-handed property unless it also has the light property, and if a martial weapon has the versatile property, you can only wield it in two hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic, Huttese, and Toydarian.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Trandoshan (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hold Breath</name>
      <text>You can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regenerative</name>
      <text>When you take damage, you can use your reaction and expend a Hit Die to regain hit points as long as the damage would not reduce your hit points to 0.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Saving Face</name>
      <text>Trandoshans are careful not to show weakness in front of their allies, for fear of losing status. If you miss with an attack roll or fail an ability check or a saving throw, you can gain a bonus to the roll equal to the number of allies you can see within 30 feet of you (maximum bonus of +5). Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Dosh. Dosh is characterized by its harsh grunts, hisses and growls, and its written form that used alphabetic glyphs.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Tusken (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Strength or Charisma score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aggressive</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Animal Handler</name>
      <proficiency>Animal Handling</proficiency>
      <text>You are proficient in Animal Handling.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Intimidating Roar</name>
      <text>Once per day, you can cast the fear force power. Charisma is your forcecasting ability for this power.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Survivors of the Sands</name>
      <text>You are proficient in Survival. Additionally, you don't treat desert terrain as difficult terrain. Lastly, you are naturally adapted to hot climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tusken Weaponry</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with the slugthrower and vibromace.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Tusken. Tusken is a guttural language characterized by its barks, growls, and roars. While Tuskens typically understand Galactic Basic, it is rare to hear them speak anything but Tusken.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Twi'lek (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Elegant Dancer</name>
      <proficiency>Performance</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency with the Performance skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Antitoxins</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison and disease, and you have resistance against poison damage (explained in Chapter 9).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unarmed Combatant</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Twi'leki. You can communicate non-verbally with other twi'leks through a complex language of subtle head-tail motions.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Ugnaught (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Your tusks are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Crafters</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one tool of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Industrial Hazards</name>
      <text>You have resistance to acid damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tech Dabbler</name>
      <text>You know the mending at-will tech power. When you reach 3rd level, you learn and can cast the analyze tech power once per day. When you reach 5th level, you learn and can cast the overheat tech power once per day. Your techcasting ability is Intelligence. You do not require use of a wristpad for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tinker</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with tinker's implements. You can use these and spend 1 hour and 100 cr worth of materials to construct a Tiny Device (AC 5, 1 hp). You can take the Use an Object action to have your device cause one of the following effects: create a small explosion, create a repeating loud noise for 1 minute, create smoke for 1 minute, cause harmless tremors for 1 minute. You can maintain a number of these devices up to your proficiency bonus at once, and a device stops functioning after 24 hours away from you. You can dismantle the device to reclaim the materials used to create it.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Undersized</name>
      <text>Your small stature makes it hard for you to wield bigger weapons. You can't use heavy shields. Additionally, you can't use martial weapons with the two-handed property unless it also has the light property, and if a martial weapon has the versatile property, you can only wield it in two hands.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Ugnaught. The Ugnaught language is composed of grunts, squeals, and chatters, and is difficult for other species to learn.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Umbaran (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Charisma or Wisdom score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Superior Darkvision</name>
      <text>You've lived most of your life without direct sunlight. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Umbaran Specialization</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one of the following skills: Insight, Technology, Deception, or Perception.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tech Dabbler</name>
      <text>You know the ward at-will tech power. When you reach 3rd level, you learn and can cast the analyze tech power once per day. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the infiltrate tech power once per day. Intelligence is your techcasting ability for these powers. You do not require use of a wristpad for these powers.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shadow People</name>
      <text>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by dim light.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
      <text>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Umbaran. Umbaran is characterized by its blending of technical jargon with informal language. It is rarely spoken off Umbara.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Verpine (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Crafters</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in one tool of your choice.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hardened Carapace</name>
      <text>While you are unarmored or wearing light armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tympanic Antennae</name>
      <text>You have tremorsense out to 30 feet. You can detect and pinpoint the origin of vibrations within that radius, provided that monster and the source of the vibrations are in contact with the same ground or substance. Tremorsense can't be used to detect flying or incorporeal creatures.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Verpine. You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic, but your vocal cords do not allow you to speak it. You can communicate with other Verpine at distances of up to a mile using your antennae.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Voss (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of grey.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Precognition</name>
      <text>You see brief visions of the future, that allow you to turn failures into successes. When you roll a 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mystic Healing</name>
      <proficiency>Medicine</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Medicine.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Voss Weapon Training</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with the blaster rifle and techblade.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Inscrutable</name>
      <text>Your calm demeanor and control make you hard to read. Wisdom (Insight) checks made against you have disadvantage, and you have advantage on any saving throw against an effect that would read your thoughts.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Voss. The Voss language is characterized by it's mystic-sounding word pairings.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Vurk (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>35</speed>
    <ability>Wisdom +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe air and water.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Athletic</name>
      <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Athletics skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to life underwater, you have superior vision in low light conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Head Crest</name>
      <text>Your head crest is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal 1d6 + your Strength modifier kinetic damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swim</name>
      <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Semblan. Semblan has a very melodic feel and often evokes images of waterfalls to those who don't understand its meanings.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Weequay (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Charming</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in Deception or Persuasion.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tanned</name>
      <text>You have tough, leathery skin. While you are unarmored or wearing light armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. Additionally, your thick hide is naturally adapted to hot climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Sriluurian. You can communicate with other Weequay within 30 feet without speaking through use of pheromones. Force attuned individuals can detect the communication but can't understand it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Wookie (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Wookiees have retractable claws. You are proficient with your claws, which deal 1d4 kinetic damage on a hit.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hide</name>
      <text>You have a thick hide. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. Additionally, your thick hide is naturally adapted to cold climates, as described in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <special>Powerful Build</special>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Treeclimber</name>
      <text>You have a climbing speed of 30 feet. You have advantage on Strength saving throws and Strength (Athletics) checks that involve climbing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Shyriiwook. You can understand spoken and written Galactic Basic, but your vocal cords do not allow you to speak it.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Yevetha (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Aggressive</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Arm Blades</name>
      <text>Your retractable dewclaws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal kinetic damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Toughness</name>
      <text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mechanical Memory</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (Technology) check related to memorizing or duplicating mechanical readouts, you are considered to have expertise in the Technology skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Yevethan. Yevetha are able to speak other languages, but their isolationist nature makes them tend to reject the languages of other species. Only rarely would a Yevethan speak Galactic Basic, as this would often decrease their social standing.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Zabrak (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Strength or Dexterity score increases by 1.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Coercive</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with Persuasion or Intimidation (your choice).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Crafters</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with with one set of artisan's implements of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Second Heart</name>
      <text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unarmed Combatant</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Zabraki.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Zeltron (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Charismatic</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with Deception or Persuasion (your choice).

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Enthralling Pheromones</name>
      <text>You can use your pheromones to influence individuals of both sexes. Whenever you roll a 1 on a Charisma (Persuasion) check, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll. Additionally, once per short or long rest, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower on a Charisma check as a 10. This feature has no effect on droids or constructs.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Empathy</name>
      <text>Zeltron's limited telepathy allow them to sense mood shifts in those around them. You have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to determine emotions against humanoids and beasts within 10 feet of you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Two-Livered</name>
      <text>Zeltron have two livers, which makes them adept at filtering toxins. You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage (explained in chapter 9).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and one language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Zygerrian (Star Wars 5e)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <trait>
      <name>Acrobatic</name>
      <proficiency>Acrobatics</proficiency>
      <text>You have proficiency in Acrobatics.

Source:	Star Wars 5e v0.9.1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 kinetic damage. You can use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have a cat's keen senses, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Notorious Slavers</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an ability check related to the buying, selling, or controlling of slaves, you are considered proficient in the check. If you would already be proficient, you instead have expertise.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Reputation for Cruelty</name>
      <text>You are proficient in Intimidation, as well as the saberwhip and vibrowhip.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Galactic Basic and Zygerrian. Zygerrian is characterized by its subtle growls and purrs.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
