<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Acolyte [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Religion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You devoted yourself to service in a temple, either nestled in a town or secluded in a sacred grove. There you performed rites in honor of a god or pantheon. You served under a priest and studied religion. Thanks to your priest's instruction and your own devotion, you also learned how to channel a modicum of divine power in service to your place of worship and the people who prayed there.

Source:	Player's Handbook 2024 p. 201</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Intelligence, Wisdom, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Magic Initiate (Cleric)</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Two Cantrips. You learn two cantrips of your choice from the Cleric, Druid, or Wizard spell list. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this feat's spells (choose when you select this feat).

Level 1 Spell. Choose a level 1 spell from the same list you selected for this feat's cantrips. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Spell Change. Whenever you gain a new level, you can replace one of the spells you chose for this feat with a different spell of the same level from the chosen spell list.

Repeatable. You can take this feat more than once, but you must choose a different spell list each time.

Source:	Player's Handbook 2024 p. 201</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Calligrapher's Supplies</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Calligrapher's Supplies, Book (prayers), Holy Symbol, Parchment (10 sheets), Robe, 8 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Criminal [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Sleight of Hand, Stealth</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You eked out a living in dark alleyways. cutting purses or burgling shops. Perhaps you were part of a small gang of like-minded wrongdoers who looked out for each other. Or maybe you were a lone wolf. fending for yourself against the local thieves' guild and more fearsome lawbreakers.

Source:	Player's Handbook 2024 p. 200</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Constitution, Intelligence</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Alert</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Initiative Proficiency. When you roll Initiative, you can add your Proficiency Bonus to the roll.

Initiative Swap. Immediately after you roll Initiative, you can swap your Initiative with the Initiative of one willing ally in the same combat. You can't make this swap if you or the ally has the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	Player's Handbook 2024 p. 200</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Thieves' Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) 2 Daggers, Thieves' Tools, Crowbar, 2 Pouches, Traveler's Clothes, 16 GP; or (B) SO GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Sage [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Arcana, History</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You spent your formative years traveling between manors and monasteries, performing various odd jobs and services in exchange for access to their libraries. You whiled away many a long evening studying books and scrolls, learning the lore of the multiverse- even the rudiments of magic- and your mind yearns for more.

Source:	Player's Handbook 2024 p. 201</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Constitution, Intelligence, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Magic Initiate (Wizard)</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

Two Cantrips. You learn two cantrips of your choice from the Cleric, Druid, or Wizard spell list. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this feat's spells (choose when you select this feat).

Level 1 Spell. Choose a level 1 spell from the same list you selected for this feat's cantrips. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Spell Change. Whenever you gain a new level, you can replace one of the spells you chose for this feat with a different spell of the same level from the chosen spell list.

Repeatable. You can take this feat more than once, but you must choose a different spell list each time.

Source:	Player's Handbook 2024 p. 201</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Calligrapher's Supplies</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or 8: (A) Quarterstaff, Calligrapher's Supplies, Book (history), Parchment (8 sheets), Robe, 8 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Soldier [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Athletics, Intimidation</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You began training for war as soon as you reached adulthood and carry precious few memories of life before you took up arms. Battle is in your blood. Sometimes you catch yourself reflexively performing the basic fighting exercises you learned first. Eventually, you put that training to use on the battlefield. protecting the realm by waging war.

Source:	Player's Handbook 2024 p. 201</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Dexterity, Constitution</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Savage Attacker</name>
      <text>You've trained to deal particularly damaging strikes. Once per turn when you hit a target with a weapon, you can roll the weapon's damage dice twice and use either roll against the target.

Source:	Player's Handbook 2024 p. 201</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Choose one kind of Gaming Set</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.

Gaming sets:
Set | Cost | Weight
Dice set | 1 sp | -
Dragonchess set | 1 gp | 1/2 lb
Playing card set | 5 sp | -
Three-Dragon Ante set | 1 gp | -</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Spear, Shortbow, 20 Arrows, Gaming Set (same as above), Healer's Kit, Quiver, Traveler's Clothes, 14 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
