<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Warlock</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Cloak (HB)</name>
        <text>Your patron ties a metal necklace inlaid with a small gem worth 100 gp to you. As an action, you can press this gem to conjure a black cloak that wraps around your body and gives off wisps of shadow as it moves. Choose an armor that you are proficient with and that is worth less than the gem. The cloak has the same statistics as that armor, but it weighs half as much and never imposes disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. The cloak remains until you dismiss it as an action.
	Using a 1 hour ritual, you can replace the inlaid gem with a more valuable one, allowing you to emulate more valuable armor.
	Magical armor cannot be replicated with the gem. While wearing other armor, you can conjure a weightless cloak that isn't considered armor, but grants the cloak's other benefits.
	While you wear the cloak, you can use a bonus action to pull mundane equipment, reconstructed with shadow magic, out from the cloak. You can summon any one of the following:

	• 20 pieces of ammunition of any type, in case or quiver.
	• ball bearings (bag of 1000)
	• block and tackle
	• caltrops (bag of 20)
	• 10 feet of chain
	• climber's kit
	• fishing tackle
	• hunting trap
	• lamp or lantern (with oil)
	• magnifying glass
	• manacles
	• mess kit
	• 50 feet of rope
	• spyglass
	• tinderbox
	• torches (3)
	• any type of artisan's tools
	• disguise kit
	• forgery kit
	• navigator's tools
	• thieves' tools

The DM might allow you to summon other equipment of similar usefulness. The equipment lasts until you dismiss it (no action required), or until you use this bonus action again. The equipment is visibly magical due to the wisps of shadow that emanate from the summoned objects.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Otherworldly Patron: The Archlich (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Otherworldly Patron: The Archlich (HB)</name>
        <text>You have made a pact with an archlich, a creature that has existed since the dawn of the last age and holds secrets of arcane magic that have been forgotten for thousands of years. Such a being desires only to expand its own power and influence, only using you as a pawn in its far larger scheme. Any lich powerful enough to form a pact has lived for many thousands of years, and many of them were involved in the invention of lichdom itself.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Expanded Spell List (The Archlich (HB))</name>
        <text>The Archlich lets you choose from an expanded list of spells
when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to
the warlock spell list for you.

Archlich Expanded Spells:
Spell Level | Spells
1st | inflict wounds, ray of sickness
2nd | blindness/deafness, Melf's acid arrow
3rd | lightning bolt, maim*
4th | fire shield, vitriolic sphere
5th | cone of cold, contagion

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Soulkeeper (The Archlich (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 1st level, you can force the souls of the dead to protect you from attack. Whenever a creature within 60 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to temporarily tether its soul to your body. Until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), your AC equals 12 + your Charisma modifier + your Dexterity modifier if you aren't wielding a shield. If you lose your concentration, the soul goes free and the bonus is lost.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Phylactery Ring (The Archlich (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, your patron grants you a magical ring that can serve to revive you from death. If you would be reduced to 0 hit points while you a have a soul tethered to you with your soulkeeper feature, the soul is first bound the ring, empowering it, before you fall unconscious. If you die while wearing the empowered ring, you are revived 24 hours later with 1 hit point, your body fully restored at the location of the ring. If you instead get up from unconsciousness, the soul is removed from the ring and re-tethers to your body.
	If you ever lose the ring, you can request your patron to grant you a replacement during a long rest.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Undying Flesh (The Archlich (HB))</name>
        <text>By 10th level, your body has taken on the attributes of undeath. You have resistance to necrotic damage, gain proficiency in Constitution saving throws, and you age at a slower rate. For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Souleater (The Archlich (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, you can consume the souls you've enslaved to heal yourself. When you lose concentration on your soulkeeper feature, you can choose to consume the soul, rather than freeing it. If you do so, you regain hit points equal to half your hit point maximum, and each creature of your choice within 10 feet of you becomes frightened of you until the end of your next turn.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Souleater</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Archlich (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Inflict Wounds</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ray of Sickness</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blindness/Deafness</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Melf's Acid Arrow</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Maim</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fire Shield</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Vitriolic Sphere</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cone of Cold</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contagion</name>
    <classes>Warlock (The Archlich (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Cloak of the Raven (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <time>1 Bonus Action</time>
    <text>Prerequisite: 15th level, Pact of the Cloak feature

You can use a bonus action on your turn to cause large, raven-like wings to sprout out of your cloak. While you wear the winged cloak, you gain a flying speed equal to your current speed. You can dismiss the wings using another bonus action.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Ghost-Iron Chains (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Chain feature

Your familiar becomes ghostly in appearance, and gains the ability to become incorporeal. Your familiar can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain, but if it ends its turn inside an object it is immediately dismissed to its pocket dimension.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Mantle of the Everlasting (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Cloak feature

You gain proficiency with medium and heavy armor.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: March of the Restless (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <text>Prerequisite: 5th level

You can cast animate dead using a warlock spell slot. You can do so twice, and regain both uses when you complete a long rest.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Mirror Blade (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature

When you conjure a one-handed weapon as your pact weapon and have nothing in your other hand, you can conjure a shadowy copy of the weapon in your other hand. You can perform two- weapon fighting with these weapons, even if the weapons aren't light, and you can perform the somatic components of spells while both your hands are wielding your pact weapons. While the second weapon counts as magical, it does not inherit any magical properties from the weapon it was copied from.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Pact of Blood (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <text>Prerequisite: 7th level

You can cast blood seal at will as a 2nd-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components. You still need to pay the hemomancy cost as normal.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Sanguine Seeker (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip

When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with eldritch blast, you can cause the beam to continue through the creature, taking on a crimson hue. Select a new target within range and make a ranged spell attack against it. That creature takes force damage equal to any excess damage left over from the previous attack, plus an additional 1d4 necrotic damage.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Necrotic Damage">1d4</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Tales of the Crimson Tome (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature

You can drop a pinch of humanoid blood into your book of shadows, and then ask one question aloud. Over the next minute, the blood manipulates itself into a language of your choice, answering your question in the process. The answer is provided using the knowledge of the humanoid that provided the blood, and is answered in less than 25 words. The blood must be from a living humanoid, and needs to be dropped into the book within a minute of it leaving the body.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Veil of the Night (HB)</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <text>Prerequisite: 9th level, Pact of the Cloak feature

When you are wearing your pact cloak, you can use your action to turn invisible until the start of your next turn. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>
