<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Ranger</name>
    <!-- Ranger Archetype: Nightstalker (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Nightstalker (HB)</name>
        <text>The Nightstalker archetype emulates a unique form of shadow magic, used to create shadowy familiars to accompany you in battle. By walking this path, you learn to use your shadow familiar like an extension of yourself, using them like a weapon as you stalk through the dim forests and vast plains of the world, searching for your prey. Your choice of familiar defines your style of fighting, with each familiar playing a different role on the hunt and on the battlefield.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shadow Familiar (Nightstalker (HB))</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to summon a creature of shadow to serve you. As a bonus action on your turn, you can conjure or dismiss your shadow familiar, which takes the form of a spectral creature that cannot be targeted or damaged. You choose the form you can create when you select this subclass.
	When you conjure your shadow familiar, it appears in an unoccupied space within 30 feet of you. As long as it is conjured, you can forgo one or more of your attacks when you use the Attack action to have your shadow familiar make attacks of its own, which use your Ranger spell attack modifier for their attack rolls, have a reach of 5 feet, and trigger any spells or features that would trigger from your own weapon attacks (such as Hunter's Mark). The familiar makes one melee weapon attack for each attack you forgo. While within 120 ft of your familiar, you can command it to move (no action required). The speeds and attacks of the three forms are listed below.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shadow Familiar: Cat (Nightstalker (HB))</name>
        <text>This form has a walking speed of 30 feet. On a hit, its attack deals 1d4 + your Wisdom modifier slashing damage, and causes the next attack made against the target by a creature other than you or the cat before the end of your next turn to be made at advantage.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Slashing Damage">1d4+%5</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shadow Familiar: Raven (Nightstalker (HB))</name>
        <text>This form has a flying speed of 90 feet, and a walking speed of 10 feet. On a hit, its attack deals 1d10 + your Wisdom modifier piercing damage.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d10+%5</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shadow Familiar: Wolf (Nightstalker (HB))</name>
        <text>This form has a walking speed of 40 feet. On a hit, its attack deals 1d6 + your Wisdom modifier piercing damage, and causes its target to have disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes before the end of its next turn.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d6+%5</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Nightstalker Magic (Nightstalker (HB))</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, based on the form you chose above, as shown in the Nightstalker Spells table. The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, but doesn't count against your spells known.

Nightstalker Spells:
Ranger Level | Cat Spells | Raven Spells | Wolf Spells
3rd | feather fall | thunderwave | cause fear
5th | invisibility | gust of wind | darkness
9th | haste | call lightning | fear
13th | greater invisibility | storm sphere | sickening radiance
17th | seeming | control winds | contagion

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shadowy Transposition (Nightstalker (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 7th level, whenever you cast a ranger spell of 1st level or higher, you can choose to swap locations with your familiar immediately before or after casting the spell.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Dark Sentinel (Nightstalker (HB))</name>
        <text>At 11th level, whenever a creature leaves the reach of your shadow familiar, you can use your reaction to have it make an attack against that creature. The disengage action and other effects that prevent opportunity attacks prevent this reaction.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Midnight Bulwark (Nightstalker (HB))</name>
        <text>Beginning at 15th level, whenever a creature within reach of your shadow familiar makes an attack against you, you can use your reaction to have the familiar make an attack against that creature.
	Additionally, whenever you command your familiar to make an attack using your reaction and the attack hits, the target's speed is reduced to 0 until the end of the target's current turn.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Feather Fall</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Thunderwave</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cause Fear</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invisibility</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Gust of Wind</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Darkness</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Haste</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Call Lightning</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fear</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Storm Sphere</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sickening Radiance</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Seeming</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Control Winds</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contagion</name>
    <classes>Ranger (Nightstalker (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
