<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Monk</name>
    <!-- Monastic Tradition: Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB)</name>
        <text>Monks of the Way of the Bloodied Fist follow a tradition that teaches them to control their own life force, as well as the life force of their foes. By focusing their ki, they exert control over blood — a powerful tool that is not to be underestimated. Their monasteries practice in secret in dark caves and high mountains, out of the eye of the common people, and their members only leave for the rare missions ordered by only the most desperate.
	Many monks of this tradition are covered in scars — some self-inflicted in their training, and others earned in battle. The monks often use their mystic energies to manipulate these scars, forming them into complex designs and symbols to represent their unique ki powers.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sanguine Arts (Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can use your ki to duplicate the effects of certain spells. As an action, you can spend 2 ki points to cast blackblood, blood seal, or sanguine rope as 2nd-level spells without providing material components. Additionally, you gain the bloodletting t cantrip if you don't already know it. You must still pay the hemomancy costs associated with each spell.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Toll of the Mystic (Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB))</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to convert your blood into a well of energy. Whenever you spend your ki points, you can choose to take necrotic damage equal to the number of ki points spent. This damage cannot be reduced through any means. If you take this damage, until the start of your next turn you gain a bonus to your speed equal to 10 times the damage taken.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Transfusion (Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB))</name>
        <text>Beginning at 11th level, whenever you hit a creature with one of the attacks granted by your Flurry of Blows, you regain 1d4 hit points, or 2d4 hit points if the attack was a critical hit.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Heal">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Heal">2d4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Dominion of Blood (Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB))</name>
        <text>At 17th level, you can take complete control of a creature by manipulating its blood. When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can spend 3 ki points to attempt to grasp control over that creature. The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or fall under your control. Constructs and elementals automatically succeed on this saving throw.
	On every subsequent turn after assuming control, you must use your action to take total and precise control of the target. To assert your control, you must be able to see the target and it must be within 120 feet of you. Until the end of your next turn, the creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn't do anything that you don't allow it to do. During this time, you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own reaction as well. If you do not take this action on your turn, the control ends prematurely. This control can last for up to 1 hour, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell).
	Each time the target takes damage, it makes a new Constitution saving throw against the effect. If the saving throw succeeds, the effect ends.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 14 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Blackblood (HB)</name>
    <classes>Monk (Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blood Seal (HB)</name>
    <classes>Monk (Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sanguine Rope (HB)</name>
    <classes>Monk (Way of the Bloodied Fist (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
