<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Bard</name>
    <!-- Bard College: College of the Shadowfell (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard College: College of the Shadowfell (HB)</name>
        <text>Bards of the College of the Shadowfell specialize in the study of that realm, gleaming great knowledge of shadow magic in the process. These bards are few in number and their study is far harder than most, for knowledge of the Shadowfell is hard to come by. These bards occasionally gather in great libraries to share their knowledge, but most of their time is spent out in the world, looking for any glimpses of knowledge that might lead them to their goal.
	These bards generally do not perform music, and are instead more inclined to creating stories and manufacturing histories, with most of these stories ending as dark as the realm they study.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (College of the Shadowfell (HB))</name>
        <text>When you join the College of the Shadowfell at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor, martial weapons, and the Stealth skill.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
        <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shadow Stride (College of the Shadowfell (HB))</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you can lace your words with shadow magic to grant an ally unnatural speed. When a creature that has a bardic inspiration die from you begins to move, it can choose to roll that die and add 5 times the number rolled to its speed until the end of its turn. For the same duration, every 2 feet of its movement in dim light or darkness only costs 1 foot of speed.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shroud of Darkness (College of the Shadowfell (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, whenever a creature rolls a bardic inspiration die from you, both you and that creature become imbued with shadow magic. Shadows envelop the two of you until the start of the roller's next turn, causing the first attack made against each of you during the duration to be made at disadvantage.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Umbral Body (College of the Shadowfell (HB))</name>
        <text>Beginning at 14th level, you gain the ability to transform into pure shadow. You can cast umbral form at will, without expending a spell slot or material components. When you cast the spell using this feature, you may only target yourself.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
