<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Rogue</name>
    <!-- Roguish Archetype: Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Roguish Archetype: Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB)</name>
        <text>Some rogues choose to delve into the intricacies of shadow magic, using its unique powers to enhance their skills in stealth and deception. These rogues are a very diverse subset, from simple thieves to hired killers to highly trained bounty hunters. By learning how to separate their shadow from their body, shadow rogues become difficult to catch and even harder to kill.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Cantrips (Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the umbraturgy cantrip and the dueling shadows cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Severed Shadow (Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can separate your shadow from your body, creating a shadowy replica of yourself and causing you to no longer cast a shadow. This replica is completely opaque and solid, and looks like a three-dimensional silhouette of yourself.
	As an action, you may separate your shadow and then move it up to 30 feet as part of the same action. The shadow shares your statistics, and can perform all movements that you would be able to, making ability checks for any movements that would normally require them, but it cannot take any actions. The shadow is susceptible to saving throws and attacks, including opportunity attacks, and it shares your AC. If it takes any damage, it instantly disappears. Your separated shadow can count as an enemy of a hostile creature for the purpose of granting sneak attack.
	On subsequent turns while you are separated from your shadow by less than 120 feet, you may move it another 30 feet (no action required). As a bonus action on your turn, you may choose to teleport to the location of your shadow, reuniting yourself with it. You can also reunite with your shadow by moving into its space.
	Once you teleport to your shadow, you can't teleport to it again until you complete a short or long rest.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Severed Shadow</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Deceiving Darkness (Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks if you are in dim light or darkness.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shadow Simulacrum (Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>At 13th level, you gain greater control over your shadow. When your shadow is separated from you, you can use your bonus action to have it perform the Help action, and your shadow can also manipulate objects weighing up to 25 pounds.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Master of Shadows (Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>When you reach 17th level, you have gained ultimate control over your shadow. When you sever your shadow, you can control its movement as long as it is within 500 feet, and you may use your bonus action to switch from using its senses to using your own, or back again. Additionally, you no longer have to complete a short or long rest before teleporting to it again.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 16 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Umbraturgy (HB)</name>
    <classes>Rogue (Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dueling Shadows (HB)</name>
    <classes>Rogue (Shadow (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
