<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Hobgoblin [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Hobgoblins are disciplined warriors with a deep connection to the Feywild, their ancient homeland. Though they have long since established themselves in the Material Plane, remnants of their fey ancestry linger in their culture and magic. Their societies are built on strict hierarchies, where honor, strategy, and unity are valued above all else. Hobgoblins thrive in structured environments, whether as mercenaries, soldiers, or adventurers, and they possess an innate ability to uplift their allies in times of need.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Persuasion</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Frightened condition on yourself.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Gift</name>
      <text>You can take the Help action as a bonus action. Additionally, once per long rest, when you use Fey Gift to help an ally, you can choose one of the following benefits to occur alongside the Help action:

	• Hospitality. You and the target each gain temporary hit points equal to 1d6 + your proficiency bonus.

	• Passage. You and the target each increase your walking speed by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.

	• Spite. The next time the target hits a creature with an attack, the creature has disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes before the start of its next turn.

At 3rd level, whenever you roll initiative, you regain all expended uses of this ability.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fortune of Many</name>
      <text>Once per turn, when you make a d20 test, you can gain a bonus to the roll equal to the number of allies within 10 feet of you (maximum bonus of +3).
	You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Hobgoblin, Koalinth/Sea [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <displayname>Koalinth</displayname>
    <ancestry>Hobgoblin</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Koalinths are the disciplined, amphibious kin of hobgoblins, adapted to life beneath the waves. Once exiled from their land-dwelling brethren, they forged their own empire in the depths of the sea, where their rigid martial traditions remain unchanged. Skilled warriors and tactical thinkers, Koalinths command the tides with the same calculated precision as their terrestrial cousins, making them formidable foes and invaluable allies in naval warfare.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft., Swim 30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Acrobatics</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Languages</name>
      <text>Goblin, Primordial (Aquan)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe both air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Martial Training</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency with all martial weapons.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Martial Advantage</name>
      <text>Once per turn, when you have advantage on a weapon or spell attack roll that deals damage, you deal additional damage equal to your proficiency bonus on a hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fortune of Many</name>
      <text>Once per turn, when you make a d20 test, you can gain a bonus to the roll equal to the number of allies within 10 feet of you (maximum bonus of +3).
	You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
