<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Lorwyn Expert [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Athletics, Nature</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You hail from Lorwyn, a land of eternal sunshine, or you have studied the place with great intensity. You consider the majestic creature Eirdu the living embodiment of the sun, and you love embarking on whimsical adventures. You hold your loved ones close, even if only emotionally, for you've seen some venture into Shadowmoor or beyond and become faded versions of themselves. You're nevertheless courageous and always long for new experiences.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Constitution, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Child of the Sun</name>
      <text>Eyes of Eirdu. You and allies within 10 feet of you have Advantage on saving throws made to avoid or end the Blinded condition.

Faerie Fire. You learn the Faerie Fire spell. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.
	When you cast Faerie Fire without a spell slot using this benefit, taking damage can't break your Concentration on the spell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Cartographer's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Quarterstaff, Cartographer's Tools, Backpack, Basket, Parchment (4 sheets), Rope, Traveler's Clothes, 29 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Shadowmoor Expert [2024]</name>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics, Deception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are from Shadowmoor or have studied it for years. It's a gloomy, chaotic place perpetually lit by pale moonlight. You might survive Shadowmoor's merciless conditions thanks to your wit and cunning, or you might keep threats at bay with your brawn and bravery. Regardless of where you tread, you keenly understand that friendship is a rare commodity. You believe that knowing who to trust and who to keep at arm's length isn't just practical—it's often a matter of life or death.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Intelligence, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Shadowmoor Hexer</name>
      <text>Hex. You always have the Hex spell prepared. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Curse Magic. When a creature that you've cursed with Hex hits you with an attack roll, the creature takes Psychic damage equal to your Proficiency Bonus. A creature takes this damage only once per turn.
      </text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Glassblower's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Dagger, Glassblower's Tools, Backpack, Hunting Trap, Lamp, Oil (3 flasks), Traveler's Clothes, Waterskin, 8 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
