<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Lorwyn Expert</name>
    <proficiency>Athletics, Nature</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You hail from Lorwyn, a land of eternal sunshine, or you have studied the place with great intensity. You consider the majestic creature Eirdu the living embodiment of the sun, and you love embarking on whimsical adventures. You hold your loved ones close, even if only emotionally, for you've seen some venture into Shadowmoor or beyond and become faded versions of themselves. You're nevertheless courageous and always long for new experiences.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Strength, Constitution, Wisdom</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Child of the Sun</name>
      <text>Eyes of Eirdu. You and allies within 10 feet of you have Advantage on saving throws made to avoid or end the Blinded condition.

Faerie Fire. You learn the Faerie Fire spell. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

When you cast Faerie Fire without a spell slot using this benefit, taking damage can't break your Concentration on the spell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Cartographer's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Quarterstaff, Cartographer's Tools, Backpack, Basket, Parchment (4 sheets), Rope, Traveler's Clothes, 29 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <background>
    <name>Shadowmoor Expert</name>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics, Deception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are from Shadowmoor or have studied it for years. It's a gloomy, chaotic place perpetually lit by pale moonlight. You might survive Shadowmoor's merciless conditions thanks to your wit and cunning, or you might keep threats at bay with your brawn and bravery. Regardless of where you tread, you keenly understand that friendship is a rare commodity. You believe that knowing who to trust and who to keep at arm's length isn't just practical—it's often a matter of life or death.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Dexterity, Intelligence, Charisma</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Shadowmoor Hexer</name>
      <text>Hex. You always have the Hex spell prepared. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Curse Magic. When a creature that you've cursed with Hex hits you with an attack roll, the creature takes Psychic damage equal to your Proficiency Bonus. A creature takes this damage only once per turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Glassblower's Tools</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) Dagger, Glassblower's Tools, Backpack, Hunting Trap, Lamp, Oil (3 flasks), Traveler's Clothes, Waterskin, 8 GP; or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Child of the Sun</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Eyes of Eirdu. You and allies within 10 feet of you have Advantage on saving throws made to avoid or end the Blinded condition.

Faerie Fire. You learn the Faerie Fire spell. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

When you cast Faerie Fire without a spell slot using this benefit, taking damage can't break your Concentration on the spell.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Shadowmoor Hexer</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

Hex. You always have the Hex spell prepared. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell (choose when you select this feat). You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have.

Curse Magic. When a creature that you've cursed with Hex hits you with an attack roll, the creature takes Psychic damage equal to your Proficiency Bonus. A creature takes this damage only once per turn.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
  </feat>
  <race>
    <name>Boggart</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Boggarts are Small, squat goblinoids found in the realm of Lorwyn-Shadowmoor. They possess bestial physical features, including horns and animal-like snouts. Beyond these commonalities, boggart appearances vary widely. One boggart may look like a hedgehog, with spiky fur and beady eyes, while another might sport the snout and fleshy ears of a swine. Boggarts tend to love crafting potions and commonly gravitate to specific areas of expertise, as noted in the sections below.

In Lorwyn

Boggarts in Lorwyn are born into communal warrens where laws and hierarchies are considered suggestions. The oldest and most powerful boggarts, known as "aunties," serve as respected leaders who keep the peace. Lorwyn boggarts value sharing knowledge and past experiences with their communities. Many are willing to brave great dangers in pursuit of new experiences, and adventurers are common.
Lorwyn boggarts also have a knack for magic. Boggarts who feel drawn to learning and using these natural affinities often become Druids. A Lorwyn boggart might alternatively find a calling as a Ranger, especially the Fey Wanderer subclass, or as a Wizard, especially the Diviner subclass, as boggarts have proven fond of ascertaining information through divination magic.


In Shadowmoor

Boggarts in Shadowmoor generally have sharper physical features than Lorwyn boggarts, including additional sets of horns. They are also known for body modifications, such as riveting armored plates to their flesh. Shadowmoor boggart society is chaotic and decentralized; their communities are few and likely to be found in isolated or dangerous environments. Aunties in Shadowmoor wander the lands, greeting those they meet with arbitrary tests, boons, or even curses.
Like their Lorwyn counterparts, Shadowmoor boggarts are drawn to magic. These boggarts might become Warlocks, particularly leaning toward the Archfey Patron subclass; some might believe their patron is Isilu. Others prove to be Sorcerers and are especially likely to manifest their power in the form of the Wild Magic Sorcery subclass.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>You are a Humanoid. You are also considered a goblinoid for any prerequisite or effect that requires you to be a goblinoid.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light and in darkness as if it were in dim light. You discern colors in that darkness only as shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the charmed condition on yourself.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fury of the Small</name>
      <text>When you damage a creature with an attack or a spell and the creature's size is larger than yours, you can cause the attack or spell to deal extra damage to the creature. The extra damage equals your proficiency bonus.

You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses when you finish a long rest, and you can use it no more than once per turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Nimble Escape</name>
      <text>You can take the Disengage or Hide action as a bonus action on each of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for your character.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Elf, Lorwyn</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Elves in the realm of Lorwyn-Shadowmoor possess black, pupilless eyes; curved horns; legs that end in cloven hooves; and pointed ears. The elves of Lorwyn exhibit stark differences physically as well as culturally from their Shadowmoor counterparts.
	  
In Lorwyn

The horns of Lorwyn elves are stubby like a goat's or curved like a ram's, but always ridged. Their pointed ears are long and slender.
In Lorwyn, elves value beauty above all, though what any given elf deems beautiful can seem arbitrary. Some Lorwyn elves assume authority over the land's other peoples, using their fallen empire to support their claims.
These elves blame the fall of their empire on outside threats, especially the Phyrexian invasion (see "Lorwyn-Shadowmoor's History"). Though the invasion was the empire's death knell, its people's self-importance and unwillingness to collaborate with other species had already led to the empire's decline.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 5-6 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 60 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Lorwyn Lineage</name>
      <text>You are part of a lineage that grants you supernatural abilities. You gain the level 1 benefit of that lineage.
	When you reach character levels 3 and 5, you learn a higher-level spell, as shown on the table. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.
	Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait (choose the ability when you select the lineage).

Lorwyn Lineage Spells:
Level | Spell
Level 1 | You know the Thorn Whip cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Druid spell list.
Level 3 | Command
Level 5 | Silence</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the charmed condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Keen Senses</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Insight, Perception, or Survival skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>You don't need to sleep, and magic can't put you to sleep. You can finish a Long Rest in 4 hours if you spend those hours in a trancelike meditation, during which you retain consciousness.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Elf, Shadowmoor</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Elves in the realm of Lorwyn-Shadowmoor possess black, pupilless eyes; curved horns; legs that end in cloven hooves; and pointed ears. The elves of Lorwyn exhibit stark differences physically as well as culturally from their Shadowmoor counterparts.

In Shadowmoor

Shadowmoor elves' horns are long, wavy, and covered with a rough, thorny texture. Their pointed ears are usually longer than those of their Lorwyn counterparts.
Like Lorwyn elves, Shadowmoor elves protect beauty, though a Shadowmoor elf's definition of "beautiful" can be abstract. Many of their kind believe beauty is gained or lost in accordance with one's actions; in particular, they consider heroism and self-sacrifice the highest forms of beauty.
Bloomseekers are Shadowmoor elves who study and explore Lorwyn. Each one carries a Reliquary of Twilight (see the introduction). Alongside Safewrights—Shadowmoor elves who venture across their realm in search of beautiful things—Bloomseekers are among the most trusted and revered members of their society.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 5-6 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 60 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Shadowmoor Lineage</name>
      <text>You are part of a lineage that grants you supernatural abilities. You gain the level 1 benefit of that lineage.
	When you reach character levels 3 and 5, you learn a higher-level spell, as shown on the table. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.
	Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait (choose the ability when you select the lineage).

Shadowmoor Lineage Spells:
Level | Spell
Level 1 | The range of your Darkvision increases to 120 feet. You also know the Starry Wisp cantrip.
Level 3 | Heroism
Level 5 | Gentle Repose</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the charmed condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Keen Senses</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Insight, Perception, or Survival skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>You don't need to sleep, and magic can't put you to sleep. You can finish a Long Rest in 4 hours if you spend those hours in a trancelike meditation, during which you retain consciousness.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Faerie</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Known for their mischief, faeries resemble insects with humanoid features. Their size and shape may vary, but all have antennae, black eyes, chitinous skin, and insectoid legs and wings. Every faerie is born from a flower and possesses innate magic, which many use to play pranks.

Some Lorwyn faeries serve Queen Oura, who has proclaimed herself the faeries' ruler. Not all faeries recognize Oura's authority, however. In Shadowmoor, faeries might instead worship Queen Maralen, the elf who overthrew the previous faerie queen and, some say, ushered in the clashing of Lorwyn and Shadowmoor.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fairy Magic</name>
      <text>You know the druidcraft cantrip. Starting at 3rd level, you can cast the faerie fire spell with this trait. Starting at 5th level, you can also cast the enlarge/reduce spell with this trait. Once you cast faerie fire or enlarge/reduce with this trait, you can't cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.

Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells when you cast them with this trait (choose when you select this race).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Flight</name>
      <text>Because of your wings, you have a flying speed equal to your walking speed. You can't use this flying speed if you're wearing medium or heavy armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Faerie Lineage</name>
      <text>As a native of either Lorwyn and Shadowmoor, you may gain additional traits.

Lorwyn. You go not gain any additional traits.

Shadowmoor. You have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for your character.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Flamekin</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Flamekin are people made from two key elements of creation: fire and stone. As a result, many flamekin feel a strong connection to the natural world. Flamekin's bodies radiate harmless magical flames, though they possess innate magic that allows them to create burning flames in a multitude of forms.

Flamekin view self-discovery and self-expression the noblest of aspirations and believe that self-realization is the most important thing an individual can do with their life. Flamekin call this lifelong pursuit the Path of Flame.

Flamekin dwell in either Lorwyn or Shadowmoor. Physically and culturally, they are similar in both lands.

Cinders
In Shadowmoor, some flamekin who have stifled their heated emotions are known as Cinders because their magical flames have dampened. Though they still have fiery abilities, these Cinders are visually distinct from other flamekin. While some eventually regain their blazing flames, others turn into rimekin, explained later in this chapter.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small or Medium</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light and in darkness as if it were dim light. You discern colors in that darkness only as shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fire Resistance</name>
      <text>You have resistance to fire damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Reach to the Blaze</name>
      <text>You know the produce flame cantrip. Starting at 3rd level, you can cast the burning hands spell with this trait. Starting at 5th level, you can also cast the flame blade spell with this trait, without a material component. Once you cast burning hands or flame blade with this trait, you can't cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.

Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells when you cast them with this trait (choose when you select this race).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for your character.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kithkin</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Kithkin are short folk with stout legs, long arms, and sturdy torsos. Their broad faces; round ears; and large, expressive eyes lend them a vaguely ursine appearance.

Most kithkin are linked by an empathic web that lets them sense the feelings of nearby kithkin. Because of this connection, many kithkin trust each other implicitly.

Some kithkin remove themselves from this empathic web temporarily or even permanently for a variety of reasons, often due to trauma suffered during the Phyrexian invasion (see "Lorwyn-Shadowmoor's History"). Regardless, kithkin typically believe that betraying their own is a heinous crime.

In Lorwyn
Lorwyn kithkin live in pastoral villages called clachans and welcome outsiders into their communities. These kithkin collect their cultural heritage in a tome called the Book of Kith and Kin. They also often entertain many superstitions, particularly related to Lorwyn's incarnations of nature.

In Shadowmoor
Shadowmoor kithkin are more insular and xenophobic. They mostly live in fortified settlements called douns, where strict customs to preserve the social order. Shadowmoor kithkin leaders keep a close eye on their communities, monitoring for any sign of crime or treason.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small (about 2-3 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Brave</name>
      <text>You have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Frightened condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Halfling Nimbleness</name>
      <text>You can move through the space of any creature that is a size larger than you, but you can't stop in the same space.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Luck</name>
      <text>When you roll a 1 on the d20 of a D20 Test, you can reroll the die, and you must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Naturally Stealthy</name>
      <text>You can take the Hide action even when you are obscured only by a creature that is at least one size larger than you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Kithkin Lineage</name>
      <text>As a native of either Lorwyn and Shadowmoor, you may gain additional traits.

Lorwyn. You go not gain any additional traits.

Shadowmoor. You have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Lorwyn Changeling</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The changelings of Lorwyn are charismatic shapeshifters able to crudely mimic the forms of creatures and plants. Unlike most shapeshifters, however, their innate powers don't allow them to truly disguise themselves; rather, their transformations are purely surface level.

No matter their form, Lorwyn changelings keep their key traits: blue-green skin, tufts of tentacle-like fur, and bulbous yellow eyes with slitted pupils. The true changeling identity of a bug-eyed tree, teal elk, or furry boulder is always easy to spot. These counterfeits are so plain that many Lorwyn denizens find the effect inexplicably charming.

Changelings from Lorwyn live in a vast, mystical cave called Velis Vel Grotto. Once per year, many changelings make a pilgrimage to the grotto to contemplate their past deeds.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 4-7 feet tall) or Small (about 2-4 feet tall), chosen when you select this species</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Shape Self</name>
      <text>As an action, you can reshape your body to a two-legged Humanoid shape or to a four-legged Beast shape. While you have a Humanoid shape, you can wear clothing and armor made for a Humanoid of your size.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Delightful Imitator</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Performance skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Unpredictable Movement</name>
      <text>When you roll Initiative and don't have Disadvantage on that roll, you can take the Dash action as a Reaction.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Rimekin</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Rimekin hail from both Lorwyn and Shadowmoor, though the first rimekin arose from flamekin during the Phyrexian invasion (see "Lorwyn-Shadowmoor's History" in the introduction). These flamekin approached their problems with cold logic and rejected reactionary responses. As a result, the magical flames that engulfed their bodies took on a frigid air, and they became rimekin.

Like flamekin, rimekin possess innate magic, but the flames they conjure burn icy blue rather than red hot. Further, these "flames" emanate a chilling cold rather than blazing heat. This effect extends, superficially, to the items rimekin touch. Any armor worn or weapons wielded by rimekin become coated in layers of spiky yet harmless hoarfrost.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 4-7 feet tall) or Small (about 2-4 feet tall), chosen when you select this species</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Cold Fire Magic</name>
      <text>You know the Ray of Frost cantrip. When you reach character levels 3 and 5, you learn the Ice Knife spell and the Flame Blade spell, respectively. You always have those spells prepared. You can cast each once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast these spells in this way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast Flame Blade using this trait, the spell deals Cold damage instead of Fire damage.

Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose the ability when you select this species).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Cold Resistance</name>
      <text>You have Resistance to Cold damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 60 feet.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <item>
    <name>Reliquary of Dawn</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>This talisman contains a discarded claw, scale, or fang from Eirdu, which many believe is the incarnation of the sun in Lorwyn. While you wear a Reliquary of Dawn, you are immune to the effects of Eventide.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Reliquary of Twilight</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>This talisman contains a discarded claw, scale, or fang from Isilu, which many believe is the incarnation of the moon in Shadowmoor. While you wear a Reliquary of Twilight, you are immune to the effects of Morningtide.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
  </item>
  <monster>
    <name>Lorwyn Giant</name>
    <sortname>Giant, Lorwyn</sortname>
    <ancestry>Giant</ancestry>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>giants</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>13</ac>
    <hp>115</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <init>1</init>
    <str>21</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>9</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>8</cha>
    <save>Wis +1, Con +1</save>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, Giant</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The giant makes two attacks, using Stone Sword or Boulder in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Stone Sword</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +8, reach 15 ft. Hit: 21 (3d10 + 5) Slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+8|3d10+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Boulder</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +8, range 60/240 ft. Hit: 14 (2d8 + 5) Bludgeoning damage. If the target is a Large or smaller creature, it has the Prone condition.</text>
      <attack>Boulder|+8|2d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Name Sleep (Recharge 5–6) (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The giant falls into a deep, restorative slumber. The giant gains 20 Temporary Hit Points and has the Unconscious condition until it takes damage or the end of its next turn. The giant has Advantage on ability checks and saving throws for 1 minute.</text>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</description>
    <environment>Planar (Feywild)</environment>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Shadowmoor Giant</name>
    <sortname>Giant, Shadowmoor</sortname>
    <ancestry>Giant</ancestry>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>giants</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <hp>172</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <init>2</init>
    <str>22</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>7</int>
    <wis>19</wis>
    <cha>8</cha>
    <save>Wis +1, Con +1</save>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Giant</languages>
    <cr>8</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The giant makes three attacks, using Tree Club or Boulder in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tree Club</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +9, reach 15 ft. Hit: 17 (2d10 + 6) Bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+9|2d10+6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Boulder</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +9, range 60/240 ft. Hit: 13 (2d6 + 6) Bludgeoning damage. If the target is a Large or smaller creature, it has the Prone condition.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+9|2d6+6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Wild Magic Cataclysm (Recharge 5–6)</name>
      <text>Dexterity Saving Throw: DC 15, each creature in a 20-foot-radius Sphere centered on a point within 120 feet. Failure: 28 (8d6) damage (roll 1d4 to determine damage type: 1—Acid; 2—Fire; 3—Lightning; 4—Thunder). Success: Half damage.</text>
      <attack>Damage||8d6</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</description>
    <environment>Planar (Feywild)</environment>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Incarnation of Transience</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>fey</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>16</ac>
    <hp>142</hp>
    <speed>40 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
    <init>8</init>
    <str>21</str>
    <dex>20</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>16</cha>
    <save>Dex +1, Con +1</save>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages>Sylvan, Telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>7</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune>grappled, paralyzed, petrified, prone, restrained</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ephemeral Movement</name>
      <text>The incarnation can move through other creatures and objects as if they were Difficult Terrain, and its movement doesn't provoke Opportunity Attacks. It takes 5 (1d10) Force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>The incarnation has Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The incarnation makes three attacks, using Bite or Miasmic Globule in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +8, reach 5 ft. Hit: 14 (2d8 + 5) Piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+8|2d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Miasmic Globule</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +8, range 60/120 ft. Hit: 15 (6d4) Acid damage, and the target's Speed is reduced by 10 feet until the end of the incarnation's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Acid Damage|+8|6d4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spectral Stampede</name>
      <text>The incarnation moves up to 80 feet in a straight line. Each creature whose space the incarnation enters is targeted once by the following effect. Dexterity Saving Throw: DC 16. Failure: 18 (4d8) Force damage. If the target is the incarnation's size or smaller, it has the Prone condition. Success: Half damage only.</text>
      <attack>Force Damage||4d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shape-Shift (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The incarnation changes its size to Medium, Large, or Huge.</text>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</description>
    <environment>Planar (Feywild)</environment>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Incarnation of Vibrance</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>fey</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <hp>230</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <init>7</init>
    <str>20</str>
    <dex>17</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>21</cha>
    <save>Con +1, Cha +1</save>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Sylvan, Telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>10</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>radiant</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune>blinded, charmed, deafened, frightened</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>The incarnation has Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The incarnation makes two Vine attacks and uses Radiant Blast. It can replace one vine attack with a use of Spellcasting to cast Blindness/Deafness if available.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The incarnation casts one of the following spells, requiring no spell components and using Charisma as the spellcasting ability:

	• At will: Daylight, Druidcraft, Plant Growth
	• 1/day: Blindness/Deafness</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Vine</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +9, reach 20 ft. Hit: 18 (3d8 + 5) Bludgeoning damage. If the target is the incarnation's size or smaller, it has the Grappled condition (escape DC 15) from one of two vines.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+9|3d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Radiant Blast</name>
      <text>Constitution Saving Throw: DC 17, each creature of the incarnation's choice in a 20-foot Emanation originating from the incarnation. Failure: The creature takes 14 (2d8 + 5) Radiant damage. Success: Half damage.</text>
      <attack>Radiant Damage||2d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shape-Shift (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The incarnation changes its size to Medium, Large, or Huge.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Teleport (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The incarnation teleports up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space it can see. The incarnation can't teleport while it has a creature Grappled.</text>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</description>
    <environment>Planar (Feywild)</environment>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Merrow Haranguer</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <hp>90</hp>
    <speed>5 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
    <init>4</init>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>18</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>19</cha>
    <save>Dex +1, Cha +1</save>
    <skill>Performance +1, Persuasion +1</skill>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages>Common, Primordial</languages>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>The merrow can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The merrow makes three attacks, using Coral Scepter and Poisoned Longbow in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Coral Scepter</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +7, reach 5 ft. Hit: 14 (2d10 + 4) Bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+7|2d10+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Poisoned Longbow</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +7, range 150/600 ft. Hit: 8 (1d8 + 4) Piercing damage plus 7 (2d6) Poison damage.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+7|1d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Invective</name>
      <text>Wisdom Saving Throw: DC 15, up to three creatures the merrow can see within 60 feet. Failure: 14 (4d6) Psychic damage, and the creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the end of the merrow's next turn. Success: Half damage only.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage||4d6</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</description>
    <environment>Planar (Feywild)</environment>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Merrow Doublespeaker</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Evil</alignment>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <hp>67</hp>
    <speed>20 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
    <init>3</init>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>17</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>16</cha>
    <save>Dex +1, Cha +1</save>
    <skill>Deception +1, Stealth +1</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Common, Primordial</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>The merrow can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mimicry</name>
      <text>The merrow can mimic voices and animal sounds. A creature that hears the mimicries can tell they are imitations with a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Insight) check.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The merrow makes three Spined Tail attacks. It can replace one of these attacks with a use of Spellcasting to cast Command.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The merrow casts one of the following spells, requiring no Material components and using Charisma as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 13):

	• At will: Command, Mage Hand, Minor Illusion</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spined Tail</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Attack Roll: +6, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft. Hit: 14 (3d6 + 4) Piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Piercing Damage|+6|3d6+4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</description>
    <environment>Planar (Feywild)</environment>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Noggle Ransacker</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>fey</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>12</ac>
    <hp>13</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>2</init>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>13</con>
    <int>8</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>12</cha>
    <skill>Stealth +1</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common, Sylvan</languages>
    <cr>1/4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Siege Monster</name>
      <text>The noggle deals double damage to objects and structures.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Sabotaging Swipe</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +4, reach 5 ft. Hit: 6 (1d8 + 2) Slashing damage. If the target is wearing armor, it is subjected to the following effect. Dexterity Saving Throw: DC 12. Failure: The armor takes a -1 penalty to the AC it offers. The target can take an action to remove the penalty from its armor.</text>
      <attack>Slashing Damage|+4|1d8+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Nimble Escape (Bonus Action)</name>
      <text>The noggle takes the Disengage or Hide action.</text>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</description>
    <environment>Planar (Feywild)</environment>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Noggle Wild Mage</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>fey</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>13</ac>
    <hp>22</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <init>3</init>
    <str>11</str>
    <dex>16</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>17</cha>
    <save>Con +1, Cha +1</save>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common, Sylvan</languages>
    <cr>1</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bloodied Wild Magic</name>
      <text>While Bloodied, the noggle has a Fly Speed of 30 feet and it can choose for any damage it deals to be Force damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The noggle makes two attacks, using Noggling Stick or Befuddling Ray in any combination.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Noggling Stick</name>
      <text>Melee Attack Roll: +5, reach 5 ft. Hit: 5 (1d4 + 3) Bludgeoning damage plus 2 (1d4) Psychic damage.</text>
      <attack>Bludgeoning Damage|+5|1d4+3</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Befuddling Ray</name>
      <text>Ranged Attack Roll: +5, range 60 ft. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) Psychic damage, and the target subtracts 1d4 from the next saving throw it makes before the end of the noggle's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Psychic Damage|+5|1d6+3</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</description>
    <environment>Planar (Feywild)</environment>
  </monster>
</compendium>
