<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Boggart [2024]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Boggarts are Small, squat goblinoids found in the realm of Lorwyn-Shadowmoor. They possess bestial physical features, including horns and animal-like snouts. Beyond these commonalities, boggart appearances vary widely. One boggart may look like a hedgehog, with spiky fur and beady eyes, while another might sport the snout and fleshy ears of a swine. Boggarts tend to love crafting potions and commonly gravitate to specific areas of expertise, as noted in the sections below.

In Lorwyn:
Boggarts in Lorwyn are born into communal warrens where laws and hierarchies are considered suggestions. The oldest and most powerful boggarts, known as "aunties," serve as respected leaders who keep the peace. Lorwyn boggarts value sharing knowledge and past experiences with their communities. Many are willing to brave great dangers in pursuit of new experiences, and adventurers are common.
	Lorwyn boggarts also have a knack for magic. Boggarts who feel drawn to learning and using these natural affinities often become Druids. A Lorwyn boggart might alternatively find a calling as a Ranger, especially the Fey Wanderer subclass, or as a Wizard, especially the Diviner subclass, as boggarts have proven fond of ascertaining information through divination magic.

In Shadowmoor:
Boggarts in Shadowmoor generally have sharper physical features than Lorwyn boggarts, including additional sets of horns. They are also known for body modifications, such as riveting armored plates to their flesh. Shadowmoor boggart society is chaotic and decentralized; their communities are few and likely to be found in isolated or dangerous environments. Aunties in Shadowmoor wander the lands, greeting those they meet with arbitrary tests, boons, or even curses.
	Like their Lorwyn counterparts, Shadowmoor boggarts are drawn to magic. These boggarts might become Warlocks, particularly leaning toward the Archfey Patron subclass; some might believe their patron is Isilu. Others prove to be Sorcerers and are especially likely to manifest their power in the form of the Wild Magic Sorcery subclass.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>You are a Humanoid. You are also considered a goblinoid for any prerequisite or effect that requires you to be a goblinoid.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light and in darkness as if it were in dim light. You discern colors in that darkness only as shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the charmed condition on yourself.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fury of the Small</name>
      <text>When you damage a creature with an attack or a spell and the creature's size is larger than yours, you can cause the attack or spell to deal extra damage to the creature. The extra damage equals your proficiency bonus.
	You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses when you finish a long rest, and you can use it no more than once per turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Nimble Escape</name>
      <text>You can take the Disengage or Hide action as a bonus action on each of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for your character.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Elf, Lorwyn [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Elves in the realm of Lorwyn-Shadowmoor possess black, pupil-less eyes; curved horns; legs that end in cloven hooves; and pointed ears. The elves of Lorwyn exhibit stark differences physically as well as culturally from their Shadowmoor counterparts.
	  
In Lorwyn:
The horns of Lorwyn elves are stubby like a goat's or curved like a ram's, but always ridged. Their pointed ears are long and slender.
	In Lorwyn, elves value beauty above all, though what any given elf deems beautiful can seem arbitrary. Some Lorwyn elves assume authority over the land's other peoples, using their fallen empire to support their claims.
	These elves blame the fall of their empire on outside threats, especially the Phyrexian invasion (see "Lorwyn-Shadowmoor's History"). Though the invasion was the empire's death knell, its people's self-importance and unwillingness to collaborate with other species had already led to the empire's decline.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 5-6 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 60 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Lorwyn Lineage</name>
      <text>You are part of a lineage that grants you supernatural abilities. You gain the level 1 benefit of that lineage.
	When you reach character levels 3 and 5, you learn a higher-level spell, as shown on the table. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.
	Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait (choose the ability when you select the lineage).

Lorwyn Lineage Spells:
Level | Spell
Level 1 | You know the Thorn Whip cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Druid spell list.
Level 3 | Command
Level 5 | Silence</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the charmed condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Keen Senses</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Insight, Perception, or Survival skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>You don't need to sleep, and magic can't put you to sleep. You can finish a Long Rest in 4 hours if you spend those hours in a trancelike meditation, during which you retain consciousness.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Elf, Shadowmoor [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Elves in the realm of Lorwyn-Shadowmoor possess black, pupil-less eyes; curved horns; legs that end in cloven hooves; and pointed ears. The elves of Lorwyn exhibit stark differences physically as well as culturally from their Shadowmoor counterparts.

In Shadowmoor:
Shadowmoor elves' horns are long, wavy, and covered with a rough, thorny texture. Their pointed ears are usually longer than those of their Lorwyn counterparts.
	Like Lorwyn elves, Shadowmoor elves protect beauty, though a Shadowmoor elf's definition of "beautiful" can be abstract. Many of their kind believe beauty is gained or lost in accordance with one's actions; in particular, they consider heroism and self-sacrifice the highest forms of beauty.
	Bloomseekers are Shadowmoor elves who study and explore Lorwyn. Each one carries a Reliquary of Twilight (see the introduction). Alongside Safewrights—Shadowmoor elves who venture across their realm in search of beautiful things—Bloomseekers are among the most trusted and revered members of their society.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 5-6 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 60 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Shadowmoor Lineage</name>
      <text>You are part of a lineage that grants you supernatural abilities. You gain the level 1 benefit of that lineage.
	When you reach character levels 3 and 5, you learn a higher-level spell, as shown on the table. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.
	Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait (choose the ability when you select the lineage).

Shadowmoor Lineage Spells:
Level | Spell
Level 1 | The range of your Darkvision increases to 120 feet. You also know the Starry Wisp cantrip.
Level 3 | Heroism
Level 5 | Gentle Repose</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the charmed condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Keen Senses</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Insight, Perception, or Survival skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>You don't need to sleep, and magic can't put you to sleep. You can finish a Long Rest in 4 hours if you spend those hours in a trancelike meditation, during which you retain consciousness.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Faerie, Lorwyn [2024]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Known for their mischief, faeries resemble insects with humanoid features. Their size and shape may vary, but all have antennae, black eyes, chitinous skin, and insectoid legs and wings. Every faerie is born from a flower and possesses innate magic, which many use to play pranks.
	Some Lorwyn faeries serve Queen Oura, who has proclaimed herself the faeries' ruler. Not all faeries recognize Oura's authority, however. In Shadowmoor, faeries might instead worship Queen Maralen, the elf who overthrew the previous faerie queen and, some say, ushered in the clashing of Lorwyn and Shadowmoor.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fairy Magic</name>
      <text>You know the druidcraft cantrip. Starting at 3rd level, you can cast the faerie fire spell with this trait. Starting at 5th level, you can also cast the enlarge/reduce spell with this trait. Once you cast faerie fire or enlarge/reduce with this trait, you can't cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.
	Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells when you cast them with this trait (choose when you select this race).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Flight</name>
      <text>Because of your wings, you have a flying speed equal to your walking speed. You can't use this flying speed if you're wearing medium or heavy armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for your character.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Faerie, Shadowmoor [2024]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Known for their mischief, faeries resemble insects with humanoid features. Their size and shape may vary, but all have antennae, black eyes, chitinous skin, and insectoid legs and wings. Every faerie is born from a flower and possesses innate magic, which many use to play pranks.
	Some Lorwyn faeries serve Queen Oura, who has proclaimed herself the faeries' ruler. Not all faeries recognize Oura's authority, however. In Shadowmoor, faeries might instead worship Queen Maralen, the elf who overthrew the previous faerie queen and, some say, ushered in the clashing of Lorwyn and Shadowmoor.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fairy Magic</name>
      <text>You know the druidcraft cantrip. Starting at 3rd level, you can cast the faerie fire spell with this trait. Starting at 5th level, you can also cast the enlarge/reduce spell with this trait. Once you cast faerie fire or enlarge/reduce with this trait, you can't cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.
	Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells when you cast them with this trait (choose when you select this race).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Flight</name>
      <text>Because of your wings, you have a flying speed equal to your walking speed. You can't use this flying speed if you're wearing medium or heavy armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for your character.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Flamekin [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <resist>fire</resist>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Flamekin are people made from two key elements of creation: fire and stone. As a result, many flamekin feel a strong connection to the natural world. Flamekin's bodies radiate harmless magical flames, though they possess innate magic that allows them to create burning flames in a multitude of forms.
	Flamekin view self-discovery and self-expression the noblest of aspirations and believe that self-realization is the most important thing an individual can do with their life. Flamekin call this lifelong pursuit the Path of Flame.
	Flamekin dwell in either Lorwyn or Shadowmoor. Physically and culturally, they are similar in both lands.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Cinders</name>
      <text>In Shadowmoor, some flamekin who have stifled their heated emotions are known as Cinders because their magical flames have dampened. Though they still have fiery abilities, these Cinders are visually distinct from other flamekin. While some eventually regain their blazing flames, others turn into rimekin.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small or Medium</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light and in darkness as if it were dim light. You discern colors in that darkness only as shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fire Resistance</name>
      <text>You have resistance to fire damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Reach to the Blaze</name>
      <text>You know the produce flame cantrip. Starting at 3rd level, you can cast the burning hands spell with this trait. Starting at 5th level, you can also cast the flame blade spell with this trait, without a material component. Once you cast burning hands or flame blade with this trait, you can't cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.
	Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells when you cast them with this trait (choose when you select this race).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for your character.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kithkin, Lorwyn [2024]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Kithkin are short folk with stout legs, long arms, and sturdy torsos. Their broad faces; round ears; and large, expressive eyes lend them a vaguely ursine appearance.
	Most kithkin are linked by an empathic web that lets them sense the feelings of nearby kithkin. Because of this connection, many kithkin trust each other implicitly.
	Some kithkin remove themselves from this empathic web temporarily or even permanently for a variety of reasons, often due to trauma suffered during the Phyrexian invasion (see "Lorwyn-Shadowmoor's History"). Regardless, kithkin typically believe that betraying their own is a heinous crime.

In Lorwyn:
Lorwyn kithkin live in pastoral villages called clachans and welcome outsiders into their communities. These kithkin collect their cultural heritage in a tome called the Book of Kith and Kin. They also often entertain many superstitions, particularly related to Lorwyn's incarnations of nature.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small (about 2-3 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Brave</name>
      <text>You have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Frightened condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Halfling Nimbleness</name>
      <text>You can move through the space of any creature that is a size larger than you, but you can't stop in the same space.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Luck</name>
      <text>When you roll a 1 on the d20 of a d20 Test, you can reroll the die, and you must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Naturally Stealthy</name>
      <text>You can take the Hide action even when you are obscured only by a creature that is at least one size larger than you.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kithkin, Shadowmoor [2024]</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Kithkin are short folk with stout legs, long arms, and sturdy torsos. Their broad faces; round ears; and large, expressive eyes lend them a vaguely ursine appearance.
	Most kithkin are linked by an empathic web that lets them sense the feelings of nearby kithkin. Because of this connection, many kithkin trust each other implicitly.
	Some kithkin remove themselves from this empathic web temporarily or even permanently for a variety of reasons, often due to trauma suffered during the Phyrexian invasion (see "Lorwyn-Shadowmoor's History"). Regardless, kithkin typically believe that betraying their own is a heinous crime.

In Shadowmoor
Shadowmoor kithkin are more insular and xenophobic. They mostly live in fortified settlements called douns, where strict customs to preserve the social order. Shadowmoor kithkin leaders keep a close eye on their communities, monitoring for any sign of crime or treason.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small (about 2-3 feet tall)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Brave</name>
      <text>You have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Frightened condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Halfling Nimbleness</name>
      <text>You can move through the space of any creature that is a size larger than you, but you can't stop in the same space.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Luck</name>
      <text>When you roll a 1 on the d20 of a D20 Test, you can reroll the die, and you must use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Naturally Stealthy</name>
      <text>You can take the Hide action even when you are obscured only by a creature that is at least one size larger than you.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Changeling, Lorwyn [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Performance</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The changelings of Lorwyn are charismatic shapeshifters able to crudely mimic the forms of creatures and plants. Unlike most shapeshifters, however, their innate powers don't allow them to truly disguise themselves; rather, their transformations are purely surface level.
	No matter their form, Lorwyn changelings keep their key traits: blue-green skin, tufts of tentacle-like fur, and bulbous yellow eyes with slitted pupils. The true changeling identity of a bug-eyed tree, teal elk, or furry boulder is always easy to spot. These counterfeits are so plain that many Lorwyn denizens find the effect inexplicably charming.
	Changelings from Lorwyn live in a vast, mystical cave called Velis Vel Grotto. Once per year, many changelings make a pilgrimage to the grotto to contemplate their past deeds.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 4-7 feet tall) or Small (about 2-4 feet tall), chosen when you select this species</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Shape Self</name>
      <text>As an action, you can reshape your body to a two-legged Humanoid shape or to a four-legged Beast shape. While you have a Humanoid shape, you can wear clothing and armor made for a Humanoid of your size.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Delightful Imitator</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Performance skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Unpredictable Movement</name>
      <text>When you roll Initiative and don't have Disadvantage on that roll, you can take the Dash action as a Reaction.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Rimekin [2024]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <resist>cold</resist>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Rimekin hail from both Lorwyn and Shadowmoor, though the first rimekin arose from flamekin during the Phyrexian invasion (see "Lorwyn-Shadowmoor's History" in the introduction). These flamekin approached their problems with cold logic and rejected reactionary responses. As a result, the magical flames that engulfed their bodies took on a frigid air, and they became rimekin.
	Like flamekin, rimekin possess innate magic, but the flames they conjure burn icy blue rather than red hot. Further, these "flames" emanate a chilling cold rather than blazing heat. This effect extends, superficially, to the items rimekin touch. Any armor worn or weapons wielded by rimekin become coated in layers of spiky yet harmless hoarfrost.

Source:	Lorwyn: First Light</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Humanoid</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 4-7 feet tall) or Small (about 2-4 feet tall), chosen when you select this species</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Cold Fire Magic</name>
      <text>You know the Ray of Frost cantrip. When you reach character levels 3 and 5, you learn the Ice Knife spell and the Flame Blade spell, respectively. You always have those spells prepared. You can cast each once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast these spells in this way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast Flame Blade using this trait, the spell deals Cold damage instead of Fire damage.
	Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose the ability when you select this species).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Cold Resistance</name>
      <text>You have Resistance to Cold damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 60 feet.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
