<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <monster>
    <name>Ancient Corpse Walker</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>undead (shapechanger)</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (Natural Armor)</ac>
    <hp>123 (13d10 + 52)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>19</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>19</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>9</cha>
    <save>Con +8, Wis +5</save>
    <skill>Persuasion +5</skill>
    <passive>15</passive>
    <languages>languages it knew in life</languages>
    <cr>10</cr>
    <exp>5900</exp>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren't silvered</resist>
    <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>exhaustion, poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cursed Gaze</name>
      <text>
A humanoid that starts its turn within 30 feet of and able to see the ancient corpse walker must succeed on a DC 16 Charisma saving throw, provided the corpse walker isn't incapacitated. On a failure, the humanoid is frightened for 1 minute. A frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, with disadvantage if not averting its eyes from the corpse walker, ending the effect on itself on a success. A creature failing two of these saving throws becomes cursed with disturbing thoughts. Such a creature can't benefit from a short or long rest until the curse is removed. On a successful save, the target is immune to any corpse walker's Cursed Gaze for the next 24 hours.

Unless surprised, a creature can avert its eyes to avoid the saving throw. If the creature does so, it can't see the corpse walker until the start of its next turn. A creature that looks at the corpse walker in the meantime must immediately make the save.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spore Calling</name>
      <text>
When the ancient corpse walker attacks, loyal undead within 120 feet of it come to its aid. Moderate or stronger wind can disperse these spores before they are effective.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spore Cloud</name>
      <text>
If the ancient corpse walker isn't in sunlight, it can use its action to polymorph into a Large cloud of spores or back into its true form. Anything it's wearing or carrying transforms with it. It reverts to its true form if it dies. In cloud form, the ancient corpse walker can't take any actions, speak, or manipulate objects. It's weightless, has a flying speed of 20 feet, can hover, and can enter a hostile creature's space and stop there. This cloud spreads around corners. If air can pass through a space, the cloud can do so without squeezing, but it can't pass through water. It has advantage on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws, except those against wind. The cloud form is immune to nonmagical damage other than that from sunlight.

A creature that starts its turn in the cloud must make a DC 16 Constitution saving throw. If the save fails, the creature takes 13 3d8 poison and 10 (3d6) necrotic damage and becomes poisoned until the start of its next turn. On a successful save, a creature takes half the damage and isn't poisoned.

After 24 hours, corpses of beasts or humanoids that were in the spore area rise as zombies loyal to the ancient corpse walker. If such a corpse is that of an evil humanoid, it instead rises as a corpse walker loyal to the ancient corpse walker. These spores can animate a corpse only once.</text>
      <attack>Spore Cloud||3d8</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||3d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spore Fortitude</name>
      <text>
If damage reduces the ancient corpse walker to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, the corpse walker drops to 1 hit point instead. When it drops to 0 hit points, the ancient corpse walker transforms into its Spore Cloud form. If it can't transform, it is destroyed. The spores of this cloud deal half their normal damage and can't animate corpses.

The ancient corpse walker can't transform back into its true form until it has at least 1 hit point. It must reach its preferred resting place within 2 hours or be destroyed. Once in its resting place, it reverts to its normal form.

It is then paralyzed and at 0 hit points for 1 hour, and then it regains 1 hit point and ceases being paralyzed.

If the ancient corpse walker takes damage while at 0 hit points, if able, it makes the same saving throw that would allow it to drop to 1 hit point. However, on a success, the ancient corpse walker remains at 0 hit points. If the ancient corpse walker fails or can't make this saving throw, it is destroyed.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Hypersensitivity</name>
      <text>
The ancient corpse walker takes 20 radiant damage when it starts its turn in sunlight. While in sunlight, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The ancient corpse walker makes two slam attacks</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Slam</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage and 10 (3d6) necrotic damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw, or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the necrotic damage taken, and the ancient corpse walker regains hit points equal to that amount. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0. A humanoid slain this way rises 24 hours later as a zombie, but it rises as a corpse walker if it was evil. These undead are loyal to the ancient corpse walker.</text>
      <attack>Slam|+8|2d6+4</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||3d6</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"They rose from their graves, some by force of magic, others cursed through their life's misdeeds. Whatever the reason, we can't let them walk among the living."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 104</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Angel of Empyreus</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>celestial</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>21 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>445 (33d10 + 264)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft., fly 90 ft.</speed>
    <str>29</str>
    <dex>23</dex>
    <con>26</con>
    <int>25</int>
    <wis>18</wis>
    <cha>30</cha>
    <save>Str +16, Int +14, Wis +111, Cha +17</save>
    <skill>Arcana +14, Insight +11, Intimidation +17, Investigation +14, Perception +11, Religion +14</skill>
    <passive>21</passive>
    <languages>all, telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>22</cr>
    <exp>41000</exp>
    <resist>fire, lightning, radiant; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>cold, necrotic, poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>blinded, charmed, deafened, exhaustion, frightened, poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>truesight 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+7</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Authoritative Mien</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus can cast the command spell at will (spell save DC 25).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Celestial Arsenal</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus' weapon attacks are magical. When it hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra 27 (6d8) radiant damage (included in the attack).</text>
      <attack>Celestial Arsenal||6d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Divine Awareness</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus knows if it hears a lie.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Holy Aura</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus can project a 60-ft. aura of holiness as a bonus action. The aura affects all creatures within its area unless the Angel of Empyreus chooses to exclude a creature from the effect. A creature remains under the aura's effect until it leaves the area, dies, or when the Angel of Empyrean chooses a new aura effect. Only one effect may be active at a time:

Judgement:
Creatures who start their turn in the aura must succeed on a DC 25 Charisma saving throw. On a failure, the creature gains a level of exhaustion as intensified feelings of guilt, doubt, remorse, and selfcriticism overwhelm the affected creature. Creatures who succeed on the saving throw are immune to the effect for one hour.

Valor:
Creatures who start their turn in the aura gain 15 temporary hit points, cannot be charmed or frightened, and have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus can make three attacks with its holy avenger.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Holy Avenger</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +24 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 23 (4d6 + 9) slashing damage plus 27 (6d8) radiant damage. If the target is a fiend or undead, it takes an additional 22 (4d10) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Holy Avenger|+24|3d6+9</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||6d8</attack>
      <attack>Fiend or Undead||4d10</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Blazing Radiance (Recharge 5-6).</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus unleashes holy fire in a 60-foot cone. Each creature in that area must succeed on a DC 25 Dexterity saving throw or take 35 10d6 fire and 35 (10d6) radiant damage. Creatures take half damage on a success.</text>
      <attack>Fire||10d6</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||10d6</attack>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <text>
The angel of empyreus can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. The angel of empyreus regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Fly</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus flies up to half its fly speed.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Sword</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus makes a holy avenger attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Hurl Sword (2 actions)</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus hurls its sword in a 30-foot line that is 5-feet wide. Each creature in that line must succeed on a DC 24 Dexterity saving throw or take 23 (4d6 + 9) slashing damage plus 27 (6d8) radiant damage. The sword immediately returns to its hand.</text>
      <attack>Hurl Sword||3d6+9</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||6d8</attack>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Recharge</name>
      <text>
The Angel of Empyreus recharges its Blazing Radiance.</text>
    </legendary>
    <spells>command</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>"I am that which can cleanse temptation from the land and restore it once more to divinity. What a weak creature of flesh you are, blessed with free will and fickle fancy. I will reveal your weakness, wretched mortal."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 104</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Avarice Seraph</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>celestial</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>17 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>199 (19d10 + 95)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft., fly 120 ft.</speed>
    <str>20</str>
    <dex>20</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>20</cha>
    <save>Con +10, Wis +8, Cha +10</save>
    <skill>Deception +10, Insight +8, Perception +9</skill>
    <passive>18</passive>
    <languages>all, telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>14</cr>
    <exp>11500</exp>
    <resist>radiant; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, frightened</conditionImmune>
    <senses>Truesight 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+5</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The seraph's spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 18). The seraph can innately cast the following spells, using only verbal components:

	• At will: detect evil and good, detect magic, invisibility (self only), light, minor illusion, thaumaturgy
	• 3/day each: identify, suggestion
	• 1/day: zone of truth</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The seraph has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Seraphic Weapons</name>
      <text>
The seraph's weapon attacks are magical. When the seraph hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra 4d8 radiant damage (included in the attack).</text>
      <attack>Seraphic Weapons||4d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The seraph makes three attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Scimitar</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d6 + 5) slashing damage, or 8 (1d6 + 5) slashing damage in Small or Medium form, and 18 (4d8) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Scimitar|+10|2d6+5</attack>
      <attack>Small||1d6+5</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||4d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Change Shape</name>
      <text>
The seraph magically polymorphs into a Small or Medium humanoid, into a Large giant, or back into its true form. Other than its size, its statistics are the same in each form. It's clothing and scimitars change size to match its new form. If the seraph dies, it reverts to its true form, and its equipment to its normal size.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Voice of Averice</name>
      <text>
he seraph presents objects of desire, which can be illusions the seraph creates, to creatures of its choice. If those creatures are within 60 feet of the seraph, able to see it and the desirable objects, and able to hear the seraph, the creatures must make a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or become charmed by the seraph until the seraph is incapacitated or fails to use a bonus action on its turn to continue to present and speak about the desirable objects.

While charmed in this way, a target can take no reactions and can use its action only to Dash. If the charmed target is more than 5 feet from the seraph, the target must move as far as it can toward the seraph, trying to come within 5 feet. The target avoids obvious danger, including opportunity attacks. If the target can't avoid such danger, the target can repeat the saving throw before entering the dangerous area. While an affected creature is within 5 feet of the seraph, the creature can't take reactions and spends its turns staring at the desirable objects.

The target also repeats the saving throw if the target is subjected to a harmful effect, if the target can't see or hear the seraph, and at the end of each of the target's turns. If a creature's saving throw is successful, the effect ends for it. A target that successfully saves is immune to the Voice of Avarice of this seraph or any lesser seraph for the next 24 hours.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>detect evil and good, detect magic, invisibility, light, minor illusion, thaumaturgy, identify, suggestion, zone of truth</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Don't go to the temple. Something sinister has claimed it. Seek shelter elsewhere."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 93</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Awakened Chapped Brute</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>126 (12d10 + 60)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>20</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>5</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>5</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Athletics +8</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Understands one language but can't speak</languages>
    <cr>7</cr>
    <exp>2900</exp>
    <resist>necrotic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>blinded</conditionImmune>
    <senses>blindsight 60 ft. (blind beyond this radius)</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>
The awakened chapped brute has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell. While deafened and unable to smell, the brute can't use its blindsight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sure-Footed</name>
      <text>
The awakened chapped brute has advantage on Strength and Dexterity saving throws made against effects that would knock it prone.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The awakened chapped brute makes two tentacle attacks or one tentacle slam.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tentacle</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 18 (3d8 + 5) bludgeoning damage. If the target is Medium or smaller, it is grappled (escape DC 16). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the brute can't use the tentacle against another target. The awakened chapped brute has two tentacles.</text>
      <attack>Tentacle|+8|3d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"The callused skin of the merchant's hulking bodyguard ripples as if something beneath is trying to wriggle free."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 68</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Beast Gnoll</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (gnoll)</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>11</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>13</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>11</con>
    <int>6</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Gnoll</languages>
    <cr>1/8</cr>
    <exp>25</exp>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rampage</name>
      <text>
When the beast gnoll reduces a creature to 0 hit points with a melee attack on its turn, the gnoll can take a bonus action to move up to half its speed and make a bite attack.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4 + 1) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+3|1d4+1</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6 + 1) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claws|+3|1d6+1</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spine Spike</name>
      <text>
Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4 + 1) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Spine Spike|+3|1d4+1</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"I never believed the rumors about the Beast and how it could change people. Then I saw how everyone at the logging camp had been transformed. It had to be a power even greater than a god's."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 60</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Bloodbonded</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (studded leather, shield)</ac>
    <hp>66 (12d8 + 12)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft. (or 10 ft. if missing a leg)</speed>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>13</con>
    <int>15</int>
    <wis>7</wis>
    <cha>18</cha>
    <save>Con +3, Wis +0</save>
    <skill>Deception +6, Insight +0, Persuasion +6</skill>
    <passive>8</passive>
    <languages>Celestial, Infernal, one national language</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <exp>1100</exp>
    <resist>necrotic, radiant</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable>psychic</vulnerable>
    <conditionImmune>charmed, frightened</conditionImmune>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bloody Inspiration</name>
      <text>
As a bonus action, the bloodbonded can inspire an ally within 30 feet to an enraged state of bloodlust for one minute. These followers gain 5 temporary hp, resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, and vulnerability to psychic damage. All attacks made by the bloodbonded followers are reckless, gaining advantage to hit enemies but granting enemies advantage on attacks against them.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Resolute Followers</name>
      <text>
Allies of the bloodbonded within 60 feet of it have advantage on Charisma and Wisdom saving throws.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Mace</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6 + 1) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Mace|+3|1d6+1</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Rage Bomb (2/Day)</name>
      <recharge>2/Day</recharge>
      <text>
As a bonus action, the bloodbonded can infuse one of its bloodbonded followers who is under the effects of Bloody Inspiration with a fatal fury. This magic causes the follower to foam bloodily at the mouth. If the follower is not slain before the start of the bloodbonded's next turn, the follower dies and explodes in a shower of superheated blood. Creatures within 10 feet must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw, taking 12 (2d8 + 3) fire damage on a failure and taking half damage on a success.</text>
      <attack>Rage Bomb||2d8+3</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Blood Boil</name>
      <text>
The bloodbonded targets a creature it can see within 60 feet and utters words of madness. The target must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or take 9 (2d8) fire damage as its blood superheats. The bloodbonded must be able to speak to use this ability.</text>
      <attack>Blood Boil||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Loyal Followers</name>
      <text>
When a bloodbonded would take damage from a melee or ranged attack it can see that targets only the bloodbonded, it can use its reaction to call on one of its followers within 5 feet to take the damage instead.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Those who've turned their back on both the Seraphs and the Daemons? That way lies madness."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 39</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Bone Trader</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>fey</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>12 (15 with bone armor)</ac>
    <hp>22 (5d8)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>11</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>18</cha>
    <save>Con +2</save>
    <skill>Animal Handling +4, Perception +4</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Sylvan, two other languages</languages>
    <cr>1</cr>
    <exp>200</exp>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>charmed</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Bone Armor (1/Day)</name>
      <recharge>1/Day</recharge>
      <text>
A bone trader in its lair can use a bonus action to summon a temporary suit of bone armor that lasts for ten minutes or until dismissed by the bone trader. While wearing its bone armor, a bone trader has advantage on Wisdom saving throws and Charisma (Intimidation) checks.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speak with Beasts</name>
      <text>
The bone trader can communicate with beasts as if they shared a language.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Bone Club</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 6 (1d8 + 2) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Bone Club|+4|1d8+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Skelesuck</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) piercing damage. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or have one of its bones sucked out, resulting in the piercing damage becoming a reduction in maximum hit points until magical healing is applied.</text>
      <attack>Skelesuck|+4|1d4+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Fey Charm</name>
      <text>
The bone trader targets one humanoid, goblinoid, fey, or beast it can see within 30 feet of it. The target must succeed on a DC 14 Wisdom saving throw or be magically charmed. The charmed creature regards the bone trader as a trusted friend to be heeded and protected. Although the target isn't under the bone trader's control, it takes the bone trader's requests or actions in the most favorable way . Each time the bone trader or its allies do anything harmful to the target, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success. Otherwise, the effect lasts 24 hours or until the bone trader dies, is on a different plane of existence from the target, or ends the effect as a bonus action. If a target's saving throw is successful, the target is immune to the bone trader's fey charm for the next 24 hours.

The bone trader can have no more than one humanoid charmed at a time, along with up to three beasts.</text>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Do you really need all of your bones? Are you sure I couldn't just snack on a few? I'll gladly pay you for them."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 13</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Candlelight Daemon</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>fiend</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>17 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>170 (20d8 + 80)</hp>
    <speed>walk 50 ft., fly 50 ft.</speed>
    <str>16</str>
    <dex>17</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>17</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Deception +7, Insight +6, Investigation +5, Perception +6, Stealth +7</skill>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>Infernal</languages>
    <cr>11</cr>
    <exp>7200</exp>
    <resist>cold, fire, lightning; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Candle Dependence</name>
      <text>
The daemon remains on the Material Plane only while the candle that summoned it burns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The daemon's spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 15, +7 to hit with spell attacks). The daemon can innately cast the following spells, requiring no components:

	• At will: detect magic, hunter sense, knock
	• 1/day each: counterspell, darkness, dispel magic, shield, suffocate</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The daemon has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Nether Step</name>
      <text>
As its movement for its turn, the candlelight daemon can teleport to an unoccupied space within 30 feet of it, provided the space it's teleporting to and from are both in dim light or darkness. The daemon doesn't need to see the destination.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shadow Stealth</name>
      <text>
While in dim light or darkness, the daemon can take the Hide action as a bonus action.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Slayer's Advantage</name>
      <text>
The candlelight daemon has advantage on attack rolls against any creature that hasn't had a turn in combat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Slayer's Attack (1/Turn)</name>
      <recharge>1/Turn</recharge>
      <text>
The candlelight daemon deals an extra 35 10d6 damage when it hits a target with an attack and has advantage on the attack roll. With the suffocate spell, the daemon deals this damage as extra bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Slayer's Attack||10d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The daemon makes two claw attacks and one gore attack. It can use hurl fire in place of any of these attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) slashing damage and 4 (1d8) fire damage.</text>
      <attack>Claw|+7|2d6+3</attack>
      <attack>Fire||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Gore</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d8 + 3) piercing damage and 4 (1d8) fire damage.</text>
      <attack>Gore|+7|2d8+3</attack>
      <attack>Fire||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Hurl Fire</name>
      <text>
Ranged Spell Attack: +7 to hit, range 120 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (3d8) fire damage.</text>
      <attack>Hurl Fire|+7|3d8</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>detect magic, hunter sense, knock, counterspell, darkness, dispel magic, shield, suffocate</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 25</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Caprathorn</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>fiend</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>19 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>250 (20d12 +120)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft., fly 40 ft. (hover)</speed>
    <str>25</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>23</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save>Int +9, Wis +10, Cha +7</save>
    <skill>Persuasion +10</skill>
    <passive>20</passive>
    <languages>all, telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>21</cr>
    <exp>33000</exp>
    <resist>cold, fire, lightning</resist>
    <immune>poison; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, frightened, poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>truesight 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+7</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Charge</name>
      <text>
If the caprathorn moves at least 20 feet straight toward a target, and then hits it with a gore attack on the same turn, the target takes an extra 18 (4d8) bludgeoning damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 22 Strength saving throw or be pushed up to 10 feet away and knocked prone.</text>
      <attack>Charge||4d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Implosion</name>
      <text>
The caprathorn implodes when it dies, leaving behind a sphere of annihilation. Each creature within 60 feet of the caprathorn when this implosion occurs must succeed on a DC 21 Strength saving throw or be pulled 10 feet toward the sphere.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/Day</recharge>
      <text>
If the caprathorn fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The caprathorn has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Weapons</name>
      <text>
The caprathorn's weapon attacks are magical.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Thornlamms</name>
      <text>
A caprathorn typically has three inanimate thornlamms (see that stat block) attached to its horns with vines. Attached thornlamms don't take damage separately, but whenever the caprathorn takes 50 or more damage in a single turn, one of the attached thornlamms dies.

While it has at least one thornlamm attached to its vines, the caprathorn can use a bonus action to consume or detach a thornlamm. If the caprathorn consumes a thornlamm, the caprathorn regains 21 hit points. When the caprathorn detaches a thornlamm, that thornlamm lands in a space within 10 feet of the caprathorn and takes a turn immediately after the caprathorn. The thornlamm obeys the caprathorn's verbal or telepathic commands (no action for the caprathorn). If issued no commands, the thornlamm acts independently, often attacking a creature that isn't its ally. A thornlamm can survive indefinitely detached from a caprathorn.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The caprathorn makes three attacks, one with its gore, one with its stomp, and one with its thorns.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Gore</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 25 (4d8 + 7) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Gore|+14|4d8+7</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Stomp</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 25 (4d8 + 7) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>&lt;stomp&gt;|+14|4d8+7</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Thorns</name>
      <text>
Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +14 to hit, reach 10 ft. or range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (4d6 + 7) piercing damage. Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn't cause the caprathorn to have disadvantage on the ranged attack roll.</text>
      <attack>Thorns|+14|4d6+7</attack>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <text>
The caprathorn can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. The caprathorn regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Attack</name>
      <text>
The caprathorn makes one attack with its gore, stomp, or thorns.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Detach Thornlamm</name>
      <text>
The caprathorn detaches a thornlamm as per the Thornlamms trait.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Grow Thornlamm</name>
      <text>
Provided it has taken no damage from a silvered weapon this round, the caprathorn grows one thornlamm as per the Thornlamms trait. A caprathorn can have up to six attached thornlamms at a time.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Consume Thornlamm (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
      <text>
The caprathorn consumes an attached thornlamm, regaining 21 hit points.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Entomb (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
      <text>
The caprathorn chooses a creature that has 0 hit points that the caprathorn can see within 30 feet of it. The target must make a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the target is immune to this effect for 24 hours. If the save fails, the target is entombed deep within the earth in a sphere of magical force that is just large enough to contain the target. Nothing can pass through the sphere, nor can any creature teleport or use planar travel to get into or out of it. A caprathorn can entomb only one target at a time. This effect ends, returning the target to where it was before being entombed, if the target regains any hit points or the caprathorn dies.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Annihilation Field (Costs 3 Actions; Recharges if an Entombed Creature Dies or after a Long Rest)</name>
      <text>
A sphere of energy ripples out in a 30-foot-radius from the caprathorn. Each creature in that area must make a DC 18 Constitution saving throw, taking 38 (7d10) force damage on a failed save, or half a s much damage on a successful one. For objects that aren't worn or carried, this emanation destroys Small and smaller ones and damages larger ones. The circle destroys a wall of force or similar structures of force in the area instantly. A creature or object is disintegrated if it drops to 0 hit points due to this magic. A disintegrated creature or object turns to fine ash, and nonmagical objects a disintegrated creature wears or carries disintegrate with it.</text>
      <attack>Annihilation Field||7d10</attack>
    </legendary>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"The temptation to aid a lost lamb should be tamped down when a thornlamm appears. Where there is one, there are many. And all lead back to a creature far more terrifying than any big, bad wolf."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 91</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Chapped Brute</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid</type>
    <alignment>Any Non-good Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>95 (10d8+50)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>7</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Athletics +6</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>understands one language but can't speak</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <exp>1100</exp>
    <resist>necrotic</resist>
    <immune>blinded</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 60 ft. (blind beyond this radius)</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing</name>
      <text>
The chapped brute has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing. While deafened, the brute can't use its blindsight.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The chapped brute makes two slam attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Slam</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Slam|+6|2d6+4</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"The callused skin of the merchant's hulking bodyguard ripples as if something beneath is trying to wriggle free."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 67</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Chapped Brute Abomination</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>161 (14d12 + 70)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>23</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>5</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>athletics +10</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>9</cr>
    <exp>5000</exp>
    <resist>Necrotic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Blinded, Prone</conditionImmune>
    <senses>blindsight 90 ft. (blind beyond this radius)</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Adaptive Hide</name>
      <text>
After taking damage, the chapped brute abomination gains resistance to that type of damage until it takes another type of damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>
The chapped brute abomination has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell. While deafened and unable to smell, the brute can't use its blindsight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unstable Life</name>
      <text>
At the start of the chapped brute abomination's turn, roll 1d20. The abomination regains hit points equal to any even result and loses hit points equal to any odd result. The abomination can neither exceed its hit point maximum with a gain nor fall below 1 hit point with a loss.</text>
      <attack>Unstable Life||1d20</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The chapped brute abomination makes two tentacle attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tentacle</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 22 (3d10 + 6) bludgeoning damage. If the target is Medium or smaller, it is grappled (escape DC 18). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the brute can't use the tentacle against another target. The chapped brute abomination has four tentacles.</text>
      <attack>Tentacle|+10|3d10+6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Engulf</name>
      <text>
Each creature grappled by the chapped brute abomination must succeed on a DC 18 Strength saving throw or be pulled into the brute's body. An engulfed target is blinded, restrained, unable to breathe, and has total cover from effects that originate outside the brute. At the start of each of the brute's turns, each engulfed creature takes 14 (4d6) acid damage. The brute can hold only one Large creature or up to four Medium or smaller creatures inside it at a time.

An engulfed creature can try to escape by taking an action to make its choice of a DC 18 Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. On a success, the creature escapes and uses 10 feet of movement to enter a space of its choice within 5 feet of the brute.

If the brute dies, an engulfed creature is no longer restrained by it and can escape from the corpse by using 10 feet of movement.

If a creature dies inside the brute, the brute doesn't roll for Unstable Life at the start of its next turn and instead regains 20 hit points. The creature's body breaks up inside the brute, and the brute expels anything the creature wore or carried.</text>
      <attack>Engulf||4d6</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"The callused skin of the merchant's hulking bodyguard ripples as if something beneath is trying to wriggle free."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 68</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Corpse Walker</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>undead</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>82 (11d8 + 33)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>16</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>6</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <save>con +6, wis +3</save>
    <skill/>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>understands languages it knew in life but can't speak</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <exp>2300</exp>
    <resist>bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks that aren't silvered</resist>
    <immune>Necrotic, Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cursed Gaze</name>
      <text>
A humanoid that starts its turn within 30 ft. of and able to see the corpse walker must succeed on a DC 14 Charisma saving throw, provided the corpse walker isn't incapacitated. On a failure, the humanoid is frightened for 1 minute. A frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, with disadvantage if not averting its eyes from the corpse walker, ending the effect on itself on a success. A creature failing two of these saving throws becomes cursed with disturbing thoughts. Such a creature can't benefit from a short or long rest until the curse is removed. On a successful save, the target is immune to any corpse walker's Cursed Gaze for the next 24 hours.

Unless surprised, a creature can avert its eyes to avoid the saving throw. If the creature does so, it can't see the corpse walker until the start of its next turn. A creature that looks at the corpse walker in the meantime must immediately make the save.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Hypersensitivity</name>
      <text>
The corpse walker takes 20 radiant damage when it starts its turn in sunlight. While in sunlight, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Undead Fortitude</name>
      <text>
If damage reduces the corpse walker to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, the corpse walker drops to 1 hit point instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The corpse walker makes two slam attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Slam</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage and 5 (2d4) necrotic damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw, or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the necrotic damage taken, and the corpse walker regains hit points equal to that amount. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0. An evil humanoid slain this way rises 24 hours later as a corpse walker.</text>
      <attack>Slam|+6|1d6+4</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||2d4</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"They rose from their graves, some by force of magic, others cursed through their life's misdeeds. Whatever the reason, we can't let them walk among the living."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 103</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Corpsejaw</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>12</ac>
    <hp>18 (4d8)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>15</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>1/4</cr>
    <exp>50</exp>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Adamantine Jaws</name>
      <text>
The corpsejaw's bite works as if made of adamantine. The bite scores a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>
The corpsejaw has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pounce</name>
      <text>
If the corpsejaw moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a claw attack on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 12 Strength saving throw or fall prone. If the target is prone, the corpsejaw can make one bite attack against it as a bonus action.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8 + 2) piercing damage. If the corpsejaw scores a critical hit and the target wears nonmagical armor, the armor takes a permanent and cumulative -1 penalty to the AC it offers. Armor reduced to an AC of 10 is destroyed.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+4|1d8+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claw|+4|1d4+2</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>Cousins to mountain lions, corpsejaws are battlefield scavengers. Their powerful jaws allow them to tear through most armor, so they can eat carrion other scavengers leave behind. Military organizations such as the Free Swords issue bounties on corpsejaws to prevent damage to valuable salvage.

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 92</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Dawndrinker</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>114 (12d10 + 48)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>19</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>11</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>stealth +5</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <exp>1800</exp>
    <resist>Fire</resist>
    <immune>Radiant</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 120 ft., darkvision 240 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Drink Light</name>
      <text>
The dawndrinker can take a bonus action to drink light within 30 feet of it. If it does so, nonmagical light sources in this area go out, extinguishing any flames that are the source of the light. Provided the light comes from an effect of 3rd level or lower, or a creature of CR 7 or lower, magical bright light becomes dim light, and magical dim light goes out. If a magical effect's light is extinguished, the effect is dispelled. A creature's or object's inherent light returns to normal after 1 minute. The dawndrinker can dim or extinguish stronger effects by succeeding on a Constitution check with a DC of 10 + the effect's level or 5 + the creator's CR, whichever is lower.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Light Sense</name>
      <text>
The dawndrinker can sense any light source within 120 feet of it. This sense penetrates most barriers, but it is blocked by 3 feet of wood or dirt, 1 foot of stone, or 1 inch of metal.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Radiant Absorption</name>
      <text>
Whenever the dawndrinker is subjected to radiant damage, it takes no damage and instead regains hit points equal to the radiant damage dealt.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shadow Cunning</name>
      <text>
In dim light or darkness, the dawndrinker can take a bonus action to use the Disengage or Hide actions.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The dawndrinker makes two slam attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Slam</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8 + 4) bludgeoning damage and 7 (2d6) cold damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the end of the dawndrinker's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Slam|+7|1d8+4</attack>
      <attack>Cold||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Sometimes it's darkest after the dawn."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 49</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Doomcaller</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>fiend</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>150 (20d8 + 60)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft., fly 40 ft. (hover)</speed>
    <str>8</str>
    <dex>17</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>21</cha>
    <save>con +8, int +7, wis +6, cha +10</save>
    <skill>arcana +7, deception +10, insight +6, perception +6, persuasion +10, religion +7</skill>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>all</languages>
    <cr>15</cr>
    <exp>13000</exp>
    <resist>Cold, Fire, Lightning, bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>Acid, Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+5</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The doomcaller has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The doomcaller is an 18th-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 18, +10 to hit with spell attacks). It has the following spells prepared:

	• Cantrips (at will): fire bolt, hunter sense, message, shocking grasp, true strike
	• 1st level (4 slots): detect magic, magic missile, shield
	• 2nd level (3 slots): detect thoughts, misty step
	• 3rd level (3 slots): bestow curse, fireball
	• 4th level (3 slots): banishment, consume mind
	• 5th level (3 slots): magic mirror, scrying
	• 6th level (1 slot): disintegrate
	• 7th level (1 slot): arboreal curse
	• 8th level (1 slot): mind blank *
	• 9th level (1 slot): gate

*The doomcaller casts this spell on itself before combat.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Slam</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) bludgeoning damage, and the target has disadvantage on their next attack roll. Additionally, all attacks against the target by allies of the doomcaller are made with advantage until the start of the doomcaller's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Slam|+8|2d6+3</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Summon Fiend (1/Day)</name>
      <recharge>1/Day</recharge>
      <text>
The doomcaller chooses what to summon and attempts a magical summoning. A doomcaller has a 60 percent chance of summoning 1d6 succubi or 1d4 barbed devils. A summoned fiend appears in an unoccupied space within 60 feet of its summoner, does as it pleases, and can't summon other fiends. The summoned fiend remains for 1 minute, until it or its summoner dies, or until its summoner takes a bonus action to dismiss it.</text>
      <attack>Succubi||1d6</attack>
      <attack>Barbed Devils||1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Ill Fortune (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/Day</recharge>
      <text>
When a creature the doomcaller can see makes an attack roll, a saving throw, or an ability check, the doomcaller can roll a d20 and choose to use this roll in place of the attack roll, saving throw, or ability check.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells>fire bolt, hunter sense, message, shocking grasp, true strike, detect magic, magic missile, shield, detect thoughts, misty step, bestow curse, fireball, banishment, consume mind, magic mirror, scrying, disintegrate, arboreal curse, mind blank, gate</spells>
    <slots>4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
    <description>"Despair, the end is nigh!"

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 47</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Downcast Apostate</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (downcast)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>12 (15 with mage armor)</ac>
    <hp>150 (20d8 + 60)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>15</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>13</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>18</cha>
    <save>wis +5, cha +8</save>
    <skill>deception +8, intimidation +8, perception +5, persuasion +8, religion +5, stealth +6</skill>
    <passive>15</passive>
    <languages>Celestial and two other languages</languages>
    <cr>11</cr>
    <exp>7200</exp>
    <resist>Necrotic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft., truesight 30 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Apostate's Weapons</name>
      <text>
The downcast apostate's weapon attacks are magical.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The downcast apostate's spellcasting ability is Charisma. The apostate can innately cast the following spells, requiring no material components:

	• At will: alter self, detect magic, invisibility, jump, mage armor, thaumaturgy</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Morningstar</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8 + 2) bludgeoning damage and 18 (4d8) necrotic or radiant damage (downcast apostate's choice).</text>
      <attack>Morningstar|+6|1d8+2</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>alter self, detect magic, invisibility, jump, mage armor, thaumaturgy, glibness, mass suggestion, plane shift, power word kill, chill touch, light, mage hand, minor illusion, sacred flame, counterspell, cure wounds, dimension door, dispel magic, flame strike, fly, greater restoration, guiding bolt, insect plague, lesser restoration, suggestion, tongues, vampiric touch, wall of fire</spells>
    <slots>0, 0, 0, 0, 4</slots>
    <description>"To assume the downcast are good at heart is foolish. Many still cling to delusions of grandeur and do anything to maintain them."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 49</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Downcast Mercenary</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>17 (half plate)</ac>
    <hp>82 (11d8 + 33)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>17</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <save>wis +4</save>
    <skill>athletics +6, perception +4, religion +4</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Celestial and two other languages</languages>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <exp>1800</exp>
    <resist>Necrotic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Action Surge (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
      <text>
The downcast mercenary takes one extra action.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Indomitable (2/Day)</name>
      <recharge>2/Day</recharge>
      <text>
If the downcast mercenary fails a saving throw, it can reroll the saving throw and use the new roll.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Thaumaturge</name>
      <text>
The downcast mercenary can cast thaumaturgy at will.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The downcast mercenary makes three attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Greatsword</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Greatsword|+6|2d6+3</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>thaumaturgy</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>"To assume the downcast are good at heart is foolish. Many still cling to delusions of grandeur and do anything to maintain them."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 49</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Eldritch Herald</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
    <alignment>Any Non-Good Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>16 (breastplate)</ac>
    <hp>78 (12d8 + 24)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>11</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>12</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>perception +6, religion +3</skill>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>any two languages</languages>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <exp>1800</exp>
    <resist>Psychic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Otherworldly Calm</name>
      <text>
The eldritch herald has advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened. Also, attempts to read the herald's thoughts fail. The creature making the attempt must succeed on a DC 14 Wisdom saving throw or take 10 (3d6) psychic damage.</text>
      <attack>Otherworldly Calm||3d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Handaxe</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Handaxe|+5|1d6+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Prophecy of Doom (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
      <text>
The eldritch herald chooses a point it can see within 120 feet of it and rolls on the Eldritch Effects table. Each creature within 15 feet of that point must succeed on a DC 14 Wisdom saving throw or be subjected to an eldritch effect for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>light, sacred flame, thaumaturgy, vicious mockery, bane, Tasha's hideous laughter, inflict wounds, sleep, detect thoughts, hold person, see invisibility, wrack, bestow curse, fear, spirit guardians, tongues, confusion, death ward, phantasmal killer, contact other plane, contagion, dream, true seeing</spells>
    <slots>4,3,3,3,2,1</slots>
    <description>Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 41</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Eldritch Priest</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
    <alignment>Any Non-good Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>13 (chain shirt)</ac>
    <hp>22 (4d8 + 4)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>11</dex>
    <con>13</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>perception +4, religion +2</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>any two languages</languages>
    <cr>2</cr>
    <exp>450</exp>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The eldritch priest is a 4th-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 12, +4 to hit with spell attacks). It has the following cleric spells prepared:

	• Cantrips (at will): eldritch blast, light, sacred flame, thaumaturgy
	• 1st level (4 slots): bane, Tasha's hideous laughter, inflict wounds, sleep
	• 2nd level (3 slots): detect thoughts, see invisibility, spiritual weapon</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Greatclub</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d8 + 1) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Greatclub|+3|1d8+1</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Prophecy of Doom (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
      <text>
The eldritch priest chooses a point it can see within 120 feet of it and rolls on the Eldritch Effects table. Each creature within 15 feet of that point must succeed on a DC 12 Wisdom saving throw or be subjected to an eldritch effect for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>eldritch blast, light, sacred flame, thaumaturgy, bane, Tasha's hideous laughter, inflict wounds, sleep, detect thoughts, see invisibility, spiritual weapon</spells>
    <slots>4,3</slots>
    <description>"First she spoke of a power greater than the gods. Then there was this ringing in my ears. I don't remember what happened after that, but the nightmares were terrible."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 41</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Elf Vampire (Ancient)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>undead</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Nx Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>18 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>209 (22d8 + 110)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft., climb 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>20</str>
    <dex>20</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>15</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>16</cha>
    <save>dex +11, wis +9, cha +9</save>
    <skill>arcana +8, athletics +11, history +8, perception +9, stealth +11</skill>
    <passive>19</passive>
    <languages>the languages known in life</languages>
    <cr>19</cr>
    <exp/>
    <resist>Necrotic, Poison, bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Unconscious</conditionImmune>
    <senses>blindsight 30 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <text>
If the vampire fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regeneration</name>
      <text>
The vampire regains 25 hit points at the start of its turn if it has at least 1 hit point. If the vampire takes radiant damage, it regains 10 hit points from the next use of this trait instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spider Climb</name>
      <text>
The vampire can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Turn Resistance</name>
      <text>
The vampire has advantage on saving throws against any effect that turns undead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Vampire Weaknesses</name>
      <text>
The vampire has the following flaws:</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Forbiddance</name>
      <text>
The vampire can't enter a residence without an invitation from one of the occupants.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stake to the Heart</name>
      <text>
The vampire dies if a piercing weapon made of wood is driven into its heart while it is incapacitated in its resting place.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The vampire makes three attacks, only one of which can be a bite.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d8 + 6) slashing damage. If the target is a creature, the vampire can grapple the target (escape DC 19).</text>
      <attack>Claws|+11|2d8+6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 15 (2d8 + 6) piercing damage and 17 (5d6) necrotic damage. The target's hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the necrotic damage taken, and the vampire regains hit points equal to that amount. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0. A humanoid slain in this way and then buried rises the following night as a vampire spawn under this vampire's control.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+11|2d8+6</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||5d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Fey Majesty</name>
      <text>
The vampire targets one creature it can see within 30 feet of it. If the target can see or hear the vampire, the target must succeed on a DC 17 Charisma saving throw or be charmed. The charmed target regards the vampire as a friend to be heeded and protected. Although not under the vampire's control, it takes the vampire's requests in the most favorable way and is a willing target for the vampire's bite.

While the target is charmed, the vampire can communicate with the target telepathically within 300 feet. The vampire can use a bonus action to force the target to repeat the saving throw. If the save fails, the vampire can render the creature full of despair (disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls) or confused (as the {@spell confusion spell) for 1 minute. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the despair or confusion on itself on a success.

Each time the vampire or the vampire's allies do anything harmful to the target, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on a success. Otherwise, the effect lasts 24 hours or until the vampire dies, is on a different plane of existence than the target, or takes a bonus action to end the effect.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Mist Form</name>
      <text>
The vampire polymorphs into a Medium cloud of mist, or back into its true form. Anything it wears or carries transforms with it. While in mist form, the vampire can't take any actions, speak, or manipulate objects. It is weightless, has a flying speed of 30 feet, can hover, and can enter a hostile creature's space and stop there. In addition, if air can pass through a space, the mist can do so without squeezing, but it can't pass through water. It has advantage on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws. A vampire in mist form is immune to nonmagical damage, except damage from sunlight, and has resistance to damage other than radiant. The vampire reverts to its true form if it dies.</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Misty Escape</name>
      <text>
When it drops to 0 hit points outside its resting place, the vampire transforms into its Mist Form instead of falling unconscious. If the vampire can't transform, it dies.

While it has 0 hit points in mist form, the vampire dies if it takes damage three times or radiant damage once. It can't willingly revert to its vampire form, and it must reach its resting place within 2 hours or die. Once in its resting place, it reverts to its vampire form. It is then paralyzed until it regains at least 1 hit point. After spending 1 hour in its resting place with 0 hit points, it regains 1 hit point.</text>
    </reaction>
    <legendary>
      <name>Move and Claw</name>
      <text>
The vampire moves up to its speed and attacks once with its claws.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Bite (2 Actions)</name>
      <text>
The vampire makes one bite attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Purify Blood (2 Actions)</name>
      <text>
Even if the vampire can't take actions, one condition ends on it.</text>
    </legendary>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 106</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Empyrean Brazen Bull</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>celestial</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Good</alignment>
    <ac>16 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>162 (12d12 + 84)</hp>
    <speed>walk 50 ft., fly 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>26</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>25</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>21</cha>
    <save>str +12, con +11, wis +7, cha +9</save>
    <skill>athletics +12, perception +7</skill>
    <passive>17</passive>
    <languages>Celestial</languages>
    <cr>10</cr>
    <exp>5900</exp>
    <resist>Acid, Cold, Lightning, bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>Fire, Necrotic, Poison, Radiant</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Frightened, Prone, Restrained</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Celestial Arsenal</name>
      <text>
The Empyrean brazen bull's weapon attacks are magical. When it hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra 18 (4d8) radiant damage (included in the attack).</text>
      <attack>Celestial Arsenal||4d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Death Throes</name>
      <text>
When the Empyrean brazen bull dies, it explodes, and each creature within 20 feet of it must make a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw, taking 21 6d6 fire and 21 (6d6) radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
      <attack>Fire||6d6</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||6d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Soulfire Nimbus</name>
      <text>
At the start of each of the Empyrean brazen bull's turns, each creature within 5 feet of it takes 10 (3d6) radiant damage. A creature that touches the Empyrean brazen bull or hits it with a melee attack while within 5 feet of it takes 10 (3d6) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Soulfire Nimbus||3d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Siege Monster</name>
      <text>
The Empyrean brazen bull deals double damage to objects and structures.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Unrelenting Charge</name>
      <text>
If the Empyrean brazen bull moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a gore attack on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 20 Strength saving thrown or be knocked prone. If the target is prone, the Empyrean brazen bull can make one attack with its bite or hooves against it as a bonus action.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target., Hit: 24 (3d10 + 8) bludgeoning damage plus 18 (4d8) radiant damage. If the target is a creature, it is grappled (escape DC 20). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the Empyrean brazen bull can't bite another target.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+12|3d10+8</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||4d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Gore</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 27 (3d12 + 8) piercing damage and 18 (4d8) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Gore|+12|3d12+8</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||4d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Hooves</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 feet., one target. Hit: 24 (3d10 + 8) bludgeoning damage and 18 (4d8) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Hooves|+12|3d10+8</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||4d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Swallow</name>
      <text>
The Empyrean brazen bull makes one bite attack against a Medium or smaller creature it is grappling. If the attack hits, that creature takes the bite's damage and is swallowed, and the grapple ends. While swallowed, the creature is blinded and restrained, it has total cover against attacks and other effects outside the Empyrean brazen bull, and it takes 21 (6d6) fire damage at the start of each of theEmpyrean brazen bull's turns. If the Empyrean brazen bull takes 30 damage or more on a single turn from a creature inside it, the Empyrean brazen bull must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw at the end of that turn or regurgitate all swallowed creatures, which fall prone in a space within 10 feet of the empyrean brazen bull. If the Empyrean brazen bull dies, a swallowed creature is no longer restrained by it and can escape from the corpse using 15 feet of movement, exiting prone.</text>
      <attack>Swallow||6d6</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"The smell of smoke and incense consumed the castle walls, and we heard the furious and gleeful bellows of the most immense bull we'd ever seen. As our battlements burned and crumbled, we knew all was lost."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 100</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Eye Crawler</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <type>aberration</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>11</ac>
    <hp>2 (1d4)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>3</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>6</int>
    <wis>11</wis>
    <cha>5</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>perception +2, stealth +5</skill>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <exp>10</exp>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Sight</name>
      <text>
The eye crawler has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
    </trait>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>An eye crawler is an ambulatory eye that observes everything. It might be spying for something else. An eye crawler has no effective attacks. Mages theorize eye crawlers derive sustenance from light or ambient magical energy.

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 82</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Eye Crow</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <type>beast</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>12</ac>
    <hp>2 (1d4)</hp>
    <speed>walk 10 ft., fly 50 ft.</speed>
    <str>2</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>perception +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <exp>10</exp>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mimicry</name>
      <text>
The eye crow can mimic simple sounds it has heard, such as a person whispering, a baby crying, or an animal chittering. A creature that hears the sounds can tell they are imitations with a successful DC 10 Wisdom (Insight) check.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pack Tactics</name>
      <text>
The eye crow has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the crow's allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn't incapacitated.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Beak</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 piercing damage. If the eye crow scores a critical hit on a creature, the target is blinded until the end of the crow's next turn.

Blinded:
	• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.</text>
      <attack>Beak|+4|1</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>Eye crows are big corvids plentiful throughout Etharis. They mimic sounds and voices, and they're extremely clever, remembering faces, locations, and how other creatures treat them. People keep eye crows as pets and often use their iridescent black feathers, which have a deep-green sheen, to decorate.

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 58</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Faevlin</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>fey</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (leather armor)</ac>
    <hp>10 (3d6)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>8</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>11</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>stealth +4</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Goblin, Sylvan</languages>
    <cr>1/4</cr>
    <exp>50</exp>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Touched</name>
      <text>
Magic can't put the faevlin to sleep. Only a creature of the fey type can cause the faevlin to become charmed, and a faevlin always knows if a nonfey creature attempted to render it charmed.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sneaky</name>
      <text>
The faevlin can use a bonus action to take the Hide action.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Scimitar</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Scimitar|+4|1d6+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shortbow</name>
      <text>
Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 80/320 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Shortbow|+4|1d6+2</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Fey Fade</name>
      <text>
When an attack misses a faevlin, the faevlin can teleport up to 30 feet in a random direction, arriving in a safe, unoccupied space.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Never make a deal with the fey. Never make a deal with a goblin. And if you ever meet a faevlin, you'll know why."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 9</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Fzeg</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>153 (18d8 + 72)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>18</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>17</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>18</cha>
    <save>dex +9, wis +7</save>
    <skill>perception +7, stealth +9</skill>
    <passive>17</passive>
    <languages>any four languages</languages>
    <cr>16</cr>
    <experience>15000</experience>
    <resist>Necrotic, bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+5</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>
The fzeg has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/Day</recharge>
      <text>
If the fzeg fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rampage</name>
      <text>
When the fzeg reduces a creature to 0 hit points with a melee attack on its turn, the fzeg can take a bonus action to move up to half its speed and make a bite attack.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regeneration</name>
      <text>
The fzeg regains 20 hit points at the start of its turn if it has at least 1 hit point. If the fzeg takes radiant damage, this trait doesn't function at the start of the fzeg's next turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shapechanger</name>
      <text>
The fzeg can use its action to polymorph into a Small or Medium humanoid or back into its true form, that of a wolfhumanoid hybrid. It can transform its body parts as part of attacking with them and can choose whether the change remains after making the attack. Other than its size, its statistics are the same in each form. Any equipment it's wearing or carrying isn't transformed. It reverts to its true form if it dies.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spider Climb</name>
      <text>
The fzeg can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The fzeg uses its howl, then attacks once with its bite and twice with its claws.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) piercing damage plus 17 (5d6) necrotic damage and is stunned until the end of its next turn. A humanoid slain after being bitten rises the following night as a fzeglaich under the fzeg's control.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+9|2d6+4</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||5d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (2d8 + 4) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claws|+9|2d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Howl</name>
      <text>
Each creature of the fzeg's choice that is within 300 feet of the fzeg and able to hear it must succeed on a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature's saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the fzeg's Howl for the next 24 hours or until it is stunned by the fzeg.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Night Children (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
      <text>
The fzeg magically calls eight wolves. These wolves arrive in 2 rounds, acting as allies of the fzeg and obeying its spoken commands. The beasts remain for 1 hour, until the fzeg dies, or until the fzeg dismisses them as a bonus action.</text>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <text>
The fzeg can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. The fzeg regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Move</name>
      <text>
The fzeg moves up to its speed without provoking opportunity attacks.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>
The fzeg attacks with its claws.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Incite</name>
      <text>
The fzeg chooses one creature that is of a lower Challenge, has a bite attack, and is within 60 feet of the fzeg. Provided the target can see or hear the fzeg, that creature can use its reaction to move up to half its speed and make a bite attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Bite (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
      <text>
The fzeg attacks with its bite.</text>
    </legendary>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"We've been led to believe that vampires and werewolves are natural enemies. Convenient that two fearsome creatures would be so opposed to the other. Never did we imagine, nor prepare, for a time when they might unite."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 80</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Fzeglaich</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>90 (12d8 + 36)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>16</str>
    <dex>16</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>11</int>
    <wis>11</wis>
    <cha>12</cha>
    <save>dex +6, wis +3</save>
    <skill>perception +3, stealth +6</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>one language</languages>
    <cr>7</cr>
    <experience>2900</experience>
    <resist>bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>
The fzeglaich has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rampage</name>
      <text>
When the fzeglaich reduces a creature to 0 hit points with a melee attack on its turn, the fzeglaich can take a bonus action to move up to half its speed and make a bite attack.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regeneration</name>
      <text>
The fzeglaich regains 10 hit points at the start of its turn if it has at least 1 hit point. If the fzeglaich takes radiant damage, this trait doesn't function at the start of the fzeglaich's next turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The fzeglaich makes two attacks, only one of which can be a bite.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 7 (1d8 + 3) piercing damage plus 7 (2d6) necrotic damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or be incapacitated until the end of its next turn. The fzeglaich regains hit points equal to the amount of necrotic damage dealt.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+6|1d8+3</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 8 (2d4 + 3) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claws|+6|2d4+3</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"We've been led to believe that vampires and werewolves are natural enemies. Convenient that two fearsome creatures would be so opposed to the other. Never did we imagine, nor prepare, for a time when they might unite."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 79</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Gegazol</name>
    <size>G</size>
    <type>undead</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>22 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>462 (25d20 + 200)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft., burrow 40 ft., fly 80 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>27</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>26</con>
    <int>16</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>23</cha>
    <save>dex +9, int +10, wis +9</save>
    <skill>perception +9</skill>
    <passive>19</passive>
    <languages>Draconic</languages>
    <cr>24</cr>
    <experience/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>Cold, Necrotic, Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Frightened, Paralyzed, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>blindsight 60 ft., darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Ice Walk</name>
      <text>
Gegazol can move across and climb icy surfaces without needing to make an ability check. Additionally, difficult terrain composed of ice or snow doesn't cost her extra movement.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/Day</recharge>
      <text>
If Gegazol fails a saving throw, she can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
Gegazol has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rejuvenation</name>
      <text>
If destroyed while her soul vessel remains intact, Gegazol's unconscious body rejuvenates within 5 feet of the soul vessel, where she regains 78 (12d12) hit points each day. When she has regained half her hit points, she regains consciousness.</text>
      <attack>Rejuvenation||12d12</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stench</name>
      <text>
Any creature not immune to the poisoned condition that starts its turn within 30 feet of Gegazol must succeed on a DC 23 Constitution saving throw or become poisoned until the start of that creature's next turn. On a successful saving throw, the creature is immune to Gegazol's stench for 1 hour.

Poisoned:
	• A poisoned creature has disadvantage on Attack rolls and Ability Checks.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Turning Defiance</name>
      <text>
Gegazol and undead within 120 feet of her have advantage on saving throws against effects that turn undead.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
Gegazol can use her frightful presence. She then makes three attacks: one with her bite and two with her claws.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (2d12 + 8) piercing damage, 9 (2d8) cold damage and 9 (2d8) necrotic damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+15|2d12+8</attack>
      <attack>Cold||2d8</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d10 + 8) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claw|+15|2d10+8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tail</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 20 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d10 + 8) bludgeoning damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 23 Strength saving throw or fall prone.</text>
      <attack>Tail|+15|2d10+8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Frightful Presence</name>
      <text>
Each creature of Gegazol's choice within 120 feet of and aware of her must succeed on a DC 21 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature's saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to Gegazol's Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.

Frightened:
	• A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.
	• The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Breath of Long Night (Recharge 5-6)</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>
Gegazol exhales frozen material and rot in a 90-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 23 Constitution saving throw, taking 45 (10d8) cold damage and 45 (10d8) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Those who fail the save also gain two levels of exhaustion until the end of Gegazol's next turn, and those who fail by 5 or more are also blinded for 1 minute. A blinded creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
      <attack>Breath of Long Night||10d8</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||10d8</attack>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <text>
Gegazol can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. Gegazol regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Daemon Sight</name>
      <text>
Gegazol gains truesight out to 120 feet until the end of her next turn and can make a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Tail</name>
      <text>
Gegazol makes a tail attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Wings of Winter (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
      <text>
Gegazol beats her wings. Each creature within 30 feet of her must succeed on a DC 23 Dexterity saving throw or take 17 (2d8 + 8) bludgeoning damage and 9 (2d8) cold damage, and then fall prone. Gegazol can then fly up to half her flying speed.</text>
      <attack>Wings of Winter||2d8+8</attack>
      <attack>Cold||2d8</attack>
    </legendary>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"The Scourge of the North is an undead dragon named Gegazol. If I hear her name, I get the hell out of there. She's powerful, cunning, and treacherous. And she's rarely alone—she always has one army or another behind her."

Gegazol's Lair:
The Scourge's lair is the sinkhole cave on an island off the northernmost shores of Etharis, north of even the raging coldfire. In this cave, the daemon's skull sits. It rests at the bottom of a deep, wet cavern upon a pedestal carved into the earth. Magic wards protect the crack above the skull. Gegazol's Immortals, a brutal cadre of undead warriors the dragon created or conquered, guard the expanded catacombs around the shrine. Gegazol needs no rest, but between campaigns, she lounges within the shrine, curled around the skull's pedestal. The whole place stinks of decay, making the site nauseating. While in her lair, Gegazol's Stench radius increases to 120 feet.

Lair Actions:
On initiative count 20 (losing initiative ties), Gegazol takes a lair action to cause one of the following effects. Gegazol can't use the same effect two rounds in a row.

Tendrils of necrotic power rise and reach for living creatures within the lair. Each living creature in the lair must attempt a DC 21 Constitution saving throw or take 13 (3d8) necrotic damage and gain one level of exhaustion until initiative count 20 on the next round.

Gegazol crashes her wings upon the ground, and rime spreads in a sphere with a 120-foot radius around her. This sphere spreads around corners and creates difficult terrain made of ice. Creatures in that area must make a DC 21 Constitution saving throw. Those who fail take 18 (4d8) cold damage and are grappled (escape DC 21). On a success, the creature takes half the damage and isn't grappled. The difficult terrain disappears on initiative count 20 on the next round.

Gegazol creates an opaque wall of black ice on a solid surface she can see within 120 feet of her. The wall is made up of twenty contiguous 10-foot square panels that are each 2 feet thick. When the wall appears, each creature in its area is pushed 5 feet out of the wall's space, appearing on whichever side of the wall the creature wants. Each 10-foot section of the wall has AC 5, 60 hit points, vulnerability to fire damage, and immunity to acid, cold, necrotic, poison, and psychic damage. The wall disappears when Gegazol uses this lair action again or when she dies.

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 117</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Gluttony Seraph</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>celestial</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>218 (19d12 + 95)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft., fly 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>21</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>13</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>16</cha>
    <save>con +10, wis +7, cha +8</save>
    <skill>insight +7, perception +7</skill>
    <passive>17</passive>
    <languages>all, telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>14</cr>
    <experience>11500</experience>
    <resist>Radiant, bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Frightened, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>truesight 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+5</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The seraph's spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 16). The seraph can innately cast the following spells, using only verbal components:

	• At will: detect evil and good, detect magic, light, thaumaturgy
	• 3/day: suggestion
	• 1/day: create food and water (the food is tasty and the seraph can create wine instead of water)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The seraph has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Seraphic Weapons</name>
      <text>
The seraph's weapon attacks are magical. When the seraph hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra (2d8) radiant damage (included in the attacks).</text>
      <attack>Radiant||2d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The seraph makes three attacks, only one of which can be a bite.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 24 (3d12 + 5) piercing damage and 9 (2d8) radiant damage. If the target is a Large or smaller creature, it is grappled (escape DC 18). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the seraph can't bite another target.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+10|3d12+5</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d6 + 5) slashing damage and 9 (2d8) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Claw|+10|2d6+5||Radiant||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tongue</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 20 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (2d4 + 5) bludgeoning damage and 9 (2d8) radiant damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 18) and pulled to within 5 feet of the seraph. Until the grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the seraph can't use its tongue or bite on another target.</text>
      <attack>Tongue|+10|2d4+5</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Swallow</name>
      <text>
The seraph makes one bite attack against a Medium or smaller creature it holds grappled. If the attack hits, the target takes the bite's damage, the grapple ends, and the target is swallowed. While swallowed, a creature is blinded and restrained, has total cover against anything originating outside the seraph, and takes 18 (4d8) acid damage and 9 (2d8) radiant damage at the start of each of the seraph's turns. The seraph can have only one creature swallowed at a time.

If the seraph takes 35 damage or more on a single turn from a creature inside it, the seraph must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw at the end of that turn or regurgitate the swallowed creature, which falls prone in a space within 10 feet of the seraph. If the seraph dies, the swallowed creature is no longer restrained by it and can escape the corpse by using 10 feet of movement, exiting prone.</text>
      <attack>Swallow||4d8</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>detect evil and good, detect magic, light, thaumaturgy, suggestion, create food and water</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Don't go to the temple. Something sinister has claimed it. Seek shelter elsewhere."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 95</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Gnoll Brute</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (gnoll)</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>52 (8d8 + 16)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>16</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>6</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>athletics +5</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Gnoll</languages>
    <cr>2</cr>
    <experience>450</experience>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Brute</name>
      <text>
A melee weapon deals one extra die of its damage when the gnoll brute hits with it (included in the attacks).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Charge</name>
      <text>
If the gnoll brute moves at least 20 feet straight toward a target and then hits it with a melee weapon attack on the same turn, the target takes one extra die of the weapon's damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or fall prone.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Instinctive</name>
      <text>
The gnoll brute has advantage on initiative rolls and saving throws against being charmed or frightened. If surprised, the gnoll can still act normally on its first turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rampage</name>
      <text>
When the gnoll brute reduces a creature to 0 hit points with a melee attack on its turn, the gnoll can take a bonus action to move up to half its speed and make a bite attack.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The gnoll brute makes one bite attack and one claws attack.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (2d4 + 3) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+5|2d4+3</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claws|+5|2d6+3</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Shared Rampage</name>
      <text>
If any creature allied with and within 100 feet of the gnoll brute uses its Rampage trait, the gnoll brute can use its Rampage trait, too, provided the brute can see that ally.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"I never believed the rumors about the Beast and how it could change people. Then I saw how everyone at the logging camp had been transformed. It had to be a power even greater than a god's."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 60</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Harvester of Lies</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>undead</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>17 (coat of lies)</ac>
    <hp>91 (14d8 + 28)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>13</str>
    <dex>20</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>11</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>15</cha>
    <save>dex +9, wis +7, cha +6</save>
    <skill>acrobatics +9, insight +7, perception +7, stealth +13</skill>
    <passive>17</passive>
    <languages>the languages it knew in life</languages>
    <cr>9</cr>
    <experience>5000</experience>
    <resist>Necrotic, bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+4</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Coat of Lies</name>
      <text>
While wearing their specially prepared coat, the harvester's AC is increase by 2 and it can use its innate spellcasting.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The harvester's spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 14). It can innately cast the following spells, requiring only that the harvester be wearing its coat of lies:

	• At will: detect thoughts, zone of truth
	• 3/day each: hold person, invisibility, misty step, silence
	• 1/day each: levitate, tongues</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hear Lies</name>
      <text>
The harvester hears all lies uttered within 1 mile of it and knows the liar's distance and direction while the harvester choses to concentrate.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spider Climb</name>
      <text>
The harvester can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trackless</name>
      <text>
The harvester leaves no tracks to indicate where it has been or where it's headed.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The harvester makes three attacks, only one of which can be sever tongue.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d6 + 5) slashing damage. If the target is Medium or smaller, it is grappled (escape DC 17).</text>
      <attack>Claw|+9|2d6+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Sever Tongue</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one humanoid grappled by the harvester of lies. Hit: 33 (8d6 + 5) slashing damage and the target must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or have their tongue ripped out. A creature without a tongue cannot speak or cast spells with verbal components. A creature is immune to this effect if it is immune to slashing damage, doesn't have or need a tongue, or has legendary actions.

A tongue can be reattached within 1 hour of being severed with a successful DC 10 Wisdom (Medicine) check, or at can be regrown using magic that replaces lost limbs.</text>
      <attack>Sever Tongue|+9|8d6+5</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>detect thoughts, zone of truth, hold person, invisibility, misty step, silence, levitate, tongues</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Don't lie to me, or the harvester will steal your tongue!"

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 13</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Horror Flit Hunter</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>aberration</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>45 (10d6 + 10)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft., climb 40 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>11</str>
    <dex>18</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>4</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>2</cr>
    <experience>450</experience>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Blinded, Prone</conditionImmune>
    <senses>blindsight 60 ft. (blind beyond this radius)</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>
The horror flit hunter can breathe air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Breed</name>
      <text>
When the horror flit hunter kills a Small or larger creature, a new horror flit swarm emerges from the corpse 1d4 hours later.</text>
      <attack>Breed||1d4</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spider Climb</name>
      <text>
The horror flit hunter can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The horror flit hunter makes two bite attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (2d4 + 4) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+6|2d4+4</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"If you see fast movement in the trees, run. It might not be enough, but it could be all you can do."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 50</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Hourglass Widow</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>undead</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <hp>187 (22d8 + 88)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft., fly 60 ft. (hover)</speed>
    <str>16</str>
    <dex>19</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>19</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>22</cha>
    <save>str +9, con +10, int +10, wis +9, cha +12</save>
    <skill>arcana +10, athletics +9, insight +9, investigation +10, perception +15</skill>
    <passive>25</passive>
    <languages>the languages it knew in life</languages>
    <cr>20</cr>
    <experience>25000</experience>
    <resist>Cold, Force, Lightning, Necrotic</resist>
    <immune>poison; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Frightened, Paralyzed, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>truesight 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+6</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The widow's spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 20, +12 to hit with spell attacks). It can innately cast the following spells, requiring no material components:

	• At will: eldritch blast (four beams), expeditious retreat *, mage armor *, mage hand
	• 3/day each: blight, disintegrate, haste, misty step, shield, slow, see invisibility
	• 1/day each: eyebite, foresight *, freedom of movement, power word stun, teleport, time stop, wall of force

*The widow casts these spells before combat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Accelerate Through Time (2/Day)</name>
      <text>
The widow takes one additional action.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Master of Time</name>
      <text>
The widow can choose to be unaffected by effects that modify time or change its speed. The widow can affect others frozen in a time stop or other stasis-like effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/Day</recharge>
      <text>
If the widow fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regeneration</name>
      <text>
The widow regains 25 hit points at the start of its turn. If it takes fire or radiant damage, this trait doesn't function at the start of the widow's next turn. The widow's body is destroyed only if it starts its turn with 0 hit points and doesn't regenerate.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Turn Resistance</name>
      <text>
The widow has advantage on saving throws against any effect that turns undead.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The widow uses disintegrating touch and withering gaze.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Disintegrating Touch</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 16 (3d6 + 6) force damage and the target must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw or have their speed decreased by 15 feet for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. The effects are cumulative.</text>
      <attack>Disintegrating Touch|+10|3d6+6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Withering Gaze</name>
      <text>
A creature within 30 feet that the widow can see suffers 21 (6d6) necrotic damage.</text>
      <attack>Withering Gaze||6d6</attack>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <name>Eldritch Blast</name>
      <text>
The widow casts eldritch blast.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Sudden Rush (2 Actions)</name>
      <text>
The widow teleports to a space it can see within 30 feet and uses disintegrating touch before or after it teleports.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Frozen in Time (3 Actions)</name>
      <text>
All creatures within 20 ft. of the widow must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed until the end of the creature's next turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <spells>eldritch blast, expeditious retreat, mage armor, mage hand, blight, disintegrate, haste, misty step, shield, slow, see invisibility, eyebite, foresight, freedom of movement, power word stun, teleport, time stop, wall of force</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>"When the clock stops, your time has run out."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 81</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Hraptnon</name>
    <size>G</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>18 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>264 (16d20 + 96)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft., burrow 20 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>21</str>
    <dex>17</dex>
    <con>22</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>17</wis>
    <cha>12</cha>
    <save>str +11, dex +9, con +12, wis +9</save>
    <skill>athletics +11, perception +9</skill>
    <passive>19</passive>
    <languages>Draconic</languages>
    <cr>18</cr>
    <experience>20000</experience>
    <resist/>
    <immune>bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from magical weapons; all damage from spells</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Frightened, Stunned, Unconscious</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+6</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (3/Day)</name>
      <recharge>3/Day</recharge>
      <text>
If the hraptnon fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The hraptnon has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Undying</name>
      <text>
Unless the hraptnon's Stillborn Heart is removed from its pool, the hraptnon's death is temporary. One of its countless xakalonus offspring grows into the hraptnon in 24 hours.

In addition, the hraptnon loses its immunities if the Stillborn Heart is removed from the pool.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The hraptnon makes three melee attacks: one bite and two claws. Alternatively, the hraptnon can make two spine attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 18 (3d8 + 5) piercing damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw or be incapacitated until the end of the hraptnon's next turn.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+11|3d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 27 (4d10 + 5) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claws|+11|4d10+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Spine</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, range 60 ft., one target. Hit: 23 (4d8 + 5) piercing damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 20 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the target is knocked prone and restrained. The target must escape (DC 20) to remove the restrained condition and be able to stand.</text>
      <attack>Spine|+11|4d8+5</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Spawn Xakalonus</name>
      <text>
If the hraptnon takes 20 points of damage or more from a single attack, it can spawn a xakalonus, which appears in a space adjacent to the hraptnon and attacks on the same initiative count as the hraptnon.</text>
    </reaction>
    <legendary>
      <text>
The hraptnon can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. The hraptnon regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
The hraptnon makes a claw attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Baneful Howl (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
      <text>
The hraptnon casts bane as a 3rd level spell (DC 20 to resist).</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Life Drain (Costs 3 Actions)</name>
      <text>
One xakalonus within 30 feet of the hraptnon dies. The hraptnon regains hit points equal to half the hit points of the xakalonus that died.</text>
    </legendary>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"The magic our wizard used just bounced off the gigantic creature, and as our fighter slashed at it with her sword, the creature's blood spawned even more monsters."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 72</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Infernal Tormentor</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>humanoid (any race, fiend)</type>
    <alignment>Any Evil Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>16 (half plate)</ac>
    <hp>97 (13d8 + 39)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>15</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>intimidation +5, perception +4</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Infernal and one other language</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <experience>2300</experience>
    <resist>Fire</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The infernal tormentor makes two greatsword attacks. It can use infernal leash in place of one attack.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Greatsword</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) slashing damage and 7 (2d6) fire damage.</text>
      <attack>Greatsword|+7|2d6+4</attack>
      <attack>Fire||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Infernal Leash (Recharge 6)</name>
      <recharge>D6</recharge>
      <text>
A flaming whip appears in the infernal tormentor's hand or from its greatsword and lashes at a creature the tormentor can see within 30 feet of it. The target must succeed on a DC 13 Charisma saving throw. A creature that has signed a fiendish contract has disadvantage on this save. On a failure, the creature takes 14 (4d6) fire damage, is pulled 10 feet closer to the tormentor, and is cursed for 1 minute or until the tormentor uses this action again. This curse also ends if the target enters hallowed ground.

While cursed, the target can't move more than 30 feet from the tormentor. Also while the curse lasts, the target takes 7 (2d6) extra fire damage from the tormentor's greatsword attacks. The tormentor can use a bonus action to move the target 10 feet to an unoccupied space within 30 feet of the tormentor. If this space is dangerous, the target receives a new saving throw before moving, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
      <attack>Infernal Leash||4d6</attack>
      <attack>Extra Fire||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"I knew when she pulled out a gold pen reeking of brimstone that I was making a mistake."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 50</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Ithjar</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>16 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>102 (12d10 + 36)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft., fly 90 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>20</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>5</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>acrobatics +8, perception +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <experience>1800</experience>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 10 ft., darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Sight</name>
      <text>
The ithjar has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Slippery Serpent</name>
      <text>
The ithjar has advantage on ability checks and saving throws made to escape a grapple or saving throws to avoid being paralyzed or restrained.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The ithjar attacks once with its bite and once with its tail.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d10 + 4) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+7|2d10+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tail</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (2d8 + 4) bludgeoning damage. If the target is a Medium or smaller creature, it is grappled (escape DC 15). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the ithjar can't use its tail on another target.</text>
      <attack>Tail|+7|2d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Writhing Escape</name>
      <text>
When grappled, the ithjar can attempt to escape.</text>
    </reaction>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"It takes mere moments for an ithjar to transform from a kite-like swirl of gray and red in the distance to a menace of snapping teeth."

Source:	Grimw Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 94</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Knifewing</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>beast</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d6 + 2)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft., climb 30 ft., fly 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>6</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>13</con>
    <int>2</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>5</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>1/8</cr>
    <experience>25</experience>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 10 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Flyby</name>
      <text>
The knifewing doesn't provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy's reach.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Glider</name>
      <text>
The knifewing can't ascend while flying and its altitude decreases by 5 feet for every 30 feet it flies. If flying, the knifewing falls if it doesn't fly at least 30 feet during its turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Knifewing (Flying Only)</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Knifewing|+4|1d6+2</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+4|1d4+2</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>A knifewing is a gliding lizard about the size of a small dog. Its gliding flaps have hard edges that are sharp while stretched taut when the lizard glides.

Source:	Grimw Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 15</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Lenchtahg</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>fiend</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>110 (13d8 + 52)</hp>
    <speed>walk 40 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>11</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>11</wis>
    <cha>13</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>perception +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Abyssal, Celestial, Infernal</languages>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <experience>1800</experience>
    <resist>bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>Fire, Poison, Radiant</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Frightened, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Berserk</name>
      <text>
Whenever the lenchtahg starts its turn with 54 hit points or fewer, roll a d6. On a 1, the lenchtahg recalls its former life and current agony, and it goes berserk. On each of its turns while berserk, the lenchtahg attacks the nearest creature it can see. It treats all creatures as enemies and makes any opportunity attack it can. Also, it has advantage on attack rolls, but all attack rolls against it have advantage. If no creature is near enough to move to and attack, the lenchtahg moves as far as it can toward the closest creature.

Once the lenchtahg goes berserk, it remains so until destroyed or it has more than 54 hit points. Also, a fiend can calm the lenchtahg. The lenchtahg must be able to understand the fiend, who must take an action to make a DC 15 Charisma (Persuasion) check. If the check succeeds, the lenchtahg ceases being berserk.</text>
      <attack>Berserk||1d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The lenchtahg has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Weapons</name>
      <text>
The lenchtahg's weapon attacks are magical.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Radiant Absorption</name>
      <text>
Whenever the lenchtahg is subjected to radiant damage from a source other than a lenchtahg, it takes no damage and instead regains hit points equal to half the radiant damage dealt to it.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Rejuvenation</name>
      <text>
If the lenchtahg's head survives its demise, the head must be doused in holy water and ritually consecrated in a 1-hour ceremony or be the target of a dispel evil and good spell. If it isn't, then the lenchtahg reappears in 6 days, emerging from a fiery explosion in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on the head. Creatures in that area must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 28 8d6 damage on a failed saving throw, or half as much damage on a successful one. The head can't rejuvenate in a holy hallow spell's area.</text>
      <attack>Rejuvenation||8d6</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Water Aversion</name>
      <text>
If drenched in 5 gallons or more of water, or any amount of holy water, the lenchtahg has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the end of its next turn.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The lenchtahg makes two claw attacks, makes one claw attack and uses radiant gaze once, or uses radiant gaze twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (2d4 + 4) slashing damage and 9 (2d8) fire damage.</text>
      <attack>Claw|+7|2d4+4</attack>
      <attack>Fire||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Radiant Gaze</name>
      <text>
The lenchtahg targets one creature it can see within 60 feet of it with burning radiance. The target gains no benefit from cover and must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or take 13 (3d8) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Radiant Gaze||3d8</attack>
    </action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>"The smoky, fiery form hisses and shrieks in a cacophony of anger and confusion. There's something almost holy in the sound."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 51</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Lesser Avarice Seraph</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>celestial</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>105 (14d8 + 42)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft., fly 90 ft.</speed>
    <str>16</str>
    <dex>18</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>13</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>16</cha>
    <save>con +6, wis +5, cha +6</save>
    <skill>deception +6, insight +5, perception +5</skill>
    <passive>15</passive>
    <languages>all, telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>7</cr>
    <experience>2900</experience>
    <resist>Radiant, bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Frightened</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The seraph's spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 14). The seraph can innately cast the following spells, using only verbal components:

	• At will: detect evil and good, detect magic, light, minor illusion, thaumaturgy
	• 1/day each: identify, suggestion</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The seraph has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Seraphic Weapons</name>
      <text>
The seraph's weapon attacks are magical. When the seraph hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra (2d8) radiant damage (included in the attack).</text>
      <attack>Radiant||2d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The seraph makes three attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Scimitar</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) slashing damage and 9 (2d8) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Scimitar|+7|1d6+3</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tempting Call</name>
      <text>
The seraph calls out a tempting promise to one creature that can hear it withing 30 feet. The creature must succeed on a DC 14 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the creature cannot take actions for 1 minute, as it dwells on the promise the seraph made. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each turn, ending the effect on a success. Each failed saving throw after the initial failure deals 9 (2d8) psychic damage to the target</text>
      <attack>Tempting Call||2d8</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>detect evil and good, detect magic, light, minor illusion, thaumaturgy, identify, suggestion</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Don't go to the temple. Something sinister has claimed it. Seek shelter elsewhere."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 94</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Lesser Gluttony Seraph</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>celestial</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>114 (12d10 + 48)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft., fly 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>19</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>15</cha>
    <save>con +7, wis +5, cha +5</save>
    <skill>insight +5, perception +5</skill>
    <passive>15</passive>
    <languages>all, telepathy 120 ft.</languages>
    <cr>7</cr>
    <experience>2900</experience>
    <resist>Radiant, bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</resist>
    <immune>Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Frightened, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The seraph's spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 13). The seraph can innately cast the following spells, using only verbal components:

	• At will: detect evil and good, detect magic, light, thaumaturgy
	• 1/day each: create food and water, suggestion</text>
    </action>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>
The seraph has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Seraphic Weapons</name>
      <text>
The seraph's weapon attacks are magical. When the seraph hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra (1d8) radiant damage (included in the attacks).</text>
      <attack>Radiant||1d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The seraph makes three attacks, only one of which can be a bite.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d10 + 4) piercing damage and 4 (1d8) radiant damage. If the target is a Medium or smaller creature, it is grappled (escape DC 15). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the seraph can't bite another target.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+7|2d10+4</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (2d4 + 4) slashing damage and 4 (1d8) radiant damage.</text>
      <attack>Claw|+7|2d4+4</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Tongue</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 15 ft., one creature. Hit: 6 (1d4 + 4) bludgeoning damage and 4 (1d8) radiant damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 15) and pulled to within 5 feet of the seraph. Until the grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the seraph can't use its tongue or bite on another target.</text>
      <attack>Tongue|+7|1d4+4</attack>
      <attack>Radiant||1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>detect evil and good, detect magic, light, thaumaturgy, create food and water, suggestion</spells>
    <slots/>
    <description>"Don't go to the temple. Something sinister has claimed it. Seek shelter elsewhere."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 94</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Lich Troll</name>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>undead</type>
    <alignment>Chaotic Evil</alignment>
    <ac>16 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>133 (14d10 + 56)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>14</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>15</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>12</cha>
    <save>con +9, int +7, wis +6</save>
    <skill/>
    <passive>16</passive>
    <languages>the languages it knew in life and Giant</languages>
    <cr>14</cr>
    <experience>11500</experience>
    <resist>Cold, Necrotic</resist>
    <immune>Fire, Poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>Charmed, Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>truesight 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+5</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>
The lich troll is an 11th-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Intelligence (spell save DC 15, +7 to hit with spell attacks). The lich troll has the following wizard spells prepared:

	• Cantrips (at will): chill touch, mage hand, prestidigitation, ray of frost
	• 1st level (4 slots): detect magic, magic missile, shield, thunderwave
	• 2nd level (3 slots): detect thoughts, invisibility, mirror image, misty step
	• 3rd level (3 slots): animate dead, counterspell, dispel magic, haste
	• 4th level (3 slots): blight, dimension door
	• 5th level (2 slots): cloudkill, scrying
	• 6th level (1 slot): create undead</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Legendary Resistance (2/Day)</name>
      <text>
If the lich troll fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Regeneration</name>
      <text>
The lich troll regains 15 hit points at the start of its turn. If the lich troll takes acid or radiant damage, this trait doesn't function until the start of the lich troll's next turn. The lich troll dies only if it starts its turn with 0 hit points and doesn't regenerate.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>
The lich troll makes two claw attacks. Alternately, the lich troll can cast chill touch or ray of frost twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) slashing damage plus 7 (2d6) cold damage.</text>
      <attack>Claw|+9|2d6+4</attack>
      <attack>Cold||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <legendary>
      <text>
The lich troll can take 2 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. The lich troll regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Cantrip</name>
      <text>
The lich troll casts a cantrip.</text>
    </legendary>
    <legendary>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>
The lich troll makes a claw attack.</text>
    </legendary>
    <spells>chill touch, mage hand, prestidigitation, ray of frost, detect magic, magic missile, shield, thunderwave, detect thoughts, invisibility, mirror image, misty step, animate dead, counterspell, dispel magic, haste, blight, dimension door, cloudkill, scrying, create undead</spells>
    <slots>4,3,3,3,2,1</slots>
    <description>"Running away from a troll is smart. Running away from a troll that casts spells is wishful thinking."

Source:	Grim Hollow: Lairs of Etharis p. 121</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
</compendium>
