<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data version="5">
  <campaign>
    <version>32</version>
    <uid>4357</uid>
    <name>A Deadly Scarab</name>
    <adventure>
      <uid>4358</uid>
      <name>Part 1: A Deadly Scarab</name>
      <note>
        <name>Introduction</name>
        <text>In this part of the module, a Calishite merchant named Nabulee el Jasafir hires the PCs to investigate the death of a Waterdhavian noble.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>The Man in the Street</name>
        <text>When you&#39;re ready to begin the adventure, read or paraphrase the text below.

It’s the middle of the afternoon. As you’re walking in the Raging Bull District of the bustling city of Waterdeep, you’re startled by loud screams of agony and terror. 
When you look to see where they came from, you see a young man wearing the latest fashion trend convulsing on the floor, his pants stained with blood. 
Another man of lower status is trying to save him, yelling for help, but to no avail. 
The young noble stops moving, and shortly after, a beetle-shaped creature drills out of his chest in a burst of gore and blood.

Nothing short of a wish spell can save the noble. Once the young man is dead, the PCs only have a small amount of time to inspect his body or talk to his domestic servant before Nabulee el Jasafir storms out of a nearby mansion to see what happened.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Inspecting the Body</name>
        <text>The cause of death is pretty obvious: a scarab- shaped construct dug through the young man&#39;s belt pouch and into his waist, drilled its way to the heart, and then burst out of his chest. Once out of the body, the creature reverted back to being an inanimate beetle-shaped brooch.
  The Scarab of Death. On a successful DC 14 Intelligence (Arcana) check, a character learns that the brooch is in fact a cursed item called
a scarab of death. On a successful check, the PC also knows how to safely store the pin (see "Scarab of Death" on page 28).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Talking to the Servant</name>
        <text>The man who tried to save the noble is called Liam Roogs. If the PCs talk to him, they learn the following:
     He says his name is Liam Roogs.
    He&#39;s a domestic servant working for the Littlehorn family. The young man who just died was his master, Aaron.
    He doesn&#39;t know what happened. It appears that the scarab-shaped brooch lying on young Aaron&#39;s chest turned into a nightmarish creature and killed him.
    Aaron found the brooch in the auction room of Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary (he points at a nearby mansion when mentioning the name of the place). It was on the floor, just a few feet away from where they were sitting.
    Aaron&#39;s behavior was odd. He noticed the scarab early during the auction, but he waited until everyone left to pick it up. Aaron was
an honest person, but he seemed intent on stealing the brooch.
    A few minutes after they left the auction house, Aaron started to scream and fell to the ground. He convulsed for a brief moment, and then the scarab burst out of his chest.
    To his knowledge, the Littlehorns don&#39;t have any enemies. He suggests taking to
Lord Archibald Littlehorn if the PCs wish to learn more about the family&#39;s business (see "Archibald Littlehorn" on page 8).
        </text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Nabulee el Jasafir</name>
        <text>Nabulee el Jasafir is the owner of Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary. He storms out of his mansion and rushes to the scene shortly after hearing Aaron scream, probably interrupting the PCs in their conversation with Liam.
  When you&#39;re ready to introduce Nabulee, read or paraphrase the following:

An overweight, eccentric-looking man with 
scruffy fiery hair bursts out of a nearby 
mansion and runs toward you with a 
preoccupied look. He’s wearing a blue tunic embroidered with silver and matching pants, 
and is holding a gold-inlaid scepter shaped as a dragon. After taking a moment to catch his breath, he gazes at the scarab on the noble’s chest and sighs.

Nabulee immediately understands that the brooch that killed Aaron is a scarab of death and that this particular one is supposed to be in his extradimensional vault. He knows who the noble is, and that his father, Archibald, has the reputation of being ruthless with those who do him harm. Fortunately, Nabulee also recognizes the PCs and knows what they&#39;re capable of. He tells them the following:
    His name is Nabulee el Jasafir. He&#39;s a merchant from the desert city of Calimport. He owns a nearby auction house called Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary.
    The young man who just died is the youngest son of the Littlehorn family, Aaron. The aristocrat was in his auction house a few minutes ago.
    The brooch that killed the noble is a scarab of death. He&#39;s pretty sure that this one belongs to him, but he doesn&#39;t know how Aaron could have acquired it. This brooch is supposed to be safely stored in an extradimensional vault that only he can access.
    Aaron&#39;s father, Archibald, is a ruthless man. Lord Littlehorn will want someone to blame, and he&#39;ll make sure this person loses his head.
    He doesn&#39;t want to die for something he didn&#39;t do. He&#39;s absolutely certain he didn&#39;t take the scarab of death out of his vault, even accidentally. If he had picked up the cursed brooch without taking special precautions, he would also be dead.
    He begs the PCs to look into the matter. He offers them a magic item from his vault in exchange for their help.
Nabulee&#39;s Suggestions
If the characters accept Nabulee&#39;s work proposition, he tells them the following:
    Constable Bernard Kothont, the person in charge of law enforcement in the Raging Bull District, is a good friend of his. Considering the PCs&#39; reputation, he shouldn&#39;t have any trouble convincing the constable to let them conduct the investigation on behalf of the city watch.
    Archibald Littlehorn will be more problematic. He&#39;s a capricious but influential man. Nabulee doubts the noble will give the PCs enough time to conduct a thorough investigation. He believes Archibald will have him arrested before the end of the day, and that he&#39;ll lose his head before sunrise.

    He recommends going to Archibald&#39;s mansion to try to negotiate some kind of truce, but he&#39;s open to other ideas to get the aristocrat out of the way.
    He suggests that the adventurers first gather whatever supplies they might need for the job and make sure that Archibald doesn&#39;t bother them.
    He&#39;ll be waiting for them at his house. When they&#39;re ready, he would like to take them to the vault so that they may see for themselves how unlikely the circumstances of Aaron&#39;s death are.

Development
If the PCs wish to first make sure they have enough time to complete their investigation before Archibald Littlehorn intervenes, please proceed to "Securing the Job" below. If the adventurers would rather go to the vault with Nabulee or start their inquest, please proceed to "Part 2: The Investigation").

Nabulee el Jasafir 
Nabulee is an overweight merchant from the desert city of Calimport. He has tan skin and scruffy, fiery hair, suggesting that the blood of an efreeti flows through his veins (he’s a fire genasi). Nabulee was born in a poor family, and spent most of his youth selling trinkets in a bazaar. His luck turned when an adventurer died of a heart attack in his shop. He stole everything that person had and fled to Waterdeep. When he arrived there, he realized that the nobles were willing to pay good money for the magic items he had taken off the adventurer’s corpse, and later opened Nabulee’s Bazaar of the Extraordinary. Nabulee didn’t receive a proper education. He’s barely literate and lacks vocabulary, which make him self-conscious. He tries to impress others with extravagant clothing and complicated vocabulary, but always gets the words wrong.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Interrogating Aaron</name>
        <text>If the PCs have the speak with dead spell prepared, they can use it to interrogate Aaron. They learn the following:
    His name is Aaron. He&#39;s the youngest son of Lord Archibald Littlehorn.
    He found the scarab-shaped brooch that killed him on the floor, in Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary.
    He wanted to give the brooch to Raferny Tchazzam, a noble girl that he&#39;s courting.
    He admits that he stole the scarab. His father is always complaining about how much money he spends, and he didn&#39;t have the heart to ask Archibald for money to buy the scarab.
    He doesn&#39;t have any enemies who would want to kill him, and to his knowledge, neither does his father.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Bringing Aaron Back to Life</name>
        <text>Some PCs will try to bring Aaron back to life with a raise dead spell or similar magic, hoping that it would solve the problem. Alas, resurrecting Aaron is not so easy. When Archibald was young, he didn&#39;t want to
have children and signed a contract with an otherworldly being; the creature would help him become rich in exchange for the souls of his children when they die. Any attempt to bring Aaron back to life fails.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Securing the Job</name>
        <text>Before the PCs begin their investigation, they
first need to make sure that Archibald Littlehorn won&#39;t get in their way. The purpose of this part is to give the PCs a strong incentive to help Nabulee and to put pressure on them so that they complete the adventure in a timely manner. You can find below some suggestions as to how the adventurers might achieve this.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Archibald Littlehorn</name>
        <text>	The easiest way to make sure Archibald Littlehorn doesn&#39;t intervene is to negotiate with him. The noble owns a mansion in the Castle Ward, just a few blocks away from Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary. Aaron&#39;s father
is overcome by grief when he learns that his son died. Ever since his first child was born, Archibald has been trying, in vain, to undo the pact that he made with the otherworldly being when he was young (see "Bringing Aaron Back to Life" on page 8). He knows Aaron is gone for good, and he wants the head of the person responsible for his son&#39;s death.
Petitioning for Time
If Archibald learns that Aaron died because of Nabulee&#39;s scarab of death, he&#39;ll hold the Calishite responsible for it. Fortunately, Lord Littlehorn won&#39;t believe Nabulee did it on purpose. He&#39;ll assume it was an accident but he&#39;ll still want to see him dead. He&#39;ll give the PCs until the sun sets on the following day before he involves the local authorities.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Gaining More Time</name>
        <text>Archibald doesn&#39;t want to come out as a wrathful tyrant in front of the PCs. He knows them by reputation and wants to make a positive impression. If he ever finds out where the otherworldly entity took Aaron&#39;s soul, he might need their help to recover it.
  If the characters present reasonable arguments to Archibald, they can make a DC 14 Charisma (Persuasion) check to convince the patriarch to give them an extra day to find out what happened to his son. No matter what the adventurers say
or do, Lord Littlehorn doesn&#39;t give them more than two days. He wants their help but he&#39;s also longing for revenge.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Talking to Archibald</name>
        <text>The PCs might take advantage of being with Archibald to ask him questions about his family or to talk more about what happened to Aaron. He tells the characters the following:
    He owns an important merchant house and recently rose to nobility.
    He has many envious competitors, but he doesn&#39;t believe any of them would kill Aaron because none of them would have anything to gain from his son&#39;s death.
    The adventurers won&#39;t be able to bring Aaron back to life because of something he did when he was younger (he doesn&#39;t want to tell them about his pact with the otherworldly being).
    He believes Nabulee was careless and left a dangerous magic item out of his sight.
    He can&#39;t fathom the idea of never seeing his son again. He wants revenge and he will get.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    The Cover Up</name>
        <text>The PCs can also cover up Aaron&#39;s death. In this case, they need to make sure Liam Roogs doesn&#39;t talk to Archibald, and that Lord Littlehorn can&#39;t interrogate his son with a speak with dead
spell. As long as the PCs don&#39;t mutilate Aaron&#39;s body and don&#39;t do anything illegal (like killing or detaining Liam Roogs), Nabulee helps them with their endeavor as best as he can.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Liam Roogs</name>
        <text>Liam Roogs is the only person who knows that Aaron found the scarab of death in Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary. If the PCs manage to convince Liam not to talk to anyone about what happened to Aaron, it will take Archibald Littlehorn until the next day at dawn to break the domestic servant and get him to confess everything. If the PCs haven&#39;t completed the adventure by then, it will be too late to negotiate with Archibald. The noble will have Nabulee arrested that very night, and the Calishite will lose his head the following morning.
  Persuading Liam. Liam Roogs is a coward, and he&#39;s afraid of what Archibald might do to him if he lies. The characters need to give Liam sufficient guarantees that he won&#39;t get into trouble to convince him to cooperate. The PCs also need to succeed on a DC 20 Charisma (Persuasion) check. On a failed check, Liam tells the characters that he&#39;s too scared to lie to his master.
  Intimidating Liam. The adventurers can also threaten to hurt Liam if he doesn&#39;t keep his mouth shut. The PCs need to succeed on a DC 14 Charisma (Intimidation) to do so. On a failed check, the domestic servant swears he
won&#39;t say anything and goes straight to Archibald afterward. The characters are entitled to a DC 13 Wisdom (Insight) check to notice that their intimidation attempt failed. If they don&#39;t do anything about it, Nabulee is arrested an hour later and is beheaded the next day at sunrise. Archibald will use spells such as locate object
to find his son&#39;s body, so the PCs need to take special precautions. Fortunately, most divination spells don&#39;t work across different planes of existence, so hiding Aaron&#39;s body in Nabulee&#39;s extradimensional vault is good enough to make sure Archibald doesn&#39;t find it.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Other Ways</name>
        <text>There are many other ways the PCs can cover up what happened to Aaron. Unfortunately, Archibald is a very resourceful man. He&#39;ll quickly learn that Aaron was last seen leaving Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary, and then use spells such as commune to learn that Nabulee is tied to his son&#39;s death. You should assume that a cover-up will give the PCs at most two days, after which Archibald has the Calishite arrested and executed on the next day.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Failing to Secure the Job</name>
        <text>The PCs will fail to secure the job either because their cover-up didn&#39;t work (for example, because they failed to intimidate Liam Roogs), or because they didn&#39;t bother talking to Archibald first. In the former case, Lord Littlehorn has the Calishite arrested immediately, and executed at sunrise
on the next day (he uses his influence to expedite the trial). In the latter, Archibald comes to Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary and asks for an explanation. At that time, the characters will have a chance to negotiate with Lord Littlehorn, but they&#39;ll have disadvantage on their Charisma (Persuasion) check to obtain more time (see "Petitioning for Time" above).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Returning to the Bazaar</name>
        <text>If the PCs leave Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the
Extraordinary to secure the job or gather supplies, they find Nabulee pacing up and down in the lobby when they get back. If the
characters haven&#39;t started their investigation yet, he suggests going to the vault to make sure that it was his scarab of death that killed Aaron (see "A3. The Vault Room" on page 13).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
    </adventure>
    <adventure>
      <uid>4359</uid>
      <name>Part 2: The Investigation</name>
      <npc>
        <uid>4366</uid>
        <label>Mugabu</label>
        <name>Iron Golem</name>
        <size>3</size>
        <type>construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <abilities>24,9,20,7,11,1,</abilities>
        <hpMax>210</hpMax>
        <hpCurrent>210</hpCurrent>
        <hd>20d10+100</hd>
        <ac>20</ac>
        <armor>natural armor</armor>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <immune>fire, poison, psychic; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren&#39;t adamantine</immune>
        <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, frightened, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
        <languages>Common</languages>
        <cr>16</cr>
        <trait>
          <name>Source</name>
          <text>Monster Manual p. 170</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Fire Absorption</name>
          <text>Whenever the golem is subjected to fire damage, it takes no damage and instead regains a number of hit points equal to the fire damage dealt.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Immutable Form</name>
          <text>The golem is immune to any spell or effect that would alter its form.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Magic Resistance</name>
          <text>The golem has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Magic Weapons</name>
          <text>The golem&#39;s weapon attacks are magical.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
          <name>Multiattack</name>
          <text>The golem makes two melee attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
          <name>Slam</name>
          <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +13 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 20 (3d8+7) bludgeoning damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <name>Slam</name>
            <atk>13</atk>
            <dmg>3d8+7</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <action>
          <name>Sword</name>
          <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +13 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 23 (3d10+7) slashing damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <name>Sword</name>
            <atk>13</atk>
            <dmg>3d10+7</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <action>
          <name>Poison Breath (Recharge 5-6)</name>
          <text>The golem exhales poisonous gas in a 15-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 19 Constitution saving throw, taking 45 (10d8) poison damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
          <attack>
            <name>Poison Breath</name>
            <dmg>10d8</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <text>Mugabu guards A3 The Vault room and is sentient but Nabulee forgets to share this piece of information with the adventurers. If the PCs notice this on their own, they can interrogate Mugabu to learn the following:

     He says his name is Mugabu.

    He&#39;s an experimental iron golem from Halruaa.

    His job is to defend the vault. Nabulee told him to stay here and attack anyone who goes down the stairs.

    Nobody, other than Nabulee, came to the extradimensional safe these past days.

The Calishite came to the vault once in the morning and multiple times in the afternoon to recover various items.</text>
      </npc>
      <npc>
        <uid>4367</uid>
        <label>Jasmin Metalwart</label>
        <name>Housekeeper</name>
        <type>humanoid (Dwarf)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
        <hpMax>4</hpMax>
        <hpCurrent>4</hpCurrent>
        <hd>1d8</hd>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
        <cr>-3</cr>
        <trait>
          <name>Source</name>
          <text>Monster Manual p. 345, Lost Laboratory of Kwalish p. 38, Dragon of Icespire Peak p. 55</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
          <name>Club</name>
          <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <atk>2</atk>
            <dmg>1d4</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <text>Jasmin Metalwart is a lazy old dwarf who has been working as a housekeeper for Nabulee for a decade. She recently acquired a ring of reduction (see "Appendix I: Monsters and Magic Items"), and she is now using it to discreetly take naps in the less accessible parts of the mansion during work hours. She was sleeping in the broom closet under the stairs when Mortimer paid Nabulee a visit in the morning, and overheard their conversation. If the PCs interrogate her, they learn the following:
    She says her name is Jasmin Metalwart.
    She started working for Nabulee as a housekeeper shortly after he arrived from Calimport.
    She spent most of her morning cleaning the auction room and the lobby.
    A man came to see Nabulee in the morning. At that time, she was getting cleaning supplies in the broom closet under the stairs. She didn&#39;t see who it was.

    She overheard their conversation. The man sounded angry at Nabulee. He said something about not being paid enough. Nabulee then asked him to keep his voice down and invited him to his office. They then went upstairs, but she doesn&#39;t know what happened after that.

    She didn&#39;t hear or see anything else out of the ordinary that morning. (She vaguely heard the flesh golem storming out the house, but the noise wasn&#39;t unusual enough for her to remember it.)</text>
        <environment>1087</environment>
      </npc>
      <npc>
        <uid>4368</uid>
        <label>Ronald Walrut</label>
        <name>Butler</name>
        <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
        <hpMax>4</hpMax>
        <hpCurrent>4</hpCurrent>
        <hd>1d8</hd>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
        <cr>-3</cr>
        <trait>
          <name>Source</name>
          <text>Monster Manual p. 345, Lost Laboratory of Kwalish p. 38, Dragon of Icespire Peak p. 55</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
          <name>Club</name>
          <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <atk>2</atk>
            <dmg>1d4</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <text>The butler is a skinny, stern-looking half-elf in his mid-forties named Ronald Walrut. The PCs can talk to Ronald and learn the following:

     He says his name is Ronald Walrut.

    He&#39;s been working at Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary as a butler for a couple of years now.

    He was out all morning running errands. He only got back to the house shortly before the afternoon&#39;s auction.

    Something unusual happened this morning. He saw Nabulee running through the streets of the Raging Bull District, a couple of blocks away from the auction house. He&#39;s pretty sure his shirt was stained with blood. (Ronald saw Mortimer&#39;s flesh golem running away; it had blood on its shirt because the scarab of death burst out of its chest in the auction room.)

    This wasn&#39;t the weirdest thing, though. Nabulee was wearing a purple Valentina tunic (Valentina is the name of Nabulee&#39;s tailor). The Calishite is notorious in the neighborhood for his poor taste in clothing, but that shirt was really over the top.

    He spent the beginning of the afternoon ushering clients and standing by the door.

    He didn&#39;t see anything unusual during the auction.</text>
        <environment>1087</environment>
      </npc>
      <npc>
        <uid>4369</uid>
        <label>Murphy Stormwind</label>
        <name>Sorcerer</name>
        <type>humanoid (human)</type>
        <alignment>chaotic good</alignment>
        <abilities>8,14,10,16,13,12,</abilities>
        <hpMax>36</hpMax>
        <hpCurrent>36</hpCurrent>
        <hd>8d8</hd>
        <ac>12</ac>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <savingThrow>
          <ability>3</ability>
          <modifier>2</modifier>
        </savingThrow>
        <savingThrow>
          <ability>4</ability>
          <modifier>2</modifier>
        </savingThrow>
        <skill>
          <id>2</id>
          <modifier>2</modifier>
        </skill>
        <skill>
          <id>8</id>
          <modifier>2</modifier>
        </skill>
        <skill>
          <id>11</id>
          <modifier>2</modifier>
        </skill>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Common, Elvish</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <slots>0,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
        <slotsCurrent>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
        <trait>
          <name>Spellcasting</name>
          <text>Murphy is a 4th-level spellcaster. His spellcasting ability is Intelligence (spell save DC 13, +5 to hit with spell attacks).</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
          <name>Dagger</name>
          <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4 + 1) piercing damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <name>Dagger</name>
            <atk>4</atk>
            <dmg>1d4</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <spell>
          <name>Burning Hands</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <level>1</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Self (15-foot cone)</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>As you hold your hands with thumbs touching and fingers spread, a thin sheet of flames shoots forth from your outstretched fingertips. Each creature in a 15-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren&#39;t being worn or carried.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 220</text>
          <roll>3d6</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Genie Efreeti)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Charm Person</name>
          <school>4</school>
          <level>1</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>30 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>1 hour</duration>
          <text>You attempt to charm a humanoid you can see within range. It must make a Wisdom saving throw, and does so with advantage if you or your companions are fighting it. If it fails the saving throw, it is charmed by you until the spell ends or until you or your companions do anything harmful to it. The charmed creature regards you as a friendly acquaintance. When the spell ends, the creature knows it was charmed by you.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 221</text>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Druid</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Fire Bolt</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>120 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>You hurl a mote of fire at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 fire damage. A flammable object hit by this spell ignites if it isn&#39;t being worn or carried.
	This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 242</text>
          <roll>1d10</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Light</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Touch</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a firefly or phosphorescent moss</materials>
          <duration>1 hour</duration>
          <text>You touch one object that is no larger than 10 feet in any dimension. Until the spell ends, the object sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light can be colored as you like. Completely covering the object with something opaque blocks the light. The spell ends if you cast it again or dismiss it as an action.
	If you target an object held or worn by a hostile creature, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw to avoid the spell.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 255</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Locate Object</name>
          <school>3</school>
          <level>2</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Self</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a forked twig</materials>
          <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
          <text>Describe or name an object that is familiar to you. You sense the direction to the object&#39;s location, as long as that object is within 1,000 feet of you. If the object is in motion, you know the direction of its movement.
	The spell can locate a specific object known to you, as long as you have seen it up close — within 30 feet — at least once. Alternatively, the spell can locate the nearest object of a particular kind, such as a certain kind of apparel, jewelry, furniture, tool, or weapon.
	This spell can&#39;t locate an object if any thickness of lead, even a thin sheet, blocks a direct path between you and the object.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 256</text>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
          <sclass>Druid</sclass>
          <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
          <sclass>Ranger</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Message</name>
          <school>8</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>120 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a short piece of copper wire</materials>
          <duration>1 round</duration>
          <text>You point your finger toward a creature within range and whisper a message. The target (and only the target) hears the message and can reply in a whisper that only you can hear.
	You can cast this spell through solid objects if you are familiar with the target and know it is beyond the barrier. Magical silence, 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood blocks the spell. The spell doesn&#39;t have to follow a straight line and can travel freely around corners or through openings.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 259</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Minor Illusion</name>
          <school>6</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>30 feet</range>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a bit of fleece</materials>
          <duration>1 minute</duration>
          <text>You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration. The illusion also ends if you dismiss it as an action or cast this spell again.
	If you create a sound, its volume can range from a whisper to a scream. It can be your voice, someone else&#39;s voice, a lion&#39;s roar, a beating of drums, or any other sound you choose. The sound continues unabated throughout the duration, or you can make discrete sounds at different times before the spell ends.
	If you create an image of an object, such as a chair, muddy footprints, or a small chest, it must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. The image can&#39;t create sound, light, smell, or any other sensory effect. Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it.
	If a creature uses its action to examine the sound or image, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 260</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Scorching Ray</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <level>2</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>120 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>You create three rays of fire and hurl them at targets within range. You can hurl them at one target or several.
	Make a ranged spell attack for each ray. On a hit, the target takes 2d6 fire damage.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you create one additional ray for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 273</text>
          <roll>2d6</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Genie Efreeti)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>See Invisibility</name>
          <school>3</school>
          <level>2</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Self</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>A pinch of Talc and a small sprinkling of powdered silver</materials>
          <duration>1 hour</duration>
          <text>For the duration, you see invisible creatures and objects as if they were visible, and you can see into the Ethereal Plane. Ethereal creatures and objects appear ghostly and translucent.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 274</text>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Shield</name>
          <school>1</school>
          <level>1</level>
          <time>1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack or targeted by the magic missile spell</time>
          <range>Self</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>1 round</duration>
          <text>An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 275</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Hexblade)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Sleep</name>
          <school>4</school>
          <level>1</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>90 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a pinch of find sand, rose petals, or a cricket</materials>
          <duration>1 minute</duration>
          <text>This spell sends creatures into a magical slumber. Roll 5d8, the total is how many hit points of creatures this spell can affect. Creatures within 20 feet of a point you choose within range are affected in ascending order of their current hit points (ignoring unconscious creatures).
	Starting with the creature that has the lowest current hit points, each creature affected by this spell falls unconscious until the spell ends, the sleeper takes damage, or someone uses an action to shake or slap the sleeper awake. Subtract each creature&#39;s hit points from the total before moving on to the creature with the next lowest hit points. A creature&#39;s hit points must be equal to or less than the remaining total for that creature to be affected.
	Undead and creatures immune to being charmed aren&#39;t affected by this spell.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, roll an additional 2d8 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 276</text>
          <roll>5d8</roll>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <text>Murphy Stormwind is an opportunistic wizard who takes advantage of the nobles’ negligence to make a small fortune recovering their lost items. He can hold his own in a fight but heavoids them when possible.</text>
        <environment>1024</environment>
      </npc>
      <npc>
        <uid>4370</uid>
        <label>Bernard Kothont</label>
        <enemy>1</enemy>
        <name>Veteran</name>
        <type>humanoid (human)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <abilities>16,13,14,10,11,10,</abilities>
        <hpMax>58</hpMax>
        <hpCurrent>58</hpCurrent>
        <hd>9d8+18</hd>
        <ac>17</ac>
        <armor>splint</armor>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <skill>
          <id>3</id>
          <modifier>5</modifier>
        </skill>
        <skill>
          <id>11</id>
          <modifier>2</modifier>
        </skill>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
        <cr>3</cr>
        <trait>
          <name>Source</name>
          <text>Monster Manual p. 350, Dragon of Icespire Peak p. 63</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
          <name>Multiattack</name>
          <text>The veteran makes two longsword attacks. If it has a shortsword drawn, it can also make a shortsword attack.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
          <name>Longsword</name>
          <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8+3) slashing damage, or 8 (1d10+3) slashing damage if used with two hands.</text>
          <attack>
            <atk>5</atk>
            <dmg>1d8+3</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <action>
          <name>Shortsword</name>
          <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) piercing damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <atk>5</atk>
            <dmg>1d6+3</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <action>
          <name>Heavy Crossbow</name>
          <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d10+1) piercing damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <atk>3</atk>
            <dmg>1d10+1</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <text>Bernard Kothont is the person in charge of law enforcement in the Raging Bull district, and a good friend of Nabulee&#39;s. He&#39;s extremely
disappointed with the PCs, and summons them to see if he can assist them in their investigation. If the characters go to the belfry, the guards bring them to Bernard&#39;s office.</text>
        <environment>1403</environment>
      </npc>
      <encounter>
        <name>The Arrest</name>
        <uid>4374</uid>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4362</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4363</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4370</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Guard 1</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Guard</name>
            <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
            <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
            <abilities>13,12,12,10,11,10,</abilities>
            <hpMax>11</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent>
            <hd>2d8+2</hd>
            <ac>16</ac>
            <armor>chain shirt, shield</armor>
            <speed>30 ft.</speed>
            <skill>
              <id>11</id>
              <modifier>2</modifier>
            </skill>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
            <cr>-2</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 347</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Spear</name>
              <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) piercing damage or 5 (1d8+1) piercing damage if used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d6+1</dmg>
              </attack>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear (Two-Handed)</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d8+1</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1150</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Guard 2</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Guard</name>
            <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
            <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
            <abilities>13,12,12,10,11,10,</abilities>
            <hpMax>11</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent>
            <hd>2d8+2</hd>
            <ac>16</ac>
            <armor>chain shirt, shield</armor>
            <speed>30 ft.</speed>
            <skill>
              <id>11</id>
              <modifier>2</modifier>
            </skill>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
            <cr>-2</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 347</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Spear</name>
              <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) piercing damage or 5 (1d8+1) piercing damage if used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d6+1</dmg>
              </attack>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear (Two-Handed)</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d8+1</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1150</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Guard 3</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Guard</name>
            <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
            <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
            <abilities>13,12,12,10,11,10,</abilities>
            <hpMax>11</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent>
            <hd>2d8+2</hd>
            <ac>16</ac>
            <armor>chain shirt, shield</armor>
            <speed>30 ft.</speed>
            <skill>
              <id>11</id>
              <modifier>2</modifier>
            </skill>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
            <cr>-2</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 347</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Spear</name>
              <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) piercing damage or 5 (1d8+1) piercing damage if used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d6+1</dmg>
              </attack>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear (Two-Handed)</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d8+1</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1150</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Guard 4</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Guard</name>
            <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
            <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
            <abilities>13,12,12,10,11,10,</abilities>
            <hpMax>11</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent>
            <hd>2d8+2</hd>
            <ac>16</ac>
            <armor>chain shirt, shield</armor>
            <speed>30 ft.</speed>
            <skill>
              <id>11</id>
              <modifier>2</modifier>
            </skill>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
            <cr>-2</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 347</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Spear</name>
              <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) piercing damage or 5 (1d8+1) piercing damage if used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d6+1</dmg>
              </attack>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear (Two-Handed)</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d8+1</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1150</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Guard 5</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Guard</name>
            <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
            <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
            <abilities>13,12,12,10,11,10,</abilities>
            <hpMax>11</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent>
            <hd>2d8+2</hd>
            <ac>16</ac>
            <armor>chain shirt, shield</armor>
            <speed>30 ft.</speed>
            <skill>
              <id>11</id>
              <modifier>2</modifier>
            </skill>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
            <cr>-2</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 347</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Spear</name>
              <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) piercing damage or 5 (1d8+1) piercing damage if used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d6+1</dmg>
              </attack>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear (Two-Handed)</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d8+1</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1150</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Guard 6</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Guard</name>
            <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
            <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
            <abilities>13,12,12,10,11,10,</abilities>
            <hpMax>11</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent>
            <hd>2d8+2</hd>
            <ac>16</ac>
            <armor>chain shirt, shield</armor>
            <speed>30 ft.</speed>
            <skill>
              <id>11</id>
              <modifier>2</modifier>
            </skill>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
            <cr>-2</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 347</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Spear</name>
              <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) piercing damage or 5 (1d8+1) piercing damage if used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d6+1</dmg>
              </attack>
              <attack>
                <name>Spear (Two-Handed)</name>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d8+1</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1150</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Sarge </label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Veteran</name>
            <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
            <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
            <abilities>16,13,14,10,11,10,</abilities>
            <hpMax>58</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>58</hpCurrent>
            <hd>9d8+18</hd>
            <ac>17</ac>
            <armor>splint</armor>
            <speed>30 ft.</speed>
            <skill>
              <id>3</id>
              <modifier>5</modifier>
            </skill>
            <skill>
              <id>11</id>
              <modifier>2</modifier>
            </skill>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>any one language (usually Common)</languages>
            <cr>3</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 350, Dragon of Icespire Peak p. 63</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Multiattack</name>
              <text>The veteran makes two longsword attacks. If it has a shortsword drawn, it can also make a shortsword attack.</text>
            </action>
            <action>
              <name>Longsword</name>
              <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8+3) slashing damage, or 8 (1d10+3) slashing damage if used with two hands.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>5</atk>
                <dmg>1d8+3</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <action>
              <name>Shortsword</name>
              <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) piercing damage.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>5</atk>
                <dmg>1d6+3</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <action>
              <name>Heavy Crossbow</name>
              <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d10+1) piercing damage.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>3</atk>
                <dmg>1d10+1</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1403</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
      </encounter>
      <note>
        <name>Introduction</name>
        <text>In this part of the adventure, the characters search for clues that might help them understand how Aaron acquired the scarab of death. The key to solving this mystery is to find discrepancies between what Nabulee remembers and what
the evidence suggests. The PCs should then understand that someone used a spell to alter Nabulee&#39;s memories, which will lead them to Mortimer Yorman. Clever PCs might also find a way to track down the person who entered
Nabulee&#39;s extradimensional vault in the morning. This will also lead them to Mortimer&#39;s house.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Interrogating the Staff</name>
        <text>If the characters interrogate the people working
at the auction house, they learn that Nabulee got into an argument with someone in the morning and that one of his employees spotted him in the streets wearing a bloodied shirt.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    The Housekeeper</name>
        <text>Jasmin Metalwart is a lazy old dwarf who has been working as a housekeeper for Nabulee for a decade. She recently acquired a ring of reduction (see "Appendix I: Monsters and Magic Items"), and she is now using it to discreetly take naps in the less accessible parts of the mansion during work hours. She was sleeping in the broom closet under the stairs when Mortimer paid Nabulee a visit in the morning, and overheard their conversation. If the PCs interrogate her, they learn the following:
    She says her name is Jasmin Metalwart.
    She started working for Nabulee as a housekeeper shortly after he arrived from Calimport.
    She spent most of her morning cleaning the auction room and the lobby.
    A man came to see Nabulee in the morning. At that time, she was getting cleaning supplies in the broom closet under the stairs. She didn&#39;t see who it was.

    She overheard their conversation. The man sounded angry at Nabulee. He said something about not being paid enough. Nabulee then asked him to keep his voice down and invited him to his office. They then went upstairs, but she doesn&#39;t know what happened after that.

    She didn&#39;t hear or see anything else out of the ordinary that morning. (She vaguely heard the flesh golem storming out the house, but the noise wasn&#39;t unusual enough for her to remember it.)
  Reading Jasmin. The well-respected dwarf isn&#39;t being completely honest with the PCs; she was taking a nap in the broom closet, and she&#39;s afraid the adventurers might find out about it. The PCs can make a DC 12 Wisdom (Insight) check to notice that she&#39;s holding something back during the conversation. The characters can then make a DC 15 Charisma check (with the appropriate skill) to persuade her to tell the truth. This doesn&#39;t have any effect on the
adventure but it allows the PCs to learn that she possesses a ring of reduction which she gladly sells for 5,000 gp.

Confronting Nabulee
If Nabulee is present when Jasmin tells the PCs about Mortimer&#39;s visit in the morning or if the characters seek him out after talking to the housekeeper, he defends himself as follows:
    He spent all morning alone in his office doing paperwork.
    He&#39;s absolutely certain he was alone. He can&#39;t explain why Jasmin says he met someone in the morning.
    He says he has a very good memory, and that he wouldn&#39;t have forgotten something like this.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    The Butler</name>
        <text>The butler is a skinny, stern-looking half-elf in his mid-forties named Ronald Walrut. The PCs can talk to Ronald and learn the following:
     He says his name is Ronald Walrut.
    He&#39;s been working at Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary as a butler for a couple of years now.
    He was out all morning running errands. He only got back to the house shortly before the afternoon&#39;s auction.
    Something unusual happened this morning. He saw Nabulee running through the streets of the Raging Bull District, a couple of blocks away from the auction house. He&#39;s pretty sure his shirt was stained with blood. (Ronald saw Mortimer&#39;s flesh golem running away; it had blood on its shirt because the scarab of death burst out of its chest in the auction room.)
    This wasn&#39;t the weirdest thing, though. Nabulee was wearing a purple Valentina tunic (Valentina is the name of Nabulee&#39;s tailor). The Calishite is notorious in the neighborhood for his poor taste in clothing, but that shirt was really over the top.
    He spent the beginning of the afternoon ushering clients and standing by the door.
    He didn&#39;t see anything unusual during the auction.

Confronting Nabulee
If Nabulee is present when Ronald tells the PCs that he saw him running in the streets or if the characters seek the merchant out after talking to the butler, he defends himself as follows:
    He spent all morning in his office doing paperwork, and only left it to conduct the afternoon&#39;s auction.
    He doesn&#39;t know why Ronald Walrut says he saw him running in the streets when he was at home.
    He would never wear something as distasteful as a purple Valentina tunic!
    Jasmin spent all morning cleaning the auction room and the lobby. If he had left the house, she would have seen him.
    Jasmin can also testify that he was in his office. She came to pick up some dirty glasses shortly before noon ( Jasmin confirms this).
The Clone Golem
Tracking down the flesh golem that Ronald saw in the streets isn&#39;t impossible but it&#39;s tricky. If the PCs try to locate the construct after talking to the butler, please proceed to "The Clone Golem" on page 18.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>The Auction House</name>
        <text>Nabulee lives in a large house in the Raging
Bull District from where he runs his magic item auctions. The interior of the place is luxurious, and has many magical trinkets which are meant to impress his clients.
  In this part of the adventure, the PCs search Nabulee&#39;s house for clues that might shed some light on what happened to Aaron. Additional information is provide in case the characters decide to rob the place.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    General Features</name>
        <text>Nabulee&#39;s mansion has the following features. Any exceptions are noted in the areas to which they apply.
  Light. During daylight hours, sunlight keeps the house properly lit. Continual flame spells illuminate the house at night.
  Windows. Nabulee&#39;s house has glass windows that are all barred. A character can try to bend the metal bars and sneak into the house with
a successful DC 15 Strength check (a PC with

a crowbar has advantage on this check). If the adventurers don&#39;t take any precautions to
muffle the sound when smashing the windows, nearby creatures can make a DC 13 Wisdom (Perception) check to hear the glass shattering.
  Doors. The doors are made of wood and are normally unlocked.
  Defenders. Nabulee el Jasafir will go to see what happened if he hears suspicious noises in his house, but he&#39;ll escape with a dimension door spell to the vault at the slightest sign of danger, and come back with his iron golem to drive intruders out.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A1. Lobby</name>
        <text>If the characters accept Nabulee&#39;s tour of the house, he proudly explains that he hired one of the best interior decorators of Waterdeep to imagine a perfect blend of Calishite and Waterdhavian styles. He tells them that the
lanterns and the mosaics are typical of his home country, and that the grandiose marble stairs and the paintings are local.
  Treasure. The eight paintings in this room are worth 100 gp apiece to a collector. Removing each of the six lanterns from the walls takes about ten minutes. The characters can then sell them for 150 gp each.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A2. Auction Room</name>
        <text>If Nabulee is accompanying the PCs, he tells them that the two stained glass windows
are copies of the ones in the throne room of Calimport&#39;s royal palace.
  Treasure. The furniture and the stained glass are all of masterful quality. If the characters somehow manage to sneak them out of the house, they can sell the two windows for 250 gp each, and the five varnished pews 25 gp apiece.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A3. The Vault Room</name>
        <text>An iron golem named Mugabu (see "Monster Statistics" below) attacks anyone who tries to pass without Nabulee accompanying them. The merchant also placed a glyph of warding spell in the area with a cloudkill spell that goes off
if anyone else tries to cross the middle of the hallway.

  The arch filled with swirling orange-brown smoke is the portal that leads to Nabulee&#39;s extradimensional vault. Even if the PCs defeat the guardian and survive the magical trap, they&#39;ll quickly realize that they can&#39;t enter the safe, as only the Calishite can use the portal. Anyone else simply passes through the smoke.
  Monster Statistics. Mugabu is an iron golem with an Intelligence score of 7 instead of 3.
Mugabu also speaks Common, albeit in a robotic monotonous tone.

Entering with Nabulee
If the PCs enter the vault room with Nabulee, he first orders the golem to stand down, and then tells them the following:

    -The archway filled with swirling orange- brown smoke is a portal that leads to his extradimensional vault.

    -He&#39;s the only person who can use the portal; anyone else simply passes through.

    -There are over 100,000 gp worth of riches in the safe (he has an extremely satisfied look on his face when he shares this information).

    -His valuables are completely secure in the vault. It&#39;s protected against teleportation, and a magical ward negates charm spells and possessions within.

    -He instructed Mugabu to attack anyone who tries to approach the portal. This is aprecaution in case someone wants to destroy the gateway out of spite.


    He asks that the PCs wait there for a minute while he enters the vault to verify that his scarab of death is still in it. Nabulee then enters the safe and returns a few minutes later with a concerned look. He searched everywhere but couldn&#39;t find the scarab. He doesn&#39;t know how his scarab of death got out of the vault. He has a very good memory and he would remember taking it out; plus, it&#39;s not the type of item you casually pick up. The scarab of death would have killed him without special precautions!

    The only possible explanation is that someone snuck into the vault and took the deadly brooch out.
    Jasmin Metalwart, the housekeeper, spent all morning cleaning the auction room and the lobby. It&#39;s a long shot, but maybe she saw or heard something.
    Ronald Walrut, the butler, was attending to his clients in the afternoon. If someone entered the vault during the auction, he might have seen who it was.

  Identifying the Golem. 
If the characters enter the vault room with Nabulee, they have plenty of time to inspect the golem, and notice multiple unusual glyphs and magical symbolson the construct&#39;s body. The PCs can make a 
-DC 17 Intelligence (Arcana) check to understand that the golem is an experimental model from Halruaa, and to recall that these types of golems are sentient and capable of speech.

Talking to the Golem
Mugabu is sentient but Nabulee forgets to share this piece of information with the adventurers. If the PCs notice this on their own, they can interrogate Mugabu to learn the following:

     He says his name is Mugabu.

    He&#39;s an experimental iron golem from Halruaa.

    His job is to defend the vault. Nabulee told him to stay here and attack anyone who goes down the stairs.

    Nobody, other than Nabulee, came to the extradimensional safe these past days.

The Calishite came to the vault once in the morning and multiple times in the afternoon to recover various items.

Confronting Nabulee
When Mugabu tells the PCs that Nabulee went to the vault in the morning, the merchant defends himself as follows:
    He spent all morning in his office doing paperwork.
    He doesn&#39;t know why Mugabu says he went to the vault in the morning.
    He doesn&#39;t know how, but someone must have tricked the golem, found a way to avoid the magical traps, and entered the extradimensional vault.
    Jasmin spent all morning cleaning the auction room and the lobby. If anyone went to the vault, she would have seen him.
    He went multiple times to his extradimensional safe during the afternoon to recover the items that he sold during the auction. He never takes more than one item out at a time, to avoid thieves.
Tinkering with the Portal
Many adventurers won&#39;t believe that Nabulee&#39;s vault is impenetrable and will want to experiment with the portal to make sure it&#39;s as safe as the Calishite says it is. Nabulee
is absolutely thrilled with the idea of testing the security of his vault. He cooperates with
whatever plan the PCs might come up with, and even lets them use spells like dominate person on him.
Stealing Nabulee&#39;s Valuables
Stealing the Calishite&#39;s valuables is easier said than done. The characters will first need to coerce Nabulee el Jasafir to help them or somehow make a near-perfect duplicate of the Calishite. (At your discretion, there might be other ways to sneak into the extradimensional room.) The interior of the vault has a magical ward that suppresses charm spells and possessions (this includes spells such a

suggestion, charm person, dominate person, and magic jar), and that prevents anyone from teleporting inside the room (people can still teleport out of it).
  If the PCs somehow manage to enter the vault, they arrive in a small room with a simple wooden table, a chair, multiple small chests, and a large cabinet. The last has a magical alarm that notifies Nabulee whenever someone opens it. A PC who carefully examines the cabinet can make a DC 15 Intelligence (Arcana) check to notice the magical alarm; they can then make a
DC 20 Intelligence (Arcana) check to disarm it. A detect magic spell reveals the presence of a faint abjuration spell on the cabinet, and an antimagic field spell temporarily suppresses the magical alarm.
  Treasure. The small chests contain 1,500 sp, 5,800 gp, 450 pp, eight red tourmalines (100 gp each), two fire opals (1,000 gp each), a box of turquoise animal figurines worth 250 gp, and a silver and gold brooch worth 750 gp. The adventurers also find the following items in the
large cabinet: a gold cup set with emeralds worth 7,500 gp, the jeweled gold crown of King Uzmut III (7,500 gp), and all the magic items listed in "Solving the Mystery" on page 24.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A4. Dining Room</name>
        <text>Read
			
			 This dining room sits eight people. A large 
tapestry completely covers the southern wall, 
and a rustic chandelier with magical flames 
provides the lighting. A wooden cupboard 
containing porcelain dishes, crystal glasses, 
and silver cutlery leans against the northern 
wall

			There isn&#39;t anything of interest in the dining room other than the tapestry and the contents of the cupboard.
  Treasure. The large tapestry is twenty feet wide, ten feet high, and weighs about one hundred pounds. If the PCs manage to take it out of the house unnoticed, they can sell it for 500 gp. The dishes, the glasses, and the cutlery are worth 100 gp in total.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A5. Kitchen</name>
        <text>Read
			
			The kitchen is a total mess. Dirty dishes are 
piling up in the sink and the floor is filthy. You 
even notice a couple of cockroaches quickly 
running for shelter when you enter the room. 
The workspace is by far the worst offender. 
The table is covered in vegetable peels and 
pieces of meat, and someone stacked a silver 
platter with two crystal glasses on top of them.

 If Nabulee is with the PCs when they enter 
the kitchen, he quickly turns red with 
embarrassment and swears the place isn’t 
normally that disgusting.
 The Crystal Glasses. Mortimer and Nabulee 
had a drink in the office in the morning. Later 
that day, the housekeeper, Jasmin Metalwart, 
went to the office, picked up the dirty glasses, 
and left them in the kitchen. If the characters 
enquire about the glasses, they learn that 
Jasmin recovered them in Nabulee’s 
office shortly before noon.
 Once the adventurers know 
that the crystal glasses aren’t 
old dishes that Jasmin forgot 
to wash, you can call for a DC 
17 Intelligence (Investigation) 
check to have them notice that 
there are two glasses, which 
suggests that Nabulee wasn’t 
alone that morning. 
Confronting Nabulee
 If the PCs ask Nabulee why 
Jasmin found two glasses in 
his office, he tells them the 
following:
 -He admits that it’s very odd. 
He can’t explain why there 
are two glasses.
 -He has a very good memory but 
he can’t seem to remember when 
he had those drinks.
 -Jasmin came to his office the night before 
to put away the glasses she had washed 
in the afternoon. His set was complete and 
clean when he went to bed
 -The only explanation is that someone had drinks in his office during the night, and that he didn&#39;t notice the dirty glasses in the morning.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A6. Larder	</name>
        <text>If Nabulee is with the PCs when they enter the kitchen, he quickly turns red with embarrassment and swears the place isn&#39;t normally that disgusting.
  The Crystal Glasses. Mortimer and Nabulee had a drink in the office in the morning. Later that day, the housekeeper, Jasmin Metalwart, went to the office, picked up the dirty glasses, and left them in the kitchen. If the characters enquire about the glasses, they learn that Jasmin recovered them in Nabulee&#39;s
office shortly before noon.
  Once the adventurers know that the crystal glasses aren&#39;t old dishes that Jasmin forgot to wash, you can call for a DC 17 Intelligence (Investigation) check to have them notice that there are two glasses, which suggests that Nabulee wasn&#39;t alone that morning.
Confronting Nabulee
If the PCs ask Nabulee why Jasmin found two glasses in his office, he tells them the following:
    He admits that it&#39;s very odd. He can&#39;t explain why there are two glasses.
    He has a very good memory but he can&#39;t seem to remember when he had those drinks.
    Jasmin came to his office the night before to put away the glasses she had washed
in the afternoon. His set was complete and clean when he went to bed.

If Nabulee is accompanying the characters, he tells them that the fungus on the ceiling and the walls is a magical mold that feeds on heat and keeps the room cold.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A7. Stairwell</name>
        <text>The door to the third floor is sealed shut with an arcane lock spell. The only people who can open it are Nabulee, Jasmin, and Ronald. If the Calishite is with the characters, he explains the following:
    This door used to have a mundane lock, but he kept losing the key.
    Fortunately, Murphy Stormwind is a good friend of his, and he gave him a discount on his services.
    It was still expensive, and so he went to Blackstaff Tower, hoping they might have a solution to his problem.
    Nabulee wanted a magic item that can cast the locate object spell every now in then (this was the spell his friend used to find his key), but the wizards suggested putting an arcane lock on the door instead.
    Murphy Stormwind is a diviner who specializes in finding lost people and objects, especially wedding rings gone missing after a trip to the local brothel.
    They can find Murphy&#39;s shop in the Raging Bull district, a couple of blocks away from his home.
Development
Murphy Stormwind is a trump card that you can play if your players get stuck in the investigation. He can help the PCs find the clone golem who entered Nabulee&#39;s vault in the morning (see "Lord Find-It-All" on page 18).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A8. Storage Room</name>
        <text>

This ordinary storage room contains tools, planks of wood, fur blankets, and other basic supplies.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A9. The Office</name>
        <text>Mortimer and Nabulee were having a conversation in the office when the flesh golem triggered the alarm in the extradimensional vault. When Nabulee asked Mortimer to leave the house, the necromancer understood that something had gone wrong.
  Mortimer&#39;s plan was to rob Nabulee without anyone knowing, and then disable the portal that leads to the extradimensional vault. That way, it would have taken Nabulee a long time to realize someone had robbed him, which would have given Mortimer more than enough time to sell his loot.
  Unfortunately, things didn&#39;t go as Mortimer had planned. The necromancer decided that the best course of action was to abort the heist, erase Nabulee&#39;s memory, and try again later. Mortimer cast a sleep spell on Nabulee, tied him to a chair when he was still unconscious, cast a modify memory spell on him, released the Calishite, and then rewrote Nabulee&#39;s memory.
  Rope Marks. Nabulee woke up before Mortimer could finish casting his modify memory spell and tried to break free of his bonds. This left faint rope marks on the varnish of the chair. If the PCs inspect it, they can make a DC 16 Intelligence (Investigation) check to notice the marks, and deduct that someone was recently tied to the chair.
  Treasure. The set of crystal glasses and the pitcher are worth 50 gp.
Confronting Nabulee
If the PCs ask Nabulee about the rope marks in his office, he tells them the following:
    He doesn&#39;t know why there are rope marks on the chair.
    The only plausible explanation is that one of his employees is secretly sneaking into his office at night, doing who knows what in there...</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A10. Bathroom</name>
        <text>One of the taps dispenses cold water and the other one hot water. Nabulee&#39;s entire house has an elaborated hydraulic system that is connected to a hot spring and a cold lake via tiny magical portals. This system provides cold and hot water to the entire house, and heating during the winter.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A11. Guests&#39; Room</name>
        <text>

This used to be the room of Nabulee&#39;s former butler before he passed. He now uses it as a small guests&#39; room as Ronald has his own house in Waterdeep.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A12. Jasmin&#39;s Room</name>
        <text>Jasmin&#39;s room is just plain filthy. There are dirty clothing all over the place and even a half-eaten sandwich in her drawer. There isn&#39;t anything of interest in this room.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A13. Master Bedroom	</name>
        <text>Nabulee sleeps in this comfortable and spacious bedroom. The closet contains a truly shocking amount of extravagant outfits, shoes, and hats.
  Treasure. Nabulee keeps a small amount of pocket change in a chest in his room. It contains 450 cp, 250 sp, and 100 gp.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A14. Lounge	</name>
        <text>This cozy lounge is where Nabulee reads books (mostly adventure ones) and gambles with his friends. There isn&#39;t anything of interest in this room.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    A15. Music Room</name>
        <text>The music stand is in fact a magical item that can create a phantasmal orchestra. If the PCs place a piece of sheet music on the stand, ghostly instruments immediately appear out of nowhere and begin to play the song written on it. If Nabulee is giving the PCs a tour of his house, he shows them how the music stand works.
  
Treasure. If the adventurers steal the magical music stand, one of the nobles of Waterdeep agrees to buy it for 2,500 gp.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Uncovering the Truth</name>
        <text>After the characters interrogate Nabulee&#39;s staff
and explore his house, they&#39;ll most certainly want some explanations that the Calishite won&#39;t be able to provide. Eventually, the adventurers will understand that someone who looked just like Nabulee entered the vault, and that someone erased the merchant&#39;s memory.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Evidence</name>
        <text>You can find below a short summary of the evidence that the PCs might have found when talking to Nabulee&#39;s staff or while searching the house:
    The housekeeper, Jasmin Metalwart, heard Nabulee talking to Mortimer in the morning (see "The Housekeeper" on page 10).
    Jasmin picked up two dirty glasses in Nabulee&#39;s office and left them in the kitchen (see area "A5. The Kitchen" on page 15).
    Mugabu, Nabulee&#39;s iron golem, saw someone that looks just like the Calishite enter the extradimensional vault in the morning (see area "A3. The Vault Room" on page 13).
    Nabulee&#39;s butler, Ronald Walrut, saw Mortimer&#39;s clone golem running in the streets of Waterdeep with a bloodied shirt. He mistook the construct for Nabulee (see "The Butler" on page 11).
    The PCs find rope mark on one of the chairs in Nabulee&#39;s office (see area "A9. The Office" on page 16).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Divination Magic</name>
        <text>Tenth-level characters have access to powerful divination magic, but none of these spells will solve this mystery for the PCs. Spells like augury or commune can help the characters confirm or invalidate some of their theories, and spells like detect thoughts or zone of truth
indicate that Nabulee isn&#39;t lying to the characters (the merchant willingly submits to a magical interrogation if the PCs ask him to).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Helping your Players</name>
        <text>It&#39;s unlikely that your players know by heart every single spell, especially the ones that don&#39;t have many practical uses in a dungeon crawl. If, while talking to each other, your players wonder whether there&#39;s a spell that can alter someone&#39;s memories or not, you can ask their characters to make a DC 15 Intelligence (Arcana) to
remember that the modify memory spell allows a magic-user to rewrite someone&#39;s memories. The PCs can also make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check to remember that a greater restoration spell can cure memory losses.
  At your discretion, the adventurers can also learn this type of information by interrogating some of the NPCs in Waterdeep.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Restoring Nabulee&#39;s Memory</name>
        <text>Once the players guess that Mortimer used a modify memory spell to erase Nabulee&#39;s
memories, the PCs only need to cast a remove curse or a greater restoration spell for him to regain his memories. Nabulee then remembers the following:
    One of his suppliers, Mortimer Yorman, came to his house this morning. He said he wasn&#39;t happy about his pay.
    He invited Mortimer to his office for a chat and a drink. During their conversation, someone triggered a magical alarm inside his extradimensional vault.
    When he asked Mortimer to leave, the wizard disabled him with a sleep spell. He woke up tied up to a chair shortly after.
    Mortimer then cast another spell on him, untied him, and ordered him to forget their meeting. He assumes Mortimer cast a modify memory spell on him to rewrite his memories.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>The Clone Golem</name>
        <text>
Earlier that day Nabulee&#39;s butler, Ronald Walrut,
saw someone who looked just like Nabulee running in the streets, a couple of blocks away from the auction house. This was Mortimer&#39;s clone golem. On his way home, the construct realized that the wound the scarab of death had dealt was bleeding, and that his stained shirt was drawing too much attention. He ditched his purple Valentina tunic, stole a mundane coat, and then went back to Mortimer&#39;s house.

There&#39;s a passage that connects the sewers to the necromancer&#39;s basement. The construct used this passage to make sure nobody saw which house he entered.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>The Valentina Tunic</name>
        <text>Finding the clone golem is tricky. Following the construct&#39;s tracks is impossible in the bustling city of Waterdeep. If the characters ask around, many people say that they saw a man looking like Nabulee and that his tunic was stained with blood. Unfortunately, nobody saw the golem enter the sewers (any attempt to track the construct fails).
  Horus Valentina is an eccentric tailor who lives in the Raging Bull District. His outfits are extremely exuberant, even to Waterdhavian standards, and Nabulee is the only person in the neighborhood who wears them. If the PCs go back to where Ronald saw the golem and cast
a locate object spell to detect a Valentina tunic, they find the construct&#39;s blood-stained shirt in a trashcan nearby.
  Tracking the Golem. The flesh golem&#39;s blood has a very distinct smell that a properly trained dog or pig can follow by scent. The animal only needs to succeed on a DC 12 Wisdom (Survival) check to track the golem back to the sewers, and then back to Mortimer&#39;s house.
  The Golem&#39;s Blood. The blood on the tunic isn&#39;t fresh. Furthermore, there&#39;s too little of it to have been caused by a deep wound, but too much of it for a graze. With a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check, a character knows that the stain is consistent with the bleeding wound of a zombie or a flesh golem. The PCs
can then use a locate creature spell to learn that the nearest flesh golem is in Mortimer&#39;s house.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Lord Find-It-All</name>
        <text>Murphy Stormwind is a diviner who helps wealthy people locate their lost items. His services are expensive, 500 gp per item, but only asks to be paid if he succeeds. If the PCs ask him for help locating the clone golem, he’ll ask them if they can think of something the person was wearing or holding that was out of the ordinary. If the characters tell him about the purple Valentina tunic, he accompanies them to where Ronald Walrut saw the golem, and then casts a locate object spell to find the shirt (see "The Valentina Tunic" above).

  Murphy can actually solve the first part of the adventure for the PCs, and many players won&#39;t enjoy a module in which the NPCs do all the hard work. If the characters seek him out too early in the adventure, you should assume that his shop is closed because he already used up all his spell slots for the day. Murphy tells them to come back in the morning.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Bernard Kothont</name>
        <text>As with any good investigation adventure, there&#39;s a small chance that the players won&#39;t put the pieces together. If by the time the PCs are done exploring the auction house the players still haven&#39;t figured out what happened, don&#39;t let the adventure drag on for too long (being stuck isn&#39;t fun for anybody). Give them at most half an hour to solve the mystery, and if that isn&#39;t enough, it will be time to have Bernard Kothont help the characters.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    The Arrest</name>
        <text>If the PCs ever get stuck in their investigation, Archibald Littlehorn changes his mind about giving them extra time, or he finds out that his son is dead and that Nabulee had something to do with it. The City Watch goes over to Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary and arrests the Calashite. Read or paraphrase the following:

As you’re searching Nabulee’s house, you’re startled by loud banging noises coming from 
the lobby, followed by men shouting. You vaguely hear them saying, “Open up or we’ll bash the door down!” By the time you get there, a small contingent of guards has arrested Nabulee and is leaving the house. When the City Watch notices you, their senior officer says, “Oh it’s you. Bernard Kothont would like to speak with you. Could you please report to the belfry? This is a request, not an order.”

No matter what the PCs say, the guards take Nabulee to jail, and the characters only have a few hours left to complete the adventure (at your discretion). There are only six guards and their sergeant (veteran). If the PCs decide to attack the City Watch, they shouldn&#39;t have any problem eliminating them but they will also become outlaws in Waterdeep (the exact consequences are left to your discretion).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    Talking to Bernard Kothont</name>
        <text>Bernard Kothont is the person in charge of law enforcement in the Raging Bull district, and a good friend of Nabulee&#39;s. He&#39;s extremely
disappointed with the PCs, and summons them to see if he can assist them in their investigation. If the characters go to the belfry, the guards bring them to Bernard&#39;s office.
  You should use Lord Kothont to highlight the important details that the characters have found during their investigation, without outright giving them the solution. You should also make suggestions of how to confirm or refute their assumptions with magic. For example:
    Are they sure Nabulee isn&#39;t lying? Have they confirmed this with a commune spell or with lie-detecting magic such as a zone of truth spell?
    Are they sure Nabulee didn&#39;t remove the scarab of death from the vault in the morning? Did they use a commune spell to confirm this?
    Are they sure someone came to visit Nabulee in the morning, and are they sure Nabulee was the person who received this mysterious visitor? Did they confirm any of this with a commune spell?
  The key to solving the mystery is to understand that Nabulee doesn&#39;t remember meeting Mortimer. As an absolute last resort, you could have Bernard figure this out and tell the PCs.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
    </adventure>
    <adventure>
      <uid>4360</uid>
      <name>Part 3: Mortimer Yorman</name>
      <npc>
        <uid>4365</uid>
        <label>Mortimito </label>
        <enemy>1</enemy>
        <name>Clone Golem</name>
        <type>construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <abilities>20,11,18,12,10,15,</abilities>
        <hpMax>102</hpMax>
        <hpCurrent>102</hpCurrent>
        <hd>12d8+48</hd>
        <ac>12</ac>
        <armor>natural</armor>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <skill>
          <id>4</id>
          <modifier>5</modifier>
        </skill>
        <skill>
          <id>6</id>
          <modifier>3</modifier>
        </skill>
        <immune>lightning, poison; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren&#39;t adamantine</immune>
        <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, frightened, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <languages>common</languages>
        <cr>7</cr>
        <trait>
          <name>Aversion of Fire</name>
          <text>If the golem takes fire damage, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the end of its next turn.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Deceitful</name>
          <text>The clone golem has advantage on his Charisma (Deception) checks when pretending to be the person whose body parts were used to create it.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Immutable Form</name>
          <text>The golem is immune to any spell or effect that would alter its form.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Lightning Absorption</name>
          <text>Whenever the golem is subjected to lightning damage, it takes no damage and instead regains a number of hit points equal to the lightning damage dealt.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Magic Resistance</name>
          <text>The golem has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Magic Weapons</name>
          <text>The golem&#39;s weapon attacks are magical.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
          <name>Mind Link</name>
          <text>The clone golem and it&#39;s creator can communicate telepathically with each other for as long as they are on the same plane.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
          <name>Multiattack</name>
          <text>The golem makes two slam attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
          <name>Slam</name>
          <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +i to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (3d8
10+5) bludgeoning damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <name>Slam</name>
            <atk>8</atk>
            <dmg>3d10+5</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <text>Clone golems are an improved version of their lesser cousins, the flesh golems. Over the years, Mortimer has perfected the technique of making these types of constructs. 

He first creates an inanimate duplicate of a person with a clone spell, tears the clone apart for raw materials, and reassembles them to create a flesh golem that is physically identical to the person he cloned, and that even retains a part of their personality.</text>
      </npc>
      <npc>
        <uid>4383</uid>
        <label>Mortimer Yorman</label>
        <enemy>1</enemy>
        <name>Necromancer</name>
        <type>humanoid (human)</type>
        <alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
        <abilities>11,15,17,19,11,8,</abilities>
        <hpMax>112</hpMax>
        <hpCurrent>112</hpCurrent>
        <hd>15d8+45</hd>
        <ac>14</ac>
        <armor>Bracers of Defense</armor>
        <speed>25 ft.</speed>
        <savingThrow>
          <ability>3</ability>
          <modifier>7</modifier>
        </savingThrow>
        <savingThrow>
          <ability>4</ability>
          <modifier>3</modifier>
        </savingThrow>
        <skill>
          <id>2</id>
          <modifier>7</modifier>
        </skill>
        <skill>
          <id>11</id>
          <modifier>3</modifier>
        </skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Common, Draconic</languages>
        <cr>8</cr>
        <slots>0,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots>
        <slotsCurrent>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
        <action>
          <name>Quarterstaff</name>
          <text>reach 5 ft., one target. bludgeoning damage.</text>
          <attack>
            <atk>3</atk>
            <dmg>1d8</dmg>
          </attack>
        </action>
        <spell>
          <name>Burning Hands</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <level>1</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Self (15-foot cone)</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>As you hold your hands with thumbs touching and fingers spread, a thin sheet of flames shoots forth from your outstretched fingertips. Each creature in a 15-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren&#39;t being worn or carried.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 220</text>
          <roll>3d6</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Genie Efreeti)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Chill Touch</name>
          <school>7</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>120 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>1 round</duration>
          <text>You create a ghostly, skeletal hand in the space of a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the creature to assail it with the chill of the grave. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 necrotic damage, and it can&#39;t regain hit points until the start of your next turn. Until then, the hand clings to the target.
	If you hit an undead target, it also has disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the end of your next turn.
	This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 221</text>
          <roll>1d8</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Cone of Cold</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <level>5</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Self (60-foot cone)</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a small crystal or glass cone</materials>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>A blast of cold air erupts from your hands. Each creature in a 60-foot cone must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 8d8 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	A creature killed by this spell becomes a frozen statue until it thaws.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 5th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 224</text>
          <roll>8d8</roll>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Hexblade)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Druid</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Fathomless)</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Genie Marid)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Dimension Door</name>
          <school>2</school>
          <level>4</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>500 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>You teleport yourself from your current location to any other spot within range. You arrive at exactly the spot desired. It can be a place you can see, one you can visualize, or one you can describe by stating distance and direction, such as 200 feet straight downward or upward to the northwest at a 45-degree angle, 300 feet.
	You can bring along objects as long as their weight doesn&#39;t exceed what you can carry. You can also bring one willing creature of your size or smaller who is carrying gear up to its carrying capacity. The creature must be within 5 feet of you when you cast this spell.
	If you would arrive in a place already occupied by an object or a creature, you and any creature traveling with you each take 4d6 force damage, and the spell fails to teleport you.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 233</text>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Disguise Self</name>
          <school>6</school>
          <level>1</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Self</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>1 hour</duration>
          <text>You make yourself, including your clothing, armor, weapons, and other belongings on your person, look different until the spell ends or until you use your action to dismiss it. You can seem 1 foot shorter or taller and can appear thin, fat, or in between. You can&#39;t change your body type, so you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs. Otherwise, the extent of the illusion is up to you.
	The changes wrought by this spell fail to hold up to physical inspection. For example, if you use this spell to add a hat to your outfit, objects pass through the hat, and anyone who touches it would feel nothing or would feel your head and hair. If you use this spell to appear thinner than you are, the hand of some one who reaches out to touch you would bump into you while it was seemingly still in midair.
	To discern that you are disguised, a creature can use its action to inspect your appearance and must succeed on an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 233</text>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Ranger (Gloom Stalker)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Disintegrate</name>
          <school>8</school>
          <level>6</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>60 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a lodestone and a pinch of dust</materials>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>A thin green ray springs from your pointing finger to a target that you can see within range. The target can be a creature, an object, or a creation of magical force, such as the wall created by Wall of Force.
	A creature targeted by this spell must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 10d6+40 force damage. The target is disintegrated if this damage leaves it with 0 hit points.
	A disintegrated creature and everything it is wearing and carrying, except magic items, are reduced to a pile of fine gray dust. The creature can be restored to life only by means of a true resurrection or a wish spell.
	This spell automatically disintegrates a Large or smaller nonmagical object or a creation of magical force. If the target is a Huge or larger object or creation of force, this spell disintegrates a 10-foot-cube portion of it. A magic item is unaffected by this spell.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by 3d6 for each slot level above 6th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 233</text>
          <roll>10d6+40</roll>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Dispel Magic</name>
          <school>1</school>
          <level>3</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>120 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>Choose any creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10+the spell&#39;s level. On a successful check, the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell&#39;s level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 234</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
          <sclass>Druid</sclass>
          <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
          <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer (Clockwork)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Fear</name>
          <school>6</school>
          <level>3</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Self (30-foot cone)</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a white feather or the heart of a hen</materials>
          <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
          <text>You project a phantasmal image of a creature&#39;s worst fears. Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or drop whatever it is holding and become frightened for the duration.
	While frightened by this spell, a creature must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest available route on each of its turns, unless there is nowhere to move. If the creature ends its turn in a location where it doesn&#39;t have line of sight to you, the creature can make a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends for that creature.

• The creature can&#39;t willingly move closer to the source of its fear.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 239</text>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Ranger (Gloom Stalker)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Finger of Death</name>
          <school>7</school>
          <level>7</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>60 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>You send negative energy coursing through a creature that you can see within range, causing it searing pain. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. It takes 7d8+30 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	A humanoid killed by this spell rises at the start of your next turn as a zombie that is permanently under your command, following your verbal orders to the best of its ability.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 241</text>
          <roll>7d8+30</roll>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Haste</name>
          <school>8</school>
          <level>3</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>30 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a shaving of licorice root</materials>
          <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
          <text>Choose a willing creature that you can see within range. Until the spell ends, the target&#39;s speed is doubled, it gains a +2 bonus to AC, it has advantage on Dexterity saving throws, and it gains an additional action on each of its turns. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.
	When the spell ends, the target can&#39;t move or take actions until after its next turn, as a wave of lethargy sweeps over it.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 250</text>
          <sclass>Ranger (Horizon Walker)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Light</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Touch</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a firefly or phosphorescent moss</materials>
          <duration>1 hour</duration>
          <text>You touch one object that is no larger than 10 feet in any dimension. Until the spell ends, the object sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light can be colored as you like. Completely covering the object with something opaque blocks the light. The spell ends if you cast it again or dismiss it as an action.
	If you target an object held or worn by a hostile creature, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw to avoid the spell.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 255</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <level>3</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Self (100-foot line)</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a bit of fur and a rod of amber, crystal, or glass</materials>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>A stroke of lightning forming a line of 100 feet long and 5 feet wide blasts out from you in a direction you choose. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 8d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	The lightning ignites flammable objects in the area that aren&#39;t being worn or carried.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot above 3rd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 255</text>
          <roll>8d6</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Fathomless)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Mage Hand</name>
          <school>2</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>30 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>1 minute</duration>
          <text>A spectral, floating hand appears at a point you choose within range. The hand lasts for the duration or until you dismiss it as an action. The hand vanishes if it is ever more than 30 feet away from you or if you cast this spell again.
	You can use your action to control the hand. You can use the hand to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can move the hand up to 30 feet each time you use it.
	The hand can&#39;t attack, activate magical items, or carry more than 10 pounds.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 256</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
          <sclass>Ranger (Swarmkeeper)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Maze</name>
          <school>2</school>
          <level>8</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>60 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
          <text>You banish a creature that you can see within range into a labyrinthine demiplane. The target remains there for the duration or until it escapes the maze.
	The target can use its action to attempt to escape. When it does so, it makes a DC 20 Intelligence check. If it succeeds, it escapes, and the spell ends (a minotaur or goristro demon automatically succeeds).
	When the spell ends, the target reappears in the space it left or, if that space is occupied, in the nearest unoccupied space.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 258</text>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Melf&#39;s Acid Arrow</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <level>2</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>90 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>powdered rhubarb leaf and an adder&#39;s stomach</materials>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>A shimmering green arrow streaks toward a target within range and bursts in a spray of acid. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 4d4 acid damage immediately and 2d4 acid damage at the end of its next turn. On a miss, the arrow splashes the target with acid for half as much of the initial damage and no damage at the end of its next turn.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage (both initial and later) increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 259</text>
          <roll>4d4</roll>
          <roll>2d4</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Minor Illusion</name>
          <school>6</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>30 feet</range>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a bit of fleece</materials>
          <duration>1 minute</duration>
          <text>You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration. The illusion also ends if you dismiss it as an action or cast this spell again.
	If you create a sound, its volume can range from a whisper to a scream. It can be your voice, someone else&#39;s voice, a lion&#39;s roar, a beating of drums, or any other sound you choose. The sound continues unabated throughout the duration, or you can make discrete sounds at different times before the spell ends.
	If you create an image of an object, such as a chair, muddy footprints, or a small chest, it must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. The image can&#39;t create sound, light, smell, or any other sensory effect. Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it.
	If a creature uses its action to examine the sound or image, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 260</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Misty Step</name>
          <school>2</school>
          <level>2</level>
          <time>1 bonus action</time>
          <range>Self</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>Briefly surrounded by silvery mist, you teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 260</text>
          <sclass>Ranger (Horizon Walker)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Modify Memory</name>
          <school>4</school>
          <level>5</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>30 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
          <text>You attempt to reshape another creature&#39;s memories. One creature that you can see must make a Wisdom saving throw. If you are fighting the creature, it has advantage on the saving throw. On a failed save, the target becomes charmed by you for the duration. The charmed target is incapacitated and unaware of its surroundings, though it can still hear you. If it takes any damage or is targeted by another spell, this spell ends, and none o f the target&#39;s m emeries are modified.
	While this charm lasts, you can affect the target&#39;s memory of an event that it experienced within the last 24 hours and that lasted no more than 10 minutes. You can permanently eliminate all memory o f the event, allow the target to recall the event with perfect clarity and exacting detail, change its memory of the details of the event, or create a memory of some other event.
	You must speak to the target to describe how its memories are affected, and it must be able to understand your language for the modified memories to take root. Its mind fills in any gaps in the details of your description. If the spell ends before you have finished describing the modified memories, the creature&#39;s memory isn&#39;t altered. Otherwise, the modified memories take hold when the spell ends.
	A modified memory doesn&#39;t necessarily affect how a creature behaves, particularly if the memory contradicts the creature&#39;s natural inclinations, alignment, or beliefs. An illogical modified memory, such as implanting a memory o f how much the creature enjoyed dousing itself in acid, is dismissed, perhaps as a bad dream. The DM might deem a modified memory too nonsensical to affect a creature in a significant manner.
	A remove curse or greater restoration spell cast on the target restores the creature&#39;s true memory.

At Higher Levels: If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can alter the target&#39;s memories o f an event that took place up to 7 days ago (6th level), 30 days ago (7th level), 1 year ago (8th level), or any time in the creature&#39;s past (9th level).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 261</text>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Ray of Enfeeblement</name>
          <school>7</school>
          <level>2</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>60 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
          <text>A black beam of enervating energy springs from your finger toward a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target deals only half damage with weapon attacks that use Strength until the spell ends.
	At the end of each of the target&#39;s turns, it can make a Constitution saving throw against the spell. On a success, the spell ends.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 271</text>
          <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Rope Trick</name>
          <school>8</school>
          <level>2</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Touch</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>powdered corn extract and a twisted loop of parchment</materials>
          <duration>1 hour</duration>
          <text>You touch a length of rope that is up to 60 feet long. One end of the rope then rises into the air until the whole rope hangs perpendicular to the ground. At the upper end of the rope, an invisible entrance opens to an extradimensional space that lasts until the spell ends.
	The extradimensional space can be reached by climbing to the top of the rope. The space can hold as many as eight Medium or smaller creatures. The rope can be pulled into the space, making the rope disappear from view outside the space.
	Attacks and spells can&#39;t cross through the entrance into or out of the extradimensional space, but those inside can see out of it as if through a 3-foot-by-5-foot window centered on the rope.
	Anything inside the extradimensional space drops out when the spell ends.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 272</text>
          <sclass>Ranger (Gloom Stalker)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Shield</name>
          <school>1</school>
          <level>1</level>
          <time>1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack or targeted by the magic missile spell</time>
          <range>Self</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>1 round</duration>
          <text>An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 275</text>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Hexblade)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Shocking Grasp</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>Touch</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
          <text>Lightning springs from your hand to deliver a shock to a creature you try to touch. Make a melee spell attack against the target. You have advantage on the attack roll if the target is wearing armor made of metal. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 lightning damage, and it can&#39;t take reactions until the start of its next turn.
	The spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 275</text>
          <roll>1d8</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
          <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Sleep</name>
          <school>4</school>
          <level>1</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>90 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a pinch of find sand, rose petals, or a cricket</materials>
          <duration>1 minute</duration>
          <text>This spell sends creatures into a magical slumber. Roll 5d8, the total is how many hit points of creatures this spell can affect. Creatures within 20 feet of a point you choose within range are affected in ascending order of their current hit points (ignoring unconscious creatures).
	Starting with the creature that has the lowest current hit points, each creature affected by this spell falls unconscious until the spell ends, the sleeper takes damage, or someone uses an action to shake or slap the sleeper awake. Subtract each creature&#39;s hit points from the total before moving on to the creature with the next lowest hit points. A creature&#39;s hit points must be equal to or less than the remaining total for that creature to be affected.
	Undead and creatures immune to being charmed aren&#39;t affected by this spell.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, roll an additional 2d8 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 276</text>
          <roll>5d8</roll>
          <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
          <sclass>Bard</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <spell>
          <name>Wall of Fire</name>
          <school>5</school>
          <level>4</level>
          <time>1 action</time>
          <range>120 feet</range>
          <v>1</v>
          <s>1</s>
          <m>1</m>
          <materials>a small piece of phosphorus</materials>
          <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
          <text>You create a wall of fire on a solid surface within range. You can make the wall up to 60 feet long, 20 feet high, and 1 foot think, or a ringed wall up to 20 feet in diameter, 20 feet high, and 1 foot think. The wall is opaque and lasts for the duration.
	When the wall appears, each creature within its area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 5d8 fire damage, or half as much damage on a successful save.
	One side of the wall, selected by you when you cast this spell, deals 5d8 fire damage to each creature that ends its turn within 10 feet of that side or inside the wall. A creature takes the same damage when it enters the wall for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there. The other side of the wall deals no damage.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 285</text>
          <roll>5d8</roll>
          <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
          <sclass>Druid</sclass>
          <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Celestial)</sclass>
          <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
          <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        </spell>
        <text>Mortimer is a 15th-level spellcaster. His spellcasting ability is Intelligence (spell save DC 15, +7 to hit with spell attacks).

Mortimer Yorman is a sinister old man who feels more comfortable around corpses than people. He has a passion for magical constructs, and dedicated his entire life to perfecting them.</text>
        <environment>1024</environment>
      </npc>
      <encounter>
        <name>B1. Atrium</name>
        <uid>4377</uid>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4362</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4363</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4365</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Specter 1</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Specter</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
            <abilities>1,14,11,10,10,11,</abilities>
            <hpMax>22</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>22</hpCurrent>
            <hd>5d8</hd>
            <ac>12</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 50 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, unconscious</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <languages>understands all languages it knew in life but can&#39;t speak</languages>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 279</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The specter can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the specter has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Spell Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (3d6) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the creature finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>4</atk>
                <dmg>3d6</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1280</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Specter 2</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Specter</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
            <abilities>1,14,11,10,10,11,</abilities>
            <hpMax>22</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>22</hpCurrent>
            <hd>5d8</hd>
            <ac>12</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 50 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, unconscious</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <languages>understands all languages it knew in life but can&#39;t speak</languages>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 279</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The specter can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the specter has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Spell Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (3d6) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the creature finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>4</atk>
                <dmg>3d6</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1280</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Specter 3</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Specter</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
            <abilities>1,14,11,10,10,11,</abilities>
            <hpMax>22</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>22</hpCurrent>
            <hd>5d8</hd>
            <ac>12</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 50 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, unconscious</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <languages>understands all languages it knew in life but can&#39;t speak</languages>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 279</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The specter can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the specter has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Spell Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (3d6) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the creature finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>4</atk>
                <dmg>3d6</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1280</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Specter 4</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Specter</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
            <abilities>1,14,11,10,10,11,</abilities>
            <hpMax>22</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>22</hpCurrent>
            <hd>5d8</hd>
            <ac>12</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 50 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, unconscious</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <languages>understands all languages it knew in life but can&#39;t speak</languages>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 279</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The specter can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the specter has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Spell Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (3d6) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the creature finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>4</atk>
                <dmg>3d6</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1280</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Specter 5</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Specter</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
            <abilities>1,14,11,10,10,11,</abilities>
            <hpMax>22</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>22</hpCurrent>
            <hd>5d8</hd>
            <ac>12</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 50 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, unconscious</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <languages>understands all languages it knew in life but can&#39;t speak</languages>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 279</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The specter can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the specter has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Spell Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (3d6) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the creature finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>4</atk>
                <dmg>3d6</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1280</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Specter 6</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Specter</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
            <abilities>1,14,11,10,10,11,</abilities>
            <hpMax>22</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>22</hpCurrent>
            <hd>5d8</hd>
            <ac>12</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 50 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, unconscious</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <languages>understands all languages it knew in life but can&#39;t speak</languages>
            <trait>
              <name>Source</name>
              <text>Monster Manual p. 279</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The specter can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the specter has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Spell Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 10 (3d6) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the creature finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <atk>4</atk>
                <dmg>3d6</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <environment>1280</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
      </encounter>
      <encounter>
        <name>B6. Washhouse</name>
        <uid>4381</uid>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4362</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4363</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Hound Wraith 1</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Hound Wraith</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
            <abilities>6,16,16,7,14,15,</abilities>
            <hpMax>67</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>67</hpCurrent>
            <hd>9d8+27</hd>
            <ac>13</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 60 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren&#39;t silvered</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>the languages it knew in life</languages>
            <cr>5</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The wraith can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the wraith has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Keen Smell</name>
              <text>Has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 21 (4d8+3) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Life Drain</name>
                <atk>6</atk>
                <dmg>4d8+3</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <action>
              <name>Create Specter</name>
              <text>The wraith targets a humanoid within 10 feet of it that has been dead for no longer than 1 minute and died violently. The target&#39;s spirit rises as a specter in the space of its corpse or in the nearest unoccupied space. The specter is under the wraith&#39;s control. The wraith can have no more than seven specters under its control at one time.</text>
            </action>
            <environment>256</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Hound Wraith 2</label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Hound Wraith</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
            <abilities>6,16,16,7,14,15,</abilities>
            <hpMax>67</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>67</hpCurrent>
            <hd>9d8+27</hd>
            <ac>13</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 60 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren&#39;t silvered</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>the languages it knew in life</languages>
            <cr>5</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The wraith can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the wraith has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Keen Smell</name>
              <text>Has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 21 (4d8+3) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Life Drain</name>
                <atk>6</atk>
                <dmg>4d8+3</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <action>
              <name>Create Specter</name>
              <text>The wraith targets a humanoid within 10 feet of it that has been dead for no longer than 1 minute and died violently. The target&#39;s spirit rises as a specter in the space of its corpse or in the nearest unoccupied space. The specter is under the wraith&#39;s control. The wraith can have no more than seven specters under its control at one time.</text>
            </action>
            <environment>256</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
      </encounter>
      <encounter>
        <name>B9. Office (Day)</name>
        <uid>4386</uid>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4362</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4363</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4383</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
      </encounter>
      <encounter>
        <name>B10. Mortimer’s Room (Day)</name>
        <uid>4389</uid>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4362</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4363</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Hound Wraith </label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Hound Wraith</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
            <abilities>6,16,16,7,14,15,</abilities>
            <hpMax>67</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>67</hpCurrent>
            <hd>9d8+27</hd>
            <ac>13</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 60 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren&#39;t silvered</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>the languages it knew in life</languages>
            <cr>5</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The wraith can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the wraith has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Keen Smell</name>
              <text>Has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 21 (4d8+3) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Life Drain</name>
                <atk>6</atk>
                <dmg>4d8+3</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <action>
              <name>Create Specter</name>
              <text>The wraith targets a humanoid within 10 feet of it that has been dead for no longer than 1 minute and died violently. The target&#39;s spirit rises as a specter in the space of its corpse or in the nearest unoccupied space. The specter is under the wraith&#39;s control. The wraith can have no more than seven specters under its control at one time.</text>
            </action>
            <environment>256</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
      </encounter>
      <encounter>
        <name>B10. Mortimer’s Room (Night)</name>
        <uid>4392</uid>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4362</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4363</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4383</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Hound Wraith </label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Hound Wraith</name>
            <type>undead</type>
            <alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
            <abilities>6,16,16,7,14,15,</abilities>
            <hpMax>67</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>67</hpCurrent>
            <hd>9d8+27</hd>
            <ac>13</ac>
            <speed>0 ft., fly 60 ft. (hover)</speed>
            <resist>acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren&#39;t silvered</resist>
            <immune>necrotic, poison</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <passive>12</passive>
            <languages>the languages it knew in life</languages>
            <cr>5</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
              <text>The wraith can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
              <text>While in sunlight, the wraith has disadvantage on attack rolls, as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Keen Smell</name>
              <text>Has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Life Drain</name>
              <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 21 (4d8+3) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Life Drain</name>
                <atk>6</atk>
                <dmg>4d8+3</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <action>
              <name>Create Specter</name>
              <text>The wraith targets a humanoid within 10 feet of it that has been dead for no longer than 1 minute and died violently. The target&#39;s spirit rises as a specter in the space of its corpse or in the nearest unoccupied space. The specter is under the wraith&#39;s control. The wraith can have no more than seven specters under its control at one time.</text>
            </action>
            <environment>256</environment>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
      </encounter>
      <encounter>
        <name>B11. Attic</name>
        <uid>4395</uid>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4362</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <uid>4363</uid>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
        <combatant>
          <monster>
            <label>Clone Golem </label>
            <enemy>1</enemy>
            <name>Clone Golem</name>
            <type>construct</type>
            <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
            <abilities>20,11,18,12,10,15,</abilities>
            <hpMax>102</hpMax>
            <hpCurrent>102</hpCurrent>
            <hd>12d8+48</hd>
            <ac>12</ac>
            <armor>natural</armor>
            <speed>30 ft.</speed>
            <skill>
              <id>4</id>
              <modifier>5</modifier>
            </skill>
            <skill>
              <id>6</id>
              <modifier>3</modifier>
            </skill>
            <immune>lightning, poison; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren&#39;t adamantine</immune>
            <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, frightened, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned</conditionImmune>
            <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
            <languages>common</languages>
            <cr>7</cr>
            <trait>
              <name>Aversion of Fire</name>
              <text>If the golem takes fire damage, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the end of its next turn.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Deceitful</name>
              <text>The clone golem has advantage on his Charisma (Deception) checks when pretending to be the person whose body parts were used to create it.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Immutable Form</name>
              <text>The golem is immune to any spell or effect that would alter its form.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Lightning Absorption</name>
              <text>Whenever the golem is subjected to lightning damage, it takes no damage and instead regains a number of hit points equal to the lightning damage dealt.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Magic Resistance</name>
              <text>The golem has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Magic Weapons</name>
              <text>The golem&#39;s weapon attacks are magical.</text>
            </trait>
            <trait>
              <name>Mind Link</name>
              <text>The clone golem and it&#39;s creator can communicate telepathically with each other for as long as they are on the same plane.</text>
            </trait>
            <action>
              <name>Multiattack</name>
              <text>The golem makes two slam attacks.</text>
            </action>
            <action>
              <name>Slam</name>
              <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +i to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (3d8
10+5) bludgeoning damage.</text>
              <attack>
                <name>Slam</name>
                <atk>8</atk>
                <dmg>3d10+5</dmg>
              </attack>
            </action>
            <text>Clone golems are an improved version of their lesser cousins, the flesh golems. Over the years, Mortimer has perfected the technique of making these types of constructs. 

He first creates an inanimate duplicate of a person with a clone spell, tears the clone apart for raw materials, and reassembles them to create a flesh golem that is physically identical to the person he cloned, and that even retains a part of their personality.</text>
          </monster>
        </combatant>
      </encounter>
      <note>
        <name>Introduction</name>
        <text>Mortimer Yorman lives in a spacious three-story house, a few blocks away from Nabulee&#39;s auction house. The Calishite knows where Mortimer lives and shares this information with the players after they restore his memories. The PCs can also find the necromancer&#39;s house by tracking down the flesh golem that entered Nabulee&#39;s vault in the morning (see "The Clone Golem" on page 18), in which case the PCs arrive via the sewers (see area "B6. Washhouse" on page 22).

  Mortimer Yorman doesn&#39;t like people and rarely leaves his house. He even went as far as creating a copy of himself that looks and behaves just like him to dodge all his social obligations (see "The Doppelganger" below).

  Whether the characters enter the necromancer&#39;s house through the front door or take the passage in the sewers, Mortimer&#39;s minions will quickly attack them. The PCs will then need to explore the mansion and find Mortimer.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>The Doppelganger</name>
        <text>Mortimer Yorman created a double of himselfto have more time for his research. The golem, Mortimito, takes care of everything that bores the wizard: he cleans the house, prepares the meals, goes to the marketplace to buy groceries, and receives guests, pretending to be Mortimer.

  Considering the veil of deception surrounding Aaron&#39;s death, most PCs will at least want to talk to Mortimer before they decide whether he&#39;s guilty or not. In all likelihood, they will meet Mortimito instead.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>  Meeting Mortimito	</name>
        <text>Mortimer is on edge after what happened at Nabulee&#39;s house. He&#39;s at home and ordered Mortimito to stay in the mansion until things settle down (neither of them go out of the house for the duration of the adventure). The PCs will need to knock on the door if they want to meet Mortimer, in which case the golem lets them in and invites them to sit on the benches in the atrium (see "B1. Atrium"). He then pretends to be the master of the house.
  
Mortimito is friendly to the characters and tells them what he knows (see "Talking to Mortimito" below). If the adventurers unmask Mortimito or accuse him of assaulting Nabulee in the morning, he attacks them (see "Fighting Mortimito" below). Mortimer also instructed Mortimito to eliminate anyone who is being too inquisitive.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>  Talking to Mortimito	</name>
        <text>The golem doesn&#39;t know anything about Aaron&#39;s death. Any attempts at obtaining more information from Mortimito automatically fail. The characters can only learn the following information:
     -He says his name is Mortimer Yorman.
    -He&#39;s a wizard from Waterdeep.
    -He has a passion for history, antiquities, and anatomy.
    -He regularly brings magic items to Nabulee that he recovers from the dungeons around Waterdeep.
    -He doesn&#39;t know anything about Aaron&#39;s death. He stayed at home all day.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>  Unmasking Mortimito</name>
        <text>Mortimito makes a convincing human, but he has a few machine-like intonations and gestures that can give him away. If the PCs succeed on a 
-DC 22 Wisdom (Insight) check, they pick up the subtle clues that suggest Mortimito is a construct. The clone golem attacks the characters if they confront him about it (see "Fighting Mortimito" below).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>  Fighting Mortimito	</name>
        <text>Mortimito (clone golem) only attacks the adventurers if he needs to. If a fight erupts while the golem and the PCs are in the atrium (see area "B1. Atrium" below), the five specters hiding in the chimney come to help the construct.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Mortimer&#39;s Mansion</name>
        <text>Mortimer lives in a large, rustic manor with visible stone walls and massive wooden beams supporting the roof. The furniture inside the house is basic and there&#39;s very little in terms of decoration, making the area feel more like a dungeon than a house.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>  General Features	</name>
        <text>Mortimer&#39;s mansion has the following features. Any exceptions are noted in the areas to which they apply.

  Light. 
During daylight hours, sunlight keeps the house properly lit. The house is dark at night.

  Windows. 
Mortimer&#39;s house only has a few glass windows that are all barred. A character can try to bend the metal bars and sneak into the house with a successful DC 15 Strength check (a PC with a crowbar has advantage to this check). If the adventurers don&#39;t take any precautions to muffle the sound when smashing the windows, nearby creatures can make a DC 13 Wisdom (Perception) check to hear the glass shattering.

  Doors. 
The doors are made of wood and are normally unlocked.

  Defenders. 
Mortimito (clone golem) wanders about the house by day and night. He spends an hour and a half in the kitchen before each meal (breakfast, lunch, and dinner) and the rest of the time cleaning the house (he doesn&#39;t need to sleep). If he hears any fighting in the mansion, he immediately rushes to where the noise is coming from to repel the assailants.

  Mortimer Yorman spends most of his time in his office. The PCs can find him there when he isn&#39;t eating in the dining room or sleeping in his room. In case of an attack, Mortimer runs to his room and waits there for the intruders.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B1. Atrium</name>
        <text>Five specters are hiding in the chimney. They attack any intruders and help Mortimito if necessary.

  If the characters knock on Mortimer&#39;s door, his golem servant lets them in and invites them to sit down on the wooden benches. They aren&#39;t allowed to enter further into the house.
        </text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B2. Dining Room	</name>
        <text>Depending on the time of the day, the PCs might find Mortimito (clone golem) here sweeping the floor or setting the table.
  Treasure. The silver chandelier is worth 250 gp, and the set of silver cutlery lying on the table 10 gp.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B3. Latrine	</name>
        <text>Mortimer&#39;s house has an efficient sewage system that goes through the house. The pipes are wide enough for an unarmored person to squeeze through to the other latrines of the house (see area "B7. Latrine") and to the washhouse in the basement (see area "B6. Washhouse").</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B4. Kitchen	</name>
        <text>Mortimito (clone golem) spends an hour and a half before each meal in this well-equipped kitchen to prepare Mortimer&#39;s food.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B5. Larder	</name>
        <text>The larder contains crates of fresh fruits and vegetables, and pieces of meat hanging on a rack.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B6. Washhouse	</name>
        <text>A small stream of clean water passes under Mortimer&#39;s house. The wizard uses it to do his laundry and to eliminate waste. The pipe
connecting all the latrines of the house (see area "B3. Latrines") sticks out of the ceiling, fifteen feet above the underground stream.

  The passage to the west leads to the city sewers. This is where the PCs arrive from if they managed to track down the flesh golem that entered Nabulee&#39;s vault in the morning (see "The Clone Golem" on page 18). The gate to the passage is locked (DC 20).
  Mortimer left two hound wraiths (see "Monster Statistics" below) to prevent intruders from entering his house though the sewers. They attack anyone who enters the washhouse, except Mortimer and his clone golems.

  Reaching the Pipe.
Reaching the pipe that connects the washhouse to the latrines is difficult. The PCs need to climb on the walls and the ceiling, which requires a 
-DC 20 Strength (Athletics) check.

  Monster Statistics. 
Hound wraith are identical to the common wraith found in the Monster Manual, except that they look like dog-shaped shadows, they have an Intelligence score of 7, and they have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell. Their behavior is also more animal than human.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B7. Latrine	</name>
        <text>This ordinary medieval privy is connected to the other stories of the house (see area "B3. Latrines").</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B8. Library	</name>
        <text>This well-stocked library contains an impressive collection of rare history books and tomes about local myths and legends.

  Mortimer is a dedicated tomb robber who spends a lot of time researching the location of ancient ruins.

  Treasure. Mortimer owns two very rare books worth 50 gp each, and a dozen others worth 25 gp each.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B9. Office</name>
        <text>The flags pinned to the map indicate the ruins that Mortimer has already plundered and the ones he still needs to visit (the flags have one color for each). The map doesn&#39;t have any purpose in the adventure but you can use the ruins Mortimer hasn&#39;t explored yet as a hook for your own stories (see "Tomb Raiders" in Concluding the Adventure).

  Treasure. 
The drawers of the desk contain a few valuable items: a +1 dagger, a potion of speed, a potion of invisibility, a spell scroll of
teleport, and Mortimer&#39;s grimoire. The spellbook contains the following spells: acid arrow, burning hands, cone of cold, detect magic, dimension door, disguise self, disintegrate, dispel magic, fear, finger of death, fly, globe of invulnerability, glyph of warding, haste, identify, lightning bolt, locate creature, locate object, magic missile, maze, mind blank, misty step, modify memory, ray of enfeeblement, rope trick, scrying, shield, sleep, teleport, and wall of fire.

Mortimer Yorman
This is where the characters can find Mortimer Yorman during the day. If the PCs made too much noise while exploring the rest of the house or if they already fought one of the two clone golems, Mortimer knows they&#39;re here and has fled to his room (see area "B10. Mortimer&#39;s Room" below). Mortimer attacks the PCs on sight.

  Treasure. 
Mortimer is wearing bracers of defense and a gold signet ring (250 gp). He has 200 gp and 4 small rubies worth 100 gp each in his belt pouch.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B10. Mortimer&#39;s Room	</name>
        <text>Read:
This spacious bedroom contains a large four-poster bed in the middle of it. A closet, a sink, and a large reinforced chest also line the walls.

The characters can find Mortimer Yorman sleeping here at night and waiting here for the PCs if he detected their presence. The wizard attacks them on sight.
The necromancer’s pet hound wraith (see “Monster Statistics” below) guards the room 
at all times. If Mortimer and the wraith are encountered together, the wizard casts a haste spell on his companion on the first round of combat. If the hound wraith succeeds on a DC 10 Wisdom (Perception) check (or against the 
characters’ Dexterity (Stealth) checks if they’re being sneaky), the undead dog hears the PCs in 
the hallway. It warns Mortimer of their presence, and the wizard has enough time to cast a haste
spell on his pet before the beginning of the encounter. Mortimer then attacks the PCs with his damaging spells, using higher level spell slots 
when possible.

  Traps. 
The windows and the door to Mortimer&#39;s room are trapped with a glyph of warding spell. Anyone who enters the room without first saying the password immediately triggers an acid arrow spell (cast as a 5th level spell; +7 bonus to the attack roll; DC 15).

  Monster Statistics.
Hound wraith are identical to the common wraith found in the Monster Manual, except that they look like dog-shaped shadows, they have an Intelligence
score of 7, and they have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell. Their behavior is also more animal than human.

  Treasure. 
Mortimer is wearing bracers of defense and a gold signet ring (250 gp). He has 200 gp and 4 small rubies worth 100 gp each in his belt pouch. The reinforced chest contains Mortimer&#39;s life savings and a few magic items he was planning on selling. The PCs find 1,500 gp, 300 pp, a cloak of elvenkind, and a stone of good luck within</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>    B11. Attic	</name>
        <text>The characters can find Mortimer Yorman sleeping here at night and waiting here for the PCs if he detected their presence. The wizard attacks them on sight.

  The necromancer&#39;s pet hound wraith (see "Monster Statistics" below) guards the room at all times. If Mortimer and the wraith are encountered together, the wizard casts a haste spell on his companion on the first round of combat. If the hound wraith succeeds on a 
-DC 10 Wisdom (Perception) check (or against the characters&#39; Dexterity (Stealth) checks if they&#39;re being sneaky), the undead dog hears the PCs in the hallway. It warns Mortimer of their presence, and the wizard has enough time to cast a haste spell on his pet before the beginning of the encounter. Mortimer then attacks the PCs with his damaging spells, using higher level spell slots when possible.

This is where Mortimer makes his constructs.

The scarab of death badly damaged Nabulee&#39;s clone golem, and Mortimer is trying to fix it. When the PCs enter the attic, the golem stands up and attacks them. Four will-o&#39;-wisps also pop out of nowhere and join the fray (they&#39;re invisible when the PCs enter the room).

  After the characters dispose of the golem and of the wisps, they can spend some time going through Mortimer&#39;s research. His notes explain at great length how to make a flesh golem that is nearly identical to someone, using a clone spell. Unfortunately, the notes are incomplete, which means the characters will need to do some research if they want to construct their own clone golems.

  Treasure. 
The PCs find a potion of clairvoyance, a potion of fire resistance, and oil of sharpness.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
    </adventure>
    <adventure>
      <uid>4361</uid>
      <name>Concluding the Adventure</name>
      <note>
        <name>Introduction</name>
        <text>The adventure ends when the characters defeat Mortimer Yorman, or when Nabulee el Jasafir is beheaded. In the latter case, Mortimer sends his clone golem to steal all of Nabulee&#39;s valuables a few days later and disables the portal that leads to the vault.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Solving the Mystery	</name>
        <text>If the PCs manage to track down Mortimer Yorman and Nabulee el Jasafir lives, award them an additional 3,000 XP each. Nabulee also gives the adventurers a magic item from his extradimensional vault, chosen from the following list: wand of lightning bolts, cloak of arachnida, sword of sharpness, robes of eyes,
ring of resistance, boots of levitation, bottomless tankard, dueling sword, purse of the lady, and ring of truthfulness (feel free to add or replace other magic items as you see fit).</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>New Magic Items</name>
        <text>The bottomless tankard, the dueling sword, the purse of the lady, and the ring of truthfulness are new magic items. You can
find their statistics in "Appendix I: Monsters and Magic Items."</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>The Auction House	</name>
        <text>Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary is one of the many ways you can introduce a magic item shop in your game world. Because it&#39;s an
auction house, you get to choose which items are available at any given time and how much they cost. Note that because Nabulee&#39;s clients are all wealthy merchants and nobles, prices will most likely be pretty steep!
  If you don&#39;t want to include a magic item shop in your game world, the local authorities later learn that Aaron had acquired the scarab of death at Nabulee&#39;s shop and close the place.
Nabulee doesn&#39;t go to jail because they also find out that Mortimer was the culprit. Nabulee leaves Waterdeep and starts a new business somewhere else.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>Tomb Raiders	</name>
        <text>If the characters searched Mortimer&#39;s house in "Part 3: Mortimer Yorman," they might have found the map in his office that shows

the location of the tombs that he still needs to explore. What the PCs find in these ancient sites is completely up to you. They could be empty because someone beat Mortimer to it, or this could be the beginning of an epic treasure hunt of your own design.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>The Grand Auction	</name>
        <text>Nabulee plans on having a major auction later this year, during which he intends to sell off the most expensive items in his vault. Nobles, wealthy merchants, and adventurers from all
over Faerun are expected to come to Waterdeep with large amounts of money. Unfortunately, the announcement of this event has also attracted dozens of thieves, cutpurses, and highwaymen who are already preparing for this grand auction.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
      <note>
        <name>The Blood Pact	</name>
        <text>Archibald Littlehorn is the youngest son of a domestic servant. He was smarter than most kids, and his mother&#39;s employer decided to take him under his wing. He taught Archibald how to read, and later hired him as an assistant. The young man quickly learned everything there was to know about being a merchant, but without money, he would never become one.

  Archibald&#39;s greed eventually drew the attention of a powerful otherworldly being who came to visit him on the material plane. The creature offered Archibald a large sum of money in exchange for the souls of his offspring when they die. At that time, Archibald was sure he wouldn&#39;t want any children. He accepted the creature&#39;s offer and signed a blood pact. Lord Littlehorn never found out who the entity was or where it came from.

  Archibald will do anything he can to get Aaron&#39;s soul back so he may resurrect him. Unfortunately, Archibald doesn&#39;t even know where to start searching. Wherever it is and whatever twisted creature has it, Archibald is going to need powerful adventurers to travel to another plane of existence, defeat the otherworldly being, and bring back Aaron&#39;s soul.</text>
        <expanded>0</expanded>
      </note>
    </adventure>
    <pc>
      <uid>4362</uid>
      <label>Test PC</label>
      <name>Human Guy</name>
      <abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
      <hd>1d8</hd>
    </pc>
    <pc>
      <uid>4363</uid>
      <label>Test PC 2</label>
      <name>Human Guy</name>
      <abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
      <hd>1d8</hd>
    </pc>
    <npc>
      <uid>4364</uid>
      <label>Nabulee el Jasafir</label>
      <name>Merchant</name>
      <type>humanoid (human)</type>
      <alignment>neutral</alignment>
      <abilities>10,13,9,9,12,17,</abilities>
      <hpMax>49</hpMax>
      <hpCurrent>49</hpCurrent>
      <hd>14d8</hd>
      <ac>15</ac>
      <armor>glamoured studded leather, ring of protection</armor>
      <speed>30 ft.</speed>
      <savingThrow>
        <modifier>2</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>1</ability>
        <modifier>3</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>2</ability>
        <modifier>1</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>3</ability>
        <modifier>1</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>4</ability>
        <modifier>3</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <savingThrow>
        <ability>5</ability>
        <modifier>5</modifier>
      </savingThrow>
      <skill>
        <id>2</id>
        <modifier>1</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>11</id>
        <modifier>3</modifier>
      </skill>
      <skill>
        <id>13</id>
        <modifier>5</modifier>
      </skill>
      <resist>Fire</resist>
      <senses>Darkvision 60ft</senses>
      <passive>13</passive>
      <languages>Common</languages>
      <cr>4</cr>
      <slots>0,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
      <slotsCurrent>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
      <trait>
        <name>Empower Spell</name>
        <text>When Nabulee rolls damage for a spell, he can reroll up to three damage dice. He must use the new rolls.</text>
      </trait>
      <trait>
        <name>Spellcasting</name>
        <text>Nabulee is an 8th-level spellcaster. His spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 14, +6 to hit with spell attacks).</text>
      </trait>
      <action>
        <name>Dagger</name>
        <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4 + 1) piercing damage.</text>
        <attack>
          <name>Dagger</name>
          <atk>4</atk>
          <dmg>1d4</dmg>
        </attack>
      </action>
      <spell>
        <name>Burning Hands</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot cone)</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>As you hold your hands with thumbs touching and fingers spread, a thin sheet of flames shoots forth from your outstretched fingertips. Each creature in a 15-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren&#39;t being worn or carried.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 220</text>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Efreeti)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Chill Touch</name>
        <school>7</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>You create a ghostly, skeletal hand in the space of a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the creature to assail it with the chill of the grave. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 necrotic damage, and it can&#39;t regain hit points until the start of your next turn. Until then, the hand clings to the target.
	If you hit an undead target, it also has disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the end of your next turn.
	This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 221</text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Dancing Lights</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a bit of phosphorus or wychwood, or a glowworm</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You create up to four torch-sized lights within range, making them appear as torches, lanterns, or glowing orbs that hover in the air for the duration. You can also combine the four lights into one glowing vaguely humanoid form of Medium size. Whichever form you choose, each light sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius.
	As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the lights up to 60 feet to a new spot within range. A light must be within 20 feet of another light created by this spell, and a light winks out if it exceeds the spell&#39;s range.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 230</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Detect Magic</name>
        <school>3</school>
        <ritual>1</ritual>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.
	The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 231</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Paladin</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Dimension Door</name>
        <school>2</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>500 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You teleport yourself from your current location to any other spot within range. You arrive at exactly the spot desired. It can be a place you can see, one you can visualize, or one you can describe by stating distance and direction, such as 200 feet straight downward or upward to the northwest at a 45-degree angle, 300 feet.
	You can bring along objects as long as their weight doesn&#39;t exceed what you can carry. You can also bring one willing creature of your size or smaller who is carrying gear up to its carrying capacity. The creature must be within 5 feet of you when you cast this spell.
	If you would arrive in a place already occupied by an object or a creature, you and any creature traveling with you each take 4d6 force damage, and the spell fails to teleport you.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 233</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Ranger (Fey Wanderer)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Fireball</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a tiny ball of bat guano and sulfur</materials>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A bright streak flashes from your pointing finger to a point you choose within range then blossoms with a low roar into an explosion of flame. Each creature in a 20-foot radius must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
	The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren&#39;t being worn or carried.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 241</text>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Efreeti)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Invisibility</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>an eyelash encased in gum arabic</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <text>A creature you touch becomes invisible until the spell ends. Anything the target is wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target&#39;s person. The spell ends for a target that attacks or casts a spell.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 254</text>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Minor Illusion</name>
        <school>6</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a bit of fleece</materials>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <text>You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration. The illusion also ends if you dismiss it as an action or cast this spell again.
	If you create a sound, its volume can range from a whisper to a scream. It can be your voice, someone else&#39;s voice, a lion&#39;s roar, a beating of drums, or any other sound you choose. The sound continues unabated throughout the duration, or you can make discrete sounds at different times before the spell ends.
	If you create an image of an object, such as a chair, muddy footprints, or a small chest, it must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. The image can&#39;t create sound, light, smell, or any other sensory effect. Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it.
	If a creature uses its action to examine the sound or image, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 260</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Prestidigitation</name>
        <school>8</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>10 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Up to 1 hour</duration>
        <text>This spell is a minor magical trick that novice spellcasters use for practice. You create one of the following magical effects within range:

• You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, faint musical notes, or an odd odor.
• You instantaneously light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire.
• You instantaneously clean or soil an object no larger than 1 cubic foot.
• You chill, warm, or flavor up to 1 cubic foot of nonliving material for 1 hour.
• You make a color, a small mark, or a symbol appear on an object or a surface for 1 hour.
• You create a nonmagical trinket or an illusory image that can fit in your hand and that lasts until the end of your next turn.

If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 267</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Ray of Frost</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A frigid beam of blue-white light streaks toward a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, it takes 1d8 cold damage, and its speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.
	The spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 271</text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Artificer</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Scorching Ray</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You create three rays of fire and hurl them at targets within range. You can hurl them at one target or several.
	Make a ranged spell attack for each ray. On a hit, the target takes 2d6 fire damage.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you create one additional ray for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 273</text>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Genie Efreeti)</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Shield</name>
        <school>1</school>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack or targeted by the magic missile spell</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 275</text>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Hexblade)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Tongues</name>
        <school>3</school>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a small clay model of a ziggurat</materials>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>This spell grants the creature you touch the ability to understand any spoken language it hears. Moreover, when the target speaks, any creature that knows at least one language and can hear the target understands what it says.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 283</text>
        <sclass>Bard</sclass>
        <sclass>Cleric</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <spell>
        <name>Wall of Fire</name>
        <school>5</school>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <v>1</v>
        <s>1</s>
        <m>1</m>
        <materials>a small piece of phosphorus</materials>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You create a wall of fire on a solid surface within range. You can make the wall up to 60 feet long, 20 feet high, and 1 foot think, or a ringed wall up to 20 feet in diameter, 20 feet high, and 1 foot think. The wall is opaque and lasts for the duration.
	When the wall appears, each creature within its area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 5d8 fire damage, or half as much damage on a successful save.
	One side of the wall, selected by you when you cast this spell, deals 5d8 fire damage to each creature that ends its turn within 10 feet of that side or inside the wall. A creature takes the same damage when it enters the wall for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there. The other side of the wall deals no damage.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 285</text>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
        <sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
        <sclass>Druid</sclass>
        <sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Celestial)</sclass>
        <sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
        <sclass>Wizard</sclass>
      </spell>
      <text>Nabulee el Jasafir is a young merchant from the desert city of Calimport. Nabulee isn’t a particularly bright sorcerer (he’s actually fairly stupid) and this reflects on his tactics in combat. 
He tends to blow things up with his fire spells, and often ends up burning everything around him (including his own house).</text>
      <environment>1028</environment>
    </npc>
    <note>
      <name>Introduction</name>
      <text>The Scarab of Death is a 5th edition module for three to five characters of levels 9 to 11. The adventure normally takes place in Waterdeep, but you can easily adapt it and run it in any large city.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>Adventure Background</name>
      <text>Nabulee el Jasafir is a merchant from the desert city of Calimport, who owns a small auction house in Waterdeep. His business is buying enchanted items that adventurers recover from the ruins of Faerûn, and reselling them to the highest bidder. Over the years, he made quite a reputation for himself, and many Waterdhavian notables now spend fortunes on his magical trinkets as a means of showing their wealth and status.

  Nabulee stores his money and his enchanted items in an extradimensional vault. He believes his safe is impenetrable because the only way to access it is via a magical portal that only
he can use. He doesn&#39;t hesitate to brag about how many valuables he has in it (always exaggerating) and he&#39;s eager to explain how the portal works.

  Mortimer Yorman is a necromancer who has been working with Nabulee for years. He has a passion for magical constructs and has learned how to make near-perfect copies of
existing people. Mortimer can use a clone spell to duplicate someone&#39;s body, tear it apart, and use the pieces to create a flesh golem that is nearly identical to the original person and that retains a large part of their personality. When Nabulee told Mortimer about his safe, the necromancer (correctly) assumed that a flesh golem made with a clone of the Calishite would be able to use the portal that leads to the extradimensional room.
  Mortimer just couldn&#39;t resist the temptation and devised a plan to rob Nabulee of all his valuables. He hired some thugs to mug the Calishite and chop off a piece of the merchant while he was unconscious (the material component of the clone spell). A few months later, Mortimer had a perfect copy of Nabulee and was ready for the heist. His plan, however, went ludicrously wrong.
  
On the morning the adventure begins, Mortimer went to visit Nabulee to complain about his pay. This was in fact a way to distract the merchant while the golem snuck into the vault. The construct first picked up a scarab- shaped brooch that was lying on a table, and then started searching the cabinet for more valuables to steal. That&#39;s when the golem triggered a magical alarm that immediately notified Nabulee of its presence.

  When the Calishite suddenly asked Mortimer to leave his house, the necromancer knew
that something had gone wrong. In a panic, he mentally ordered his golem to put all the stolen items back where they belonged and to leave the vault. He then cast a sleep spell on Nabulee to disable him, tied him to a chair (to have enough time to cast his spells), and erased any trace of his presence from the merchant&#39;s memory with a modify memory spell. Nabulee doesn&#39;t remember seeing Mortimer that morning.

  In the meantime, the scarab the golem had taken from the table turned into a nightmarish beetle-shaped creature that drilled into its flesh. It burrowed inside the golem searching for a way to kill it, but the construct was immune to the scarab&#39;s deadly curse. The beetle eventually gave up and burst out of the golem&#39;s body as it was running toward the exit. Later that day, a young Waterdhavian noble picked up the scarab at the end of an auction and died a block away from Nabulee&#39;s house.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>Adventure Synopsis</name>
      <text>In the first part of the adventure, the PCs encounter a dead noble in the streets of Waterdeep and witness a beetle-shaped construct bursting out of his chest (see "Part 1: A Deadly Scarab"). A moment later, an eccentric- looking man runs out of a nearby mansion toward the scene. When he realizes what has occurred, he hires the PCs to investigate the noble&#39;s death.
  Most of the adventure takes place in Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary (see "Part 2: The Investigation"). It&#39;s a fairly straightforward inquest in which the PCs learn that the noble apparently had picked up a scarab of death (see "Appendix I: Monsters and Magic Items") on
his way out of Nabulee&#39;s auction house. As the characters continue their investigation, they&#39;ll learn that someone other than Nabulee entered his extradimensional vault and that someone was with the merchant in his office that morning. The adventurers will then either have to track down the person who was in the vault or restore Nabulee&#39;s memories. Either way will lead them to the person responsible for the noble&#39;s death.
  In the last part of the adventure ("Part 3: Mortimer Yorman"), the PCs go to Mortimer&#39;s house to try to find out how the necromancer managed to enter Nabulee&#39;s vault and take out the scarab of death.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>Running the Adventure</name>
      <text>When preparing to DM this adventure, several tools can help you start strong and run it smoothly.
	  
Getting the PCs Involved

The adventure begins when the PCs are walking around Waterdeep, and more specifically, in
the Raging Bull District (see "Appendix II: The Raging Bull District"), but you can run the module in any major city. How the characters get there is left to your discretion. (Note that this can be as simple as going back to town to rest after the PCs&#39; latest adventure.)
  The module also assumes that Nabulee hires the characters because he knows them by reputation and because he recognizes them. If the adventurers are new to the region, this is unlikely to happen. In this case, you should start the adventure with a short prelude. For example, the PCs could help the local authorities stop
a murderous stone golem that escaped from a local wizards&#39; guild. Naturally, Nabulee witnesses the PCs defeating the golem and will recognize them when the time comes.

Roleplaying

The module lists the information that the NPCs know as bullet points for your convenience, but feel free to roleplay the interactions if you want to, and reveal what the NPCs know as part of a conversation.
  Similarly, when the PCs need to make a Charisma check to obtain information, the adventure only indicates the DC of the check, but you can ask your players to impersonate their character, or describe their actions before allowing the check.
Monster Statistics
This adventure features new monsters and NPCs. You can find their statistics in "Appendix I: Monsters and Magic Items." Except when otherwise specified, all NPCs are commoners.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>The Raging Bull District</name>
      <text>The Raging Bull District was named after the pretentious statue that stands in the middle of the plaza with the same name. It&#39;s a bohemian neighborhood with many small theaters, music halls, art galleries, and alehouses. It&#39;s also a place where you can buy all sorts of strange and esoteric items if you know where to look.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    Recent History	</name>
      <text>Not so long ago, mostly modest people lived in the Raging Bull District. When Nabulee opened his Bazaar of the Extraordinary, he slowly made a reputation for himself, and more and more wealthy citizens were drawn to his auction house. The Raging Bull District is now a trendy place to go for the young Waterdhavian elite.
This has caused prices to rise drastically in the neighborhood, and frustration
is spreading among those who don&#39;t benefit from this wealthy crowd.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    Important NPCs and Groups</name>
      <text>You will find below a quick summary of the important NPCs of the Raging Bull District and their roles in the adventure.
	  
The Bellowing Bulls
   The Bellowing Bulls is the name of a resistance movement that aims to draw "wealthy kids" out of the neighborhood. The Bellowing Bulls are harmless but many of their members are on the city watch&#39;s "most wanted" list because of the foul guerilla tactics they use. They believe that if they harass the "pompous equines" enough, the latter will stop coming to their neighborhood. Their modus operandi is to go fishing for excrements in the sewers, and then use charm spells to force the merchants and nobles to throw them at each other&#39;s faces.
They also leave fish to rot in buckets in the less accessible parts of the sewers to cover up the smell, and pour the soiled water in the places the aristocrats like to go.

Constable Bernard Kothont
   Bernard is an ambitious politician who perfectly understands how to gain the trust of other nobles (mostly through flattery) and how to manipulate them. He was born into a minor aristocratic family in the Castle Ward, and spent most of his youth in a monastery in the countryside where he received a proper education. Bernard started his career as a simple administrative clerk, doing the bidding of more prominent nobles, but quickly rose in the hierarchy. He&#39;s now in charge of law enforcement in the Raging Bull District.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
    <note>
      <name>    Notables Places	</name>
      <text>You can find below the most significant landmarks of the Raging Bull District.
	  
The Belfry
   This large stone tower is where the city watch attends to the public and locks up criminals while waiting for their trial.

The Sewers
   A long time ago, tanners lived in the Raging Bull District. It has an extensive underground sewage system that they used to evacuate the large amounts of filthy water that their craft produced. Today, the main canals are still in use, but most of the side ones are out of maintenance and forgotten.

The Raging Bull Plaza
   The Raging Bull Plaza is the heart of the district, and where most of the alehouses are. The statue of a bull in a fighting stance stands in the middle of the plaza.

Shops	
   The Raging Bull District has dozens of small shops that sell all kinds of bizarre and exotic items, most of which nobody wants. You can find below the ones that might be of interest to the PCs.

Horus Valentina
   Horus is the illegitimate son of a wealthy noble of Waterdeep. His father gives him a decent amount of coin each month in exchange for his discretion. Horus uses this money to sustain himself and to create some of the most ridiculously flamboyant outfits that Waterdeep has ever seen. 
  In the Adventure. Mortimer&#39;s clone golem of Nabulee was wearing a purple Valentina shirt when it entered the Calishite&#39;s extradimensional vault. Because Nabulee is the only person who wears Horus&#39;s clothing, the PCs can track down the golem&#39;s tunic with a locate object spell (see "The Clone Golem" on page 18). Jefra&#39;s Exotic Smells
A female half-orc named Jefra runs this shop. Jefra has the keen sense of smell of a pig, and is capable of discerning subtle scents like no human can. She uses her gift to make exquisite perfumes. Jefra is also a skilled alchemist who secretly sells poisons and potions to those who can afford them. 

Lord Find-It-All
Murphy Stormwind-aka Lord Find-it-All-is a diviner who helps wealthy aristocrats find their lost objects (mostly wedding rings that all too often go missing after a visit to the brothel). Murphy Stormwind is an opportunistic wizard who takes advantage of the nobles&#39; negligence to make a small fortune recovering their lost items. He can hold his own in a fight but he avoids them when possible.
  In the Adventure. Murphy is an expert at finding items and people. He can help the PCs locate the golem that entered Nabulee&#39;s vault on the morning the adventure begins (see "The Clone Golem" on page 18).

Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary
Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary is a magic item auction house. Many notables of Waterdeep go to this luxurious mansion to buy magical trinkets (which rarely have any use to adventurers). Nabulee el Jasafir is a young merchant from the desert city of Calimport. Nabulee isn&#39;t a particularly bright sorcerer (he&#39;s actually fairly stupid) and this reflects on his tactics in combat. He tends to blow things up with his fire spells, and often ends up burning everything around him (including his own house).
  In the Adventure. In "Part 2: The Investigation," the PCs talk to Nabulee&#39;s staff and search the auction house in search for clues on how Aaron might have acquired the scarab of death that killed him.

The White Buck Inn
The White Buck Inn is the only inn in the Raging Bull District. A gnome named Bartolomeo Berrick (Bart for short) runs the place with his daughter Decibel. It&#39;s cozy and clean, the food is excellent, and it has a couple of luxury suites where many nobles stay when they come to Waterdeep to go to Nabulee&#39;s Bazaar of the Extraordinary.</text>
      <expanded>0</expanded>
    </note>
  </campaign>
</data>