<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Duelist (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points, melee weapons only, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you are hit by a melee attack you can see, you can use your reaction to add 1 to your AC.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Enhanced Weapon (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 3 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Infusion (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 5 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose a damage type from: acid, cold, fire, force, lightning, necrotic, poison, psychic, radiant, and thunder. Your weapon attacks from this weapon deal an additional d6 damage of that type.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Magus (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 5 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>Whilst holding this weapon you have a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls and a +1 bonus to AC.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Magical Core (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any cantrip. You can use an action to cast this cantrip from the weapon. You can use this ability twice per long rest. The spell attack bonus of this spell is +4, and the spell save DC is 12.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Slayer (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 5 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose an enemy type from, beasts, fey, humanoids, monstrosities, or undead. Your weapon attacks from this weapon deal 2d6 additional damage to all creatures of this type.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Spell Link (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points, spellcasters only, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain an additional level 1 spell slot. This spell slot is refreshed on a long rest.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Spell Storing (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any level 1 spell. You can use an action to cast this spell from the weapon. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

The spell attack bonus of this spell is +4, and the spell save difficulty is 12.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Spell Storing (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 4 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any level 2 spell. You can use an action to cast this spell from the weapon. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

The spell attack bonus of this spell is +4, and the spell save difficulty is 12.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Bully</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks when the target can see you and you are holding this weapon.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Charmward</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>You have advantage on saving throws against the charmed condition.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Darkvision</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You have darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, increase the range by 60 feet.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 7</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Deathward</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>You have advantage on death saving throws.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Fearward</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>You have advantage on saving throws against the frightened condition.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Focus</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points, spellcasters only</prerequisite>
    <text>This weapon counts as a spellcasting focus.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Giant-Bane</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You weapon attacks deal an additional d6 damage to creatures of large size or larger.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Gripped</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>You cannot be made to drop this weapon against your will.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Guiding</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>The weapon sheds bright light in a 15-foot radius, and dim light for an additional 15-foot. When you select this upgrade, you choose the color of the light.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Hidden</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to speak this weapon's command word, the weapon appears as an diffferent item of a similar size until you speak the command word again to end this effect. The weapon retains all abilities during this time, and if a creature uses its action to examine the item, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful DC 12 Intelligence (Investigation) check. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Hinge-Bane</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point, melee weapons only</prerequisite>
    <text>You deal maximum damage against inanimate objects with attacks made from this weapon.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Indomitable (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can immediately make an attack with this weapon before you fall unconscious.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Jarring (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Any enemy that suffers damage from a weapon attack made by this weapon cannot make attacks of opportunity against you until the beginning of your next turn.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Marksman</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 3 Spirit points, ranged weapon only</prerequisite>
    <text>This weapon does not require physical ammo, upon readying this weapon a spectral arrow or bolt is notched that acts as magical ammo of its normal type.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Overpower (Brawler)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20, you can force a creature that suffers damage from this weapon to make a DC 14 Strength saving throw, in addition to any damage caused. On a failed save, it is knocked prone.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Overpower (Brutish)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20, you can force a creature that suffers damage from this weapon to make a DC 14 Strength saving throw, in addition to any damage caused. On a failed save, it is shoved 10 feet in a direction of your choice.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Overpower (Dread)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20, you can force a creature that suffers damage from this weapon to make a DC 14 Wisdom saving throw, in addition to any damage caused. On a failed save, it is frightened of you for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on it on a success.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Overpower (Disarming)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20, you can force a creature that suffers damage from this weapon to make a DC 14 Strength saving throw, in addition to any damage caused. On a failed save, you can target one item the creature is holding, it drops that item. If it is holding the item in two or more hands, it has advantage on this check.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Overpower (Hamstring)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20, you can force a creature that suffers damage from this weapon to make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw, in addition to any damage caused. On a failed save, its movement speed is halved until your next turn.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Overpower (Poisonous)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20, you can force a creature that suffers damage from this weapon to make a DC14 Constitution saving throw, in addition to any damage caused. On a failed save, it gains the poisoned condition. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on it on a success.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 8</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Poisonward</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>You have advantage on saving throws against the poisoned condition.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Proficient (Lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain proficiency in a skill of your choice.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Quick</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>You have advantage on saving throws against the poisoned condition.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Ritualist</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>The time to ritual cast spells is halved whilst this weapon is in your possession.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Shadowed</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>When in cover, you count the cover as being one degree higher than it is, for example 1/2 cover counts as 3/4 cover.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Unflinching</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged attack rolls.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 1: Willing</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 1+, 1 Spirit point</prerequisite>
    <text>You can add 1d4 to a skill check, you may use this ability after rolling the check, but before you know if it was successful. You must declare you are using this feature before you make the roll, and you must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Amplify (Lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain +1 to an ability score of your choice, to a maximum of 20.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Duelist (Lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, melee weapons only, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you are hit by a melee attack you can see, you can use your reaction to add 2 to your AC.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Enhanced Weapon (Lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 6 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 9</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Guardian (Lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain proficiency in a saving throw of your choice.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 10</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Keen (Lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>The weapon causes a critical hit when the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 10</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Magical Core (Lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any cantrip. You can use an action to cast this cantrip from the weapon. You can use this ability at will. The spell attack bonus of this spell is +4, and the spell save DC is 14.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 10</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Spell Link (Lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, spellcasters only, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain an additional level 2 spell slot. This spell slot is refreshed on a long rest.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 10</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Spell Storing (Lvl 3)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 6 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any level 3 spell. You can use an action to cast this spell from the weapon. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

The spell attack bonus of this spell is +6, and the spell save difficulty is 14.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 10</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Stern</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, requires a weapon with the heavy trait, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>At the beginning of your turn, you can declare you are using this ability. Until the beginning of your next turn, you gain a +2 bonus to your AC, and your movement speed is reduced to 0. You cannot take any reactions whilst this ability is in effect.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 10</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Barbaric</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with this weapon, you gain advantage on your next attack.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 10</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Battlemage</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, spellcasters only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you cast a spell, you can use your bonus action to make an attack with this weapon.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Blindside (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, rogues only</prerequisite>
    <text>You increase the damage of your sneak attacks made by this weapon by d6.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Bolstering</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>When you are the target of a spell that causes you to regain hit points, you regain additional hit points equal to your Constitution modifier.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Challenge</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, barbarians only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you use the reckless attack feature nominate one creature you can see, that creature does not gain advantage against you from that feature until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Charged Smite (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points, paladins only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you deal damage with the divine smite feature, you deal an additional d8 radiant damage.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Distracting (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points, ranged weapons only</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to make an attack with this weapon, after you do so you can move up to half your speed. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Divine Grace</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points, clerics only</prerequisite>
    <text>You can spend 10 minutes concentrating on this weapon to commune with your deity. Over the next 24 hours you can reroll any one dice of your choosing, though you must take the second result. After you have used this reroll, you must complete a short or long rest before you can commune with your deity again to gain this benefit.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Divine Touch</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, clerics, druids, or paladins only</prerequisite>
    <text>The first time each turn you deal melee damage with this weapon, an ally within 5 foot regains d4 hit points.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Doomerang</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>The weapon gains the thrown trait. When used this way it flies back to your hand at the end of your turn via the most direct route. Any creature in its path must make DC 10 Dexterity saving throw, suffering d6 damage of the weapon's type on a failed save.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: En Guard</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points, fighters only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you or an ally within 5ft is the target of an attack you can see, you can use your reaction for one of the following benefits:

	• +5 bonus AC to the target for the duration of the attack.
	• After the attack you may move up to your speed. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks
	• Make a melee weapon attack against the attacking creature.
	• Gain advantage against the attacking creature until the end of your next turn.

You must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Eye of the Storm</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 5 Spirit points, monks only</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to restore ki points equal to half your monk level, rounded down. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Guard</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, melee weapon only</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on a weapon attack you can see that is targeting an ally within 5ft.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Hunter's Watch</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points, rangers only</prerequisite>
    <text>You may use your reaction to make an attack of opportunity against a creature moving within 30 feet of you. A creature hit by this attack must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw, in addition to any damage caused. On a failed save, its movement is reduced to 0. You must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Jarring (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Any enemy that you make a weapon attack against with this weapon cannot make attacks of opportunity against you until the beginning of your next turn.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Mobile (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Your base movement speed is increased by 5 feet.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Precise (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can reroll damage results of 1 from this weapon, you must accept the second result.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Proficient (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain proficiency in 2 skills of your choice.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 11</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Piercing (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You have +2 on attack rolls against enemies with shields.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Power of the Ancestors</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, sorcerers only</prerequisite>
    <text>Once per day when you expend sorcery points, you instead do not expend any.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Quickshot</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, ranged weapon only</prerequisite>
    <text>The first time you hit with an attack on your turn, gain advantage on your next attack with this weapon until the end of your turn.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Rampaging</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points, melee weapon only</prerequisite>
    <text>You have advantage on attacks with this weapon if you began your turn over 20 foot away from the target.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Reckless</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>When you have advantage on attacks made with this weapon, you can reroll your damage dice. You must accept the second result.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Reverberation</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 5 Spirit points, bards only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you make an attack with this weapon, you can expend a bardic inspiration to instill a tale into your attack. If a creature takes damage from this attack it must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell DC. On a failed roll, the creature is frightened of, or charmed by you, (your choice) for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on it on a success.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Scout</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You have advantage on attacks with this weapon in the first round of combat.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Sniping</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points, requires a ranged weapon</prerequisite>
    <text>When making attacks with this weapon, your target's cover counts as being one degree lower than it is. For example 3/4 cover counts as 1/2 cover. This has no effect against creatures not in cover.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Spellhunter</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Attacks with this weapon deal an additional 2d6 psychic damage versus spellcasters.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Sprightly</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use your bonus action to gain advantage on your next attack roll, if the attack hits you must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Telepathic Link</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>The weapon gifts you the ability to communicate telepathically with any creature you are familiar with within 60 feet, that you can see.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Transforming</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to turn this weapon into a mundane version of itself, during this period it cannot be seen by the detect magic spell or similar, and loses all abilities. You can use an action to speak the weapon's command word, restoring it to its magical form.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Transposed</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use your bonus action to summon or dismiss this weapon to/from a pocket dimension.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Trapped Spell</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points, warlocks only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you complete a long rest you can store one spell you know in this weapon. You can as an bonus action release this spell from the weapon. You do not need to expend a spell slot, and you ignore any verbal or somatic components.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Underhanded</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use your reaction to cause a melee attack targeting you, or an ally within 5 foot, to be made at disadvantage. If this attack misses, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Vicious (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 20, your critical hit deals an extra 2d6 damage of the weapon's type.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Wild Spell</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 3 Spirit points, druids only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you use your wild shape feature you can expend a spell slot of the relevant level to ready a spell. Once during your transformation, you can use an action to cast that spell.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 12</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 2: Will of the Ancestors</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to release the wills of your ancestors from the blade. "Each enemy within 15 feet must make a DC 14 Wisdom saving throw. An enemy takes 2d8 psychic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. You must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Duelist (lvl 3)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 5+, 6 Spirit points, melee weapons only, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you are hit by a melee attack you can see, you can use your reaction to add 3 to your AC.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Duelist (lvl 3)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 6 Spirit points, melee weapons only, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you are hit by a melee attack you can see, you can use your reaction to add 3 to your AC.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Enhanced Weapon (lvl 3)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 10 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Flying</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 6 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain a flying speed equal to your movement speed.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Infusion (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 10 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose an damage type from acid, cold, fire, force, lightning, necrotic, poison, psychic, radiant, and thunder. Your weapon attacks from this weapon deal an additional 2d6 damage of that type.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Magical Core (lvl 3)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 6 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any level 1 spell. You can use an action to cast this spell from the weapon. You can use this ability twice per long rest. The spell attack bonus of this spell is +8, and the spell save DC is 16.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Magus (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 8 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>Whilst holding this weapon you have a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls and a +2 bonus to AC.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Spell Storing (lvl 4)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 8 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any level 4 spell. You can use an action to cast this spell from the weapon. You must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again. The spell attack bonus of this spell is +8, and the spell save difficulty is 16.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Spell Link (lvl 3)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 6 Spirit points, spellcasters only, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain an additional level 3 spell slot. This spell slot is refreshed on a long rest.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Blindside (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 8 Spirit points, rogues only</prerequisite>
    <text>You increase the damage of your sneak attacks made by this weapon by 2d6.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Blood-drinker (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20, you gain temporary hit points equal to half the damage dealt by this weapon, rounded down.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Brawn</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You cannot be knocked prone, and have advantage on grapple checks.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 13</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Charged Smite (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 4 Spirit points, paladins only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you deal damage with the divine smite feature, you deal an additional 2d8 radiant damage.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Distracting (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 4 Spirit points, ranged weapons only</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to make an attack with this weapon, before you do so you can move up to half your speed. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Elemental Manipulation</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>When you cast a spell with a spell slot that deals acid, cold, fire, force, lightning, necrotic, radiant, or thunder damage, you can substitute that damage type with one other type from that list (you can change only one damage type per casting of a spell).

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Focused</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, pick an ability score. A creature that suffers damage from this weapon suffers disadvantage on saves relating to this ability score until your next turn.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Hardy</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to spend up to half your hit dice, recovering that much health. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Indomitable (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can immediately take the Attack action using this weapon before you fall unconscious.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Lashing</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>When you make an opportunity attack you may make an additional attack with this weapon, you do not add your ability modifier to the damage of this attack.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Nemesis</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can nominate a Nemesis for this weapon by spending 10 minutes in concentration, thinking of a target creature you are familiar with. Attacks from this weapon deal an additional 2d8 psychic damage against the target. You cannot change the Nemesis, or select a new one if the target is dead, until 1 week has passed.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Nemesis</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can nominate a Nemesis for this weapon by spending 10 minutes in concentration, thinking of a target creature you are familiar with. Attacks from this weapon deal an additional 2d8 psychic damage against the target. You cannot change the Nemesis, or select a new one if the target is dead, until 1 week has passed.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Rapid Strike</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 4 Spirit points, melee weapon; 6 Spirit points, ranged weapon</prerequisite>
    <text>When you make an attack with this weapon you can use your bonus action to make an additional attack against a different creature within range. You do not add your ability modifier to the damage of this attack.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Proficient (lvl 3)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 6 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain proficiency in 3 skills of your choice.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Shimmering</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Ranged weapon attacks against you have disadvantage whilst you are within 5 feet of another creature.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Spelleater</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>After a creature casts a spell whilst within 5 foot, you can spend your reaction to make an attack of opportunity against that creature.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Spellhunter</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Concentration checks caused by this weapon are made at disadvantage.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Sustaining</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You do not need to eat, drink, or sleep whilst this weapon is in your possession.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Tracking</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 2 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to learn the exact direction of a creature who has taken damage from this weapon. This will only work against creatures who were damaged in the last week, whilst they are within 10 miles.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 3: Will (lvl 1)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 10+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can re-roll a failed concentration check. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 14</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Amplify (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 10 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain +2 to an ability score of your choice, to a maximum of 20.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Guardian (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 7 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain proficiency on a saving throw of your choice. If you can see the source of the effect, you also gain advantage on these saving throws.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Magical Core (lvl 4)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 8 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any level 1 spell. You can use an action to cast this spell from the weapon. You can use this ability at will.

The spell attack bonus of this spell is +8, and the spell save DC is 16.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Slayer (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 10 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose an enemy type from, beasts, fey, humanoids, monstrosities, or undead. Your weapon attacks from this weapon deal 4d6 additional damage to all creatures of this type.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Spell Storing (lvl 4)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 10 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>When you select this upgrade, choose any level 5 spell. You can use an action to cast this spell from the weapon. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

The spell attack bonus of this spell is +8, and the spell save difficulty is 16.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Spell Link (lvl 4)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 8 Spirit points, spellcasters only, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain an additional level 4 spell slot. This spell slot is refreshed on a long rest.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Truesight</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 10 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>You have truesight when holding this weapon.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Beacon</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to plant this weapon in the ground. For the next 1 minute, whilst your weapon remains planted, the weapon glows with a divine light, shining bright light in a 30-foot radius, and dim light for an additional 30-foot. All allies within 15 feet gain a +1 bonus to their AC, and their attacks deal d6 additional force damage. Any ally that can draw line of sight to the weapon can take a bonus action to move up to half their movement towards the weapon. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.

You must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Blood-drinker (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 7 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 19 or 20, you temporary hit points equal to the damage dealt.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Dancing</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 5 Spirit points, melee weapon only</prerequisite>
    <text>You use an action to speak the command word allowing this weapon to attack independently for 1 minute. For this duration, the weapon floats in the air and fights independently of you.

You may use a bonus action to move the weapon up to 20 feet and make a melee attack as though you were holding it, and you may use your reaction to allow the weapon to make an opportunity attack from the weapon's location, following the normal attack of opportunity rules. You must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Homing</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 5 Spirit points, ranged weapons only</prerequisite>
    <text>You may attack creatures within range even if you cannot draw line of sight. These attacks are made at disadvantage. Any creature targeted this way counts as being in 3/4 cover.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 15</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Keen (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 10 Spirit points, limited</prerequisite>
    <text>The weapon causes a critical hit when the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 18, 19 or 20.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Mentor</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 3 Spirit points, spellcasters only</prerequisite>
    <text>You can cast any spell you know, even one that is not prepared, by expending a spell slot of the highest level available to you. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Mobile (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 7 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Your base movement speed is increased by 10 feet.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Piercing (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You have +4 on attack rolls against enemies with shields.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Power Surge</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Once per day you can use a spell slot to cast a spell you know of up to 2 levels higher than that of the spell slot.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Precise (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 6 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can reroll damage results from this weapon, you must accept the second result.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Proficient (lvl 4)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain proficiency in 4 skills of your choice.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Protective</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 3 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can make a saving throw at advantage, you must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Rallying</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use an action to raise this weapon in the air and let out a war cry bolstering your allies. For the next minute your weapon lets of a shining radiance, all allies within 30 feet gain advantage on Wisdom saving throws and are immune to the frightened condition. Any ally moving directly towards you during this time can increase their movement speed by 10 feet. You must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Spectral Reach</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Increase the range of this weapon by 5 feet for 1 minute. For the duration, the weapon inflicts an additional d4 damage. You must complete a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Venomous</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 7 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>Each creature damaged by this weapon must succeed on a DC15 Constitution save or suffer 2d6 poison damage at the start of their round for 1 minute. If the creatures saving throw is successful they are immune to this effect for the next 24 hours.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Vicious (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 4 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>If the d20 roll for an attack made with this weapon is a 20, your critical hit deals an extra 4d6 damage of the weapon's type.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Will (lvl 2)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 5 Spirit points, spellcasters only</prerequisite>
    <text>When you fail a concentration check, you can choose to pass instead. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Ancestral Weapons Tier 4: Whirlwind</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 15+, 5 Spirit points</prerequisite>
    <text>You can use your action to perform a melee attack against each creature within 5 feet.

Source:	Ancestral Weapons p. 16</text>
  </feat>
</compendium>
