<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Smutsia (UA)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Con 2, Int 1</ability>
    <proficiency/>
    <spellAbility/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Intelligent and curious beings, Smutsia are eager to explore and figure out all sorts of things. Smutsia are mammals and can at most birth one child a year. When a Smutsia is approaching maturity, it is sent ut to explore more of the world and find new places to live. All Smutsia are monogamous and have one partner for life, which they may have many children with over their lifetime. 

Having lived mostly in burrows and explored during the night, most Smutsia are somewhat afraid of direct sunlight as they don't know what it might do to them.

Your evolution from pangolins has lead to you having similar traits

Source:	Homebrew by Daniel</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Baby smutsia learn to walk within days after their birth, reaching maturity at around 7 years old. It is rare for a smutsia to live longer than 25 years.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Adult Smutsia stand 4 feet tall and 5 feet long, averaging 70 pounds. Your size is small.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d4
Height = 3 feet + 8 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 55 + (2d6 × your size modifier)
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to life underground, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hefty Claws</name>
      <text>Your claws have evolved to dig for various insects through differing terrain. You have a base burrowing speed of 15 feet. In addition, your claws serve as your natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit, you deal 1d4 + your Strength modifier slashing damage.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Armor</name>
      <text>The tough keratin scales covering your entire body grant you a great defensive advantage. Your base armor class is 14 + your Dexterity modifier and is not lowered by having worse armor. Unarmored defenses granted by classes also start with this bonus.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tuck and Ball</name>
      <text>As a reaction when attacked before knowing if it hit, you can tuck into a ball. Granting a +5 to Armor Class, advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws, and disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws. In addition, your speed becomes 0 and cannot be raised. These effects end as you emerge on the start of your next turn. You can use this feature a number of times equivalent to your proficiency bonus, gaining back all expended uses after a short or long rest.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
      <text>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Undercommon.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
