<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Chromatic Dragonborn</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability/>
    <spellAbility>Constitution</spellAbility>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Dragonborn with chromatic ancestry claim the raw elemental power of chromatic dragons. The vibrant colors of black, blue, green, red, and white dragons gleam in those dragonborn's scaled skin and in the deadly energy of their breath weapons. Theirs is the raw elemental fury of the volcano, of biting arctic winds, and of raging lightning storms, as well as the subtle whisper of swamp and forest, toxic and corrosive.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 10</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increases</name>
      <text>When determining your character's ability scores, you increase one of those scores by 2 and increase a different score by 1, or you increase three different scores by 1. Follow this rule regardless of the method you use to determine the scores, such as rolling or point buy.</text>
      <text />
      <text>The "Quick Build" section for your character's class offers suggestions on which scores to increase. You're free to follow those suggestions or to ignore them. Whichever scores you decide to increase, none of the scores can be raised above 20.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 10</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Chromatic Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have a chromatic dragon ancestor, granting you a special magical affinity. Choose one kind of dragon from the Chromatic Ancestry table. This determines the damage type for your other traits, as shown in the table.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Chromatic Ancestry</text>
      <text>Dragon | Damage Type</text>
      <text>Black | Acid</text>
      <text>Blue | Lightning</text>
      <text>Green | Poison</text>
      <text>Red | Fire</text>
      <text>White | Cold</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 10</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Breath Weapon</name>
      <text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with an exhalation of magical energy in a 30-foot line that is 5 feet wide. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus). On a failed save, the creature takes 1d10 damage of the type associated with your Chromatic Ancestry. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage. This damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</text>
      <text />
      <text>You can use your Breath Weapon a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 10</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Draconic Resistance</name>
      <text>You have resistance to the damage type associated with your Chromatic Ancestry.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 10</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Chromatic Warding</name>
      <text>Starting at 5th level, as an action, you can channel your draconic energy to protect yourself. For 1 minute, you become immune to the damage type associated with your Chromatic Ancestry. Once you use this trait, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 10</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>Your character can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for the character. The Player's Handbook offers a list of widespread languages to choose from. The DM is free to add or remove languages from that list for a particular campaign.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 10</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Gem Dragonborn</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability/>
    <spellAbility>Constitution</spellAbility>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Gem dragonborn partake of the heritage of gem dragons, who claim to be heirs of Sardior, the Ruby Dragon. The colors and mysterious powers of gem dragons—amethyst, crystal, emerald, sapphire, and topaz—gleam in these dragonborn's scaled skin and course through their veins. Theirs are the wonders of the mind, the force of will, the brilliant light of insight, and the resounding echo of discovery—but also the desiccation of despair.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 11</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increases</name>
      <text>When determining your character's ability scores, you increase one of those scores by 2 and increase a different score by 1, or you increase three different scores by 1. Follow this rule regardless of the method you use to determine the scores, such as rolling or point buy.</text>
      <text />
      <text>The "Quick Build" section for your character's class offers suggestions on which scores to increase. You're free to follow those suggestions or to ignore them. Whichever scores you decide to increase, none of the scores can be raised above 20.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 11</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gem Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have a gem dragon ancestor, granting you a special magical affinity. Choose one kind of dragon from the Gem Ancestry table. This determines the damage type for your other traits, as shown in the table.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Gem Ancestry</text>
      <text>Dragon | Damage Type</text>
      <text>Amethyst | Force</text>
      <text>Crystal | Radiant</text>
      <text>Emerald | Psychic</text>
      <text>Sapphire | Thunder</text>
      <text>Topaz | Necrotic</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 11</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Breath Weapon</name>
      <text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with an exhalation of magical energy in a 15-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus). On a failed save, the creature takes 1d10 damage of the type associated with your Gem Ancestry. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage. This damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</text>
      <text />
      <text>You can use your Breath Weapon a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 11</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Draconic Resistance</name>
      <text>You have resistance to the damage type associated with your Gem Ancestry.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 11</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Psionic Mind</name>
      <text>You can send telepathic messages to any creature you can see within 30 feet of you. You don't need to share a language with the creature for it to understand these messages, but it must be able to understand at least one language to comprehend them.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 11</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gem Flight</name>
      <text>Starting at 5th level, you can use a bonus action to manifest spectral wings on your body. These wings last for 1 minute. For the duration, you gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed and can hover. Once you use this trait, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 11</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>Your character can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for the character. The Player's Handbook offers a list of widespread languages to choose from. The DM is free to add or remove languages from that list for a particular campaign.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 11</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Metallic Dragonborn</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability/>
    <spellAbility>Constitution</spellAbility>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Dragonborn with metallic ancestry lay claim to the tenacity of metallic dragons—brass, bronze, copper, gold, and silver—whose hues glint in their scales. Theirs is the fire of hearth and forge, the cold of high mountain air, the spark of inspiration, and the scouring touch of acid that purifies.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 12</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increases</name>
      <text>When determining your character's ability scores, you increase one of those scores by 2 and increase a different score by 1, or you increase three different scores by 1. Follow this rule regardless of the method you use to determine the scores, such as rolling or point buy.</text>
      <text />
      <text>The "Quick Build" section for your character's class offers suggestions on which scores to increase. You're free to follow those suggestions or to ignore them. Whichever scores you decide to increase, none of the scores can be raised above 20.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 12</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Metallic Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have a metallic dragon ancestor, granting you a special magical affinity. Choose one kind of dragon from the Metallic Ancestry table. This determines the damage type for your other traits, as shown in the table.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Metallic Ancestry</text>
      <text>Dragon | Damage Type</text>
      <text>Brass | Fire</text>
      <text>Bronze | Lightning</text>
      <text>Copper | Acid</text>
      <text>Gold | Fire</text>
      <text>Silver | Cold</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 12</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Breath Weapon</name>
      <text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with an exhalation of magical energy in a 15-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus). On a failed save, the creature takes 1d10 damage of the type associated with your Metallic Ancestry. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage. This damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</text>
      <text />
      <text>You can use your Breath Weapon a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 12</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Draconic Resistance</name>
      <text>You have resistance to the damage type associated with your Metallic Ancestry.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 12</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Metallic Breath Weapon</name>
      <text>At 5th level, you gain a second breath weapon. When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with an exhalation in a 15-foot cone. The save DC for this breath is 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus. Whenever you use this trait, choose one:</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Enervating Breath. Each creature in the cone must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or become incapacitated until the start of your next turn.</text>
      <text>Repulsion Breath. Each creature in the cone must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 20 feet away from you and be knocked prone.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>	Once you use your Metallic Breath Weapon, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 12</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>Your character can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your DM agree is appropriate for the character. The Player's Handbook offers a list of widespread languages to choose from. The DM is free to add or remove languages from that list for a particular campaign.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source: Fizban's Treasury of Dragons p. 12</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>