<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Bard [2024]</name>
    <!-- Bard College: College of Shadow (Third Party) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard Subclass: College of Shadow (Third Party) (Legacy)</name>
        <text>Fear of darkness is one of the most primal emotions, and bards of the College of Shadow manipulate such fears to enhance their artistry. These bards weave the gray boundaries between light and dark to terrify and inspire captive audiences.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 43 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Dancing Shadows (College of Shadow (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>When you join the College of Shadow at 3rd level, you gain the ability to weave a pocket of protective shadows.
	As a bonus action, you can expend a Bardic Inspiration to create a 20-foot-radius sphere of shifting shadows centered on you. The sphere moves with you, spreads around corners, and lasts for I minute or until you are incapacitated or die.
	Allied creatures (including you) standing in the sphere have half cover, and creatures outside the sphere have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to perceive anything inside the sphere. Darkvision does not nullify this effect. Creatures that don't rely on eyesight are immune to this effect.
	If any of this effect's area overlaps with an area of light created by a spell of 2nd level or lower, the spell that created the light is dispelled.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 43 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Fear of the Dark (College of Shadow (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, your intimate knowledge of darkness allows you to harness its frightful properties to the fullest and keep your allies grounded. While in dim light or darkness, you and any allies that can see you have advantage against fear effects. Additionally, any hostile creatures that can see you roll with disadvantage against fear effects.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 43 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Shade Step (College of Shadow (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>At 6th level, shadow gathers around those you inspire. Immediately after a creature adds one of your Bardic Inspiration dice to its ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, the creature can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space it can see. Moving in this manner does not provoke attacks of opportunity.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 43 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Night Music (College of Shadow (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you can imbue your spellcasting with the full energy and terror of night. When you cast a spell, you can spend your reaction to also choose a number of creatures within 60 feet of you who saw and heard you cast the spell, up to a number equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Each target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your spell save DC or be frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 43 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Night Music</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>College of Shadow (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
