<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Wizard [2024]</name>
    <!-- Arcane Tradition: Shadow Arcane Tradition (Third Party) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: Shadow Arcane Tradition (Third Party) (Legacy)</name>
        <text>The powers of shadow are an obsession for wizards who follow the Shadow Arcane tradition. Because they understand shadow's tantalizing powers—and seek to learn more-these practitioners infuse their very beings with it to discover its secrets firsthand.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 47 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass:  (Legacy)</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you bond a living shadow to your body, wearing it like a second skin. While you are bonded in this way, you gain the following:

	• You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range is extended by 60 feet.

	• You can see in magical darkness out to a range of 30 feet.

	• You have sunlight sensitivity, and while in sunlight, you have disadvantage on attack rolls as well as on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 47 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass:  (Legacy)</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can feed energy to your symbiote to transform it. As a bonus action, you can expend two spell slots to recover one spell slot equal to or less than the total combined value of the expended spell slots. For example, you could expend a 1st-level spell slot and a 2nd-level spell slot to recover one 3rd-level spell slot.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 47 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass:  (Legacy)</name>
        <text>At 6th level, your shadow symbiote can expand to hide you from foes. When a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to encase yourself in a 10-foot-radius sphere of magical darkness (imposing disadvantage on attacks against you if a creature cannot see through magical darkness. If the triggering target hits you with the attack, you can't use this feature on the attacker again until you finish a long rest. The darkness persists until the beginning of your next turn.
	You must choose to use this feature before knowing whether the attack hits or misses. Creatures that don't rely on eyesight are immune to this effect.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 47 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Orb of Night</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Shadow Arcane Tradition (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass:  (Legacy)</name>
        <text>Starting at 10th level, your shadow symbiote camouflages you, allowing you to get the drop on your enemies. Whenever you roll initiative while in dim light or darkness, you are automatically hidden from all creatures at least 10 feet away from you. You are no longer hidden if you move, attack, or cast a spell.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 47 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass:  (Legacy)</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, your shadow symbiote shares your pain. While in dim light or darkness, you have a +2 to AC and resistance to all bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 47 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
