<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric [2024]</name>
    <!-- Divine Domain: Keeper Domain (Third Party) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy)</name>
        <text>The Keeper domain focuses on social bonds and well-regulated communities. These communities might be as small as an adventuring party or as large as a city, but all require safety and comfort to thrive. Keeper domain clerics excel in leadership positions and are the first to take up arms when their homes or allies need protection.

Domain Spells:
At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.

Keeper Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
1st | command, hunter's mark
3rd | calm emotions, warding bond
5th | beacon of hope, spirit guardians
7th | death ward, guardian of faith
9th | hallow, telepathic bond

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 43 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Blessed Chosen (Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can assert your divine will to protect your allies. When an enemy within 30 feet of you that you can see attacks one of your allies, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll before it hits or misses.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 44 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Bonus Proficiencies (Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons. You also gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 44 (Third Party)</text>
        <proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Blessed Chosen</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Channel Divinity: Divine Initiative (Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to enhance your allies' potential.
	As an action, you present your holy symbol and choose a number of creatures that you can see and that can see you within 60 feet of you, up to a number equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of one). Each of them gains 5 temporary hit points. When a target gains these temporary hit points, they can immediately use their reaction to make one weapon attack.
	The number of temporary hit points increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to 8 at 6th level, 11 at 8th level, and 14 at 17th level.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 44 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Fighting Fit (Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to shore up your allies' reserves. As a reaction, when you or an ally that you can see within 30 feet of you is charmed, frightened, paralyzed, or stunned, you can remove that condition.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 44 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Fighting Fit</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 8: Hobbling Strike (Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the target must make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC or be knocked prone. When you reach 14th level, the target's speed is also halved until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 44 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Duty Over Death (Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 17th level, you can exert your power to call companions back from the brink of death. When an ally you can see within 60 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, they instead remain conscious and regain hit points equal to half their maximum hit points. You can use this feature only if you aren't incapacitated. Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.

Source:	Book of Ebon Tides p. 44 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Duty Over Death</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Keeper Domain (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Divine Domain: Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy)</name>
        <text>The shadow domain embraces the darkness that surrounds all things and manipulates the transitory gray that separates light from dark. Shadow domain clerics walk a subtle path, frequently changing allegiances and preferring to operate unseen.

Domain Spells:
At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.

Shadow Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
1st | bane, false life
3rd | blindness/deafness, darkness
5th | blink, fear
7th | Evard's black tentacles, greater invisibility
9th | cone of cold, dream

Source:	Tome of Heroes p. 71 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Cover of Night (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>When you choose this domain at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Stealth skill and darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range increases by 30 feet. In addition, when you are in dim light or darkness, you can use a bonus action to Hide.

Source:	Tome of Heroes p. 71 (Homebrew)</text>
        <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Lengthen Shadow (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can manipulate your own shadow to extend your reach. When you cast a cleric spell with a range of touch, your shadow can deliver the spell as if you had cast the spell. Your target must be within 15 feet of you, and you must be able to see the target. You can use this feature even if you are in an area where you cast no shadow.
	When you reach 10th level in this class, your shadow can affect any target you can see within 30 feet of you.

Source:	Tome of Heroes p. 71 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Channel Divinity: Shadow Grasp (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to turn a creature's shadow against them. As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 30 feet of you. That creature must make a Strength saving throw. If the creature fails the saving throw, it is restrained by its shadow until the end of your next turn. If the creature succeeds, it is grappled by its shadow until the end of your next turn. You can use this feature even if the target is in an area where it casts no shadow.

Source:	Tome of Heroes p. 71 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Fade to Black (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you can conceal yourself in shadow. As a bonus action when you are in dim light or darkness, you can magically become invisible for 1 minute. This effect ends early if you attack or cast a spell. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Tome of Heroes p. 71 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Fade to Black</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 8: Potent Spellcasting (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.

Source:	Tome of Heroes p. 71 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Fade to Black</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Fade to Black</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Army of Shadow (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy))</name>
        <text>At 17th level, you can manipulate multiple shadows simultaneously. When you use Shadow Grasp, you can affect a number of creatures equal to your proficiency bonus.

Source:	Tome of Heroes p. 71 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Fade to Black</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party) (Legacy)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Command [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hunter's Mark [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Calm Emotions [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Warding Bond [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Beacon of Hope [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spirit Guardians [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Death Ward [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Guardian of Faith [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallow [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Telepathic Bond [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Keeper Domain (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bane [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>False Life [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blindness/Deafness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Darkness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blink [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fear [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Evard's Black Tentacles [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cone of Cold [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dream [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Shadow Domain (Book of Ebon Tides) (Third Party))</classes>
    <text/>
  </spell>
</compendium>
