<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Bard</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard College: College of Harmony (HB)</name>
        <text>Bards of the College of Harmony are masters of teamwork and bringing out the best in people. Often natural leaders, bards of this college sometimes favor coordinating the efforts of the party from a ranged position, while some choose to be on the front lines to inspire and encourage their allies.

Not only do their abilities allow them to increase the effectiveness of their comrades, but these bards can bind the group together in magical harmony, allowing each of them to bestow protection on one another and to share in the beneficial effects the bard can produce.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of Harmony (HB): Harmonic Bond</name>
        <text>You learn to link your allies with magical synergy to inspire themselves and each other to keep in the fight. When a creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you takes damage, it can roll the die and reduce the damage taken by an amount equal to that number plus your Charisma modifier.

Alternatively, a creature with a Bardic Inspiration die from you can use its reaction to grant this benefit to another creature within 30 feet of it, when that other creature takes damage.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of Harmony (HB): Guided Initiative</name>
        <text>You learn the guidance cantrip, which counts as a bard cantrip for you but doesn't count against your number of bard cantrips known. For you, it has a range of 30 feet.

Additionally, whenever you roll initiative, you can use your reaction to grant one creature other than yourself within 30 feet of you a 1d4 bonus to its initiative result.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of Harmony (HB): Shared Spell</name>
        <text>When you cast a spell that can only target one creature, and that does not have a range of self, you can instead target two creatures if one of them has a Bardic Inspiration die from you.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of Harmony (HB): Harmonic Link</name>
        <text>You can link your allies in perfect harmony, working effortlessly as a team to bolster each other's defenses. When a creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you is hit by an attack, it can spend its die to magically reach out to nearby allies. Each creature within 30 feet can use its reaction to grant the target a +2 bonus to the targeted creature's AC.

This effect is cumulative. For example, if two creatures use their reactions to grant this benefit, the creature gains a +4 bonus to its AC against the triggering attack.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>


    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard College: College of Pantomime (HB)</name>
        <text>The College of Pantomime is the home of bards who found that the world is a cacophonous place with too much noise and distractions to truly appreciate the Words of Creation or the magic which stemmed from it. They have therefore opted not to add their voices to the multitudes, instead choosing to remain silent, focusing instead on their movements and intentions to weave their magic as they trace the echoes of the Words of Creations which vibrate throughout the planes.

Bards of this college are often considered odd and offputting. There's something about a performer who won't speak that seems to give onlookers a feeling that something just isn't right. This can be explained by the fact that these silent performers are in fact altering the weave around them through their intricate and specific movements. Members of this college are usually more level-headed than their counterparts from other colleges, or at least seem so since they cannot voice any ridiculous plans they have out loud. Though those who spend enough time around them to gain an insight into their gesticulations may disagree with the previous assertion.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of Pantomime (HB): Silence is Golden</name>
        <text>When you join the College of Pantomime at 3rd level you gain a better understanding of how to manipulate the weave of magic around you with your performance. When casting a spell you can replace any verbal components with somatic components. If a spell requires both verbal and somatic components, you can ignore the verbal components. By mastering the use of your gesticulations you have negated the need to vocalize your intentions.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of Pantomime (HB): Invisible Blades</name>
        <text>As a bonus action, you can expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration to pantomime an invisible blade in your hand. This blade deals 1d6 slashing damage and uses your Charisma modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity, for the attack and damage rolls. It has the Light property. The blade ceases to exist after 1 hour, if you are incapacitated, or if you let go of it. You can also dismiss it at will.

The damage for this attack increases when you reach 5th level (1d8), 10th level (1d10), and 15th level (1d12).

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of Pantomime (HB): Convincing Performance</name>
        <text>As an action, you can mime the form of any inanimate object with which you are familiar, creating an invisible version of it in your hands. An object created in this way can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds. It ceases to exist after 1 hour, when you dismiss it as an action, when you use this feature again, or if it takes or deals any damage.

You cannot use this feature to create items that ordinarily require a high degree of craftsmanship, such as weapons or armor, unless you have proficiency with the type of artisan's tools used to craft such objects.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of Pantomime (HB): Trapped in a Box</name>
        <text>At 14th level, by perfecting the art of mime and listening for the Words of Creation, you have developed a mastery of imposing your vision and will on the weave around you.

As an action you may summon up to 6 invisible panels in any orientation and position in any unoccupied spaces within 60 feet of you, each panel must share at least one side with one other panel. The panels exist for up to 1 minute, until you dismiss them as an action or until they are destroyed. The panels are 5 foot squares that are 1 inch thick. A creature can determine the location and orientation of these panels by interacting with them or by succeeding on a Wisdom (Perception) check against your spell save DC.

If a creature would be surrounded on all sides by the panels (or the panels and another solid surface), that creature can make a Dexterity saving throw. On a success, it can use its reaction to move up to its speed so that it is no longer enclosed by the panels.

The panels are magical objects, each one has AC 15 and 30 hit points, and is immune to poison and psychic damage. A dispel magic or disintegrate spell will immediately destroy a single panel.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and expended uses are replenished when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 1 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- College of the Requiem -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard College: College of the Requiem (HB)</name>
        <text>Bards of the College of the Requiem, often called lamenters, eulogists, or requiem singers, regardless of whether or not their requiem involves any singing, dedicate themselves to all things pertaining to death. This branches out into several different paths as some prefer funerary rites, while others keep the unnatural undead at bay. Other requiem singers still, have been known to turn this power to the bolstering of undeath, and as such, you can even see requiem singers in the armies of evil rulers that rely on the dead to bolster their ranks.

Bards of this college are a varied bunch, turning their talents to the requiem of the dead for different reasons. In Eberron, a requiem singer could be found amongst the ranks of Karrnath's death knights and skeleton soldiers. While a requiem singer could just as easily be found in Thrane, trying to hold off the undead of Karrnath.

In Faerun, requiem singers that bolster undead are not uncommon in Thay amongst those that wish to serve but choose not to become true Thayan wizards.

And organizations like the Harpers always could use more requiem singers to keep the hordes of undead away from civilized lands.

In Theros, bards of this college might be tasked with keeping the returned from running amok in the various city-states, while a group of returned could in turn be led by a particularly charismatic returned who is themself a requiem singer.

In Ravnica, city of guilds, the guild most likely to have a member turn to this particularly niche style of music is the Rakdos. Music has long been a part of the demonic carnarium and leading the dead in a song and dance like grim puppets suits the sense of humor of the Rakdos quite well. However, the Golgari and Orzhov guilds wouldn't be too far a stretch for one of this college as well.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Requiem (HB): Requiem Magic</name>
        <text>You learn the two cantrips spare the dying and toll the dead. Additionally, you learn additional spells when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the College of the Requiem Spells table. These spells count as a bard spell for you, but don't count against the number of bard spells you know.

College of the Requiem Spells:
Bard Level | Spells
3rd | gentle repose, ray of enfeeblement
5th | animate dead, magic circle
7th | aura of life, blight
9th | antilife shell, danse macabre

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Requiem (HB): Dealing with Death</name>
        <text>Spells cast by you can affect the undead as though they weren't undead. Additionally, when a creature uses bardic inspiration granted by you, if they are undead or are using it against an undead creature, they can roll the inspiration die twice and keep the higher result.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Requiem (HB): Moment of Silence</name>
        <text>When a creature within 60 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to cast the silence spell with a radius of 60 feet, centered on the creature, which will last until the start of your next turn. The silence lasts for one minute, still requires concentration, and you can end it early as a bonus action. Once you have used this feature, you may not do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Requiem (HB): Rest in Peace</name>
        <text>When you use your Song of Rest feature during a short rest, you can create a magical barrier to protect you and your allies for the duration of the short rest. Undead creatures cannot willingly come within 60 feet of you by nonmagical means, unless you permit them to do so. If an undead creature tries to use teleportation or interplanar travel to do so, it must first succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your spell save DC. Undead that are already within 60 feet of you when you use this feature are immune to this effect. Once you have used this feature, you may not do so again until you finish a long rest. Additionally, when undead creatures would regain hit points from your song of rest feature, they can also gain temporary hit points equal to the amount of hit points gained.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Requiem (HB): Death's Grip</name>
        <text>As an action on your turn you can cast one of the following spells without requiring material components: mass suggestion (only being able to target undead creatures), finger of death, or raise dead. Once you have used this feature for any of these options, you may not do so again for any of them until you finish a long rest.

Source:	Tasha's Crucible of Everything Else, Volume 2 p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>