<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Psion (UA) [2024]</name>
    <hd>6</hd>
    <proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom, Arcana, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>
    <armor/>
    <weapons>Simple Weapons</weapons>
    <tools/>
    <wealth>5d4x10</wealth>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <slots>2,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <slots>2,3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <slots>2,4,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4">
      <slots>2,4,3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <slots>2,4,3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <slots>2,4,3,3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <slots>2,4,3,3,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <slots>2,4,3,3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <slots>2,4,3,3,3,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <slots>3,4,3,3,3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <slots>3,4,3,3,3,2,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12">
      <slots>3,4,3,3,3,2,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <slots>3,4,3,3,3,2,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>4</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>5</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>6</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>7</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>9</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>10</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>11</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>12</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>14</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>15</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>16</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>16</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>17</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>17</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>18</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>18</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>19</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>20</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>21</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <counter>
        <name>Spells Known</name>
        <value>22</value>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <trait>
      <name>Psion</name>
      <text>A Master of Psionic Power

Psions weave magic and extraordinary powers through the power of their minds. They develop their minds as fonts of power that manifest spells and grow stronger over the course of their adventuring careers. You can find everything you need to play one of these psionic powerhouses in the next few sections.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>What Is a Psion?</name>
      <text>Psions are spellcasters who use innate mental powers to gain extraordinary abilities and unleash the magic of their minds. Psions and their magic (sometimes called "psionics") can trace their history back to the appendix of the first edition Player's Handbook, and a psionicsusing class first appeared in The Complete Psionics Handbook in 1991. Psionics have taken numerous forms in D&amp;D, from alternative magic systems to options that dovetail with other D&amp;D rules. In the fifth edition, psychic power is synonymous with magic, and the magic of the mind flavors numerous spells, monsters, and subclasses—like the Psi Warrior Fighter and the Aberrant Sorcery Sorcerer in the Player's Handbook. In this edition, the Psion is a spellcaster who interfaces with magic and spellcasting similarly to other classes in the game.

This UA provides the Psion with unique twists to spellcasting using Psionic Energy Dice and the Psionic Spellcasting feature, carving out a space to make the Psion stand out from its spellcasting peers.</text>
    </trait>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Becoming A Psion As A Level 1 Character</name>
        <text>As a 1st-level Psion, you begin play with 6 + your Constitution modifier hit points.

Core Artificer Traits
Primary Ability: Intelligence
Hit Point Die: D6 per Psion level
Saving Throw Proficiencies: Intelligence and Wisdom
Skill Proficiencies: Choose 2: Arcana, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, Persuasion
Weapon Proficiencies: Simple weapons
Armor Training: None
Starting Equipment: Choose A or B: (A) Spear, 2 Daggers, Light Crossbow, 20 Bolts, Case, Dungeoneer's Pack, and 6 GP; or (B) 50 GP

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Becoming A Psion As A Multiclass Character</name>
        <text>Core Artificer Traits
Hit Point Die: D6 per Psion level

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 1: Spellcasting</name>
        <text>You have learned how to channel magical energy using the power of your mind. See the Player's Handbook for the rules on spellcasting. The information below details how you use those rules with Psion spells, which appear in the Psion spell list later in the class's description.

Cantrips. You know two Psion cantrips of your choice. Minor Illusion and Telekinetic Fling are recommended.
	Whenever you gain a Psion level, you can replace one of your cantrips from this feature with another Psion cantrip of your choice.
	When you reach Psion levels 10 and 14, you learn another Psion cantrip of your choice, as shown in the Cantrips column of the Psion Features table.

Spell Slots. The Psion Features table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your level 1+ spells. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a Long Rest.

Prepared Spells of Level 1+. You prepare the list of level 1+ spells that are available for you to cast with this feature. To start, choose four level 1 Psion spells. Charm Person, Command, Dissonant Whispers, and Mage Armor are recommended.
	The number of spells on your list increases as you gain Psion levels, as shown in the Prepared Spells column of the Psion Features table. Whenever that number increases, choose additional Psion spells until the number of spells on your list matches the number in the table. The chosen spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For example, if you're a level 3 Psion, your list of prepared spells can include six Psion spells of levels 1 and 2 in any combination.
	If another Psion feature gives you spells that you always have prepared, those don't count against the number of spells you can prepare with this feature, but those spells otherwise count as Psion spells for you.

Changing Your Prepared Spells. Whenever you gain a Psion level, you can replace one spell on your list with another Psion spell of an eligible level.

Spellcasting Ability. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your Psion spells.

Psionic Spellcasting. When you cast a Psion spell, that spell doesn't require a Verbal or Material component, even if the spell includes "V" or "M" in its "Components" entry, except Material components that are consumed by the spell or have a cost specified in the spell.

Spells Prepared:
Level | Prepared Spells
1 | 4
2 | 5
3 | 6
4 | 7
5 | 9
6 | 10
7 | 11
8 | 12
9 | 14
10 | 15
11 | 16
12 | 16
13 | 17
14 | 17
15 | 18
16 | 18
17 | 19
18 | 20
19 | 21
20 | 22

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 1: Psionic Power</name>
        <text>You harbor a wellspring of psionic energy within yourself. This energy is represented by your Psionic Energy Dice. Your Psion level determines the die size and number of Psionic Energy Dice you have, as shown in the Energy Die and Number of Dice columns of the Psion Features table.
	Your Psionic Energy Dice are used to enhance or fuel certain Psion features. You start with two such features: Telekinetic Propel and Telepathic Connection, each of which is detailed below. Some of your powers expend the Psionic Energy Dice, as specified in a power's description, and you can't use a power if it requires you to use a die when all your Psionic Energy Dice are expended.
	You regain one expended Psionic Energy Die when you finish a Short Rest, and you regain all of them when you finish a Long Rest.
	Some features that use Psionic Energy Dice require your target to make a saving throw. The save DC equals the spell save DC from this class's Spellcasting feature.

Telekinetic Propel. As a Bonus Action, choose one Large or smaller creature other than you that you can see within 30 feet of yourself, and then roll one Psionic Energy Die. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed or pulled (your choice) up to a number of feet straight away from yourself equal to 5 times the number rolled. The die is expended only if the target fails the saving throw.

Telepathic Connection. You have telepathy with a range of 5 feet. As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die and roll it. For a number of minutes equal to your Psion level, the range of your telepathy increases by a number of feet equal to 10 times the number rolled.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 1: Subtle Telekinesis</name>
        <text>You know the Mage Hand cantrip. You can cast it without Somatic components, and you can make the spectral hand Invisible when you cast it.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice Size</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 2: Psionic Discipline</name>
        <text>You learn further psionic techniques that are fueled by your Psionic Energy Dice. You gain two disciplines of your choice, such as Expanded Awareness and Id Insinuation. Disciplines are described in the "Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options" spell list.
	You can use only one Discipline each turn and only once per turn unless otherwise noted in one of those options.
	Whenever you gain a Psion level, you can replace one of your Psionic Discipline options with one you don't know. You gain two more options at Psion level 17.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 2: Psionic Modes</name>
        <text>You have honed your psionic powers to act as both a shield and a weapon in battle. As a Bonus Action, you can choose one of the following modes, granting you certain benefits for 1 minute or until you use this feature again:

Attack Mode. Damage from your weapon attacks, Psion spells, and Psion features ignores Resistance to Psychic damage. In addition, when you roll damage for a spell, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die to reroll a number of damage dice up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one),
and you must use the new rolls.

Defense Mode. You have Resistance to Psychic damage. In addition, when you fail an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw, you can take a Reaction to expend one Psionic Energy Die; roll the Psionic Energy Die and add the number rolled to the saving throw, potentially turning a failure into a success.

You can use this feature twice, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 3</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 3: Psion Subclass</name>
        <text>You gain a Psion subclass of your choice. The Metamorph, Psi Warper, Psykinetic, and Telepath subclasses are detailed after this class's description. A subclass is a specialization that grants you features at certain Psion levels. For the rest of your career, you gain each of your subclass's features that are of your Psion level or lower.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 4: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify. You gain this feature again at Psion levels 8, 12, and 16.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 5: Psionic Restoration</name>
        <text>When you finish a Short Rest, you can regain expended Psionic Energy Dice, but no more than a number equal to half your number of dice (round down). Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice Size</name>
        <value>8</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Restoration</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 7: Psionic Surge</name>
        <text>When you roll Initiative, you can expend one of your Hit Point Dice and regain one expended use of Psionic Modes.
	In addition, after you roll one or more Psionic Energy Dice, you can expend one of your Hit Point Dice and treat any roll of 1, 2, or 3 on those Psionic Energy Dice as 4.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 8: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice</name>
        <value>8</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice Size</name>
        <value>10</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 12: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice</name>
        <value>10</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 16: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Psionic Discipline Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain two more options at Psion level 17.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice Size</name>
        <value>12</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Psionic Energy Dice</name>
        <value>12</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 19: Epic Boon</name>
        <text>You gain an Epic Boon feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify. Boon of Energy Resistance is recommended.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 20: Enkindled Lifeforce</name>
        <text>Once per turn, when you expend one Psionic Energy Die and roll it for a Psion feature or Psionic Discipline, you can expend two of your Hit Point Dice to roll two additional Psionic Energy Dice and add the numbers rolled to the total.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Psion Subclass: Metamorph -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Psion Subclass: Metamorph</name>
        <text>Psychically Sculpt Life and Flesh

Your mastery of psionic powers turns inward. Your own flesh becomes like clay to you, and you mold it to turn it into the perfect vessel of your psionic powers. Experience in manipulating your life energy also enables you to adjust the life force of friends and foes alike.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Metamorph Spells (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>When you reach a Psion level specified in the Metamorph Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Metamorph Spells:
Psion Level | Spells
3 | Alter Self, Cure Wounds, Inflict Wounds, Lesser Restoration
5 | Aura of Vitality, Haste
7 | Polymorph, Stoneskin
9 | Contagion, Mass Cure Wounds

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Organic Weapons (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>You can shape your limbs into weapons. Whenever you take the Attack action or make an Opportunity Attack, you can reform your free hand into one of the following organic weapons: Bone Blade, Flesh Maul, or Viscera Launcher. Your limb immediately returns to its previous form after your Organic Weapon hits or misses its target.
	Whenever you attack with the weapon, you can use your Intelligence modifier for the attack and damage rolls instead of using Strength or Dexterity; and you can cause the weapon to deal Psychic damage or its normal damage type.

Bone Blade. A blade made of bone springs from your forearm or extends from your hand. The blade counts as a Simple Melee weapon with the Finesse property, and it deals 1d8 Piercing damage on a hit. You have Advantage on the attack roll you make with the blade if at least one of your allies is within 5 feet of the target and the ally doesn't have the Incapacitated condition.

Flesh Maul. Your fist and forearm coalesce into a hardened mass of flesh and bone. The maul counts as a Simple Melee weapon and deals 1d10 Bludgeoning damage on a hit. A creature hit by the maul has Disadvantage on the next Strength or Constitution saving throw it makes before the start of its next turn.

Viscera Launcher. Your hand and forearm transform into a crossbow made of muscle and sinew that fires bolts of bile. The launcher counts as a Simple Ranged weapon with a normal range of 30 feet and a long range of 90 feet, and it deals 1d6 Acid damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with an attack roll using the launcher, you can deal an extra 1d6 Acid damage to the target.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Organic Weapons: Bone Blade (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>A blade made of bone springs from your forearm or extends from your hand. The blade counts as a Simple Melee weapon with the Finesse property, and it deals 1d8 Piercing damage on a hit. You have Advantage on the attack roll you make with the blade if at least one of your allies is within 5 feet of the target and the ally doesn't have the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
        <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d8</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Organic Weapons: Flesh Maul (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>Your fist and forearm coalesce into a hardened mass of flesh and bone. The maul counts as a Simple Melee weapon and deals 1d10 Bludgeoning damage on a hit. A creature hit by the maul has Disadvantage on the next Strength or Constitution saving throw it makes before the start of its next turn.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
        <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Organic Weapons: Viscera Launcher (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>Your hand and forearm transform into a crossbow made of muscle and sinew that fires bolts of bile. The launcher counts as a Simple Ranged weapon with a normal range of 30 feet and a long range of 90 feet, and it deals 1d6 Acid damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with an attack roll using the launcher, you can deal an extra 1d6 Acid damage to the target.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
        <roll description="Acid Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Extend Limbs (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die. For the next minute, you gain the following benefits.

Reach. Your reach increases by 5 feet.

Speed. Your Speed increases by 5 feet.

Touch. When you cast a spell that has a range of Touch and a casting time of an action, you can make the spell's range 10 feet.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Extra Attack (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>You can attack twice instead of once whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.
	In addition, you can cast one of your Psion cantrips that has a casting time of an action in place of one of those attacks.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Quickened Healing (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>When you cast Cure Wounds, you can expend two Psionic Energy Dice to change the casting time to a Bonus Action for this casting. When you do, you can roll one Psionic Energy Die and add the number rolled to the total amount of Hit Points restored.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Mutable Form (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>When you use Extend Limbs, the duration increases to 10 minutes and you gain one of the following benefits of your choice, the effects of which last until Extend Limbs ends.

Stony Epidermis. You have Advantage on Constitution saving throws to maintain Concentration. In addition, choose one of the following damage types: Acid, Bludgeoning, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Piercing, Poison, Slashing, or Thunder. You gain Resistance to the chosen damage type.

Superior Stride. While you aren't wearing armor, you can take the Dash action as a Bonus Action and you have a Climb Speed and Swim Speed equal to your Speed.

Unnatural Flexibility. You gain a +2 bonus to AC, and your body, along with any equipment you're wearing or carrying, becomes pliable. You can move through any space as narrow as 1 inch, and you can spend 5 feet of movement to escape from nonmagical restraints or end the Grappled condition.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Life-bending Weapons (Metamorph)</name>
        <text>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your Organic Weapon, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die and roll it. Each creature of your choice in a 10-foot Emanation originating from you regains Hit Points equal the number rolled plus your Intelligence modifier. Additionally, one creature of your choice in that area takes Necrotic damage equal to the number rolled.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Psion Subclass: Psi Warper -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Psion Subclass: Psi Warper</name>
        <text>Warp Space with the Power of Your Mind

Psi Warpers tune their psionic powers to manipulating the space between objects. Capable of teleporting across the battlefield and creating vacuums in space, a Psi Warper is never in one place for too long.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Psi Warper Spells (Psi Warper)</name>
        <text>When you reach a Psion level specified in the Psi Warper Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Psi Warper Spells:
Psion Level | Spells
3 | Expeditious Retreat, Feather Fall, Misty Step, Shatter
5 | Blink, Haste
7 | Banishment, Dimension Door
9 | Steel Wind Strike, Teleportation Circle

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Teleportation (Psi Warper)</name>
        <text>You can cast Misty Step without expending a spell slot, and you must finish a Long Rest before you can cast it in this way again. You can also restore your use of it by expending one Psionic Energy Die (no action required).

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Warp Propel (Psi Warper)</name>
        <text>When a target fails its saving throw against your Telekinetic Propel, instead of pushing it, you can teleport the target to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of you that is horizontal to you.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Teleportation</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Psi Warper</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Warp Space (Psi Warper)</name>
        <text>When you cast Shatter, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die to modify the spell so that the radius of the spell's Sphere becomes 20 feet.
	In addition, creatures that fail the saving throw against the spell are pulled straight toward the center of the Sphere, ending in an unoccupied space as close to center of the Sphere as possible.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Teleporter Combat (Psi Warper)</name>
        <text>Immediately after you cast Misty Step, you can cast one of your Psion cantrips that has a casting time of an action as part of the Bonus Action.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Duplicitous Target (Psi Warper)</name>
        <text>When a creature you can see makes an attack roll against you, you can take a Reaction to expend one Psionic Energy Die and choose a willing creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself that doesn't have the Incapacitated condition. You and the willing creature teleport, swapping places with each other. The creature then becomes the target of the attack roll.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Mass Teleportation (Psi Warper)</name>
        <text>As a Magic action, you expend four Psionic Energy Dice and choose Huge or smaller creatures within 30 feet of yourself, up to a number of creatures equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one creature). Each of the chosen creatures is teleported to an unoccupied space you can see within 150 feet of you. An unwilling creature that succeeds on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC is unaffected.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Psion Subclass: Psykinetic -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Psion Subclass: Psykinetic</name>
        <text>Mold Psionic Force for Creation and Destruction

A Psykinetic controls their psionic powers like a malleable force. They bend their telekinetic energies into sturdy barriers and strike with the force of a battering ram.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Psykinetic Spells (Psykinetic)</name>
        <text>When you reach a Psion level specified in the Psykinetic Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Psykinetic Spells:
Psion Level | Spells
3 | Cloud of Daggers, Levitate, Shield, Thunderwave
5 | Slow, Telekinetic Crush
7 | Otiluke's Resilient Sphere, Stone Shape
9 | Telekinesis, Wall of Force

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Telekinetic Techniques (Psykinetic)</name>
        <text>When you use your Telekinetic Propel, you can impose one of the following effects on that target.

Boost. The target's Speed increases by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.

Disorient. The target can't make Opportunity Attacks until the start of its next turn.

Telekinetic Bolt. If the target fails the saving throw, it takes Force damage equal to the number rolled on the Psionic Energy Die.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Empowered Attack Mode (Psykinetic)</name>
        <text>While your Attack Mode is active, you gain a Fly Speed of 60 feet and can hover, and when you cast a Psion spell, you can add your Intelligence modifier to one damage roll of that spell.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 9</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Rebounding Field (Psykinetic)</name>
        <text>When you cast Shield in response to being hit by an attack roll and cause the triggering attack to miss, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die to launch the force back at the attacker. The attacker makes a Dexterity saving throw. Roll two Psionic Energy Dice. On a failed save, the attacker takes Force damage equal to the amount rolled and you gain Temporary Hit Points equal to that amount. On a successful save, the attacker takes half as much damage only.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Enhanced Telekinetic Crush (Psykinetic)</name>
        <text>When you cast Telekinetic Crush, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die to modify the spell so that whether a creature fails or succeeds on the saving throw against the spell, its Speed is halved until the start of your next turn.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Heightened Telekinesis (Psykinetic)</name>
        <text>When you cast Telekinesis, you can expend four Psionic Energy Dice to modify the spell so that it doesn't require Concentration. If you do so, the spell's duration becomes 1 minute for that casting, and you can target Gargantuan creatures and objects.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Psion Subclass: Telepath -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Psion Subclass: Telepath</name>
        <text>Master Tactics in the Landscape of the Mind

Telepaths are masters of mind magic. They use their psionic powers for all matters of the mind, whether they bolster the mental defenses of allies or probe the thoughts of others undetected. A telepath can be a bastion of psionic aid or a crafty manipulator.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Telepath Spells (Telepath)</name>
        <text>When you reach a Psion level specified in the Telepath Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Telepath Spells:
Psion Level | Spells
3 | Bane, Command, Detect Thoughts, Mind Spike
5 | Counterspell, Speak with Plants
7 | Compulsion, Confusion
9 | Awaken, Modify Memory

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Mind Infiltrator (Telepath)</name>
        <text>When you cast Detect Thoughts, you can expend two Psionic Energy Dice to modify the spell so that the spell doesn't require spell components or Concentration, and the target does not know you're probing its mind if it fails the Wisdom saving throw.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Telepathic Hub (Telepath)</name>
        <text>You have telepathy with a range of 10 feet. When you expend a Psionic Energy Die as part of using Telepathic Connection to increase the range of your telepathy, for the duration of the effect, you can simultaneously contact a number of creatures equal to 1 plus the number rolled on the Psionic Energy Die.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Empowered Defense Mode (Telepath)</name>
        <text>While your Defense Mode is active, whenever you make a saving throw, you add 1d4 to the save.
	In addition, while your Defense mode is active, you can extend this benefit to creatures you are telepathically connected with using your Telepathic Connection.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Potent Thoughts (Telepath)</name>
        <text>You add your Intelligence modifier to the damage you deal with any Psion cantrip.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Telepatic Bolstering (Telepath)</name>
        <text>You have telepathy out to 30 feet. When you or a creature you can see within range of your telepathy fails an ability check or misses with an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to expend one Psionic Energy Die, roll the die, and add the number rolled to the d20, potentially turning a failed check into a success or a miss into a hit. The Psionic Energy Die is expended only if the check succeeds or the attack hits.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Scramble Minds (Telepath)</name>
        <text>When you cast Confusion, you can expend four Psionic Energy Dice to modify the spell so that the radius of the spell's Sphere becomes 30 feet.
	In addition, creatures under the effect of the spell roll two d10s, and you choose which roll determines their behavior on their turns.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Biofeedback</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a Psion spell from the Necromancy or Transmutation school, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die and roll it. You gain a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to the number rolled plus your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Destructive Thoughts</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a Psion spell from the Conjuration or Evocation school and a creature you can see succeeds on a saving throw against the spell, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die and roll it. The creature takes Psychic damage equal to the number rolled plus your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Devilish Tongue</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When you take the Influence action, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die, roll it, and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Ego Whip</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When a creature provokes an Opportunity Attack from you by leaving your reach, you can take a Reaction to roll one Psionic Energy Die and force the creature to make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, the target's Speed is reduced by 10 feet and it subtracts the number rolled from the next damage roll it makes before the end of its next turn. The die is expended only if the target fails the saving throw.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Expanded Awareness</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When you take the Search action, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die, roll it, and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Id Insinuation</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a Psion spell from the Enchantment or Illusion school that forces a creature to make a saving throw, you can expend two Psionic Energy Dice and roll one Psionic Energy Die. One target of the spell you can see subtracts the number rolled from its saving throw against the spell.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Inerrant Aim</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When you make an attack roll against a creature and miss, you can roll one Psionic Energy Die and add the number rolled to the attack roll, potentially turning the miss into a hit. If this causes the a to hit, the die is expended.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Psionic Backlash</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>Immediately after a creature you can see hits you with an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to expend one Psionic Energy Die, roll two Psionic Energy Dice, and subtract the number rolled on each die from the total. In addition, you can force the attacker to make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes Psychic damage equal to the amount rolled on the two Psionic Energy Dice.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 4</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Psionic Guards</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>At the start of your turn, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die. Until the start of your next turn, you have Immunity to the Charmed and Frightened conditions and Advantage on Intelligence saving throws. If you are Charmed or Frightened when you use this discipline, the condition ends on you.
	When you use Psionic Guards, you can also use a different Psionic Discipline this turn.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 5</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Swift Precognition</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a Psion spell from the Abjuration or Divination school with a casting time of an action, you can expend a number of Psionic Energy Dice to change the casting time to a Bonus Action for this casting. The number of dice equals one plus the spell's level.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 5</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Psionic Discipline: Tactical Mind</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]: Psionic Discipline Options</classes>
    <text>When you take the Study action, you can expend one Psionic Energy Die, roll it, and add the number rolled to the ability check.

Source:	UA2025-ThePsion p. 5</text>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="1">1d6</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="5">1d8</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="13">1d10</roll>
    <roll description="Psionic Energy Die" level="17">1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blade Ward [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dancing Lights [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Friends [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Light [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mage Hand [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mending [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Message [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mind Sliver [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Minor Illusion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Prestidigitation [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>True Strike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Animal Friendship [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Charm Person [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Command [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Comprehend Languages [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Magic [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dissonant Whispers [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Feather Fall [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Identify [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Jump [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Longstrider [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mage Armor [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Silent Image [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sleep [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Speak with Animals [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tasha's Hideous Laughter [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tenser's Floating Disk [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Animal Messenger [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blindness/Deafness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Calm Emotions [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Crown of Madness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Thoughts [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Enhance Ability [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Enlarge/Reduce [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Enthrall [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Heat Metal [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Person [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invisibility [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Knock [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Locate Animals or Plants [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Locate Object [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Magic Mouth [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mind Spike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mirror Image [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Force [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>See Invisibility [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shatter [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Silence [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Suggestion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Zone of Truth [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Animate Dead [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bestow Curse [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Clairvoyance [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Magic [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fear [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fly [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hypnotic Pattern [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Major Image [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Nondetection [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sending [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tongues [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Eye [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Banishment [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Charm Monster [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Compulsion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Confusion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dimension Door [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Freedom of Movement [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallucinatory Terrain [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Locate Creature [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Killer [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Polymorph [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Raulothim's Psychic Lance [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Summon Aberration [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Animate Objects [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Awaken [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contact Other Plane [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dominate Person [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dream [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Geas [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Monster [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Legend Lore [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mislead [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Modify Memory [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Rary's Telepathic Bond [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Scrying [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Seeming [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Synaptic Static [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Telekinesis [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Teleportation Circle [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024], Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blade Barrier [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Disintegrate [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Eyebite [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Find the Path [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mass Suggestion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Move Earth [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Otto's Irresistible Dance [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Programmed Illusion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>True Seeing [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Etherealness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Forcecage [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mirage Arcane [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plane Shift [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Power Word Fortify [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Project Image [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Reverse Gravity [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Teleport [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Antipathy/Sympathy [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Befuddlement [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dominate Monster [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Glibness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Maze [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mind Blank [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Power Word Stun [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Telepathy [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Astral Projection [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Foresight [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Power Word Heal [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Power Word Kill [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shapechange [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Time Stop [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Weird [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024]</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Alter Self [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cure Wounds [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Inflict Wounds [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Lesser Restoration [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Vitality [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Haste [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph), Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Stoneskin [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contagion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mass Cure Wounds [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Metamorph)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Expeditious Retreat [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Misty Step [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blink [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Steel Wind Strike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psi Warper)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cloud of Daggers [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Levitate [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shield [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Thunderwave [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Slow [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Telekinetic Crush [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Otiluke's Resilient Sphere [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Stone Shape [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Force [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Psykinetic)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bane [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Counterspell [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Speak With Plants [2024]</name>
    <classes>Psion (UA) [2024] (Telepath)</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
