<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <item>
    <name>Harkon's Bite</name>
    <detail>uncommon, cursed (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight/>
    <text>A dire wolf tooth dangles from this simple cord necklace. While you wear it, the necklace grants you a +1 bonus to ability checks and saving throws.

Curse. Attuning to Harkon's Bite curses you until either Harkon Lukas removes the necklace from you or you are targeted by a remove curse spell or similar magic. As long as you remain cursed, you cannot remove the necklace.

donning or removing the necklace, whether you are attuned to it or not, you are afflicted with werewolf lycanthropy as detailed in the Monster Manual. The curse lasts until the dawn after the next full moon. If you are still wearing the necklace at this time, you are afflicted with the lycanthropy again.

Source:	Van Richten's Guide to Ravenloft p. 137</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Saving Throws +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Initiative +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Acrobatics +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Animal handling +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Arcana +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Athletics +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Deception +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">History +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Insight +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Intimidation +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Investigation +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Medicine +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Nature +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Perception +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Performance +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Persuasion +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Religion +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Sleight of Hand +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Stealth +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="skill">Survival +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Nepenthe</name>
    <detail>longsword, legendary (requires attunement by a Paladin)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <text>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you hit a fiend or an undead with it, that creature takes an extra 2d10 radiant damage.

While you hold the drawn sword, it creates an aura in a 10-foot radius around you. You and all creatures friendly to you in the aura have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. If you have 17 or more levels in the paladin class, the radius of the aura increases to 30 feet.

Sentience. Nepenthe is a sentient, neutral evil weapon with an Intelligence of 10, a Wisdom of 8, and a Charisma of 18. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. It can read and understand Elvish. It can also speak Elvish, but only through the voice of its wielder, with whom the sword can communicate telepathically.

Personality. In its lifetime, the sword has beheaded thousands of criminals, not all of whom were guilty of the crimes for which they were convicted. The sword cannot distinguish the guilty from the innocent. With each beheading, it hungers for more justice and blood. The sword is corrupt and irredeemable.

Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Proficiency: martial, longsword
Source:	Van Richten's Guide to Ravenloft p. 86</text>
    <value/>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Damage +3</modifier>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <property>M,V</property>
    <range/>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ivana's Whisper</name>
    <detail>poison (inhaled)</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight/>
    <text>This poison bears a distinct scent and chemical message from Ivana Boritsi. A creature subjected to this poison must succeed on a DC 18 Constitution saving throw or experience the effects of a dream spell created by Ivana the next time they sleep. This poison is nonmagical, and Ivana doesn't directly communicate with those affected during the dream. Rather, she creates the illusion of speaking with her intended target by alchemically crafting her message, predicting her target's reactions, and chemically encoding in her responses. She wears this poison as a perfume or hides it within gift bouquets, allowing it to convey her message later.

Inhaled: These poisons are powders or gases that take effect when inhaled. Blowing the powder or releasing the gas subjects creatures in a 5-foot cube to its effect. The resulting cloud dissipates immediately afterward. Holding one's breath is ineffective against inhaled poisons, as they affect nasal membranes, tear ducts, and other parts of the body.

Source:	Van Richten's Guide to Ravenloft p. 83</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cracked Driftglobe</name>
    <detail>uncommon</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>This small sphere of thick glass weighs 1 pound. If you are within 60 feet of it, you can speak its command word and cause it to emanate the light spell.

Source:	Candlekeep Mysteries p. 110</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gloves Of Soul Catching</name>
    <detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight/>
    <text>Your Constitution score is 20 while you wear these gloves. This property of the gloves has no effect on you if your Constitution is already 20 or higher.

After making a successful unarmed strike while wearing these gloves, you can use the gloves to deal an extra 2d10 force damage to the target, and you regain a number of hit points equal to the force damage dealt. Alternatively, instead of regaining hit points in this way, you can choose to gain advantage on one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make before the end of your next turn.

Crafting the gloves requires silver thread, fine leather, and other material components worth a total of 5,000 gp. To imbue the gloves with magic, a ritual must be performed, and this ritual requires three sacrifices: a being of great intellect, a being of strong body, and a being of pure heart. The ritual must take place under the light of a full moon and requires 5 hours to perform. The ritual consumes and destroys the souls of those who are sacrificed, meaning they can't be brought back from the dead.

Source:	Candlekeep Mysteries p. 169</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Radiance</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement by a Spellcaster)</detail>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While holding this wand, you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls. In addition, you ignore half cover when making a spell attack. Radiance is in the form of an exquisite golden hand mirror.

While surrounded by darkness, it sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius. A creature that is attuned to Radiance can use a bonus action while holding the mirror to cast the enhance ability spell, choosing itself and no other creature as the spell's target. Once this property of the wand is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.

Source: Candlekeep Mysteries p. 87</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">spell attack +1</modifier>
  </item>
</compendium>
