<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Goblin (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <displayname>Goblin  (HB)</displayname>
    <ancestry>Goblin  (HB)</ancestry>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Goblins are small, resourceful fey creatures known for their cunning, tenacity, and boundless energy. Though many associate them with mischief and trickery, goblins are survivors at heart, thriving in the wild, in cities, and in the unpredictable courts of the Feywild. Their fey heritage grants them an uncanny resilience against fear, while their natural agility and ferocity make them dangerous foes despite their small stature. Whether as sneaky rogues, cunning spellcasters, or fearless warriors, goblins bring a mix of scrappy ingenuity and raw determination to any challenge.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Stealth</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Frightened condition on yourself.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Nimble Escape</name>
      <text>You can take the Disengage or Hide action as a bonus action on each of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fury of the Small</name>
      <text>When you damage a creature that is at least one size category larger than you with an attack or a spell, you can deal extra damage equal to your character level. Once you use this trait, you can't do so again until you finish long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Small Goblin Energy</name>
      <text>Once per round, when you hit a creature that is at least one size category larger than you with an attack or a spell that requires you to make an attack roll, you deal extra damage equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down, minimum of 1). However, you can only benefit from this trait while Fury of the Small is still available.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Bloodied Fury</name>
      <text>The first time you gain the Bloodied condition in a combat encounter, you can use your reaction to make a single melee attack against a creature within 5 feet of you that is at least one size category larger than you. If you hit, you deal the weapon's normal damage plus extra damage equal to your character level.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Goblin, Cragmaw (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <displayname>Cragmaw Goblin</displayname>
    <ancestry>Goblin</ancestry>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <resist>psychic</resist>
    <proficiency>Arcana</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Cragmaw Goblins are a savage and twisted variant of their kin, native to the Sword Coast. Their exposure to a fragment of a Netherese obelisk has left them permanently altered, warping their minds and bodies. They bear a more menacing, bestial appearance with jagged teeth, glowing eyes, and an unsettling aura that unnerves even seasoned warriors. This exposure has granted them unnatural resilience and latent psionic energy, making them both cunning and terrifying foes. Though they still possess the goblin drive for survival, their altered nature makes them more aggressive, unpredictable, and prone to violent outbursts.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Fey</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Resistances</name>
      <text>Psychic</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Arcana</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Nimble Escape</name>
      <text>You can take the Disengage or Hide action as a bonus action on each of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Fury of the Small</name>
      <text>When you damage a creature that is at least one size category larger than you with an attack or a spell, you can deal extra Psychic damage equal to your character level. Once you use this trait, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Small Goblin Energy</name>
      <text>Once per round, when you hit a creature that is at least one size category larger than you with an attack or a spell that requires an attack roll, you deal extra Psychic damage equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down, minimum of 1). However, you can only benefit from this trait while Fury of the Small is still available.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Toothy Grin</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you flash a menacing, unnatural grin at a creature within 30 feet. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become Frightened of you for 1 minute. The DC for this saving throw is equal to your passive Intimidation score (10 + your Intimidation modifier). The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. Once you use this ability, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
