<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Rogue [2024]</name>
    <!-- Rogue Subclass: Scion Of The Three (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Rogue Subclass: Scion Of The Three (UA)</name>
        <text>Become a Gruesome Agent of Malice

A Scion of the Three draws power from a group of malevolent gods known as the Dead Three: Bane, deity of tyranny; Bhaal, deity of violence and murder; and Myrkul, deity of death. While some Rogues of this subclass pledge themselves ardently to those three macabre gods, others find themselves thrust on this path by a curse. Either way, a scion's power manifests as various occult gifts, as well as an uncanny talent for striking and terrifying foes.

Scions of the Three are most common in Baldur's Gate, where the Dead Three have long competed for influence over mortal hearts. Underground cults to Bane, Bhaal, and Myrkul often count Scions of the Three among their most useful agents. Outside Baldur's Gate, secular thieves' guilds such as the Shadow Thieves of Amn or Xanathar's guild in Waterdeep might cautiously call on a Scion of the Three to undertake an especially violent contract.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Bloodthirst (Scion Of The Three (UA))</name>
        <text>If your Sneak Attack hits a Bloodied creature, the target takes extra damage of the weapon's type equal to half your Rogue level (round up).

In addition, when an enemy you can see is reduced to 0 Hit Points, you can take a Reaction and teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of yourself. You can then make one melee attack. You can use this Reaction a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Dread Allegiance (Scion Of The Three (UA))</name>
        <text>Choose one of the Dead Three: Bane, Bhaal, or Myrkul. You gain Resistance to one type of damage and the ability to cast a cantrip, as detailed in the table below; Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this cantrip. When you finish a Long Rest, you can change your choice.

Dread Allegiance:
God | Damage Resistance | Cantrip
Bane | Psychic | Minor Illusion
Bhaal | Poison | Blade Ward
Myrkul | Necrotic | Chill Touch

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Strike Fear (Scion Of The Three (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the following Cunning Strike option.

Terrify (Cost: 1d6). The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw, or it has the Frightened condition for 1 minute. The Frightened target repeats the save at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 13: Aura Of Malevolence (Scion Of The Three (UA))</name>
        <text>You radiate malignant power associated with one of the Dead Three. At the start of each of your turns, each creature of your choice within a 10-foot Emanation originating from you takes damage equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1); the damage type is the same as the damage Resistance granted by your choice in the Dread Allegiance feature.

Damage dealt by this aura ignores Resistance. The aura is inactive while you have the Incapacitated condition.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Dread Incarnate (Scion Of The Three (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

Battle Tyrant. You have Advantage on attack rolls against any creature with the Frightened condition.

Murderous Intent. When you roll for your Sneak Attack damage, you can treat a roll of a 1 or 2 on the die as a 3.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
