<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Warlock</name>
    <!-- Otherworldly Patron: Hexblade (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Otherworldly Patron: Hexblade (UA)</name>
        <text>You've made a pact with a sentient magic weapon and the cursed forces contained within its blade. Such a weapon could be the sword sheathed at a Warlock's side, or it could be an infamous magic weapon stored elsewhere, projecting its power across the multiverse to further its cunning plans. To those who are willing to follow this weapon's whims, these inscrutable patrons offer the power to bestow malignant curses, deliver punishing blows, and bolster the wielder.

Design Note: Hexblade Patron Updates:
Here are the main updates in this subclass since its appearance in Xanathar's Guide to Everything:

	• Hexblade Spells (formerly Expanded Spell List) now gives you a list of always prepared spells. The spells granted have been revised.

	• Hexblade Manifest is a new feature, allowing you to cast Hex a number of times without a spell slot. It also grants you a handful of unique ways to interact with your cursed target.

	• Life Stealer is a new feature that interacts with the Hex spell to provide healing and reliable damage.

	• Armor of Hexes now more reliably reduces damage taken.

	• Masterful Hex is a new feature that boosts the power of Hexblade Manifest.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hexblade Spells (Hexblade (UA))</name>
        <text>
The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Warlock level specified in the Hexblade Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Hexblade Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3 | Arcane Vigor, Hex, Magic Weapon, Shield, Wrathful Smite
5 | Conjure Barrage, Dispel Magic
7 | Freedom of Movement, Staggering Smite
9 | Animate Objects, Steel Wind Strike

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hexblade Manifest (Hexblade (UA))</name>
        <text>Your patron grants you the power to summon cursed echoes of its blade to hinder your foes. You gain the following benefits.

Hexblade's Curse. You can cast Hex without expending a spell slot a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest. When you cast Hex, a spectral weapon resembling your patron orbits the cursed target.

Hexblade's Maneuvers. Once per turn, when you hit a target cursed by your Hex with an attack roll, you can cause one of these additional effects:

	• Draining Slash. The target makes a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the target can't make Opportunity Attacks and its Speed is halved until the start of your next turn.

	• Harrowing Blade. The target makes a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the next time the target makes an attack roll against a creature other than you before the start of your next turn, the target takes Necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier.

	• Stymying Mark. The target has Disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes before the start of your next turn.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Life Stealer (Hexblade (UA))</name>
        <text>Your patron's might allows you to drain vitality from those you curse, granting you the following benefits.

Hungering Hex. Whenever the target cursed by your Hex drops to 0 Hit Points, you regain Hit Points equal to 1d8 plus your Charisma modifier.

Inevitable Blade. Once per turn, if you make an attack roll against the target cursed by your Hex and miss, you can deal Necrotic damage to that creature equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 Necrotic damage).

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Armor of Hexes (Hexblade (UA))</name>
        <text>When you take damage from the cursed target of your Hex, you can take a Reaction to reduce the damage taken by an amount equal to 2d8 plus your Charisma modifier. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 8</text>
        <roll description="Damage Reduction">2d8+%6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Masterful Hex (Hexblade (UA))</name>
        <text>Your patron's accursed might flows even more strongly through you, granting the following benefits.

Accursed Critical. Any attack roll you make against the target cursed by your Hex scores a Critical Hit on a roll of a 19 or 20 on the d20.

Infectious Hex. When you use one of your Hexblade's Maneuvers, you can target one additional creature within 30 feet of the cursed target. The additional target takes 1d6 Necrotic damage.

Resilient Hex. Taking damage can't break your Concentration on Hex.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Otherworldly Patron: Undead Patron (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Otherworldly Patron: Undead Patron (UA)</name>
        <text>Defy Death for Profane Power

You've made a pact with a creature that defies the cycle of life and death: a powerful lich, vampire, or other entity of undeath. Having once been mortal themselves, these ancient patrons know firsthand the paths of ambition and the routes past the doors of death. They eagerly share this profane knowledge, along with other secrets, with those who work their will among the living.

Design Note: Undead Patron:
Here are the main updates in this subclass since its appearance in Van Richten's Guide to Ravenloft:

	• Undead Spells (formerly Expanded Spell List) now gives you a list of always prepared spells.

	• Grave Touched now allows your spells and attacks to ignore Resistance to Necrotic damage.

	• Necrotic Husk no longer requires a Reaction to use its secondary feature, and it restores you to a number of Hit Points equal to 10 times your Charisma modifier.

	• Superior Dread is a new feature that improves your Form of Dread, allowing you to fly, regain Hit Points, and improve your spellcasting.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 8</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Form of Dread (Undead Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you transform into an avatar of your patron's dreadful power, gaining the benefits below for 1 minute, until you have the Incapacitated condition, or until you end the form (no action required). You can transform a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Facsimile of Life. You gain Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d10 plus your Warlock level.

Frightful Avatar. You have Immunity to the Frightened condition. Additionally, once per turn, when you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can force it to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the target has the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Undead Spells (Undead Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have
certain spells ready; when you reach a Warlock level
specified in the Undead Spells table, you thereafter
always have the listed spells prepared.

Undead Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3 | Blindness/Deafness, False Life, Phantasmal Force, Ray of Sickness
5 | Speak with Dead, Vampiric Touch
7 | Death Ward, Phantasmal Killer
9 | Antilife Shell, Cloudkill

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Grave Touched (Undead Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>Your patron's powers have a profound effect on your body and magic, granting you the following benefits.

Arcane Necrosis. Whenever you cast a spell or hit a creature with an attack roll and deal Necrotic damage, the damage dealt ignores Resistance to Necrotic damage.
	Additionally, once per turn when you cast a spell that deals damage while using your Form of Dread, you can change that spell's damage type to Necrotic.

Undead Endurance. You don't gain Exhaustion levels from dehydration, malnutrition, or suffocation. In addition, you don't need to sleep, and magic can't put you to sleep.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Necrotic Husk (Undead Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>Your connection to undeath now saturates your body. You gain the following benefits.

Necrotic Resilience. You have Resistance to Necrotic damage. While using your Form of Dread, you have Immunity to Necrotic damage.

Unholy Resuscitation. If you drop to 0 Hit Points and don't die outright, you can cause your body to erupt with deathly energy. Each creature of your choice in a 30-foot Emanation originating from you makes a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, taking Necrotic damage equal to 2d10 plus your Warlock level on a failure or half as much damage on a success. Your Hit Points then change to 10 times your Charisma modifier (minimum of 10 Hit Points), and you gain 1 Exhaustion level.
	Once you use this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Unholy Resuscitation</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Undead Patron (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Superior Dread (Undead Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Form of Dread improves, granting you the following benefits while you are using it.

Flight. You have a Fly Speed equal to your Speed and can hover.

Profane Casting. Whenever you cast a Warlock spell from the Conjuration or Necromancy school, you cast it without any Verbal, Somatic, or Material components, except Material components that are consumed by the spell or that have a cost specified in the spell.

Vitality Siphon. Once per turn when you deal Necrotic damage to a creature, you regain Hit Points equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 Hit Point).

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 9</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Vigor [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hex [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Magic Weapon [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shield [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wrathful Smite [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Conjure Barrage [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Magic [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Freedom of Movement [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Staggering Smite [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Animate Objects [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Steel Wind Strike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Hexblade (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blindness/Deafness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>False Life [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Force [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ray of Sickness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Speak with Dead [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Vampiric Touch [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Death Ward [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Killer [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Antilife Shell [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cloudkill [2024]</name>
    <classes>Warlock (Undead Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
