<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Bard [2024]</name>
    <!-- Bard College: College of Spirits (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard College: College of Spirits (UA)</name>
        <text>Call Forth Spirits from Beyond the Grave

Using occult trappings, Bards of the College of Spirits conjure legendary and long-dead spirits to change the world once more. But such entities are capricious, and what a Bard summons isn't always entirely under their control.

Design Note: College of Spirits Updates
Here are the main updates in this subclass since its appearance in Van Richten's Guide to Ravenloft:

	• Guiding Whispers and Spiritual Focus are now combined into a single feature, Channeler. This new feature also grants you proficiency with playing cards.

	• Spirits from Beyond (formerly Tales from Beyond) has been reworked to improve its action economy and produce more immediate effects. The options on the feature's table have been revised as well.

	• Empowered Channeling is a new feature that allows the Bard to cast and alter the Spirit Guardians spell.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Channeler (College of Spirits (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn how to contact spirits beyond the grave, letting their power and knowledge flow through you. You gain the following benefits.

Guiding Whispers. You know the Guidance cantrip. It has a range of 60 feet when you cast it.

Spiritual Focus. You employ tools that aid you in channeling spirits. You gain a Gaming Set (Playing Cards). You have proficiency with this Gaming Set, and you can use the cards or one of the following items as a Spellcasting Focus for your Bard spells: Arcane Focus (Crystal or Orb), Candle, or Ink Pen.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Spirits from Beyond (College of Spirits (UA))</name>
        <text>While holding a Spellcasting Focus, you can take a Bonus Action to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration and call forth the powers of a spirit. Roll the Bardic Inspiration die and refer to the Spirits from Beyond table to determine the spirit you channel, then choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself as the spirit's target. The spirit immediately takes effect; if a spirit's effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals your Bard spell save DC.

Spirits from Beyond:
Bardic Insp. Die | Spirit
1 | Beloved. The target regains Hit Points equal to one roll of your Bardic Inspiration die plus your Charisma modifier.
2 | Sharpshooter. The target takes Force damage equal to one roll of your Bardic Inspiration die plus your Charisma modifier.
3 | Avenger. Until the end of your next turn, any creature that hits the target with a melee attack roll takes Force combined into a single feature, Channeler. This new damage equal to a roll of your Bardic Inspiration die.
4 | Renegade. The target can immediately take a Reaction to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space it can see.
5 | Fortune Teller. The target has Advantage on D20 Tests until the start of your next turn.
6 | Wayfarer. The target gains Temporary Hit Points equal to a roll of your Bardic Inspiration die plus your Bard level. While it has these Temporary Hit Points, the target's Speed increases by 10 feet.
7 | Trickster. The target makes a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes Psychic damage equal to two rolls of your Bardic Inspiration die and has the Charmed condition until the start of your next turn. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage only.
8 | Shade. The target gains the Invisible condition until the end of its next turn or until the target makes an attack roll, deals damage, or casts a spell. When the invisibility ends, each creature in a 5-foot Emanation originating from the target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take Necrotic damage equal to two rolls of your Bardic Inspiration die.
9 | Arsonist. The target makes a Dexterity saving throw, taking Fire damage equal to four rolls of your Bardic Inspiration die on a failed save or half as much on a successful one.
10 | Coward. The target and each creature of your choice in a 30-foot Emanation originating from the target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition until the start of your next turn. While Frightened, a creature's Speed is halved, and it can take either an action or a Bonus Action, not both.
11 | Brute. Each creature of your choice in a 30-foot Emanation originating from the target makes a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes Thunder damage equal to three rolls of your Bardic Inspiration die and has the Prone condition. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage only.
12 | Controlled Channeling. You determine the spirit's effect by choosing one of the other rows in this table.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 3</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Empowered Channeling (College of Spirits (UA))</name>
        <text>Your ability to channel spirits improves. You gain the following benefits.

Power from Beyond. Once per turn, when you cast a Bard spell that deals damage or restores Hit Points, roll a d6. You gain a bonus to one of the spell's damage rolls or to the total Hit Points the spell restores equal to the number rolled.

Spiritual Manifestation. You always have the Spirit Guardians spell prepared. You can cast the spell once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in this way when you finish a Long Rest.

Whenever you start casting the spell, you can modify it so the spirits also guard against worldly threats. When cast in this way, you and allies within the spell's Emanation have Half Cover. Once you modify the spell in this way, you can't do so again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Mystical Connection (College of Spirits (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain mastery over the spirits you call forth. Whenever you roll on the Spirits from Beyond table, you can roll the die twice and choose which of the two effects to bestow.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 4</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
