<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Barbarian</name>
    <hd>12</hd>
    <proficiency>Strength, Constitution, Animal Handling, Athletics, Intimidation, Nature, Perception, Survival</proficiency>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>
    <armor>Light Armor, Medium Armor, Shields</armor>
    <weapons>Simple Weapons, Martial Weapons</weapons>
    <tools>None</tools>
    <wealth>2d4x10</wealth>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Starting Barbarian</name>
        <text>As a 1st-level Barbarian, you begin play with 12 + your Constitution modifier hit points.

You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.

	• Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields
	• Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons
	• Tools: none
	• Skills: Choose 2 from Animal Handling, Athletics, Intimidation, Nature, Perception and Survival

You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.

	• (a) a greataxe or (b) any martial melee weapon
	• (a) two handaxes or (b) any simple weapon
	• An explorer's pack, and four javelins

If you forgo this starting equipment, as well as the items offered by your background, you start with 2d4 × 10 gp to buy your equipment.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Barbarian</name>
        <text>If your group uses the optional rule on multiclassing in the Player's Handbook, here's what you need to know if you choose barbarian as one of your classes.

Ability Score Minimum:
As a multiclass character, you must have at least the following ability score(s) to take a level in this class, or to take a level in another class if you are already a barbarian.

	• Strength 13

Proficiencies Gained:
When you gain your first level in a class other than your initial class, you gain only some of your new class's starting proficiencies, here are the proficiencies you gain when you take your first level as a barbarian.

	• Armor: shields
	• Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons
	• Tools: none

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Features</name>
        <text>When you gain a new level in a class, you get its features for that level. You don't, however, receive the class's starting equipment, and a few features have additional rules when you're multiclassing: Channel Divinity, Extra Attack, Unarmored Defense, and Spellcasting.

Channel Divinity:
If you already have the Channel Divinity feature and gain a level in a class that also grants the feature, you gain the Channel Divinity effects granted by that class, but getting the feature again doesn't give you an additional use of it. You gain additional uses only when you reach a class level that explicitly grants them to you. For example, if you are a cleric 6/paladin 4, you can use Channel Divinity twice between rests because you are high enough level in the cleric class to have more uses. Whenever you use the feature, you can choose any of the Channel Divinity effects available to you from your two classes.

Extra Attack:
If you gain the Extra Attack class feature from more than one class, the features don't add together. You can't make more than two attacks with this feature unless it says you do (as the fighter's version of Extra Attack does).
	Similarly, the warlock's eldritch invocation Thirsting Blade doesn't give you additional attacks if you also have Extra Attack.

Unarmored Defense:
If you already have the Unarmored Defense feature, you can't gain it again from another class.

Spellcasting:
Your capacity for spellcasting depends partly on your combined levels in all your spellcasting classes and partly on your individual levels in those classes. Once you have the Spellcasting feature from more than one class, use the rules below. If you multiclass but have the Spellcasting feature from only one class, you follow the rules as described in that class.

Spells Known and Prepared:
You determine what spells you know and can prepare for each class individually, as if you were a single-classed member of that class. If you are a ranger 4/wizard 3, for example, you know three 1 st-level ranger spells based on your levels in the ranger class. As a 3rd-level wizard, you know three wizard cantrips, and your spellbook contains ten wizard spells, two of which (the two you gained when you reached 3rd level as a wizard) can be 2nd-level spells. If your Intelligence is 16, you can prepare six wizard spells from your spellbook.
	Each spell you know and prepare is associated with one of your classes, and you use the spell casting ability of that class when you cast the spell. Similarly, a spellcasting focus, such as a holy symbol, can be used only for the spells from the class associated with that focus.
	If a cantrip of yours increases in power at higher levels, the increase is based on your character level, not your level in a particular class.

Spell Slots:
You determine your available spell slots by adding together all your levels in the bard, cleric, druid, sorcerer, and wizard classes, half your levels (rounded down) in the paladin and ranger classes, and a third of your fighter or rogue levels (rounded down) if you have the Eldritch Knight or the Arcane Trickster feature. Use this total to determine your spell slots by consulting the Multiclass Spellcaster table.
	If you have more than one spellcasting class, this table might give you spell slots of a level that is higher than the spells you know or can prepare. You can use those slots, but only to cast your lower-level spells. If a lower level spell that you cast, like burning hands, has an enhanced effect when cast using a higher-level slot, you can use the enhanced effect, even though you don't have any spells of that higher level.
	For example, if you are the aforementioned ranger 4/ wizard 3, you count as a 5th-level character when determining your spell slots: you have four 1st-level slots, three 2nd-level slots, and two 3rd-level slots. However, you don't know any 3rd-level spells, nor do you know any 2nd-level ranger spells. You can use the spell slots of those levels to cast the spells you do know-and potentially enhance their effects.

Pact Magic:
If you have both the Spellcasting class feature and the Pact Magic class feature from the warlock class, you can use the spell slots you gain from the Pact Magic feature to cast spells you know or have prepared from classes with the Spellcasting class feature, and you can use the spell slots you gain from the Spellcasting class feature to cast warlock spells you know.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Rage</name>
        <text>In battle, you fight with primal ferocity. On your turn, you can enter a rage as a bonus action.
	While raging, you gain the following benefits if you aren't wearing heavy armor:

	• You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.

	• When you make a melee weapon attack using Strength, you gain a bonus to the damage roll that increases as you gain levels as a barbarian. At 1st level, you have a +2 bonus to damage. Your bonus increases to +3 at 9th level and to +4 at 16th.

	• You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.

If you are able to cast spells, you can't cast them or concentrate on them while raging.
	Your rage lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are knocked unconscious or if your turn ends and you haven't attacked a hostile creature since your last turn or taken damage since then. You can also end your rage on your turn as a bonus action.
	Once you have raged the maximum number of times for your barbarian level, you must finish a long rest before you can rage again. You may rage 2 times at 1st level, 3 at 3rd, 4 at 6th, 5 at 12th, and 6 at 17th.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
        <roll description="Rage Damage" level="1">+2</roll>
        <roll description="Rage Damage" level="9">+3</roll>
        <roll description="Rage Damage" level="16">+4</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Unarmored Defense</name>
        <text>While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
        <special>Unarmored Defense: Constitution</special>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Rage</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Reckless Attack</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can throw aside all concern for defense to attack with fierce desperation. When you make your first attack on your turn, you can decide to attack recklessly. Doing so gives you advantage on melee weapon attack rolls using Strength during this turn, but attack rolls against you have advantage until your next turn.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Danger Sense</name>
        <text>At 2nd level, you gain an uncanny sense of when things nearby aren't as they should be, giving you an edge when you dodge away from danger.
	You have advantage on Dexterity saving throws against effects that you can see, such as traps and spells. To gain this benefit, you can't be blinded, deafened, or incapacitated.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Primal Path</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you choose a path that shapes the nature of your rage from the list of available paths. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th levels.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Rage</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Extra Attack</name>
        <text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Fast Movement</name>
        <text>Starting at 5th level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you aren't wearing heavy armor.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
        <modifier category="bonus">speed +10</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Path Feature</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you gain a feature from your Primal Path.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Rage</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature>
        <name>Feral Instinct</name>
        <text>By 7th level, your instincts are so honed that you have advantage on initiative rolls.
	Additionally, if you are surprised at the beginning of combat and aren't incapacitated, you can act normally on your first turn, but only if you enter your rage before doing anything else on that turn.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature>
        <name>Brutal Critical (1 die)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 9th level, you can roll one additional weapon damage die when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.
	This increases to two additional dice at 13th level and three additional dice at 17th level.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Path Feature</name>
        <text>At 10th level, you gain a feature from your Primal Path.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Relentless Rage</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, your rage can keep you fighting despite grievous wounds. If you drop to 0 hit points while you're raging and don't die outright, you can make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw. If you succeed, you drop to 1 hit point instead.
	Each time you use this feature after the first, the DC increases by 5. When you finish a short or long rest, the DC resets to 10.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Rage</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature>
        <name>Brutal Critical (2 dice)</name>
        <text>At 13th level, you can roll two additional weapon damage dice when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.
	This increases to three additional dice at 17th level.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Path Feature</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you gain a feature from your Primal Path.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature>
        <name>Persistent Rage</name>
        <text>Beginning at 15th level, your rage is so fierce that it ends early only if you fall unconscious or if you choose to end it.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature>
        <name>Brutal Critical (3 dice)</name>
        <text>At 17th level, you can roll three additional weapon damage dice when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Rage</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Indomitable Might</name>
        <text>Beginning at 18th level, if your total for a Strength check is less than your Strength score, you can use that score in place of the total.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Primal Champion</name>
        <text>At 20th level, you embody the power of the wilds. Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 4. Your maximum for those scores is now 24.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
        <modifier category="ability score">strength +4</modifier>
        <modifier category="ability score">constitution +4</modifier>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Primal Path: Path of the Berserker -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Primal Path: Path of the Berserker</name>
        <text>For some barbarians, rage is a means to an end | that end being violence. The Path of the Berserker is a path of untrammeled fury, slick with blood. As you enter the berserker's rage, you thrill in the chaos of battle, heedless of your own health or well-being.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Frenzy (Path of the Berserker)</name>
        <text>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, you can go into a frenzy when you rage. If you do so, for the duration of your rage you can make a single melee weapon attack as a bonus action on each of your turns after this one. When your rage ends, you suffer one level of exhaustion.

Exhaustion:
Some special abilities and environmental hazards, such as starvation and the long-term effects of freezing or scorching temperatures, can lead to a special condition called exhaustion. Exhaustion is measured in six levels. An effect can give a creature one or more levels of exhaustion, as specified in the effect's description.

Exhaustion Levels:
Level | Effect
1 | Disadvantage on ability checks
2 | Speed halved
3 | Disadvantage on attack rolls and saving throws
4 | Hit point maximum halved
5 | Speed reduced to 0
6 | Death

If an already exhausted creature suffers another effect that causes exhaustion, its current level of exhaustion increases by the amount specified in the effect's description.
	A creature suffers the effect of its current level of exhaustion as well as all lower levels. For example, a creature suffering level 2 exhaustion has its speed halved and has disadvantage on ability checks.
	An effect that removes exhaustion reduces its level as specified in the effect's description, with all exhaustion effects ending if a creature's exhaustion level is reduced below 1.
	Finishing a long rest reduces a creature's exhaustion level by 1, provided that the creature has also ingested some food and drink. Also, being raised from the dead reduces a creature's exhaustion level by 1.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mindless Rage (Path of the Berserker)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, you can't be charmed or frightened while raging. If you are charmed or frightened when you enter your rage, the effect is suspended for the duration of the rage.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Intimidating Presence (Path of the Berserker)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 10th level, you can use your action to frighten someone with your menacing presence. When you do so, choose one creature that you can see within 30 feet of you. If the creature can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn. On subsequent turns, you can use your action to extend the duration of this effect on the frightened creature until the end of your next turn. This effect ends if the creature ends its turn out of line of sight or more than 60 feet away from you.
	If the creature succeeds on its saving throw, you can't use this feature on that creature again for 24 hours.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Retaliation (Path of the Berserker)</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, when you take damage from a creature that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
