<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: Eldritch Blast cantrip

When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Ascendant Step</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 9th level Warlock

You can cast levitate on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Bewitching Whispers</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 7th level Warlock

You can cast compulsion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature

You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list (the two needn't be from the same list). The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.
	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Chains of Carceri</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 15th level, Pact of the Chain

You can cast hold monster at will-targeting a celestial, fiend, or elemental-without expending a spell slot or material components. You must finish a long rest before you can use this invocation on the same creature again.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Dreadful Word</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 7th level Warlock

You can cast confusion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: Eldritch Blast cantrip

When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can read all writing.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.

Blinded:
	• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

Deafened:
	• A deafened creature can't hear and automatically fails any ability check that requires hearing.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Lifedrinker</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 12th level, Pact of the Blade

When you hit a creature with your pact weapon, the creature takes extra necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1).

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Master of Myriad Forms</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 15th level Warlock

You can cast alter self at will, without expending a spell slot.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Minions of Chaos</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 9th level Warlock

You can cast conjure elemental once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Mire the Mind</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 5th level Warlock

You can cast slow once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: One with Shadows</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 5th level Warlock

When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move or take an action or a reaction.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Otherworldly Leap</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 9th level Warlock

You can cast jump on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: Eldritch Blast cantrip

When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Sculptor of Flesh</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 7th level Warlock

You can cast polymorph once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Sign of Ill Omen</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 5th level Warlock

You can cast bestow curse once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Thirsting Blade</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade

You can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Visions of Distant Realms</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 15th level Warlock

You can cast arcane eye at will, without expending a spell slot.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain

You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Whispers of the Grave</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 9th level Warlock

You can cast speak with dead at will, without expending a spell slot.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Witch Sight</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 15th level Warlock

You can see the true form of any shapechanger or creature concealed by illusion or transmutation magic while the creature is within 30 feet of you and within line of sight.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Metamagic: Careful Spell</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <components>(1 sorcery point)</components>
    <classes>Metamagic Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a spell that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the spell's full force. To do so, you spend 1 sorcery point and choose a number of those creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Metamagic: Distant Spell</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <components>(1 sorcery point)</components>
    <classes>Metamagic Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a spell that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double the range of the spell.
	When you cast a spell that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 sorcery point to make the range of the spell 30 feet.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Metamagic: Empowered Spell</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <components>(1 sorcery point)</components>
    <classes>Metamagic Options</classes>
    <text>When you roll damage for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). You must use the new rolls.
	You can use Empowered Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Metamagic: Extended Spell</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <components>(1 sorcery point)</components>
    <classes>Metamagic Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Metamagic: Heightened Spell</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <components>(3 sorcery points)</components>
    <classes>Metamagic Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw to resist its effects, you can spend 3 sorcery points to give one target of the spell disadvantage on its first saving throw made against the spell.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Metamagic: Quickened Spell</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <components>(2 sorcery points)</components>
    <classes>Metamagic Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Metamagic: Subtle Spell</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <components>(2 sorcery points)</components>
    <classes>Metamagic Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to cast it without any somatic or verbal components.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Metamagic: Twinned Spell</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <components>(1 sorcery point or more)</components>
    <classes>Metamagic Options</classes>
    <text>When you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn't have a range of self, you can spend a number of sorcery points equal to the spell's level to target a second creature in range with the same spell (1 sorcery point if the spell is a cantrip).
	To be eligible, a spell must be incapable of targeting more than one creature at the spell's current level. For example, magic missile and scorching ray aren't eligible, but ray of frost and chromatic orb are.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
  </spell>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Style: Archery</name>
    <prerequisite>Fighting Style Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
    <special>Fighting Style: Archery</special>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
    <prerequisite>Fighting Style Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
    <special>Fighting Style: Defense</special>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
    <prerequisite>Fighting Style Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
    <special>Fighting Style: Dueling</special>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name>
    <prerequisite>Fighting Style Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
    <special>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</special>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Style: Protection</name>
    <prerequisite>Fighting Style Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
    <special>Fighting Style: Protection</special>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name>
    <prerequisite>Fighting Style Feature</prerequisite>
    <text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
    <special>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</special>
  </feat>
</compendium>
