<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric</name>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain: Mushroom Domain</name>
        <text>The massive, strange mushroom jungles pulse with an inherent energy that is considered to be a kind of anima mundi suffusing all, its power springing from the massive, gorgeous jumble of colors, spores and life pulsing eternally in the underworld. The propagation of these places and the protection of their biomes have become nigh rapturous experiences for some of the devout, with enlightenment beckoning in the hallucinogenic spores, teas and armors crafted from the very mushrooms themselves.

Mushroom Domain Spells:
Level | Spells
1st | medicinal mushrooms, entangle
3rd | fiber shape, peripheral fungi
5th | fungal infestation, plant growth
7th | mushroom mount, grasping vine
9th | carnivorous mushroom,

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 326 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mushroom Domain: Mushroom-Whisperer</name>
        <text>At 1st level, you learn the language of mushrooms, allowing you to enter a strange form of communication with mushrooms. By touching a mushroom, you can imbue it with limited sentience, allowing it to communicate with you. You can question fungi about events within 30 feet of their location that have transpired within the day, gleaning information about creatures that have passed, weather and similar circumstances. You also become proficient in your choice two of the following skills: Insight, Medicine, Nature, or Survival. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make using either of those skills chosen.

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 326 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mushroom Domain: Channel Divinity: Explosive Caps</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to grow special, magically imbued explosive mushroom caps on either yourself or the immediate vicinity.

You gain a total number of explosive caps equal to twice your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier. Explosive caps last for 1 day or until you complete a long rest before withering and becoming inert. You treat explosive caps as simple ranged weapons with the finesse and thrown properties (range 20 ft./60 ft.). You are proficient with explosive caps. Explosive caps deal 2d6 force damage. The damage increases by 1d6 each time your proficiency bonus increases.

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 326 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mushroom Domain: Hallucinogenic Visions</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, your explosive caps contain inert, but hallucinogenic spores over which you can exert a modicum of control. When you throw an explosive cap, it detonates and leaves behind a wispy cloud of spores that lasts until the end of your next turn.

The cloud is a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on the target and it does not impede sight. As an action on your turn, you can will the spores to coalesce on a target currently within the cloud of spores that you can see. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature succeeds on the saving throw, you can't use this feature on it again until you finish a long rest. If the creature fails its save, it experiences strange hallucinations and must roll on Hallucinations table. The effects of hallucinogenic visions last for 1 minute.

Hallucinations:
d6 | You see...
1 | You're sinking into quicksand!
2 | You're being swarmed by tiny spiders!
3 | An item you're holding turns into a viper!
4 | The air is suffering as you breath it!
5 | You've shrunk to the size of an acorn!
6 | Gravity has reversed! Hold on!

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 326 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mushroom Domain: Potent Visions</name>
        <text>At 8th level, you control the hallucinations of your hallucinogenic visions. Your hallucinations can impart the blinded, charmed, frightened, or paralyzed conditions.

Blinded:
	• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

Charmed:
	• A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

Frightened:
	• A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.
	• The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.

Paralyzed:
	• A paralyzed creature is incapacitated, meaning it can't take actions or reactions, and can't move or speak.
	• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.
	• Any attack that hits the creature is a critical hit if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature.

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 326 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Mushroom Domain: Spell-Powered Caps</name>
        <text>At 17th level, you can spend spell slots to enhance your explosive caps as part of making an attack with an explosive cap. You gain a number of cap-points equal to the level of the spell slot you expended, which you can use to modify the respective attack.

Boomcap (1 point):
Your explosive caps deal an additional 1d6 force damage. For each additional die of damage, double the points required to a maximum of 4d6 for 8 points.

Cap Launch (1 point):
The normal range of your explosive caps increases by 10 feet. For each additional increase, double the points required to a maximum of +40 ft. for 8 points. The long range is three times the normal range.

Lingering Cloud (2 points):
Your spore cloud lingers for an additional round, allowing you to affect an additional creature with hallucinogenic visions.

Potent Spores (4 points):
Creatures suffer from disadvantage on saves against your hallucinogenic visions.

Puff Cloud (1 spoint):
Your spore cloud obscures sight as a fog cloud.

Regrow Cap (1 point):
You regrow an explosive cap after the attack.

Sporegale (1 point):
The radius of your spore cloud increases by 10 feet.

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 326 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain: Venomshade Domain</name>
        <text>Naraneus grants certain faithful drow access to a mote of her divine power over venom and shadows. These drow name this power the venomshade domain.

Venomshade Domain Spells
Level | Spells
1st | disguise self, shadow mote
3rd | see invisibility, shadow cast
5th | loom large, dispel magic
7th | dimension door, form of shadows
9th | modify memory, umbral step

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 327 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Venomshade Domain: Blessing of Poison</name>
        <text>Starting when you choose this domain at 1st level, you choose either Dexterity (Stealth) or Charisma (Deception). Once made, this choice cannot be reversed, unless you complete an appropriate quest (subject to GM's approval). You can grant yourself or a creature you touch advantage on checks with the chosen skill. This blessing lasts for 1 hour or until you use this feature again. You also gain proficiency with the poisoner's kit.

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 327 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Venomshade Domain: Channel Divinity: Poisonous Cunning</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to invoke the divine favor of Naraneus upon those wielding or subject to poison.

As an action, you call your deity's name. Up to two allies, one of which may be you, who are currently wielding a poisonous weapon or who are suffering from the poisoned condition, may spend their reactions to make an attack with their weapons. If these attacks hit, they add your Wisdom modifier to the damage dealt. At 11th level, allies (or yourself) who hit with this attack deal an additional 1d8 poison damage on a hit. At 17th level, allies (or yourself) who hit with this attack deal an additional 2d8 poison damage.

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 327 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Venomshade Domain: Pure Spite</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, whenever you are below half of your maximum hit points and suffering from either the grappled, poisoned or prone conditions due to the actions of an enemy that has not yet been vanquished, you may treat any result of 1 or 2 as a 3 on dice you roll to determine damage or healing effects for attacks you execute and spells you cast. This immediately ends if the foe is brought to 0 HP or if the condition ends.

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 327 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Venomshade Domain: Poisonous Shadows</name>
        <text>Starting at 8th level, whenever you would lose your shadow due to an effect, spell or similar circumstance, you may use your reaction to regrow your shadow and negate any and all negative effects associated with having no shadow.

Additionally, any beneficial spell or ability that requires the use of your shadow that may currently be in effect is not ended by this, allowing you to potentially have more than one spell or ability that uses your shadow in effect at any given time. You can use this feature again after completing a short rest.  Furthermore, as a reaction to being poisoned or to suffering poison damage, you can siphon poison coursing through your veins into your shadow, immediately ending any ongoing poison damage and the poisoned condition. You are still treated as poisoned for the purpose of this domain's abilities for as long as your shadow that absorbed the poison persists. Abrupt exposure to total darkness or magical light ends this boon. Your shadow may only hold one poison at any given time. If your shadow holds a poison and you complete a long rest, it is no longer considered to be holding poison.

Source:	Rise of the Drow p. 327 (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
