<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <monster>
    <name>Guardian Sprout</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <type>Plant</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>27 (5d6+10)</hp>
    <speed>20 ft.</speed>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>9</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>8</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Druidic</languages>
    <cr>1/4</cr>
    <vulnerable>fire</vulnerable>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 30 ft.</senses>
    <action>
      <name>Branch Slam</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (2d4 + 1) bludgeoning damage and the guardian sprout can cause the target to become grappled if its size is Medium or smaller (escape DC 13). Until this grapple ends, the guardian sprout can't use its Branch Slam on other targets.</text>
      <attack>Branch Slam|+3|2d4+1</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 223 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Guardian Shrub</name>
    <ancestry>Guardian Sprout</ancestry>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>Plant</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>84 (8d10+40)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>8</dex>
    <con>20</con>
    <int>7</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Druidic</languages>
    <cr>2</cr>
    <vulnerable>fire</vulnerable>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 30 ft.</senses>
    <action>
      <name>Branch Slam</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (2d8 + 4) bludgeoning damage and the guardian shrub can cause the target to become grappled if its size is Large or smaller (escape DC 16). Until this grapple ends, the guardian shrub can't use its Branch Slam on other targets.</text>
      <attack>Branch Slam|+6|2d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Root Entanglement (Recharge 5-6)</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>The guardian shrub takes root in the ground and causes them to sprout in a 20-foot radius around it. All creatures in the area must succeed on a DC 16 Strength saving throw or be restrained by the entangling roots. A creature restrained by the guardian shrub can use its action to make a Strength saving throw. On a success, it frees itself. As long as there is a restrained creature, the guardian shrub has its speed reduced to 0, if it moves on its turn the restrained creature is released.</text>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 223 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Guardian Bush</name>
    <ancestry>Guardian Sprout</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Plant</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>39 (6d8+12)</hp>
    <speed>25 ft.</speed>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>9</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>7</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Druidic</languages>
    <cr>1</cr>
    <vulnerable>fire</vulnerable>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 30 ft.</senses>
    <action>
      <name>Branch Slam</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (2d6 + 2) bludgeoning damage and the guardian bush can cause the target to become grappled if its size is Large or smaller (escape DC 14). Until this grapple ends, the guardian bush can't use its Branch Slam on other targets.</text>
      <attack>Branch Slam|+4|2d6+2</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 223 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Guardian Tree</name>
    <ancestry>Guardian Sprout</ancestry>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>Plant</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>112 (9d12+54)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>20</str>
    <dex>7</dex>
    <con>22</con>
    <int>7</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages>Druidic</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable>fire</vulnerable>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 30 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>3/Day</recharge>
      <text>The guardian tree can innately cast the goodberry spell, three times per day, requiring no material components.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Branch Slam</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 16 (2d10 + 5) bludgeoning damage and the guardian tree can cause the target to become grappled if its size is Huge or smaller (escape DC 17). Until this grapple ends, the guardian tree can't use its Branch Slam on other targets.</text>
      <attack>Branch Slam|+7|2d10+5</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Root Entanglement (Recharge 5-6)</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>The guardian tree takes root in the ground and causes them to sprout in a 30-foot radius around it. All creatures in the area must succeed on a DC 17 Strength saving throw or be restrained by the entangling roots. A creature restrained by the guardian tree can use its action to make a Strength saving throw. On a success, it frees itself. As long as there is a restrained creature, the guardian tree has its speed reduced to 0, if it moves on its turn the restrained creature is released.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Goodberry</spells>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 224 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Ancient Guardian</name>
    <sortname>Guardian, Ancient</sortname>
    <ancestry>Guardian Sprout</ancestry>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>Plant</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>16 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>121 (9d12+63)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>22</str>
    <dex>7</dex>
    <con>24</con>
    <int>7</int>
    <wis>16</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Druidic</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <vulnerable>fire</vulnerable>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 30 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <recharge>3/Day</recharge>
      <text>The ancient guardian can innately cast the goodberry, three times per day, requiring no material components.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The ancient guardian can make two Branch Slam attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Branch Slam</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 17 (2d10 + 6) bludgeoning damage and the ancient guardian can cause the target to become grappled if its size is Huge or smaller (escape DC 20). The ancient guardian can grapple up to two creatures simultaneously, and while it is grappling two creatures it can't use its Branch Slam attack against creatures other than the grappled ones until it releases one of them.</text>
      <attack>Branch Slam|+9|2d10+6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Root Entanglement (Recharge 5-6)</name>
      <recharge>D5</recharge>
      <text>The ancient guardian takes root in the ground and causes them to sprout in a 30-foot radius around it. All creatures in the area must succeed on a DC 20 Strength saving throw or be restrained by the entangling roots. A creature restrained by the ancient guardian can use its action to make a Strength saving throw. On a success, it frees itself. As long as there is a restrained creature, the ancient guardian has its speed reduced to 0, if it moves on its turn the restrained creature is released.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Goodberry</spells>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 224 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Sloth Invocation</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Aberration</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>12</ac>
    <hp>5</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Class</name>
      <text> 12 + 1 for each 2 sorcerer levels</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5x sorcerer level</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aura of Laziness (15 ft)</name>
      <text>Any creature that enters or starts its turn in the aura must make a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, its speed is halved for the next minute. An affected creature that leaves the aura can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The sloth invocation makes a number of attacks equal to your proficiency bonus.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: sloth invocation STR modifier (4) + your proficiency bonus, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d10 + 4 + your proficiency bonus piercing damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
      <attack>Bite||1d10+1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 250 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Gluttony Invocation</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Aberration</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>10</ac>
    <hp>5</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Class</name>
      <text> 10 + 1 for each 2 sorcerer levels</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5x sorcerer level</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Blood Frenzy</name>
      <text>The gluttony invocation has advantage on melee attack rolls against creatures that don't have all hit points.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The gluttony invocation makes a number of attacks equal to your proficiency bonus.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: sluttony invocation STR modifier (4) + your proficiency bonus, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d10 + 4 + your proficiency bonus piercing damage. The Gluttony Invocation gains half of damage in temporary hit points. If the target is a living creature it must succeed on a DC 12 Wisdom saving throw or be cursed. A cursed creature has disadvantage on attack rolls until eating during a short or long rest, being targeted by a remove curse spell, or eating a berry created by a goodberry spell.</text>
      <attack>Bite||1d10+4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 251 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Envy Invocation</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Aberration</type>
    <alignment>Neutral Evil</alignment>
    <ac>10</ac>
    <hp>5</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>18</dex>
    <con>15</con>
    <int>14</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>psychic</immune>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Armor Class</name>
      <text> 10 + 1 for each 2 sorcerer levels</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hit Points</name>
      <text>5x sorcerer level</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Pack Tactics</name>
      <text>The envy invocation has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of its allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn't incapacitated.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The envy invocation makes a number of attacks equal to your proficiency bonus.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Resentment Blast</name>
      <text>Ranged Spell Attack: Envy Invocation DEX modifier (4) + your proficiency bonus, range 60 ft., one target. Hit: 1d8 + 4 + your proficiency bonus psychic damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
      <attack>Bite||1d8+4+%8</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 251 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tanarean Pegasus</name>
    <ancestry>Pegasus</ancestry>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>Celestial</type>
    <alignment>Good</alignment>
    <ac>12</ac>
    <hp>66 (7d8+28)</hp>
    <speed>60 ft., fly 90 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Perception +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr/>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune>radiant</immune>
    <conditionImmune>charmed, exhaustion, frightened</conditionImmune>
    <senses/>
    <action>
      <name>Hooves</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Hooves|+6|2d6+4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The tanarean pegasus is a stunning creature, known for its striking beauty and natural grace. This breed of pegasus boasts an impressive wingspan of up to 20 feet, making it a highly coveted mount for those seeking swift transportation and superior strength. However, training and handling this creature can present unique challenges. The tanarean pegasus lacks the intelligence of its regular pegasus counterpart, making it skittish and difficult to gain trust and obedience from. These instincts of self-preservation and tendency to flee can make the training process longer and more complicated.

To train a tanarean pegasus successfully, a trainer must create a secure and comfortable environment, introduce it to other trained mounts to develop socialization skills, and establish trust through consistent, patient handling and training. Despite these challenges, the tanarean pegasus is a valuable asset in Tanares, with its beauty, strength, and speed making it a worthy mount for those willing to put in the effort to train it.

Cost to training and Flying Points:
Base: 6 Flying Points
Monthly Cost | Extra Flying Points
20 gp | +1d6
50 gp | +2d6
80 gp | +3d6
120 gp | +4d6

Flying Maneuvers:

Rescue (2 FP). You can save an ally from falling. Use your reaction to fly to an ally that is falling within your flying range and hold them in the air. Apply only if another flying mounted enemy caused the falling.

Dive (2 FP). Using your mount's flight superiority, you quickly get out of the way of danger. You can take a reaction when you succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against an effect from another flying mounted enemy that would cause you to take half damage, such as fireball, to take no damage from the effect.

Flight Tenacity (4 FP). You know the dangerous movements of mounted enemies that would make you fall from the griffon. Whenever you or your mount would begin to fall due to an effect caused by a flying-mounted enemy, you can use this maneuver as a reaction to prevent the fall, considering a failed saving throw or ability check, if any, as a success.

Aerial Sprint (2 FP). The pegasus' instinct takes over and it charges against the mounted creature. As a bonus action, the mount gains extra flying speed for the current turn. The increase equals twice its flying speed (after applying any modifiers), but the mount must move toward a target flying-mounted enemy.

Inspiring Flying (3 FP). All allies gain 2 Flying Points. The mount regains this use after finishing a short or long rest.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 296 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tanarean Griffon</name>
    <ancestry>Griffon</ancestry>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>Monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>12</ac>
    <hp>59 (7d10+21)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft., fly 80 ft.</speed>
    <str/>
    <dex/>
    <con/>
    <int/>
    <wis/>
    <cha/>
    <save/>
    <skill>Perception +5</skill>
    <passive>15</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>2</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Sight</name>
      <text>Keen Sight: The griffon has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The griffon makes two attacks: one with its beak and one with its claws.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Beak</name>
      <text>Beak: Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8 + 4) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Beak|+6|1d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Claws: Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claws|+6|2d6+4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The tanarean griffon is a fearsome creature with the powerful body of a lion and the majestic wings and head of an eagle. With a more muscular body than a regular griffon, it is a formidable opponent in combat. Though the tanarean griffon lacks intelligence and magical abilities, it more than makes up for it with its ferocity and strength. This makes it a difficult creature to train and control, requiring a patient and skilled trainer to gain its trust and loyalty.

The tanarean griffon can be unpredictable and aggressive, with a tendency to assert dominance over weaker foes. To successfully train one, a trainer must establish their own dominance and earn the griffon's respect through consistent handling and training. Providing a secure and comfortable environment is crucial to developing the creature's trust and obedience. Despite its challenges, the tanarean griffon is a powerful and imposing creature that can serve as a mount or companion for those who are willing to put in the effort to train it.

Cost to training and Flying Points:
Base: 6 Flying Points
Monthly Cost | Extra Flying Points
25 gp | +1d6
60 gp | +2d6
90 gp | +3d6
130 gp | +4d6

Flying Maneuvers:

Flight Destabilization (3 FP). A powerfull bull rush that can unbalance flying mounted enemies. As an attack, you try to destabilize the target's flight. The target must make a Dexterity or Strength saving throw with DC = 8 + griffon's Strength modifier + proficiency bonus. If it fails, it plummets towards the ground.

Winged Resilience (3 FP). The griffon's agility can be very effective against flying mounted enemies. Spend Flying Points to reduce the damage inflicted by a flying mounted enemy's attack by 12 points.

Flight Tenacity (4 FP). You know the dangerous movements of mounted enemies that would make you fall from the griffon. Whenever you or your mount would begin to fall due to an effect caused by a flying-mounted enemy, you can use this maneuver as a reaction to prevent the fall, considering a failed saving throw or ability check, if any, as a success.

Aerial Sprint (2 FP). The griffon' instinct takes over and it charges against a target flying mounted enemy. As a bonus action, the mount gains extra flying speed for the current turn. The increase equals twice its flying speed (after applying any modifiers), but the mount must move toward a target flying-mounted enemy.

Fearsome Claws (3FP). Three enemies lose 2 Flying Points. The mount regains this use after finishing a short or long rest.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 297 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tanarean Hippogriff</name>
    <ancestry>Hippogriff</ancestry>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>Monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>11</ac>
    <hp>19 (3d10+3)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft., fly 60 ft.</speed>
    <str>17</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>13</con>
    <int>2</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>8</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Perception +5</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>1</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Sight</name>
      <text>The hippogriff has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Flyby</name>
      <text>The hippogriff doesn't provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy's reach.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The hippogriff makes two attacks: one with its beak and one with its claws.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Beak</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d10 + 3) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Beak|+5|1d10+3</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claws</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claws|+5|2d6+3</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The tanarean hippogriff is a majestic creature with the body of a horse and the head and wings of an eagle. Like its regular hippogriff counterpart, it can grow up to 10 feet in length and possesses incredible speed and agility. However, the tanarean hippogriff lacks intelligence, making it challenging to train and control. It can be skittish and easily frightened, requiring a patient and skilled trainer to gain its trust and obedience.

To train a tanarean hippogriff successfully, a trainer must create a safe and comfortable environment and introduce the hippogriff to other trained mounts to develop socialization skills. The trainer must also establish trust through consistent handling and training. Despite its challenges, the tanarean hippogriff is a valuable and sought-after creature, prized for its speed, agility, and even beauty.

Cost to training and Flying Points:
Base: 4 Flying Points
Monthly cost | Extra Flying Points
15 gp +1d4
30 gp +2d4
50 gp +3d4
75 gp +4d4

Flying Maneuvers:

Flight Destabilization (3 FP). A powerfull bull rush that can unbalance flying mounted enemies. As an attack, you try to destabilize the target's flight. The target must make a Dexterity or Strength saving throw with DC = 8 + hippogriff 's Strength modifier + proficiency bonus. If it fails, it plummets towards the ground.

Rescue (2 FP). Observing the movement of the mounted enemy, you can save your ally from the falling. Use your reaction to fly to an ally that falls within your flying range and hold them in the air. Apply only it another mounted creature caused the falling.

Winged Resilience (3 FP). The griffon's claws can be very effective against flying mounted enemies. Spend Flying Points to reduce the damage inflicted by a flying mounted enemy's attack by 12 points.

Forced Landing (1 FP). When a flying mounted enemy makes your mount fall, you can use this maneuver to land safely on the ground without suffering any damage from falling. Your mount can take to the air again on your next turn.

Inner Strenght (3 FP). As a bonus action, you allow a creature to immediately use its reaction to make a maneuver using Flying Points, but with the cost reduced by 2. The mount regains this use after finising a short or long rest.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 298 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tanarean Desert Drake</name>
    <sortname>Tanarean Drake, Desert</sortname>
    <ancestry>Drake</ancestry>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>Dragon</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>45 (6d10+12)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft., burrow 30 ft., fly 60 ft.</speed>
    <str>15</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>13</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Perception +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>2</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>necrotic</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Assault</name>
      <text>If the desert drake moves at least 15 feet before it hits with a Bite attack on the same turn, the target takes an extra 4 (1d8) additional piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Assault||1d8</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Wild Accuracy</name>
      <text>For each other desert drake within 30 feet, this drake receives +1 on attack rolls (max +5).</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d10 + 2) piercing damage plus 7 (2d6) necrotic damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+4|1d10+2</attack>
      <attack>Necrotic||2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Necrotic Breath (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
      <recharge>SHORT</recharge>
      <text>The desert drake exhales necrotic energy in a 30-foot cone. Each creature in that area must take a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw, taking 21 (6d6) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
      <attack>Necrotic Breath||6d6</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The drake is a formidable creature that strikes fear into the hearts of many adventurers. With its muscular body, sharp claws, and fiery breath, it is a formidable opponent in combat. The drake is a solitary beast that does not form bonds with others. This makes it difficult to train and control, as it will only obey those it is intimidated by. The drake is also intelligent and can be difficult to outsmart, requiring a trainer with considerable skill and experience. To gain dominance over a drake, a trainer must establish authority and maintain a constant level of intimidation. While firm vocalization and daunting body language are usually sufficient, drakes occasionally try to engage in fights to demonstrate physical superiority. Therefore, it will sometimes be necessary to resort to physical intimidation with them, but it must be administered carefully to avoid triggering a worse violent response. Once the drake has been subdued, it can be trained in a variety of techniques, such as hunting and aerial combat exercises.

Drakes are carnivorous creatures that feed on a variety of prey, such as mammals and other creatures of the sky. Their diet is essential to maintaining their physical strength and agility. Training a Drake is a dangerous and difficult task, but those who are able to successfully train one will have a loyal and powerful companion that will serve them well in any adventure.

Cost to training and Flying Points
Base: 8 Flying Points
Monthly cost | Extra Flying Points
50 gp | +1d8
120 gp | +2d8
250 gp | +3d8
500 gp | +4d8

Flying Maneuvers:
Winged Resilience (3 FP). The drake's tough scales are highly effective against mounted enemies in the air. Spend Flying Points to reduce the damage inflicted by a flying mounted enemy's attack by 12 points.

Flight Destabilization (3 FP). A powerful bull rush that can unbalance even the most skilled flying mounted enemies.

As an attack, you to try to destabilize the target's flight. The target must make a Dexterity or Strength saving throw with DC = 8 + drake's Strength modifier + proficiency bonus. If it fails, it plummets towards the ground.

Flight Blindness (4 FP). This powerful maneuver weakens the connection between a flying mount and its rider. It generates a powerful wave that interferes with their flight, preventing the mounted enemy from using any Flying Points until the start of your next turn. The only way to avoid this effect is to spend 6 Flying Points.

Forced Landing (1 FP). When a flying mounted enemy makes your mount fall, you can use this maneuver to land safely on the ground without suffering any damage from falling. Your mount can take to the air again on your next turn.

Final Breath (5 FP). The Drake's fiery breath is a fearsome weapon against flying mounted enemies. When you use it, you can also utilize any of your Flying Maneuvers at no cost against one of the targets the breath is aimed at. The drake this use after finishing a short or long rest.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 299 (Homebrew),
		Tanares Sourcebook p. 306 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tanarean Jungle Drake</name>
    <sortname>Tanarean Drake, Jungle</sortname>
    <ancestry>Drake</ancestry>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>Dragon</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>59 (7d10+21)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft., climb 30 ft., fly 60 ft.</speed>
    <str>19</str>
    <dex>11</dex>
    <con>17</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>11</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Perception +2</skill>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>acid</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Spiked Body</name>
      <text>A creature that touches the jungle drake or hits it with a melee attack while within 5 feet of it takes 5 (1d10) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Spiked Body||1d10</attack>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Wild Strength</name>
      <text>For each other jungle drake within 30 feet, this drake receives +1 to damage rolls of its attacks (max +5).</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The jungle drake makes three melee attacks, one with its Bite and two with Claws.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d10 + 4) piercing damage plus 3 (1d6) acid damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+6|1d10+4</attack>
      <attack>Acid||1d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Claw</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8 + 4) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Claw|+6|1d8+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Acid Breath (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
      <recharge>SHORT</recharge>
      <text>The jungle drake exhales acid in a 45-foot line. Each creature in that line must make a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw, taking 28 (8d6) acid damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
      <attack>Acid Breath||8d6</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The drake is a formidable creature that strikes fear into the hearts of many adventurers. With its muscular body, sharp claws, and fiery breath, it is a formidable opponent in combat. The drake is a solitary beast that does not form bonds with others. This makes it difficult to train and control, as it will only obey those it is intimidated by. The drake is also intelligent and can be difficult to outsmart, requiring a trainer with considerable skill and experience. To gain dominance over a drake, a trainer must establish authority and maintain a constant level of intimidation. While firm vocalization and daunting body language are usually sufficient, drakes occasionally try to engage in fights to demonstrate physical superiority. Therefore, it will sometimes be necessary to resort to physical intimidation with them, but it must be administered carefully to avoid triggering a worse violent response. Once the drake has been subdued, it can be trained in a variety of techniques, such as hunting and aerial combat exercises.

Drakes are carnivorous creatures that feed on a variety of prey, such as mammals and other creatures of the sky. Their diet is essential to maintaining their physical strength and agility. Training a Drake is a dangerous and difficult task, but those who are able to successfully train one will have a loyal and powerful companion that will serve them well in any adventure.

Cost to training and Flying Points
Base: 8 Flying Points
Monthly cost | Extra Flying Points
50 gp | +1d8
120 gp | +2d8
250 gp | +3d8
500 gp | +4d8

Flying Maneuvers:
Winged Resilience (3 FP). The drake's tough scales are highly effective against mounted enemies in the air. Spend Flying Points to reduce the damage inflicted by a flying mounted enemy's attack by 12 points.

Flight Destabilization (3 FP). A powerful bull rush that can unbalance even the most skilled flying mounted enemies.

As an attack, you to try to destabilize the target's flight. The target must make a Dexterity or Strength saving throw with DC = 8 + drake's Strength modifier + proficiency bonus. If it fails, it plummets towards the ground.

Flight Blindness (4 FP). This powerful maneuver weakens the connection between a flying mount and its rider. It generates a powerful wave that interferes with their flight, preventing the mounted enemy from using any Flying Points until the start of your next turn. The only way to avoid this effect is to spend 6 Flying Points.

Forced Landing (1 FP). When a flying mounted enemy makes your mount fall, you can use this maneuver to land safely on the ground without suffering any damage from falling. Your mount can take to the air again on your next turn.

Final Breath (5 FP). The Drake's fiery breath is a fearsome weapon against flying mounted enemies. When you use it, you can also utilize any of your Flying Maneuvers at no cost against one of the targets the breath is aimed at. The drake this use after finishing a short or long rest.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 299 (Homebrew),
		Tanares Sourcebook p. 307 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tanarean Ridge Drake</name>
    <sortname>Tanarean Drake, Ridge</sortname>
    <ancestry>Drake</ancestry>
    <size>L</size>
    <type>Dragon</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>52 (7d10+14)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft., burrow 30 ft., fly 60 ft.</speed>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>16</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Perception +4</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages/>
    <cr>3</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist>cold</resist>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
      <name>Wild Reflexes</name>
      <text>For each other ridge drake within 30 feet., this drake receives +1 to its AC (max +5).</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (2d10 + 2) piercing damage plus 3 (1d6) cold damage.</text>
      <attack>Bite|+4|2d10+2</attack>
      <attack>Cold||1d6</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Cold Breath (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
      <recharge>SHORT</recharge>
      <text>The ridge drake exhales an icy blast in a 30-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 12 Constitution saving throw, taking 27 (5d10) cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
      <attack>Cold Breath||5d10</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The drake is a formidable creature that strikes fear into the hearts of many adventurers. With its muscular body, sharp claws, and fiery breath, it is a formidable opponent in combat. The drake is a solitary beast that does not form bonds with others. This makes it difficult to train and control, as it will only obey those it is intimidated by. The drake is also intelligent and can be difficult to outsmart, requiring a trainer with considerable skill and experience. To gain dominance over a drake, a trainer must establish authority and maintain a constant level of intimidation. While firm vocalization and daunting body language are usually sufficient, drakes occasionally try to engage in fights to demonstrate physical superiority. Therefore, it will sometimes be necessary to resort to physical intimidation with them, but it must be administered carefully to avoid triggering a worse violent response. Once the drake has been subdued, it can be trained in a variety of techniques, such as hunting and aerial combat exercises.

Drakes are carnivorous creatures that feed on a variety of prey, such as mammals and other creatures of the sky. Their diet is essential to maintaining their physical strength and agility. Training a Drake is a dangerous and difficult task, but those who are able to successfully train one will have a loyal and powerful companion that will serve them well in any adventure.

Cost to training and Flying Points
Base: 8 Flying Points
Monthly cost | Extra Flying Points
50 gp | +1d8
120 gp | +2d8
250 gp | +3d8
500 gp | +4d8

Flying Maneuvers:
Winged Resilience (3 FP). The drake's tough scales are highly effective against mounted enemies in the air. Spend Flying Points to reduce the damage inflicted by a flying mounted enemy's attack by 12 points.

Flight Destabilization (3 FP). A powerful bull rush that can unbalance even the most skilled flying mounted enemies.

As an attack, you to try to destabilize the target's flight. The target must make a Dexterity or Strength saving throw with DC = 8 + drake's Strength modifier + proficiency bonus. If it fails, it plummets towards the ground.

Flight Blindness (4 FP). This powerful maneuver weakens the connection between a flying mount and its rider. It generates a powerful wave that interferes with their flight, preventing the mounted enemy from using any Flying Points until the start of your next turn. The only way to avoid this effect is to spend 6 Flying Points.

Forced Landing (1 FP). When a flying mounted enemy makes your mount fall, you can use this maneuver to land safely on the ground without suffering any damage from falling. Your mount can take to the air again on your next turn.

Final Breath (5 FP). The Drake's fiery breath is a fearsome weapon against flying mounted enemies. When you use it, you can also utilize any of your Flying Maneuvers at no cost against one of the targets the breath is aimed at. The drake this use after finishing a short or long rest.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 299 (Homebrew),
		Tanares Sourcebook p. 307 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Butler</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>10</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Insight +3, Perception +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <action>
      <name>Dagger</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Dagger|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The butler is the mainstay of your operation, responsible for maintaining the Headquarters with cleaning, organization, and caretaking services. Additionally, they provide support to the Adventure Team, acting as a receptionist for visitors and facilitating communication between the team and the rest of the Headquarters. By ensuring everything runs smoothly, the butler allows the Adventure Team to focus on their heroic pursuits.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 304 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Arcane Scholar</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>10</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Arcana +3, Religion +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Ritualistic</name>
      <text>When inside an Arcane Library of the Headquarters, the arcane scholar can cast 1st and 2nd level spells as rituals, provided that they have the ritual tag and the arcane scholar has a spellbook containing the spell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>Arcane scholar's spellcasting ability is Intelligence (spell save DC 11). The arcane scholar knows the following spells:

	• Cantrips (at will): mage hand, prestidigitation
	• 1st level (only ritual): detect magic, identify</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Dagger</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Dagger|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>Mage Hand, Prestidigitation, Detect Magic, Identify</spells>
    <description>The library is not just a collection of books and artifacts. It is also home to the arcane scholar, a dedicated staff member who compensates for their lack of combat ability with their vast knowledge of magic. Assigned to the Arcane Library, the arcane scholar is able to identify magic items, obtain components, and perform rituals, thus enhancing the library's capabilities and the Adventure Team's magical knowledge.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 305 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Breeder</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>11</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Animal Handling +3, Nature +2</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The breeder's spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 11). It can innately cast the following spells, requiring no material components:

	• 1/Day: animal friendship</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Dagger</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4 +1) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Dagger|+3|1d4+1</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Whip</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4 + 1) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Whip|+3|1d4+1</attack>
    </action>
    <spells>Mage Hand, Prestidigitation, Detect Magic, Identify</spells>
    <description>With the aid of a skilled breeder, the stable staff, the Stables can not only provide care and training for the mounts but also produce offspring that can be sold for significant amounts of gold. The breeder possesses great empathy when dealing with animals and can even tame ever more powerful creatures as they gain experience.

To utilize the services of the breeder, the Stable structure is required. Whether it's a quick rest or a longer stay, the Stable is the perfect place to keep your mounts safe and well taken care of while adventuring in the dangerous lands of Tanares.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 306 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Craftsman</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>14 (chain shirt)</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Athletics +2</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Profession (Crafter)</name>
      <text>The craftsman adds their proficiency bonus (+2) when using a tool (not supplies, kits or utensils) from the artisan's tools.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Light hammer</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Light hammer|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The craftsman is a skilled artisan who dedicates their callused hands and sweat-stained clothing to producing high-quality items and equipment from diverse materials. Their passion for their craft is only matched by their expertise, and they thrive in the Workshop's creative environment. They not only produce masterpieces but also generate value for the Adventure Team by selling their creations, making the Workshop an indispensable resource.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 307 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Tavern Keeper</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>11 (leather armor)</ac>
    <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>12</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Insight +2, Persuasion +3</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any two languages</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Profession (Chef)</name>
      <text>The tavern keeper adds their proficiency (+2) when using brewer's supplies or cook's utensils.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Club</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Club|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The tavern keeper is the staff member in charge of the Tavern's operation, from serving customers to managing inventory and finances. With their expertise, they know how to handle unruly patrons and entice new customers with alluring deals. As the tavern's profits grow, the tavern keeper's skills develop, and they can increase the establishment's earnings and make it a truly profitable venture for the Adventure Team.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 308 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Doctor</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>10 (leather armor)</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save>Wis +3</save>
    <skill>Medicine +3, Nature +3</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Innate Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The doctor's spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 11). It can innately cast the following spells, requiring no material components:

	• at will: light, spare the dying</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Treatment (1/Day)</name>
      <recharge>1/Day</recharge>
      <text>Creatures that take a short rest under the care of the doctor recover the maximum amount of hit points from the Hit Dice they spend during the rest. The doctor can treat up to 4 creatures at the same time with this ability.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Club</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage</text>
      <attack>Club|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>First Aid (10/Day)</name>
      <recharge>10/Day</recharge>
      <text>The doctor performs first aid on a humanoid creature that is not dead and has 0 hit points, restoring 1 hit point to it.</text>
    </action>
    <spells>Light, Spare the Dying</spells>
    <description>The doctor is a skilled healer who oversees the Healing Hall and tends to the injured and sick members of the team. Their expertise in medicine and healing magic is invaluable in restoring hit points to the PCs, ensuring they are ready for their next adventure. With each upgrade to the Healing Hall, the doctor gains access to more advanced medical tools and supplies, allowing them to better care for those in need.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 309 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Wayfinder</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>10</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save>Int +1</save>
    <skill>Nature +1, Survival +1</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any two languages</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Profession (Mapper)</name>
      <text>The wayfinder adds their proficiency (+2) when using calligrapher's supplies, cartographer's tools, or navigator's tools.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Log Mind</name>
      <text>The wayfinder always knows the direction of north and the time of day</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Quarterstaff</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d6) bludgeoning damage, 4 (1d8) bludgeoning damage if wielded with two hands.</text>
      <attack>Quarterstaff|+2|1d6</attack>
      <attack>Quarterstaff (Two-Handed)|+2|1d8</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The wayfinder is a learned scholar who possesses knowledge of celestial bodies, space, and the land and its terrain, aiding the Adventure Team in their journeys. With expertise in astronomy and cartography, the wayfinder creates precise maps of the land and cosmos, predicts the alignment of stars, and performs magical feats to help the group navigate. As they continue to hone their skills, the wayfinder becomes an invaluable member of the Adventure Team, unlocking the secrets of the world around them.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 310 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Head Guard</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>16 (chain mail armor)</ac>
    <hp>16 (3d8+3)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>12</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save>Str +1</save>
    <skill>Athletics +3, Intimidation +2</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>1/4</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Brave</name>
      <text>The head guard has advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Longsword</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d8 + 1) slashing damage.</text>
      <attack>Longsword|+3|1d8+1</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The head guard is the master of military defense for the Headquarters. With their vast knowledge of combat strategies, both in open fields and siege tactics, they ensure an unrivaled shield for the fortress. Their experience in training and leading soldiers is crucial for the recruitment and management of a strong defense force, ready to repel any threat to the Headquarters.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 311 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Farmer</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>11 (leather armor)</ac>
    <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Animal Handling +3, Nature +2</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Vitality</name>
      <text>The farmer has advantage on saving throws against exhaustion.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Club</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Club|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The farmer is a seasoned expert in the art of cultivation and livestock management. With a keen sense of the land and its natural rhythms, they bring forth bountiful harvests and raise healthy livestock. Their expertise in managing the Farm ensures that the crops and animals continue to flourish and produce, providing an abundance of food and resources to support the community and the Adventure Team.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 312 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Curator</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>10</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>History +5, Perception +3, Religion +3</skill>
    <passive>13</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any three languages</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Connoisseur</name>
      <text>The curator has advantage on any ability check to determine whether an archaeological or art piece is legitimate or imitation.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Dagger</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Dagger|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>Behind thick glasses and with one or two thick books always at their waist, the curator is the guardian of the Museum's vast collection. Responsible for guiding visitors through the halls and showcasing the Adventure Team's latest discoveries, they are also charged with studying ancient tomes to aid the group in their quest for precious artifacts. With an unwavering dedication to the protection of the Museum's treasures, the curator ensures that the Headquarters remains a place of knowledge for all adventurers.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 313 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Harbor Master</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>11 (leather armor)</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>12</cha>
    <save>Cha +3</save>
    <skill>Athletics +2, Deception +3, Persuasion +3</skill>
    <passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common, plus any two languages</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Coast-born</name>
      <text>The harbor master has advantage on Strength (Athletics) checks related to swimming.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Dagger</name>
      <text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) piercing damage.</text>
      <attack>Dagger|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>With a clipboard in hand, the harbor master oversees all arrivals and departures from the endless sea, ensuring a smooth operation of the Pier. Their management skills allow the Adventure Team to control larger vessels and increase their profits over time. The harbor master also spreads the word about the team's accomplishments to the taverns of the harbor district, earning them a reputation as successful traders and explorers.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 314 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Herbalist</name>
    <ancestry>Commoner</ancestry>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>11 (leather armor)</ac>
    <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>10</str>
    <dex>10</dex>
    <con>10</con>
    <int>12</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill>Nature +3, Survival +3</skill>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Common, Sylvan, plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Profession (Herbalist)</name>
      <text>The herbalist adds their proficiency bonus (+2) when using a herbalism kit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speak with Plants</name>
      <text>The herbalist can communicate with plants as if they shared a language.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Club</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
      <attack>Club|+2|1d4</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The herbalist is a skilled cultivator and alchemist, able to nurture and extract the purest potion or the most nefarious poison from the natural treasures of various regions. Their ability to cultivate and care for the plants in the Garden ensures that each vial is filled with a much stronger compound than usual, at a lower cost than standard. With an advanced herbalist, the Garden can produce rare and potent ingredients that can be used to create powerful magic items.

Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 315 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Heroic Staff</name>
    <npc>YES</npc>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Humanoid (Any Species)</type>
    <alignment>Any Alignment</alignment>
    <ac>19 (splint armor, shield)</ac>
    <hp>85 (10d8+40)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>18</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
    <save>Str +7, Con +7</save>
    <skill>Animal Handling +4, Athletics +7, , Intimidation +3, Perception +4</skill>
    <passive>14</passive>
    <languages>Common plus any one language</languages>
    <cr>5</cr>
    <vulnerable/>
    <resist/>
    <immune/>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses/>
    <trait>
      <name>Proficiency Bonus</name>
      <text>+3</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Brave</name>
      <text>The heroic staff has advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Determination</name>
      <text>A melee weapon deals one extra die of its damage when the heroic staff hits with it (included in the attack).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Training</name>
      <text>The Heroic Staff retains all previous abilities and proficiencies it had.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Multiattack</name>
      <text>The heroic staff makes three melee attacks.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Longsword</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (2d8 + 4) slashing damage. Versatility: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 15 (2d10 + 4) slashing damage</text>
      <attack>Longsword|+7|2d8+4</attack>
      <attack>Longsword (Two-Handed)|+7|2d10+4</attack>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Shield Bash</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (2d4 + 4) bludgeoning damage. If the target is a Medium or smaller creature, it must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
      <attack>Shield Bash|+7|2d4+4</attack>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Block</name>
      <text>The heroic staff gains a +3 bonus to Dexterity saving throws imposed by spells or area effects. To do so, the heroic staff must see the attacker or origin of effect and must be wielding a shield.</text>
    </reaction>
    <reaction>
      <name>Parry</name>
      <text>The heroic staff adds 3 to its AC against one melee attack that would hit it. To do so, the heroic staff must see the attacker and be wielding a melee weapon.</text>
    </reaction>
    <description>Source:	Player's Guide to Tanares p. 317 (Homebrew)</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
</compendium>
