<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Kenku [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Long ago, the Kenku soared the skies, their wings carrying them across vast landscapes while their voices wove enchanting songs. But their hubris angered a powerful being, who struck them with a terrible curse—stealing their wings and warping their voices. Now, while Kenku can still speak clearly, most instinctively communicate through mimicry, repeating the voices and sounds they have heard throughout their lives.
	Living in the shadows, many Kenku seek to undo the curse that plagues their species, while others search for magic or inventions that might one day return them to the sky. Clever and resourceful, they use their talents to survive in a world that often sees them as little more than remnants of a forgotten past.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Monstrosity</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>two skills of your choice (Stealth and Performance are recommended)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Languages</name>
      <text>Primordial (Auran)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Expert Duplication</name>
      <text>You have an uncanny ability to replicate craftsmanship. You gain the Crafter feat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Kenku Recall</name>
      <text>You have the ability to recall details with remarkable clarity.

	• Recall Lore. When you make an Intelligence check to recall information, you can give yourself advantage on the roll. You can do this a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

	• Practiced Hand. Once per day, when you make a skill check with one of the two skills you chose when making your Kenku, you can give yourself expertise in that skill for that roll (adding twice your proficiency bonus).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Mimicry</name>
      <text>You can mimic sounds and voices you have heard. A creature that hears the sounds you make can tell they are imitations with a Wisdom (Insight) check against your passive Deception (10 + your deception modifier).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Cursed</name>
      <text>Because you already live with a life-altering curse, you have advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the effects of other Curses.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
