<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Sorcerer [2024]</name>
    <!-- Sorcerous Origin: Shadow Sorcery (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerous Origin: Shadow Sorcery (UA)</name>
        <text>Bend Darkness and Doom to Your Will

Your innate magic comes from the Shadowfell itself. You might trace your lineage to an entity from that place, or perhaps you were exposed to the Shadowfell's sinister energy and were transformed by it. Your shadowy magic allows you to command darkness, undeath, and woe with ease.

Design Note: Shadow Sorcery Updates:
Here are the main updates in this subclass since its appearance in Xanathar's Guide to Everything:

	• Eyes of the Dark now also grants you Blindsight and the ability to see through the Darkness of any spell you cast.

	• Shadow Spells is a new feature that provides a list of always prepared spells.

	• Spirits of Ill Omen (formerly Hound of Ill Omen) now uses the Summon Undead spell, allowing for more versatility and scaling.

	• Umbral Form now gives you one free use of the form per Long Rest. Strength of the Grave has been improved and moved to the benefits of this form.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Eyes of the Dark (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>You have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet and Blindsight with a range of 10 feet.
	In addition, if a spell you cast creates an area of Darkness, you can see normally through that spell's Darkness.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Shadow Spells (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Sorcerer level specified in the Shadow Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Shadow Spells:
Sorcerer Level | Spells
3 | Bane, Darkness, Inflict Wounds, Pass without Trace
5 | Hunger of Hadar, Summon Undead
7 | Greater Invisibility, Phantasmal Killer
9 | Contagion, Creation

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Spirits of Ill Omen (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>You can cast Summon Undead without a Material component. You can also cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in this way when you finish a Long Rest.
	Whenever you start casting the spell, you can modify it so that it doesn't require Concentration. If you do so, the spell's duration becomes 1 minute for that casting, and the spell ends early if you cast it again.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Shadow Walk (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>While you are in Dim Light or Darkness, you can take a Bonus Action to teleport up to 120 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in Dim Light or Darkness.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 18: Umbral Form (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you adopt a shadowy form, gaining the benefits below for 1 minute, until you have the Incapacitated condition, or until you end the form (no action required). Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest unless you spend 6 Sorcery Points (no action required) to restore your use of it.

Incorporeal Movement. You can move through occupied spaces as if they were Difficult Terrain. If you end your turn in such a space, you take 1d10 Force damage.

Shadow Resilience. You have Resistance to all damage except Force and Radiant damage.

Strength of the Grave. If you would drop to 0 Hit Points and not die outright, you can make a Charisma saving throw (DC 5 plus half the damage taken). If you succeed, your Hit Points instead change to a number equal to three times your Sorcerer level.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Bane [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Darkness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Inflict Wounds [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Pass without Trace [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hunger of Hadar [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Summon Undead [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Killer [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contagion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Creation [2024]</name>
    <classes>Sorcerer (Shadow Sorcery (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
