<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric [2024]</name>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Grave Domain (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Grave Domain (UA)</name>
        <text>Embody Deific Forces of Death

The Grave Domain concerns itself with the boundary between life and death. To those who tap into this domain's power, death is a foundational, natural, and inevitable part of the multiverse. Such Clerics seek to destroy Undead and strive to shepherd spirits to the afterlife (whether those spirits want to go or not).
	The magic of this domain also allows these Clerics to stave off death for a time, particularly for those who still have some great work to accomplish in the world. But this is merely a delay of death, not a denial of it, for the grave will always claim its due.

Design Note: Grave Domain Updates
Here are the main updates in this subclass since its appearance in Xanathar's Guide to Everything:

	• Circle of Mortality now also grants you a small damage boost against Bloodied creatures.

	• Grave Domain Spells has been updated to include more versatility and combat-relevant spells.

	• Path to the Grave now produces an ongoing curse effect in addition to boosting the damage of an attack.

	• Sentinel at Death's Door now can trigger on any attack, not just Critical Hits.

	• Divine Reaper is a new feature that absorbs the previous benefits of Keeper of Souls and provides a boost to the Cleric's Necromancy spells.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 4</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Circle of Mortality (Grave Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the ability to manipulate the balance between life and death, granting you the following benefits.

Pull of Death. Once per turn, when you cast a spell or hit with an attack roll and deal damage to a Bloodied creature, that creature takes an extra 1d4 Necrotic damage.

Return to Life. When you would normally roll one or more dice to restore Hit Points to a creature at 0 Hit Points with a spell or Channel Divinity, don't roll those dice for the healing; instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d4 Hit Points to a creature at 0 Hit Points with a spell, you restore 8.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 4</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Heal">2d4</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Grave Domain Spells (Grave Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the Grave Domain Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Grave Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
3 | Bane, Chill Touch, Detect Evil and Good, Gentle Repose, Ray of Enfeeblement
5 | Revivify, Vampiric Touch
7 | Blight, Dispel Evil and Good
9 | Hold Monster, Raise Dead

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 4</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Path To the Grave (Grave Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you present your Holy Symbol and expend a use of your Channel Divinity to curse one creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself until the start of your next turn. While cursed, the creature has Disadvantage on attack rolls and saving throws.
	When you or an ally you can see hits the cursed target with an attack roll, you can end the curse early (no action required) to make the attack deal extra Necrotic or Radiant damage (your choice) equal to 1d8 plus your Cleric level.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 5</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic or Radiant Damage">1d8+%7</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Sentinel At Death's Door (Grave Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>When you or a Bloodied creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself is hit with an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to halve that attack's damage.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Divine Reaper (Grave Domain (UA))</name>
        <text>Your deep connection to this domain renders you a hallowed harbinger of death, granting you the following benefits.

Enhanced Necromancy. When you cast a spell of level 5 or lower from the Necromancy school that targets one creature or a spell from the Grave Domain Spells table, you can expend a use of Channel Divinity to target a second creature within the spell's range. If the spell requires costly or consumed Material components, you must provide Material components for each target.

Keeper of Souls. When an enemy dies within 60 feet of you, you or one creature you can see within 60 feet of yourself regains Hit Points equal to three times your Cleric level. You can't use this feature if you have the Incapacitated condition. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Keeper of Souls</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Grave Domain (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Bane [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Chill Touch [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Evil and Good [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Gentle Repose [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ray of Enfeeblement [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Revivify [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Vampiric Touch [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blight [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Evil and Good [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Monster [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Raise Dead [2024]</name>
    <classes>Cleric [2024] (Grave Domain (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
