<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Rogue [2024]</name>
    <!-- Rogue Subclass: Phantom (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Rogue Subclass: Phantom (UA)</name>
        <text>Embrace Death and Wield Ghostly Power

Some Rogues walk along the veil between life and death, shepherding opponents to the grave and slipping through the world as undetectable as a spirit. In these pursuits, a Rogue might discover a mystical connection to death itself. Such an individual becomes immersed in negative energy, infusing their strikes with deathly energy and stealing knowledge from souls who have passed on. Thieves' guilds value Rogues of this persuasion as highly effective information gatherers and spies.

Design Note: Phantom Updates:
Here are the main updates in this subclass since its appearance in Tasha's Cauldron of Everything:

	• Wails from the Grave now links its number of uses to the Rogue's Dexterity modifier.

	• Tokens of the Departed now provides soul trinkets whenever you finish a Long Rest, allowing more reliable usage of the feature's benefits.

	• Voice of Death is a new feature that allows you to cast Speak with Dead.

	• Death's Friend now lets you gain a soul trinket when you roll Initiative and have no soul trinkets.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Wails From the Grave (Phantom (UA))</name>
        <text>Immediately after you deal your Sneak Attack damage to a creature on your turn, you can target a second creature that you can see within 30 feet of the first creature. Roll half the number of Sneak Attack dice for your level (round up), and the second creature takes Necrotic damage equal to the roll's total as wails of the dead momentarily sound around them.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Dexterity modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Whispers of the Dead (Phantom (UA))</name>
        <text>Whenever you finish a Short or Long Rest, you can choose one skill or tool proficiency that you lack and gain it, as a ghostly presence shares its knowledge with you. You lose this proficiency when you use this benefit again to choose a different proficiency.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Tokens of the Departed (Phantom (UA))</name>
        <text>The spirits of the dead are drawn to you, and echoes of their past lives magically manifest as strange curios with resonant power.
	Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you gain two soul trinkets; each soul trinket is a Tiny object (the DM determines the trinket's form or has you roll on the Trinkets table in the Player's Handbook to generate it). These trinkets last until you finish another Long Rest, at which point they disintegrate.
	If you ever move more than 30 feet from a trinket, the trinket immediately teleports to you, appearing somewhere on your person.
	The number of soul trinkets you gain when you finish a Long Rest increases when you reach Rogue levels 13 (three trinkets) and 17 (four trinkets).

Using Soul Trinkets. You can use soul trinkets in the following ways:

	• Death's Knell. When you deal Sneak Attack damage on your turn, you can expend one soul trinket and immediately use Wails from the Grave without expending a use of that feature. The expended trinket is destroyed.

	• Life Essence. While you have at least one soul trinket, you have Advantage on Death Saving Throws and Constitution saving throws.

	• Spirit Query. You can take a Magic action to expend one soul trinket and immediately cast the Augury spell, requiring no spell components and using Dexterity as the spellcasting modifier. The expended trinket is destroyed.

Regaining Soul Trinkets. When a creature you can see within 30 feet of you dies, you can take a Reaction to regain one expended soul trinket.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Voice of Death (Phantom (UA))</name>
        <text>You can cast Speak with Dead once without a spell slot, requiring no spell components and using Dexterity as the spellcasting modifier. You regain the ability to cast it this way when you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Soul Trinkets</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Phantom (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Voice of Death</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Phantom (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 13: Ghost Walk (Phantom (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you assume a spectral form, gaining the benefits below for 10 minutes or until you end them (no action required). Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest unless you expend and destroy one of your soul trinkets from Tokens of the Departed (no action required) to restore your use of it.

Flight. You gain a Fly Speed of 10 feet and can hover.

Hazy Form. Attack rolls have Disadvantage against you.

Incorporeal Movement. You can move through occupied spaces as if they were Difficult Terrain. If you end your turn in such a space, you take 1d10 Force damage.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Soul Trinkets</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Phantom (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Death's Friend (Phantom (UA))</name>
        <text>Your association with death has become so close that you gain the following benefits.

Death's Lament. When you use your Wails from the Grave feature, you can deal the Necrotic damage to both the first and the second creature.

Draw of Death. When you roll Initiative, you regain one soul trinket for your Tokens of the Departed if you have none remaining.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 7</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Soul Trinkets</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Phantom (UA)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
