<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Ranger [2024]</name>
    <!-- Ranger Subclass: Hollow Warden (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Subclass: Hollow Warden (UA)</name>
        <text>Draw on the Might of Ancient Wild Terrors

Legends tell that the most ancient and fearsome terrors lurk deep within the old places of the earth—unfathomable and bloodthirsty entities of fallow soil and sharpened claws. Hollow Wardens venerate and draw power from such beings, transforming themselves into similarly merciless and monstrous guardians that stalk along jagged coastlines, across steep mountain crags, and through other dark and wild places.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hollow Warden Spells (Hollow Warden (UA))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Ranger level specified in the
Hollow Warden Spells table, you thereafter always
have the listed spell prepared.

Hollow Warden Spells:
Ranger Level | Spells
3 | Wrathful Smite
5 | Spike Growth
9 | Phantom Steed
13 | Hallucinatory Terrain
17 | Awaken

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Wrath of the Wild (Hollow Warden (UA))</name>
        <text>You draw on the strange and ancient horrors of the land for power. When you cast Hunter's Mark, you transform, gaining the following benefits for the duration of the spell.

Ancient Armor. You gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of +1). Your body is wreathed in rotten bark or beastly bristles.

Unnerving Aura. When an enemy starts its turn within a 10-foot Emanation originating from you, it makes a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, it can take either an action or a Bonus Action on this turn, not both. Your shadow lengthens and twists around you, or you sprout unnatural growths like bloody antlers or putrid fangs.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Hungering Might (Hollow Warden (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain a bonus to Constitution saving throws equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of +1).
	In addition, once per turn when you hit a creature with an attack roll while you are transformed using Wrath of the Wild, you regain a number of Hit Points equal to 1d10 plus your Wisdom modifier, provided you are Bloodied when you hit.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Rot And Violence (Hollow Warden (UA))</name>
        <text>Your dedication to eldritch forest beings alters you further. When transformed using Wrath of the Wild, you gain the following additional benefits.

Eerie Aura. When a creature fails its saving throw against your Unnerving Aura, it also takes Necrotic, Poison, or Psychic damage (your choice) equal to your Ranger level. This damage ignores Resistance.

Strangling Roots. When you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon, you can activate the Sap or Slow mastery property in addition to a different mastery property you're using with that weapon.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 5</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Ancient Endurance (Hollow Warden (UA))</name>
        <text>You become wholly suffused with the forest's ancient power, granting you the following benefits.

Persistent Hunt. If you drop to 0 Hit Points while transformed using Wrath of the Wild and don't die outright, you can expend a level 4+ spell slot (no action required). Your Hit Points then instead change to an amount equal to five times the level of the spell slot expended.

Timeless. You have Immunity to the Exhaustion condition.

Source:	UA2024-Horror Subclasses p. 6</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Wrathful Smite [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Hollow Warden (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spike Growth [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Hollow Warden (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantom Steed [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Hollow Warden (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallucinatory Terrain [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Hollow Warden (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Awaken [2024]</name>
    <classes>Ranger [2024] (Hollow Warden (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
