<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <!--race>
    <name>Bugbear (Eberron)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Str 2, Dex 1</ability>
    <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Bugbears rely on stealth and strength to attack, preferring to operate at night. When they're not in battle, bugbears spend much of their time resting or dozing, and bully weaker creatures into doing their bidding. From the viewpoint of the rest of the world, their aggression and savagery are thankfully offset by their rarity and lethargy.

Source: Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 25</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Bugbears reach adulthood at age 16 and live up to 80 years.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Bugbears live on the fringes of society even in Darguun, where they value self-sufficiency and violence. They are generally chaotic, organizing in loose tribes under charismatic and powerful leaders.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Long-Limbed</name>
      <text>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sneaky</name>
      <text>You are proficient in the Stealth skill.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Surprise Attack</name>
      <text>If you surprise a creature and hit it with an attack on your first turn in combat, the attack deals an extra 2d6 damage to it. You can use this trait only once per combat.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Goblin.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race-->
  <race>
    <name>Changeling</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Cha 2</ability>
    <proficiency />
    <spellAbility />
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Changelings can shift their forms with a thought. Many changelings use this gift as a form of artistic and emotional expression. It's also an invaluable tool for grifters, spies, and others who wish to deceive. This leads many people to treat changelings with suspicion.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 17,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 60</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2. In addition, one other ability score of your choice increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Changelings mature slightly faster than humans but share a similar lifespan—typically a century or less. While a changeling can transform to conceal their age, the effects of aging affect them similarly to humans.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Changelings tend toward pragmatic neutrality, and few changelings embrace evil.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>In their natural forms, changelings average between 5 to 6 feet in height, with a slender build. Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shapechanger</name>
      <text>As an action, you can change your appearance and your voice. You determine the specifics of the changes, including your coloration, hair length, and sex. You can also adjust your height and weight, but not so much that your size changes. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You can't duplicate the appearance of a creature you've never seen, and you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs that you have. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this trait.

You stay in the new form until you use an action to revert to your true form or until you die.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Changeling Instincts</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Deception, Insight, Intimidation, and Persuasion.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and two other languages of your choice.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Goblin</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dex 2, Con 1</ability>
    <proficiency></proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Goblins occupy an uneasy place in a dangerous world, and they react by lashing out at any creatures they believe they can bully. Cunning in battle and cruel in victory, goblins are fawning and servile in defeat.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 26,
		Explorer's Guide to Wildemount p. 174</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Goblins reach adulthood at age 8 and live up to 60 years.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>In Eberron, goblins are usually neutral. They tend to look out for themselves, preferably without drawing unwanted attention from any larger, more powerful people.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Small.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fury of the Small</name>
      <text>When you damage a creature with an attack or a spell and the creature's size is larger than yours, you can cause the attack or spell to deal extra damage to the creature. The extra damage equals your level. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Nimble Escape</name>
      <text>You can take the Disengage or Hide action as a bonus action on each of your turns.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Goblin.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Half-Orc (Mark of Finding)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Con 1, Wis 2</ability>
    <proficiency></proficiency>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>When alliances between humans and orcs are sealed by marriages, half-orcs are born. Some half-orcs rise to become proud chiefs of orc tribes, their human blood giving them an edge over their full-blooded orc rivals. Some venture into the world to prove their worth among humans and other more civilized races. Many of these become adventurers, achieving greatness for their mighty deeds and notoriety for their barbaric customs and savage fury.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 41,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 98</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Half-orcs mature a little faster than humans, reaching adulthood around age 14. They age noticeably faster and rarely live longer than 75 years.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Half-orcs inherit a tendency toward chaos from their orc parents and are not strongly inclined toward good. Half-orcs raised among orcs and willing to live out their lives among them are usually evil.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Half-orcs are somewhat larger and bulkier than humans, and they range from 5 to well over 6 feet tall. Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hunter's Intuition</name>
      <text>When you make a Wisdom (Perception) or Wisdom (Survival) check, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Finder's Magic</name>
      <text>You can cast the hunter's mark spell with this trait. Starting at 3rd level, you can also cast the locate object spell with it. Once you cast either spell with this trait, you can't cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Goblin.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spells of the Mark</name>
      <text>Mark of Finding Spells
If you have the Spellcasting or the Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Finding Spells table are added to the spell list of your spellcasting class.

Spell Level — Spells
1st — faerie fire, longstrider
2nd — locate animals or plants, locate object
3rd — clairvoyance, speak with plants
4th — divination, locate creature
5th — commune with nature
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Hobgoblin</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Con 2, Int 1</ability>
    <proficiency></proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>War is the lifeblood of hobgoblins. Its glories are the dreams that inspire them. Its horrors don't feature in their nightmares. Cowardice is more terrible to hobgoblins than dying, for they carry their living acts into the afterlife. A hero in death becomes a hero eternal.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 26,
		Explorer's Guide to Wildemount p. 175</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Hobgoblins mature at the same rate as humans and have lifespans similar in length to theirs.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Hobgoblin society in Eberron is shaped by the ideal of a strict code of honor and rigid martial discipline. Most hobgoblins are lawful, tending toward harsh enforcement of their laws.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Martial Training</name>
      <text>You are proficient with two martial weapons of your choice and with light armor.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Saving Face</name>
      <text>Hobgoblins are careful not to show weakness in front of their allies, for fear of losing status. If you miss with an attack roll or fail an ability check or a saving throw, you can gain a bonus to the roll equal to the number of allies you can see within 30 feet of you (maximum bonus of +5). Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Goblin.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Kalashtar</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wis 2, Cha 1</ability>
    <proficiency></proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The kalashtar are a compound race created from the union of humanity and renegade spirits from the plane of dreams - spirits called quori. Kalashtar are often seen as wise, spiritual people with great compassion for others. But there is an unmistakable alien quality to the kalashtar, as they are haunted by the conflicts of their otherworldly spirits.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 29,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 62</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Kalashtar mature and age at the same rate as humans.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>The noble spirit tied to a kalashtar drives it toward lawful and good behavior. Most kalashtar combine strong self-discipline with compassion for all beings, but some kalashtar resist the virtuous influence of their spirit.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Dual Mind</name>
      <text>You have advantage on all Wisdom saving throws.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mental Discipline</name>
      <text>You have resistance to psychic damage.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Mind Link</name>
      <text>You can speak telepathically to any creature you can see, provided the creature is within a number of feet of you equal to 10 times your level. You don't need to share a language with the creature for it to understand your telepathic utterances, but the creature must be able to understand at least one language.

When you're using this trait to speak telepathically to a creature, you can use your action to give that creature the ability to speak telepathically with you for 1 hour or until you end this effect as an action. To use this ability, the creature must be able to see you and must be within this trait's range. You can give this ability to only one creature at a time; giving it to a creature takes it away from another creature who has it.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Severed from Dreams</name>
      <text>Kalashtar sleep, but they don't connect to the plane of dreams as other creatures do. Instead, their minds draw from the memories of their otherworldly spirit while they sleep. As such, you are immune to spells and other magical effects that require you to dream, like dream, but not to spells and other magical effects that put you to sleep, like sleep.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Quori, and one other language of your choice.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Orc (Eberron)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Str 2, Con 1</ability>
    <proficiency></proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Savage and fearless, orc tribes are ever in search of elves, dwarves, and humans to destroy. Motivated by their hatred of the civilized races of the world and their need to satisfy the demands of their deities, the orcs know that if they fight well and bring glory to their tribe, Gruumsh will call them home.

Source: Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 31</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Orcs reach adulthood at age 12 and live up to 50 years.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>The orcs of Eberron are a passionate people, given to powerful emotion and deep faith. They are generally chaotic, but can be any alignment.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Aggressive</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your movement speed toward a hostile creature you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Primal Intuition</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, and Survival.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Orc.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Shifter, Beasthide</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Con 2, Str 1</ability>
    <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Shifters are sometimes called the weretouched, as many believe that they are the descendants of humans and lycanthropes. They are humanoids with a bestial aspect; while they cannot fully change shape they can temporarily enhance their animalistic features - a state they call shifting. Whatever their origins, shifters have evolved into a unique race. A shifter walks on the knife's edge between the wilds and the world around them. Do they embrace their primal instincts or the path of civilization?

Beasthide often signifies the bear or boar: stoic, stubborn and thick-skinned.

Stoic and solid, a beasthide shifter draws strength and stability from the beast within. Beasthide shifters are typically tied to the bear or the boar, but any creature known for its toughness could apply.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 34,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 64</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Athlete</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Athletics skill.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shifting Feature</name>
      <text>Whenever you shift, you gain 1d6 additional temporary hit points. While shifted, you have a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Shifters are quick to mature both physically and emotionally, reaching young adulthood at age 10. They rarely live to be more than 70 years old.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Shifters tend toward neutrality, being more focused on survival than concepts of good and evil. A love of personal freedom can drive shifters toward chaotic alignments.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shifting</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can assume a more bestial appearance. This transformation lasts for 1 minute, until you die, or until you revert to your normal appearance as a bonus action. When you shift, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 temporary hit point). You also gain additional benefits that depend on your shifter subrace, described below.

Once you shift, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Shifter, Longtooth</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Str 2, Dex 1</ability>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Shifters are sometimes called the weretouched, as many believe that they are the descendants of humans and lycanthropes. They are humanoids with a bestial aspect; while they cannot fully change shape they can temporarily enhance their animalistic features - a state they call shifting. Whatever their origins, shifters have evolved into a unique race. A shifter walks on the knife's edge between the wilds and the world around them. Do they embrace their primal instincts or the path of civilization?

Longtooth shifters typically have lupine traits and prefer to run with a pack.

Longtooth shifters are fierce and aggressive, but they form deep bonds with their friends. Many longtooth shifters have canine traits that become more pronounced as they shift, but they might instead draw on tigers, hyenas, or other predators.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 34,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 64</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fierce</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shifting Feature</name>
      <text>While shifted, you can use your elongated fangs to make an unarmed strike as a bonus action. If you hit with your fangs, you can deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Shifters are quick to mature both physically and emotionally, reaching young adulthood at age 10. They rarely live to be more than 70 years old.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Shifters tend toward neutrality, being more focused on survival than concepts of good and evil. A love of personal freedom can drive shifters toward chaotic alignments.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shifting</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can assume a more bestial appearance. This transformation lasts for 1 minute, until you die, or until you revert to your normal appearance as a bonus action. When you shift, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 temporary hit point). You also gain additional benefits that depend on your shifter subrace, described below.

Once you shift, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Shifter, Swiftstride</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dex 2, Cha 1</ability>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics</proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Shifters are sometimes called the weretouched, as many believe that they are the descendants of humans and lycanthropes. They are humanoids with a bestial aspect; while they cannot fully change shape they can temporarily enhance their animalistic features — a state they call shifting. Whatever their origins, shifters have evolved into a unique race. A shifter walks on the knife's edge between the wilds and the world around them. Do they embrace their primal instincts or the path of civilization?

Swiftstride are often predatory and feline, but a swiftstride could also be a cunning rat who darts through the shadows.

Swiftstride shifters are graceful and quick. Typically feline in nature, swiftstride shifters are often aloof and difficult to pin down physically or socially.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 34,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 64</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Graceful</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Acrobatics skill.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shifting Feature</name>
      <text>While shifted, your walking speed increases by 10 feet. Additionally, you can move up to 10 feet as a reaction when a creature ends its turn within 5 feet of you. This reactive movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Shifters are quick to mature both physically and emotionally, reaching young adulthood at age 10. They rarely live to be more than 70 years old.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Shifters tend toward neutrality, being more focused on survival than concepts of good and evil. A love of personal freedom can drive shifters toward chaotic alignments.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shifting</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can assume a more bestial appearance. This transformation lasts for 1 minute, until you die, or until you revert to your normal appearance as a bonus action. When you shift, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 temporary hit point). You also gain additional benefits that depend on your shifter subrace, described below.

Once you shift, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Shifter, Wildhunt</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wis 2, Dex 1</ability>
    <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Shifters are sometimes called the weretouched, as many believe that they are the descendants of humans and lycanthropes. They are humanoids with a bestial aspect; while they cannot fully change shape they can temporarily enhance their animalistic features — a state they call shifting. Whatever their origins, shifters have evolved into a unique race. A shifter walks on the knife's edge between the wilds and the world around them. Do they embrace their primal instincts or the path of civilization?

Wildhunt shifters are born from any creature that tracks its prey.

Wildhunt shifters are sharp and insightful. Many are constantly alert, ever wary for possible threats. Others focus on their intuition, searching within. Wildhunt shifters are excellent hunters, and they also tend to become the spiritual leaders of shifter communities.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 34,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 64</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Tracker</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Survival skill.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shifting Feature</name>
      <text>While shifted, you have advantage on Wisdom checks, and no creature within 30 feet of you can make an attack roll with advantage against you, unless you're incapacitated.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Shifters are quick to mature both physically and emotionally, reaching young adulthood at age 10. They rarely live to be more than 70 years old.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Shifters tend toward neutrality, being more focused on survival than concepts of good and evil. A love of personal freedom can drive shifters toward chaotic alignments.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shifting</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can assume a more bestial appearance. This transformation lasts for 1 minute, until you die, or until you revert to your normal appearance as a bonus action. When you shift, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 temporary hit point). You also gain additional benefits that depend on your shifter subrace, described below.

Once you shift, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Warforged</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Con 2</ability>
    <proficiency></proficiency>
    <spellAbility></spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The warforged were built to fight in the Last War. The first warforged were mindless automatons, but House Cannith devoted vast resources to improving these steel soldiers. An unexpected breakthrough produced fully sentient soldiers, blending organic and inorganic materials. Warforged are made from wood and metal, but they can feel pain and emotion. Built as weapons, they must now find a purpose beyond the war. A warforged can be a steadfast ally, a cold-hearted killing machine, or a visionary in search of purpose and meaning.

Source:	Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 35,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 67</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>A typical warforged is between two and thirty years old. The maximum warforged lifespan remains a mystery; so far, warforged have shown no signs of deterioration due to age. You are immune to magical aging effects.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Most warforged take comfort in order and discipline, tending toward law and neutrality. But some have absorbed the morality, or lack thereof, of the beings with which they served.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Constructed Resilience</name>
      <text>You were created to have remarkable fortitude, represented by the following benefits:

	• You have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned, and you have resistance to poison damage.
	• You don't need to eat, drink, or breathe.
	• You are immune to disease.
	• You don't need to sleep, and magic can't put you to sleep.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Sentry's Rest</name>
      <text>When you take a long rest, you must spend at least six hours in an inactive, motionless state, rather than sleeping. In this state, you appear inert, but it doesn't render you unconscious, and you can see and hear as normal.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Integrated Protection</name>
      <text>Your body has built-in defensive layers, which can be enhanced with armor:

	• You gain a +1 bonus to Armor Class.
	• You can don only armor with which you have proficiency. To don armor other than a shield, you must incorporate it into your body over the course of 1 hour, during which you remain in contact with the armor. To doff armor, you must spend 1 hour removing it. You can rest while donning or doffing armor in this way.
	• While you live, the armor incorporated into your body can't be removed against your will.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialized Design</name>
      <text>You gain one skill proficiency and one tool proficiency of your choice.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language of your choice.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Dwarf, Mark of Warding</name>
    <ability>Con 2, Int 1</ability>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Kingdoms rich in ancient grandeur, halls carved into the roots of mountains, the echoing of picks and hammers in deep mines and blazing forges, a commitment to clan and tradition, and a burning hatred of goblins and orcs — these common threads unite all dwarves.

The Mark of Warding helps its bearers protect things of value. Using the mark, a dwarf can weave wards with mystic force. It also provides its bearer with an intuitive understanding of locks used to protect and seal.

Source:	Player's Handbook p. 20,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 108,
		Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 51</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Dwarves mature at the same rate as humans, but they're considered young until they reach the age of 50. On average, they live about 350 years.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Most dwarves are lawful, believing firmly in the benefits of a well-ordered society. They tend toward good as well, with a strong sense of fair play and a belief that everyone deserves to share in the benefits of a just order.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Dwarves stand around 5 feet tall and average about 150 pounds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d4
Height = 4 feet + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 115 + (2d6 x your size modifier)
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your speed is not reduced by wearing heavy armor.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to life underground in your race's ancient past, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Dwarven Resilience</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Dwarven Combat Training</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with the battleaxe, handaxe, light hammer, and warhammer.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency with the artisan's tools of your choice: smith's tools, brewer's supplies, or mason's tools.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stonecunning</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (History) check related to the origin of stonework, you are considered proficient in the History skill and add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Warder's Intuition</name>
      <text>When you make an Intelligence (Investigation) check or an ability check using thieves' tools, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Wards and Seals</name>
      <text>You can cast the Alarm and Mage Armor spells with this trait. Starting at 3rd level, you can also cast the Arcane Lock spell with it. Once you cast either spell with this trait, you can't cast that spell again until you finish a Long Rest. Intelligence is your Spellcasting Ability for these spells, and you don't require material components when you cast them with this trait.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spells of the Mark</name>
      <text>If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature, the spells on the Mark of Warding Spells table are added to the spell list of your Spellcasting class.

Mark of Warding Spells:
Spell Level — Spell
1st — Alarm, Armor of Agathys
2nd — Arcane Lock, Knock
3rd — Glyph of Warding, Magic Circle
4th — Leomund's Secret Chest, Mordenkainen's Faithful Hound
5th — Antilife Shell
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Dwarvish. Dwarvish is full of hard consonants and guttural sounds, and those characteristics spill over into whatever other language a dwarf might speak.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Dwarf, Mark of Warding (WGtE)</name>
    <ability>Con 2, Dex 1, Int 1</ability>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Kingdoms rich in ancient grandeur, halls carved into the roots of mountains, the echoing of picks and hammers in deep mines and blazing forges, a commitment to clan and tradition, and a burning hatred of goblins and orcs — these common threads unite all dwarves.

The Mark of Warding helps its bearers protect things of value. Using the mark, a dwarf can weave wards with mystic force. It also provides its bearer with an intuitive understanding of locks used to protect and seal.

Source:	Player's Handbook p. 20,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 108</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Dwarves mature at the same rate as humans, but they're considered young until they reach the age of 50. On average, they live about 350 years.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Most dwarves are lawful, believing firmly in the benefits of a well-ordered society. They tend toward good as well, with a strong sense of fair play and a belief that everyone deserves to share in the benefits of a just order.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Dwarves stand around 5 feet tall and average about 150 pounds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d4
Height = 4 feet + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 115 + (2d6 x your size modifier)
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your speed is not reduced by wearing heavy armor.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to life underground, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Dwarven Resilience</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Dwarven Combat Training</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with the battleaxe, handaxe, light hammer, and warhammer.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency with the artisan's tools of your choice: smith's tools, brewer's supplies, or mason's tools.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Stonecunning</name>
      <text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (History) check related to the origin of stonework, you are considered proficient in the History skill and add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Dwarvish. Dwarvish is full of hard consonants and guttural sounds, and those characteristics spill over into whatever other language a dwarf might speak.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Master of Locks</name>
      <text>When you make an Intelligence (History), Intelligence (Investigation), or Thieves' Tools check involving lock and trap mechanisms, you can roll one Intuition die, a d4, and add the number rolled to the ability check.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Wards and Seals</name>
      <text>You can use your mark to cast the alarm spell as a ritual. Starting at 3rd level you can cast arcane lock once with this trait and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Elf, Mark of Shadow</name>
    <ability>Dex 2, Cha 1</ability>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Elves are a magical people of otherworldly grace, living in places of ethereal beauty, in the midst of ancient forests or in silvery spires glittering with faerie light, where soft music drifts through the air and gentle fragrances waft on the breeze. Elves love nature and magic, art and artistry, music and poetry.

The Mark of Shadow lets an elf weave illusions, crafting magic to distract or delight. It also allows its bearer to sculpt shadows, making it easy to avoid detection.

Source:	Player's Handbook p. 23,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 105,
		Eberron: Rising from the Last War p. 49</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Although elves reach physical maturity at about the same age as humans, the elven understanding of adulthood goes beyond physical growth to encompass worldly experience. An elf typically claims adulthood and an adult name around the age of 100 and can live to be 750 years old.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Elves love freedom, variety, and self-expression, so they lean strongly toward the gentler aspects of chaos. They value and protect others' freedom as well as their own, and they are more often good than not.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Elves range from under 5 to over 6 feet tall and have slender builds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d10
Height = 4 feet + 6 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 90 + (1d4 x your size modifier)
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Senses</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.

If you meditate during a long rest, you finish the rest after only 4 hours. You otherwise obey all the rules for a long rest; only the duration is changed.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Cunning Intuition</name>
      <text>Whenever you roll a Dexterity (Stealth) check or a Charisma (Performance) check, roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the total ability check.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shape Shadows</name>
      <text>You know the Minor Illusion cantrip. Starting at 3rd level, you can also cast the Invisibility spell with this trait. Once you cast either spell with this trait, you can't cast that spell again until you finish a long rest. Charisma is your Spellcasting Ability for these spells.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Spells of the Mark</name>
      <text>If you have the Spellcasting or Pact Magic class features, the spells on the Mark of Shadow Spells table are added to the spell list of your spellcasting class.

Mark of Shadow Spells:
Spell — Level	Spell
1st — Disguise Self, Silent Image
2nd — Darkness, Pass Without Trace
3rd — Clairvoyance, Major Image
4th — Greater Invisibility, Hallucinatory Terrain
5th — Mislead
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Elf, Mark of Shadow (WGtE)</name>
    <ability>Dex 2, Cha 1</ability>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Elves are a magical people of otherworldly grace, living in places of ethereal beauty, in the midst of ancient forests or in silvery spires glittering with faerie light, where soft music drifts through the air and gentle fragrances waft on the breeze. Elves love nature and magic, art and artistry, music and poetry.

The Mark of Shadow lets an elf weave illusions, crafting magic to distract or delight. It also allows its bearer to sculpt shadows, making it easy to avoid detection.

Source:	Player's Handbook p. 23,
		Wayfinder's Guide to Eberron p. 105</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Although elves reach physical maturity at about the same age as humans, the elven understanding of adulthood goes beyond physical growth to encompass worldly experience. An elf typically claims adulthood and an adult name around the age of 100 and can live to be 750 years old.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Elves love freedom, variety, and self-expression, so they lean strongly toward the gentler aspects of chaos. They value and protect others' freedom as well as their own, and they are more often good than not.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Elves range from under 5 to over 6 feet tall and have slender builds. Your size is Medium.

To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:

Size modifier = 2d10
Height = 4 feet + 6 inches + your size modifier in inches
Weight in pounds = 90 + (1d4 x your size modifier)
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Senses</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Fey Ancestry</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Trance</name>
      <text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.

If you meditate during a long rest, you finish the rest after only 4 hours. You otherwise obey all the rules for a long rest; only the duration is changed.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Talent</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency with one musical instrument or the Performance skill.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Gift of the Shadows</name>
      <text>When you make a Charisma (Performance) or Dexterity (Stealth) check, you can roll one Intuition die, a d4, and add the number rolled to the ability check.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Shape Shadows</name>
      <text>You know the minor illusion cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this trait.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Slip Into Shadows</name>
      <text>You can use the Hide action as a bonus action, even if you have no cover or if you're under observation. Regardless of whether you succeed or fail, once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
