<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Surgeon [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Medicine</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You came of age in blood-soaked tents and dimly lit backrooms, where screams were common and survival was never certain. Whether tending to soldiers on the battlefield, treating plague victims in overcrowded wards, or apprenticing under a grizzled barber-surgeon, you learned to keep calm under pressure and work with whatever tools were at hand. Where others saw carnage, you saw opportunity—to learn, to mend, to endure. You may not have divine magic or formal training, but your hands know how to save lives.

Source:	The Barber by Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Scores: Intelligence, Wisdom, Dexterity</name>
      <text>A background lists three of your character's ability scores. Increase one by 2 and another one by 1, or increase all three by 1. None of these increases can raise a score above 20.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feat: Healer</name>
      <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Battle Medic. If you have a Healer's Kit, you can expend one use of it and tend to a creature within 5 feet of yourself as a Utilize action. That creature can expend one of its Hit Point Dice, and you then roll that die. The creature regains a number of Hit Points equal to the roll plus your Proficiency Bonus.

	Healing Rerolls. Whenever you roll a die to determine the number of Hit Points you restore with a spell or with this feat's Battle Medic benefit, you can reroll the die if it rolls a 1, and you must use the new roll.

Source:	The Barber by Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency: Herbalism Kit</name>
      <text>Each background gives a character proficiency with one tool—either a specific tool or one chosen from the Artisan's Tools category.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Starting Equipment</name>
      <text>Choose A or B: (A) 2 Daggers, Herbalism Kit, 2 Healers Kits, Book (Medicine), Candle, Fine Clothes 10 GP, or (B) 50 GP</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
