<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <feat>
    <name>Origin: Mundane Healing [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Surgical Instinct. You gain proficiency with the Medicine skill.

	Mundane Healing. You can spend 1 minute tending to the wounds of yourself or an ally within 5 feet. Make a DC 10 Wisdom (Medicine) check. On a success, the target regains hit points equal to 1d10 + your proficiency bonus. A creature can only benefit from this healing once per long rest.

Source:	The Barber by Sewage Orc</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Tricky Tonics [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+</prerequisite>
    <text>During a long rest, you can create a number of healing tonics equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1).
	When a creature drinks a tonic, as a bonus acton, they regain 1d8 hit points and roll a d4 to determine a side effect:

Tricky Tonics:
d4 | Effect
1 | Exhausted. The creature gains 1 level of exhaustion until they finish a short or long rest.
2 | Clumsy. The creature's speed increases by 5 feet, but they take a –1 penalty to AC for 1d6 rounds.
3 | No Side Effect. The tonic functions as normal.
4 | Potent Brew. The creature regains an additional 1d8 hit points.

Source:	The Barber by Sewage Orc</text>
  </feat>
  <feat>
    <name>Weave Stitcher [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <prerequisite>Level 4+</prerequisite>
    <text>You learn the Cure Wounds spell.

You always have this spells prepared. You can cast it a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast this spell using this trait, you choose Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma asyour spellcasting ability (choose the ability when you take this feat).
	Each time you cast Cure Wounds using this feat, you can choose to alter the spell in one of the following ways:

	• Quickened. You can cast the spell as a Bonus Action.

	• Heightened. You cast the spell at 2nd level (3d8 healing).

	• Twinned. You can target two creatures instead of one, as long as both creatures are within 5 feet of you.

Source:	The Barber by Sewage Orc</text>
  </feat>
</compendium>
