<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Warlock [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: Black Forest Patron (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: Black Forest Patron (HB)</name>
        <text>Bound to the ancient, vengeful spirits of the deep forest, wielding wild and eerie magic

"In the Heart of Darkness, lies the beauty of the Black Forest"

Theme: A pact with an ancient forest spirit or the primal force of the wild. The Black Forest Keeper embodies nature's wrath and protective vengeance.

Playstyle: Focuses on entangling foes, summoning nature-based defenses, and controlling terrain.

Nestled among the hills of Southwest Germany lies one of Europe's most iconic and mysterious forests—the Black Forest. Shrouded in legends and myths, this ancient wilderness has captivated travelers for centuries. From its dense stands of evergreens to its mysterious wildlife, the Black Forest is home to a wealth of wonders just waiting to be discovered.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 58 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Black Forest Spells (Black Forest Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Warlock level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Black Forest Patron Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3rd | Entangle, Fog Cloud, Thorn Whip, Pass Without Trace, Hold Person
5th | Plant Growth, Speak with Dead
7th | Blight, Hallucinatory Terrain
9th | Insect Plague, Tree Stride

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 58 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Thorned Wrath (Black Forest Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you summon thorny vines that erupt in a 20-foot radius centered on a point you can see within 60 feet. The terrain in the area becomes difficult for 1 minute.
All creatures in the area must make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Restrained condition for 1 minute. Can repeat the save at the end of each of its turns to end the condition on a success.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 58 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Thorned Wrath</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Black Forest Patron (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Guardian's Roots (Black Forest Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can root yourself in place for 1 minute. While rooted, your AC increases by 3, and you can't use your Speed. You can't be moved or pushed and you are Immune to the Prone condition.
	Additionally, each creature of your choice that moves for the first time in a turn within 5 feet of you or ends its turn there takes 2d6 Piercing damage.
	You can end this effect earlier as a Bonus Action.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 58 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Guardian's Roots</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Black Forest Patron (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Fey Ward (Black Forest Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain Advantage on saving throws against the Charmed or Frightened condition, and you can't be put to sleep by magical means.
	Additionally, you can cast the Protection from Energy spell once without expending a spell slot.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 58 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Nature's Reckoning (Black Forest Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>You summon a massive spectral tree to crush your enemies. As a Magic Action, choose a 30-foot radius area centered on a point that you can see within 60 feet of you. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: 6d10 Bludgeoning damage and Prone condition. Success: half damage.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 58 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Nature's Reckoning</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Black Forest Patron (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: Hag Patron (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: Hag Patron (HB)</name>
        <text>Bound to powers of witchcraft

"These hags, these great beauties, these mermaids who taunt, who feast, who slash, who steal, these succubae who cannot rest, my mothers, my sisters, my unborn friends, my keepers, my guardians"

Theme: Inspired by the hags of european legend, this subclass embodies the creeping horror of ancient curses and shapeshifting magic.

Playstyle: Specializes in debuffs, transformation, and control, excelling at weakening foes, altering reality, and instilling fear through supernatural presence.

In European folklore, a hag is an ugly and malicious old woman who practices witchcraft, with or without supernatural powers; hags are often said to be aligned with the devil or the dead.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 56 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hag Spells (Hag Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Warlock level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Hag Patron Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3rd | Hex, Disguise Self, Ray of Sickness, Silent Image, Charm Person
5th | Lesser Restoration, Prayer of Healing, Hold Person, Phantasmal Force
7th | Bestow Curse, Major Image
9th | Polymorph, Phantasmal Killer

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 56 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Mark of the Hag (Hag Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>Your patron brands you with a supernatural mark. You can cast the Hex spell once per Long Rest without expending a spell slot.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 56 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Mark of the Hag</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Hag Patron (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Hag's Flesh (Hag Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to your patron warps your body in unnatural ways. You gain:

	Warped Resilience. When you take damage, you can use your Reaction to gain Resistance to that damage type until the end of your next turn. You can use this a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

	Dark Adaptation. You gain Darkvision up to 120 feet. If you already have Darkvision, you can see through magical darkness as well.

	Witch's Breath. You can breathe underwater, and you gain Advantage on saving throws against Poison damage and the Poisoned condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 56 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Crone's Sight (Hag Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>Your hag's influence sharpens your perception of the unseen:

	• You gain Truesight 30 feet.
	• You can cast the Scrying spell once per Long Rest without using a spell slot. When you use this spell, you also hear everything around the target.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 56 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Crone's Sight</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Hag Patron (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Wicked Metamorphosis (Hag Patron (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you invoke your hag's monstrous gifts, transforming for 1 minute. While transformed, you gain:

	Twisted Resilience. You have Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, Slashing, Poison, Acid, Cold, and Fire damage.

	Terrifying Claws. Your hands become clawed talons. When you take the Attack Action, you can make two Unarmed Strikes using your Charisma modifier and your Proficiency Bonus. Each strike deals 1d10 + your Charisma modifier Slashing damage.

	Dread Presence. When you hit a creature with an attack, you can force them to make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Frightened condition until the end of its next turn.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 56 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Wicked Metamorphosis</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Hag Patron (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: Pact of the Muse (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: Pact of the Muse (HB)</name>
        <text>A warlock gifted (or cursed) by a celestial or fey patron of art and inspiration

"Ma qui la morta poesì resurga, o sante Muse, poi che vostro sono; e qui Calïopè alquanto surga, seguitando il mio canto con quel suono di cui le Piche misere sentiro lo colpo tal, che disperar perdono."
— Dante, Divine Comedy , Purgatory I, 7-12

Theme: The Muse represents a pact with an otherworldly source of inspiration—a celestial being, an ancient spirit of art, or a fey patron of creativity. This pact enhances the warlock's ability to inspire allies and bewilder foes, blending artistry with magical power.

Playstyle: Support-focused on bolstering allies through inspiration and disrupts enemies through beguiling magic.

In ancient Greek religion and mythology, the Muses (Ancient Greek: Μοῦσαι, romanized: Moûsai, Greek: Μούσες, romanized: Múses) are the inspirational goddesses of literature, science, and the arts. They were considered the source of the knowledge embodied in the poetry, lyric songs, and myths that were related orally for centuries in ancient Greek culture. The number and names of the Muses differed by region, but from the Classical period the number of Muses was standardized to nine, and their names were generally given as Calliope, Clio, Polyhymnia, Euterpe, Terpsichore, Erato, Melpomene, Thalia, and Urania. In medieval figurative usage, a muse was someone who serves as someone's source of artistic inspiration.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 59 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Muse Spells (Pact of the Muse (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Warlock level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Pact of the Muse Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3rd | Charm Person, Dissonant Whispers, Tasha's Hideous Laughter, Heroism, Silent Image
5th | Suggestion, Enthrall
7th | Greater Invisibility, Confusion
9th | Seeming, Hold Monster

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 59 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Enrapturing Verse (Pact of the Muse (HB))</name>
        <text>You speak words of inspiration imbued with your patron's magic.
	As a Bonus Action, choose a creature within 60 feet. That creature gains a bonus to its next Test within the end of its next round equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum +1). Alternatively, you can force a creature to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Disadvantage on attack rolls until the end of its next turn.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 59 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Enrapturing Verse</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Pact of the Muse (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Gilded Inspiration (Pact of the Muse (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in Performance and Persuasion, if you don't already have them, and you add double your proficiency bonus to these checks.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 59 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Beguiling Presence (Pact of the Muse (HB))</name>
        <text>Your patron's charm radiates through you. As a Magic Action, you exude an aura of beauty and wonder. Creatures of your choice that can see you within 30 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Charmed condition for 1 minute. A Charmed creature has Disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you. An affected creature can make another Wisdom saving throw at the end of each of its next turns, ending the condition on itself on a success.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 59 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Beguiling Presence</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Pact of the Muse (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Masterpiece Manifestation (Pact of the Muse (HB))</name>
        <text>You channel your patron's inspiration into a dazzling display. As a Magic Action, you create a 20-foot radius Sphere of radiant energy in a point that you can see within 60 feet of you. Creatures of your choice within the Sphere must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: 6d10 Radiant damage and the Blinded condition until the end of their next turn. Success: Half damage.
	The Sphere lasts for 1 minute. Creatures of your choice must also make a Constitution saving throw the first time they enter the Sphere in a turn, or when they start their turn there.
	Alternatively, creatures of your choice within the Sphere gain Advantage on each Test made there.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 59 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Masterpiece Manifestation</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Pact of the Muse (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB)</name>
        <text>Empowered by the spirit of conquest, enforce dominion over all before them

"Then I saw when the Lamb broke one of the seven seals, and I heard one of the four living creatures saying as with a voice of thunder, "Come!" I looked, and behold, a white horse, and he who sat on it had a bow; and a crown was given to him, and he went out conquering and to conquer"
— Revelation, 6:1-2

Theme: This warlock serves a being of dominance and ambition, spreading conquest through magical and martial prowess.

Playstyle: A hybrid of support and control, excelling in empowering allies and subduing foes.

In John's revelation the first horseman rides a white horse, carries a bow, and is given a crown as a figure of conquest, perhaps invoking pestilence, or the Antichrist.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 61 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Pale Rider Conquest Spells (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Warlock level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Pale Rider Conquest Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3rd | Command, Zephyr Strike, Shield of Faith, Magic Weapon, Hold Person
5th | Crusader's Mantle, Branding Smite
7th | Aura of Purity, Banishment
9th | Geas, Dominate Person

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 61 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Commanding Presence (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</name>
        <text>You exude authority in battle. As a Bonus Action, you can target one creature that can hear or see you within 30 feet of you. It must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: obey one command (no action required by you) issued by you until the start of your next turn (e.g., kneel, drop weapons).

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 61 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Rider's Advance (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</name>
        <text>When you move toward a Hostile creature, your Speed increases by 10 feet and you don't provoke Opportunity Attacks.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 61 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Irresistible Authority (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</name>
        <text>You can cast the Dominate Person spell once without expending a spell slot. You regain this ability when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 61 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Irresistible Authority</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: March of Conquest (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you create a 30-foot Emanation of an aura of power for 1 minute.
	Hostile creatures within the Emanation have Disadvantage on saving throws against the Frightened or Charmed condition, while your allies within the Emanation add your Charisma modifier to attack rolls and saving throws.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 61 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>March of Conquest</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: The Pale Rider - Death (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: The Pale Rider - Death (HB)</name>
        <text>Be an arbiter of the end of all things

When the Lamb broke the fourth seal, I heard the voice of the fourth living creature saying, "Come". I looked, and behold, an ashen horse; and he who sat on it had the name Death; and Hades was following with him. Authority was given to them over a fourth of the Earth, to kill with sword and with famine and with pestilence and by the wild beasts of the Earth.
— Revelation, 6:7-8

Theme: The harbinger of mortality and the end, this pact revolves around killing magic and finality.

Playstyle: A single-target damage dealer with a focus on instant death effects.

The fourth and final Horseman is named Death (Greek: Θᾰ́νᾰτος, Thánatos, Latin: Mŏrs or Thanatus). Death, known in Latin as Mŏrs and in Greek as Thánatos (Θᾰ́νᾰτος), of all the riders, he is the only one to whom the text itself explicitly gives a name. Unlike the other three, he is not described as carrying a weapon or other object, instead, he is followed by Hades (Greek: ᾍδης, Hā́idēs, latinized as Hādēs), which here refers not to the pagan god of death and his abode in Greek mythology, but simply to the place of the dead in the Greek language, and which is called Īnfernus ("[the] Underworld", a clipping of īnfernus lŏcus, "[the] lower place") in Latin. However, illustrations commonly depict him carrying a scythe, sword, or another implement, he is no different than typical portrayals of Death, and is the only horseman who doesn't appear to be a human.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 64 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Pale Rider Death Spells (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Warlock level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Pale Rider Death Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3rd | Toll the Dead, False Life, Detect Evil and Good, Bane, Cause Fear
5th | Gentle Repose, Darkness
7th | Phantasmal Killer, Death Ward
9th | Cloudkill, Danse Macabre

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 64 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Mark of Death (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you mark a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. The mark lasts for 1 minute.
	When you and your Allies hit that creature with a weapon attack, it takes additional Necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 64 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Mark of Death</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Death (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Soul Drain (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</name>
        <text>When a creature dies within 30 feet of you, you can use your Reaction to regain Hit Points equal to half your Warlock level.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 64 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Death's Grasp (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</name>
        <text>You can cast the Finger of Death spell once without expending a spell slot. You regain this feature after a long rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 64 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Death's Grasp</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Death (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Apocalypse Rider (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you summon a wave of deathly energy centered on you. All creatures of your choice in a 60-foot radius must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: 6d10 Necrotic damage and Paralyzed condition for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turns to end the condition on itself. Success: Half damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 64 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">6d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: The Pale Rider - Famine (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</name>
        <text>Bring ruin, scarcity, and suffering, draining life from all around you

When He broke the third seal, I heard the third living creature saying, "Come". I looked, and behold, a black horse; and he who sat on it had a pair of scales in his hand. And I heard something like a voice in the center of the four living creatures saying, "A quart of wheat for a denarius, and three quarts of barley for a denarius; but do not damage the oil and the wine"
— Revelation, 6:5-6

Theme: This pact embodies deprivation and decay, spreading hunger and weakening foes.

Playstyle: A debuff-focused subclass that saps the strength of enemies while bolstering resilience.

The third Horseman rides a black horse and is popularly understood to be Famine, as the Horseman carries a pair of balances or weighing scales (Greek ζυγόν, zugón), indicating the way that bread would have been weighed during a famine. The rider is typically portrayed as an emaciated man. Other authors interpret the third Horseman as the "Lord as a Law-Giver", holding Scales of Justice.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 63 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Pale Rider Famine Spells (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Warlock level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Pale Rider Famine Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3rd | Ray of Sickness, Inflict Wounds, Chill Touch, Goodberry, Protection from Poison
5th | Wither and Bloom, Vampiric Touch
7th | Blight, Aura of Life
9th | Cloudkill, Contagion

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 63 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Withering Touch (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you touch a creature within your reach. It must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: 2d8 + your Charisma modifier Necrotic damage. Success: Half damage.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 63 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">2d8+%6</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Withering Touch</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <counter>
        <name>Withering Touch</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Feast of Despair (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</name>
        <text>When a creature that you can see within 30 feet fails a Test, you can use your Reaction to sap its vitality. You deal to the target Necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier and you regain an equal amount of Hit Points.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 63 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Feast of Despair</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Withering Touch</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Feast of Despair</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Lingering Decay (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</name>
        <text>When you deal Necrotic damage, you can choose to have the damage linger. The target takes additional Necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier at the start of its next turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 63 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Withering Touch</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Feast of Despair</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Blightbringer (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you create a 30-foot-radius Emanation of an aura of famine for 1 minute. When the Emanation enters a Hostile creature's space and whenever that creature enters the Emanation for the first time in a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: 2d8 Necrotic damage. Success: Half damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 63 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">2d8</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Withering Touch</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Feast of Despair</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: The Pale Rider - War (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: The Pale Rider - War (HB)</name>
        <text>Bound to the essence of war itself, leave carnage in your wake

"When He broke the second seal, I heard the second living creature saying, "Come". And another, a red horse, went out; and to him who sat on it, it was granted to take peace from Earth, and that men would slay one another; and a great sword was given to him"
— Revelation, 6:3-4

Theme: The embodiment of carnage and destruction, this pact revolves around enhancing combat prowess and wreaking havoc.

Playstyle: Damage-focused, with abilities that bolster melee combat and devastate enemies.

The rider of the second horse is often taken to represent War (he is often pictured holding a sword upwards as though ready for battle) or mass slaughter. His horse's color is red (πυρρός, purrhós from πῦρ, fire), and in some translations, the color is specifically a "fiery" red. The color red, as well as the rider's possession of a great sword (μάχαιρα, mákhaira), suggests blood that is to be spilled.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 62 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Pale Rider War Spells (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Warlock level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Pale Rider War Spells:
Warlock Level | Spells
3rd | Wrathful Smite, Thunderwave, Magic Missile, Branding Smite, Burning Hands
5th | Shatter, Spiritual Weapon
7th | Fireball, Blinding Smite
9th | Wall of Fire, Flame Strike

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 62 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: War Cry (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you unleash a terrifying battle cry. Creatures of your choice within 30 feet that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: 1d6 Psychic damage plus your Charisma modifier and Disadvantage equal on attack rolls until the start of your next turn. Success: Half damage.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 62 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>War Cry</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - War (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Battle Frenzy (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</name>
        <text>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can use your Reaction to make another weapon attack.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 62 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Aura of Carnage (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</name>
        <text>You and each creature Allied to you within 10 feet of you gain a bonus to damage made with your melee weapon attack rolls equal to your Charisma modifier.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 62 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Rider's Wrath (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you unleash a wave of destruction in a 30-foot radius centered on you. Each creature of your choice within the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. Failure: 6d10 Force damage. Success: Half damage.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 62 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Rider's Wrath</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>The Pale Rider - War (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Hex</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Disguise Self</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ray of Sickness</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Silent Image</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Charm Person</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Lesser Restoration</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Prayer of Healing</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Person</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Force</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bestow Curse</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Major Image</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Polymorph</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Killer</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Hag Patron (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Entangle</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fog Cloud</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Thorn Whip</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Pass without Trace</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plant Growth</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Speak with Dead</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blight</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallucinatory Terrain</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Insect Plague</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tree Stride</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Black Forest Patron (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dissonant Whispers</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tasha's Hideous Laughter</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Heroism</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Suggestion</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Enthrall</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Confusion</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Seeming</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Monster</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Pact of the Muse (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Command</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Zephyr Strike</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shield of Faith</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Magic Weapon</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Crusader's Mantle</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Branding Smite</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Purity</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Banishment</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Geas</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dominate Person</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Conquest (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wrathful Smite</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Thunderwave</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Magic Missile</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Burning Hands</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shatter</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spiritual Weapon</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fireball</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blinding Smite</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Fire</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Flame Strike</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - War (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Inflict Wounds</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Chill Touch</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Goodberry</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Protection from Poison</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wither and Bloom</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Vampiric Touch</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Life</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cloudkill</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB)), Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contagion</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Famine (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Toll the Dead</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>False Life</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Evil and Good</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bane</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cause Fear</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Gentle Repose</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Darkness</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Death Ward</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Danse Macabre</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Finger of Death</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (The Pale Rider - Death (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
