<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Wizard [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: School of Circean Enchantment (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: School of Circean Enchantment (HB)</name>
        <text>Enthrall the others with charming magic

"And I will tell you of all the wicked witchcraft that Circe will try to practice upon you. She will mix a mess for you to drink, and she will drug the meal with which she makes it"
— Homer, Odyssey X

Theme: Inspired by the sorceress Circe from The Odyssey, this subclass focuses on enchanting, transforming, and manipulating others, blending charm and transmutation magic.

Playstyle: Circean Enchanters are masters of control, turning enemies into allies and reshaping their forms.

Circe is known for her role in Homer's Odyssey when Odysseus visits her island of Aeaea on the way back from the Trojan War. Circe had a vast knowledge of potions and herbs. Through the use of these and a magic wand or staff, she transformed her enemies, or those who offended her, into animals.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 67 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Enchanting Voice (School of Circean Enchantment (HB))</name>
        <text>You learn the Charm Person spell and you can cast it without expending a spell slot once per Long Rest. When you cast the Charm Person spell, you can target an additional creature.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 67 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Will of the Sorceress (School of Circean Enchantment (HB))</name>
        <text>When you cast a spell of the enchantment school that targets a creature, you can force that creature to have Disadvantage on the saving throw.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 67 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Enchanting Voice</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of Circean Enchantment (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Will of the Sorceress</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>School of Circean Enchantment (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Transmutation's Touch (School of Circean Enchantment (HB))</name>
        <text>You learn the Polymorph spell, but it doesn't count against your spells prepared.
	You can cast it once without expending a spell slot once per Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 67 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Transmutation's Touch</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of Circean Enchantment (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Beguile and Transform (School of Circean Enchantment (HB))</name>
        <text>Your spells ignore Immunity to the Charmed condition. Your spells can also change the shape of creatures whose form is usually immutable, such as Constructs.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 67 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Circe's Dominion (School of Circean Enchantment (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you target a creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature is transformed into a harmless beast (CR 0) for to 1 minute. The creature retains its alignment and personality but is unable to act against you.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 67 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Circe's Dominion</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of Circean Enchantment (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: School of Illuminism (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: School of Illuminism (HB)</name>
        <text>Bring the light of knowledge in the darkness

"Education is bitter, but its fruit is sweet"

Theme: Inspired by the Enlightenment, this subclass reflects a pursuit of knowledge, logic, and understanding of the natural world, using magic to illuminate both metaphorically and literally.

Playstyle: Illuminists excel at uncovering secrets, countering lies, and shedding light on mysteries. They have abilities that disrupt illusions, reveal hidden truths, and empower their allies with clarity.

The Enlightenment was an intellectual and philosophical movement taking place in Europe from the late 17th century to the early 19th century. The central doctrines of the Enlightenment were individual liberty, representative government, the rule of law, and religious freedom, in contrast to an absolute monarchy or single party state and the religious persecution of faiths other than those formally established and often controlled outright by the State.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 68 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Light of Truth (School of Illuminism (HB))</name>
        <text>You learn the Detect Magic and Identify spells, which don't count against your spells prepared. You can cast each of these once without expending a spell slot, regaining the feature when you finish a Short or Long rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 68 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Dispel the Shadows (School of Illuminism (HB))</name>
        <text>When you cast a spell that creates light (such as Light or Daylight), the radius of the light is doubled.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 68 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Light of Truth</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of Illuminism (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Unveiling Insight (School of Illuminism (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain Advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) and Wisdom (Insight) checks. Additionally, as a Magic Action, you can focus your mind to gain Truesight up to 30 feet for 1 minute.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 68 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Unveiling Insight</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of Illuminism (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Illuminated Mind (School of Illuminism (HB))</name>
        <text>Your mind resists magical manipulation. You are Immune to the Charmed condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 68 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Brilliant Revelation (School of Illuminism (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you emit a burst of magical light in a 30-foot radius. Creatures of your choice within the radius must make a Constitution saving throw against a spell save DC. Failure: Blinded condition for 1 minute. While Blinded, can't have the Invisible condition. An affected creature can make another Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its next turns, ending the condition on itself on a success.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 68 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Brilliant Revelation</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of Illuminism (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: School of the Alchemist (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: School of the Alchemist (HB)</name>
        <text>Master of Transformation and Elixirs

"Every element holds a secret, every reaction a revelation. To seek the philosopher's stone is to seek the divine"

Theme: Rooted in medieval alchemical traditions, this subclass focuses on transmutation, creation, and the pursuit of perfection.

Playstyle: Alchemists are versatile, able to create potions, transmute materials, and alter the battlefield.

The School of Alchemy is a discipline of arcane science, blending mystical knowledge with chemistry, metallurgy, and the natural philosophy of medieval and Renaissance Europe. These wizards embody the historical alchemists who sought the Philosopher's Stone, dabbled in transmutation, and believed that magic and science were two sides of the same coin. Rooted in the traditions of figures like Paracelsus, Albertus Magnus, and Nicolas Flamel, this school explores the alchemical mysteries of matter, energy, and spiritual transformation.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Transmutation Magic (School of the Alchemist (HB))</name>
        <text>You learn the Alter Self spell, which doesn't count against your spells prepared. You can cast it once without expending a spell slot, once per Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Alchemical Recipes (School of the Alchemist (HB))</name>
        <text>During a Long Rest, you can create a potion. Choose from the following: healing, resistance (to one damage type), or speed (increases movement by 10 feet for 1 hour). The DM has the statistics for the potions.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Transmutation Magic</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of the Alchemist (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Magnum Opus (School of the Alchemist (HB))</name>
        <text>You advance in your studies of alchemical transmutation, allowing you to tap into deeper arcane formulas.
	You can create a special elixir that mimics the effects of a lesser restoration spell. The drinker can remove one disease, condition (Blinded, Deafened, Poisoned, Paralyzed), or regain lost ability score points. Once used, you cannot create this elixir again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Magnum Opus</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of the Alchemist (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Great Work of the Alchemist (School of the Alchemist (HB))</name>
        <text>Your knowledge of mystical chemistry allows you to manipulate the very structure of magic and matter.
	When you cast a spell that deals Acid, Fire, Poison, or Necrotic damage, you can change its damage type to Force or Radiant, representing the purified essence of alchemy.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Elixir of Immortality (School of the Alchemist (HB))</name>
        <text>You have uncovered the secrets of longevity and perfected the final stages of the Magnum Opus.
	During a Long Rest action, you can create a perfected alchemical elixir. When you drink it as a Bonus Action, it alters your form for 1 minute. Choose one of the following effects:

	• Adamantine Flesh. You gain Resistance to all damage except Psychic.

	• Liquid Essence. You can move through small openings, difficult terrain does not slow you, and you gain Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.

	• Purified Form. You are immune to Poison damage and the Frightened, Charmed and Poisoned conditions.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 66 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Elixir of Immortality</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of the Alchemist (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: School of the Renaissance (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: School of the Renaissance (HB)</name>
        <text>Mix magic with the power of art and invention

"Knowledge is not inherited, nor granted by gods—it is created. Let the old world tremble before new ideas"

Theme: Drawing from the creativity and ingenuity of the Italian Renaissance, this subclass combines art and invention, creating magical constructs and enhancing spells with artistic flair.

Playstyle: Renaissance Wizards are versatile, with abilities to summon magical objects, enhance their spell effects with artistry, and create magical blueprints.

Renaissance' means 're-birth' and during this time Europe left behind the fixed ideas of the Middle Ages and created the beginnings of the modern world as we know it. The civilizations of ancient Greece and Rome were rediscovered, inspiring an interest in Classical learning which challenged medieval beliefs and ideas.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 69 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Magical Craftsmanship (School of the Renaissance (HB))</name>
        <text>You can cast the Unseen Servant spell without expending a spell slot, regaining the feature when you finish a Long Rest.
	You also learn the Mending and Prestidigitation cantrips, which don't count against your known cantrips.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 69 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Artistic Infusion (School of the Renaissance (HB))</name>
        <text>When you cast a spell, you can flavor it with artistic elements, such as radiant paintings or bursts of music. When a creature succeeds a saving throw against a spell you cast, you can impose Disadvantage on its next Test before the end of your next turn.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 69 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Magical Craftsmanship</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of the Renaissance (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Artistic Infusion</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of the Renaissance (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Inspired Creation (School of the Renaissance (HB))</name>
        <text>During a Long Rest, you can create a magical construct using your spellbook. Choose one of the following effects:

	• A tiny modron floating around a creature of your choice granting a +2 to its AC.

	• A hovering platform that can carry up to 500 pounds and moves 30 feet per round as a Bonus Action action.

These constructs last until you finish a Long Rest or dismiss them.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 69 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Artful Enhancement (School of the Renaissance (HB))</name>
        <text>When you cast a spell, you can grant a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you Temporary Hit Points equal to your Wizard level.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 69 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Artful Enhancement</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of the Renaissance (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Masterpiece (School of the Renaissance (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you create a magical masterpiece, such as an intricate sculpture or mural. Choose one of the following effects:

	Mural of Glory. All your Allies within 30 feet of you gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your Wizard level + Intelligence modifier and have Advantage on a Test of their choice within 1 minute.

	Sculpture of Binding. A creature within 30 feet must make on a Dexterity saving throw Failure: Restrained condition for 1 minute. Success: Restrained condition until the end of your next turn.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 69 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Masterpiece</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>School of the Renaissance (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
