<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Paladin [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Hospitaller (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Hospitaller (HB)</name>
        <text>Heal the sick and protect the weak

"Mercy and might are brothers, and I wield them both. To defend, to heal, to endure—I shall fail neither my god nor my sword."

Theme: Devoted to healing, mercy, and protection of the weak, the Hospitallers are inspired by historical knightly orders that combined martial prowess with the duties of caretakers and medics. They embody compassion and sacrifice.

Playstyle: Healing and support-focused. Excel in restoring health and removing conditions from allies while providing a steady front-line presence.

Tenets of the Oath of the Hospitaller:
	• Charity: Provide aid to the sick, wounded, and helpless.
	• Sanctuary: Protect those seeking shelter under your care.
	• Compassion: Act with kindness and mercy whenever possible.

Hospitallers, a religious military order that was founded at Jerusalem in the 11th century and that, headquartered in Rome, continues its humanitarian tasks in most parts of the modern world under several slightly different names and jurisdictions. The origin of the Hospitallers was an 11th-century hospital founded in Jerusalem by Italian merchants from Amalfi to care for sick and poor pilgrims. After the Christian conquest of Jerusalem in 1099 during the First Crusade, the hospital's superior, a monk named Gerard, intensified his work in Jerusalem and founded hostels in Provençal and Italian cities on the route to the Holy Land. The order was formally named and recognized on February 15, 1113, in a papal bull issued by Pope Paschal II. Along with the Templars, the Hospitallers became the most formidable military order in the Holy Land.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 41 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Protective Ward (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Reaction, you expend one use of your Channel Divinity to grant to a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you a +5 bonus to its AC until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 41 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oath of the Hospitaller Spells (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your Oath ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Paladin level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Oath of the Hospitaller Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3rd | Cure Wounds, Bless
5th | Lesser Restoration, Prayer of Healing
9th | Aura of Vitality, Revivify
13th | Guardian of Faith, Aura of Life
17th | Mass Cure Wounds, Raise Dead

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 41 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Aura of Compassion (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</name>
        <text>Within your Aura of Protection, you and your allies regain additional Hit Points equal to your Charisma modifier whenever you receive magical healing.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 41 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Hospitaller's Grace (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain immunity to Poison damage, the Poisoned condition, and to disease.
Additionally, whenever you restore Hit Points to a creature with spells or features, you can also remove one condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 41 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 20: Beacon of Hope (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</name>
        <text>Within your Aura of Protection, you and your allies regain 10 Hit Points up to your maximum at the start of each of your turns, and Hostile creatures have Disadvantage on any Test.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 41 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Round Table (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Round Table (HB)</name>
        <text>Follow duty and honor to protect the innocent

"Honor is not a gift bestowed, but a burden carried. Let my blade serve the worthy and strike down the false."

Theme: Inspired by the chivalric knights of Arthurian legend, these Paladins swear to uphold honor, unity, and the protection of those who cannot defend themselves. They lead by example and inspire camaraderie.

Playstyle: Team-focused support and protection. Excel in boosting the effectiveness of allies, providing defensive buffs, and shining in group coordination.

Tenets of the Round Table:

	• Chivalry: Act with honor, courtesy, and humility in all matters.
	• Justice: Fight for the oppressed and uphold fairness in every judgment.
	• Loyalty: Be true to your liege, your companions, and your principles.

The Knights of the Round Table are characters in the legends about King Arthur. They were the best knights in Arthur's kingdom, and lived in the King's castle-city of Camelot. They were called the Knights of the Round Table because of a special table that was in Camelot, that was round instead of rectangular. This meant that everyone who sat around it was seen as trust worthy and equal. In order to become a Knight of the Round Table, a knight had to prove he was chivalrous (polite) enough. In the legend, the knights swore a Code of Chivalry, which is much like an oath is today. This meant that they promised to uphold the rules given to them once they became a Knight of the Round Table.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 39 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Smite the Tyrant (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</name>
        <text>When you make a successful melee weapon attack, you use a Bonus Action to expend a use of your Channel Divinity to deal an additional 3d10 Radiant damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 39 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Radiant Damage">3d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oath of the Round Table Spells (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your Oath ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Paladin level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Oath of the Round Table Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3rd | Heroism, Sanctuary
5th | Enhance Ability, Warding Bond
9th | Beacon of Hope, Daylight
13th | Aura of Purity, Freedom of Movement
17th | Banishing Smite, Greater Restoration

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 39 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Aura of Nobility (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</name>
        <text>While in your Aura of Protection, you and your allies have Advantage on saving throws against the Frightened or Blinded condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 39 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Knight's Resolve (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</name>
        <text>You are Immune to the Stunned and Paralyzed conditions, and when you make a death saving throw, you can choose to automatically roll a 20.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 39 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Knight's Resolve</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oath of the Round Table (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 20: King's Champion (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action you and your allies within your Aura of Protection have Advantage on any Test.
	Additionally, you can make one additional attack when you take the Attack Action.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 39 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Templar (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Templar (HB)</name>
        <text>Defend the church and the faithful

"Non Nobis Domine
Non Nobis Sed Nomini
Tuo Da Gloriam"
— Templar Motto

Theme: Devotion to a holy order or faith, fighting as a militant defender of the church or a divine institution. The Templar embodies religious zeal and serves as a frontline protector of the faithful, opposing heretics and unholy forces.

Playstyle: Defensive and radiant-focused. Excel in enduring prolonged combat while shielding the party from harm.

Tenets of the Templar:

	• Faithfulness. Serve your god and holy order with unwavering devotion.
	• Protection. Shield the innocent and the faithful from harm.
	• Purity. Keep yourself free from corruption and act as an example of virtue.

Templar, member of the Poor Knights of Christ and of the Temple of Solomon, a religious military order of knighthood established at the time of the Crusades that became a model and inspiration for other military orders. Originally founded to protect Christian pilgrims to the Holy Land, the order assumed greater military duties during the 12th century. Its prominence and growing wealth, however, provoked opposition from rival orders. Falsely accused of blasphemy and blamed for Crusader failures in the Holy Land, the order was destroyed by King Philip IV of France.
	The Poor Fellow-Soldiers of Christ and of the Temple of Solomon, mainly known as the Knights Templar, was a French military order of the Catholic faith, and one of the wealthiest and most popular military orders in Western Christianity. They were founded in 1118 to defend pilgrims on their way to Jerusalem, with their headquarters located there on the Temple Mount, and existed for nearly two centuries during the Middle Ages. Officially endorsed by the Roman Catholic Church by such decrees as the papal bull Omne datum optimum of Pope Innocent II, the Templars became a favored charity throughout Christendom and grew rapidly in membership and power. The Templar knights, in their distinctive white mantles with a red cross, were among the most skilled fighting units of the Crusades.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 37 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oath of the Templar Spells (Oath of the Templar (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your Oath ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Paladin level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Oath of the Templar Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3rd | Shield of Faith, Compelled Duel
5th | Zone of Truth, Spiritual Weapon
9th | Crusader's Mantle, Spirit Guardians
13th | Guardian of Faith, Death Ward
17th | Holy Weapon, Dispel Evil and Good

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 37 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Divine Bulwark (Oath of the Templar (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you present your Holy Symbol and expend one use of your Channel Divinity to grant all creatures of your choice within 10 feet of you Temporary Hit Points equal to your Paladin level + your Charisma modifier.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 37 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Aura of Conviction (Oath of the Templar (HB))</name>
        <text>While in your Aura of Protection, you and your allies have Advantage on saving throws against the Frightened or Charmed condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 37 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Sanctified Armaments (Oath of the Templar (HB))</name>
        <text>Your attacks cause Radiant or Force damage (your choice) instead of the normal damage they would cause. In addition, your weapon attacks deal an extra 1d8 Radiant damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 38 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Extra Radiant Damage">1d8</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 20: Divine Champion (Oath of the Templar (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain resistance to all types of damage from Fiends and Undead.
	Additionally, as a Magic Action, you can unleash a burst of radiant energy, forcing all creatures of your choice within 30 feet to make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: 6d10 Radiant damage and Blinded condition until the end of your next turn. Success: Half damage.
	You can use this feature twice, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 38 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Radiant Damage">6d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Divine Champion</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oath of the Templar (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Paladin Subclass: Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB)</name>
        <text>Protect your liege even with death

"I am not of this land, but my oath binds me more than blood ever could. I stand, I fight, I do not falter"

Theme: Sworn defenders and elite warriors of royalty or sacred institutions, inspired by the historical mercenary guards of Byzantine emperors. These Paladins are disciplined soldiers devoted to the cause they protect, even unto death.

Playstyle:Tactical mobility and defensive combat for battlefield control.

Tenets of the Varangian Guard:
	• Loyalty: Serve your liege with absolute fidelity.
	• Strength: Prove your worth through physical might and martial prowess.
	• Honor the Oath: Never abandon your duty, even in the face of death.

The Varangian Guard was a most modern phenomenon; an international mercenary group, assembled from the world's most terrifying warriors, who faithfully guarded the Byzantine Emperor for almost four centuries from X to XIV century. The Varangian Guard was known for being primarily composed of recruits from Northern Europe, including mainly Norsemen from Scandinavia but also Anglo-Saxons from England. The recruitment of distant foreigners from outside Byzantium to serve as the emperor's personal guard was pursued as a deliberate policy, as they lacked local political loyalties and could be counted upon to suppress revolts by disloyal Byzantine factions.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Battle Cry (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you expend one use of your Channel Divinity to grant to each creature of your choice that you can see within 30 feet Advantage on a Test of their choice within 1 minute.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oath of the Varangian Guard Spells (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</name>
        <text>The magic of your Oath ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Paladin level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Oath of the Varangian Guard Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3rd | Command, Shield of Faith
5th | Misty Step, Branding Smite
9th | Aura of Vitality, Crusader's Mantle
13th | Freedom of Movement, Stoneskin
17th | Banishing Smite, Wall of Force

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Aura of Vigilance (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</name>
        <text>While in your Aura of Protection, you and your allies have Advantage on Initiative rolls.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Unyielding Defender (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 20: Vanguard's Wrath (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, for 1 minute, you can enter a battle frenzy. During this time, you have Advantage on all attack rolls, and Hostile creatures within your Aura of Protection take 2d8 Radiant damage at the start of each of their next turns.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 40 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d8</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Shield of Faith</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB)), Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Compelled Duel</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Zone of Truth</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spiritual Weapon</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Crusader's Mantle</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB)), Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spirit Guardians</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Guardian of Faith</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB)), Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Death Ward</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Holy Weapon</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Evil and Good</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Templar (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Command</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Misty Step</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Branding Smite</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Vitality</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB)), Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Freedom of Movement</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB)), Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Stoneskin</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Banishing Smite</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB)), Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Force</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Varangian Guard (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cure Wounds</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bless</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Lesser Restoration</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Prayer of Healing</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Revivify</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Life</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mass Cure Wounds</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Raise Dead</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Hospitaller (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Heroism</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sanctuary</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Enhance Ability</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Warding Bond</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Beacon of Hope</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Daylight</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Purity</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Restoration</name>
    <classes>Paladin [5.5e] (Oath of the Round Table (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
