<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Rogue [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Rogue Subclass: Highwayman (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Rogue Subclass: Highwayman (HB)</name>
        <text>Ambush stealthily your opponents

"Gold belongs to those bold enough to take it. If you hear my name, it is already too late"

Theme: Bold, daring outlaws of the road, Highwaymen use their wits and combat prowess to ambush targets, escape pursuit, and live another day. Their tactics rely on mobility, intimidation, and ambushes.

Playstyle: A skirmisher who excels in hit-and-run tactics, controlling the battlefield with mobility and debuffing enemies with fear and distraction.

A highwayman was a robber who stole from travelers. This type of thief usually travelled and robbed by horse as compared to a footpad who travelled and robbed on foot; mounted highwaymen were widely considered to be socially superior to footpads. Highwaymen increased in number in the early 18th century. They targeted stagecoaches, carriages, farmers returning from market and the mail coaches. Such criminals operated until the mid- or late 19th century.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 49 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Ambush Tactics (Highwayman (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain advantage on Initiative rolls.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 49 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Daring Escape (Highwayman (HB))</name>
        <text>When you use the Dash action, you can also gain Resistance to any type of damage until the start of your next turn.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 49 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Daring Escape</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Highwayman (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <counter>
        <name>Daring Escape</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Highwayman (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Fearsome Reputation (Highwayman (HB))</name>
        <text>You can use your Bonus Action to intimidate foes. Choose one creature within 30 feet of you that can see or hear you. It must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Charisma modifier). Failure: Frightened condition for 1 minute.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 49 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Daring Escape</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Highwayman (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Fearsome Reputation</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Highwayman (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 13: Ghost of the Road (Highwayman (HB))</name>
        <text>While you are in Dim Light or Darkness, you have the Invisible condition also to creatures that rely on Darkvision to see you.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 49 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Daring Escape</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Highwayman (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Legendary Outlaw (Highwayman (HB))</name>
        <text>When you hit a creature, you can force it to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Charisma modifier). Failure: Stunned condition until the end of your next turn.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 49 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Daring Escape</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Highwayman (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Rogue Subclass: Spanish Duelist (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Rogue Subclass: Spanish Duelist (HB)</name>
        <text>Fight gracefully following a code of honor

"A blade is not just steel, but wit and grace—if you must die, at least do so beautifully"

Theme: Masters of fencing and honor, Spanish Duelists embody precision and grace in combat. They fight with deadly efficiency, outmaneuvering their foes with quick reflexes and unerring strikes.

Playstyle: A melee-focused rogue specializing in oneon-one combat, parrying blows, and precision strikes.


La Verdadera Destreza is the conventional term for the Spanish tradition of fencing of the early modern period. The word destreza literally translates to 'dexterity' or 'skill, ability', and thus la verdadera destreza to 'the true skill' or 'the true art'. While destreza is primarily a system of swordsmanship, it is intended to be a universal method of fighting, applicable to all weapons in principle, but in practice dedicated to the rapier specifically, or the rapier combined with a defensive weapon such as a cloak, a buckler or a parrying dagger.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 50 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Duelist's Precision (Spanish Duelist (HB))</name>
        <text>When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can reroll one of the weapon's damage dice and use either roll.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 50 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Parry and Riposte (Spanish Duelist (HB))</name>
        <text>When a creature within your reach misses you with a melee attack, you can use your Reaction to make a melee weapon attack against it.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 50 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Bladesman's Grace (Spanish Duelist (HB))</name>
        <text>When you take the Dodge action, your Speed increases by 10 feet until the end of your turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 50 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 13: Perfect Tempo (Spanish Duelist (HB))</name>
        <text>If you reduce a creature to 0 hit points on your turn, you can take one additional Action between: Attack, Dash, or Dodge

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 50 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Master Duelist (Spanish Duelist (HB))</name>
        <text>Once per turn, when you make an attack roll with Advantage, you can treat a roll of 9 or lower on the d20 as a 10.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 50 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Rogue Subclass: Venetian Mask (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Rogue Subclass: Venetian Mask (HB)</name>
        <text>Engage in courtly life and espionage

"A face is but a story told to the world—mine is a thousand tales, and none of them are true"

Theme: Masters of intrigue, disguise, and social deception, Venetian Masks thrive in the shadows of court politics and crowded masquerade balls. They use misdirection and trickery to infiltrate, manipulate, and eliminate targets.

Playstyle: Social-focused rogue with strong infiltration, disguise, and crowd manipulation abilities.

The city-state of Venice emerged on a lagoon from the ruins of the Roman and Byzantine empires in the 9th century and grew to become the greatest seaport in late medieval Europe and an important centre of commerce linking the continent to the East. A wealthy city throughout most of its history, Venice was involved not only in the lucrative trade of silk and spices but also in the exchange of an equally lucrative commodity: secrets. By the 14th century, Venice's network of state-sponsored professional and amateur spies overseen by the 'spy chiefs', the Council of Ten, brought home new technologies, handled state secrets and listened in on conspiracies and betrayals of its own citizens, creating a system of fear and suspicion that can be likened to the paranoia and atmosphere of surveillance that pervades the modern world.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 48 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Masquerade Veil (Venetian Mask (HB))</name>
        <text>You have a magical mask that you can don as a Bonus Action, granting you Advantage on Deception and Persuasion checks.
	While wearing the mask, you can cast the Disguise Self spell without requiring a spell slot.
	The effects of the magical mask last for 1 hour but you can end them earlier as a Bonus Action.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 48 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Dance of Shadows (Venetian Mask (HB))</name>
        <text>When you are in a crowd of at least 3 creatures, you gain Advantage on Stealth checks when you take the Hide Action.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 48 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Masquerade Veil</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Venetian Mask (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <counter>
        <name>Masquerade Veil</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Venetian Mask (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Eyes Behind the Mask (Venetian Mask (HB))</name>
        <text>You develop an uncanny ability to discern lies and uncover secrets. You gain Proficiency in Insight, and you can add double your Proficiency Bonus to Insight checks.
	You have Advantage on saving throws against the Charmed condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 48 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Masquerade Veil</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Venetian Mask (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 13: Enigmatic Presence (Venetian Mask (HB))</name>
        <text>You can exude an aura of intrigue and menace. As a Magic Action, you can force all creatures of your choice that can see you within 30 feet of to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Charisma modifier). Failure: Frightened or Charmed condition (your choice) for 1 minute.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 48 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Masquerade Veil</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Venetian Mask (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Enigmatic Presence</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Venetian Mask (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Shadow Masquerade (Venetian Mask (HB))</name>
        <text>You can cast the Mislead spell without requiring a spell slot.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.
	Additionally, you can assume the shape of a creature of Medium or smaller Size that you have seen at least once for 1 hour. Only creatures with Truesight can reveal the illusion. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 48 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Masquerade Veil</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Venetian Mask (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Shadow Masquerade</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Venetian Mask (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
