<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Druid [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Druid Subclass: Circle of the Labyrinth (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Druid Subclass: Circle of the Labyrinth (HB)</name>
        <text>Draw power from mysterious mazes

"Every path leads somewhere. Every step is a choice. The maze holds answers—if you can find them"

Theme: Draw from the power of mazes from Minoan and Greek mythology and their mysteries, focusing on mental fortitude and cunning.

Playstyle: Tactical play and exploration.

In Greek mythology, the Labyrinth (Ancient Greek: λαβύρινθος, romanized: Labúrinthos) is an elaborate, confusing structure designed and built by the legendary artificer Daedalus for King Minos of Crete at Knossos. Its function was to hold the Minotaur, the monster eventually killed by the hero Theseus. Daedalus had so cunningly made the Labyrinth that he could barely escape it after he built it. Labyrinths are often described as paths of wisdom and peace. One of the oldest of symbols, the labyrinth dates back more than 4000 years. Long used as a meditation and prayer tool, this ancient art form speaks to people of different backgrounds and various religions.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Circle of the Labyrinth Spells (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Druid level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Circle of the Labyrinth Spells:
Druid Level | Prepared Spells
3 | Disguise Self, Dissonant Whispers, Expeditious Retreat, Tasha's Hideous Laughter
5 | Hold Person, Misty Step
7 | Hypnotic Pattern, Nondetection
9 | Freedom of Movement, Greater Invisibility

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Maze Walker (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</name>
        <text>You have Advantage on any check to navigate mazes, solve puzzles, or find hidden paths.
	Additionally, you can also use a Bonus Action to impose Disadvantage on a creature's Wisdom (Perception) checks to detect you or an ally you can see within 30 feet of you.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Maze Walker</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Labyrinth (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <counter>
        <name>Maze Walker</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Labyrinth (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Illusory Maze (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you create a 30-foot-radius Sphere of shifting walls of illusion centered on a point that you can see within 60 feet of you. The Sphere is Difficult Terrain and Lightly Obscured. Creatures of your choice within the Sphere have Disadvantage on saving throws. The Sphere lasts for 1 minute or until you dismiss it as a Bonus Action.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Illusory Maze</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Labyrinth (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Maze Walker</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Labyrinth (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Mind's Compass (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</name>
        <text>You are Immune to the Charmed, Frightened, and Stunned conditions. Additionally, you can always recall the exact layout of any area you've been to.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Maze Walker</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Labyrinth (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Master of Mazes (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</name>
        <text>You can cast the Maze spell without expending a spell slot. When you cast it, you can target two creatures instead of one.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 29 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Maze Walker</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Labyrinth (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Druid Subclass: Circle of the Stone (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Druid Subclass: Circle of the Stone (HB)</name>
        <text>Uses the ancient strength of the stones

"The earth endures, the mountain watches, and the stones whisper secrets older than time."

Theme: Draw strength from the eternal resilience of stone, especially megalithic stones of prehistoric Europe, focusing on earth magic and endurance.

Playstyle: A tanky defender for team resilience.

Megaliths — literally "big stones" — were widely used by prehistoric communities to build monuments, burial places, and sanctuaries. Megalithic tombs, dolmens and other monuments represent the oldest surviving indigenous architecture of Europe. Understanding this heritage is essential to tracing our very origins. Megalithic monuments are among the most widespread remains of man in time and space. Some of these monuments have been interpreted as observatories, through which it is possible to chart the movement of celestial objects, as they are all oriented towards the movement of the sun. Some, such as Stonehenge, have been perceived as tools for the prediction of solar and lunar eclipses. Europe has a vast megalithic heritage, which can be explored through many different routes covering Sweden, Denmark, Germany, the Netherlands, Spain, Great Britain, Italy and France.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Circle of the Stone Spells (Circle of the Stone (HB))</name>
        <text>When you reach a Druid level specified in the Circle of the Stone Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Circle of the Stone Spells:
Druid Level | Prepared Spells
3 | Absorb Elements, Earth Tremor, Longstrider, Thunderwave
5 | Shatter, Spike Growth
7 | Erupting Earth, Meld into Stone
9 | Transmute Rock, Wall of Stone

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Stoneskin Aura (Circle of the Stone (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can manifest a protective aura of stone around you as a 10-foot Emanation that lasts for 1 minute. You and any creature of your choice in the Emanation gain Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Stoneskin Aura</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Stone (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Earthen Stability (Circle of the Stone (HB))</name>
        <text>TYou cannot be moved or pushed against your will or have the Prone condition while standing on the ground. Additionally, you can use your Reaction to grant a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you Immunity to the Prone condition or pushed when they are the target of an effect.
	You can use this feature twice, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Earthen Stability</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Stone (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Stonecaller (Circle of the Stone (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain the ability to manipulate earth and stone. You can cast the Stone Shape and Erupting Earth spells without expending a spell slot.
	You can cast each of these spells once, and you regain the expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Stonecaller</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Stone (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Living Bastion (Circle of the Stone (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to stone makes you a symbol of endurance. As a Bonus Action, you regain Hit Points equal to twice your Druid level.
	You can use this feature twice, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.
	Additionally, while the Stoneskin Aura is active, you and each creature of your choice are also Immune to the Paralyzed and Restrained condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 28 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Living Bastion</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Circle of the Stone (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Absorb Elements</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Earth Tremor</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Longstrider</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Thunderwave</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shatter</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spike Growth</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Erupting Earth</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Meld Into Stone</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Transmute Rock</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Stone</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Stone Shape</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Stone (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Disguise Self</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dissonant Whispers</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Expeditious Retreat</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tasha's Hideous Laughter</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Person</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Misty Step</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hypnotic Pattern</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Nondetection</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Freedom of Movement</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Maze</name>
    <classes>Druid [5.5e] (Circle of the Labyrinth (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
