<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Ranger [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Ranger Subclass: Outlaw of Sherwood (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Subclass: Outlaw of Sherwood (HB)</name>
        <text>Fight cunningly tyranny and oppression

Lythe and listen, gentlemen
That be of free-born blood
I shall you tell of a good yeoman
His name was Robyn Hode
— A Gest of Robyn Hode, lines 1-4

Theme: Inspired by Robin Hood and his Merry Men, these rangers use cunning and trickery to protect the downtrodden and combat oppression.

Playstyle: A rogue-like ranger, focusing on stealth, ambushes, and guerrilla tactics. Excel at disrupting enemies and aiding allies, embodying the spirit of a trickster.

The Merry Men are the group of outlaws who follow Robin Hood in English literature and folklore. The group appears in the earliest ballads about Robin Hood and remains popular in modern adaptations. The Merry Men are Robin Hood's group who work to rob from the rich and give to the poor. They have antagonized the tyrannical rule of Prince John while King Richard is fighting in the Crusades. This also puts them into conflict with Prince John's minions, Guy of Gisbourne and the Sheriff of Nottingham.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 45 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Guerrilla Tactics (Outlaw of Sherwood (HB))</name>
        <text>You can take the Dash or Hide Action as a Bonus Action.
	When you make a ranged attack against a creature and you have the Invisible condition, the attack deals an extra 1d6 damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 45 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Extra Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Robin's Rally (Outlaw of Sherwood (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you grant Temporary Hit Points equal to your Ranger level plus your Wisdom modifier to each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you. Additionally, target creatures can use their Reaction to move up to half their Speed without provoking Opportunity Attacks.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 45 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Robin's Rally</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Outlaw of Sherwood (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Forest's Wrath (Outlaw of Sherwood (HB))</name>
        <text>When you make a ranged weapon attack against a creature, you can use a Bonus Action to make the area within 10 feet of the target Difficult Terrain until the start of your next turn.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.
	Additionally, your ranged weapon attacks ignore Half and Three-Quarters Cover.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 45 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Forest's Wrath</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Outlaw of Sherwood (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Forest's Wrath</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Outlaw of Sherwood (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Trickster's Gambit (Outlaw of Sherwood (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Reaction when a creature attacks you, you can force it to target a creature of your choice within 5 feet of you instead.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 45 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Trickster's Gambit</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Outlaw of Sherwood (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Forest's Wrath</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Outlaw of Sherwood (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Trickster's Gambit</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Outlaw of Sherwood (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Ranger Subclass: Stone Age Tracker (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Subclass: Stone Age Tracker (HB)</name>
        <text>Roam the land surviving in the wild

"The land speaks, and I listen. The old ways are not forgotten, only waiting to be remembered"

Theme: Tapping into the primal instincts and survival skills of prehistoric hunters, Stone Age Trackers are masters of tracking prey, setting traps, and thriving in harsh wilderness. Their connection to the land is deep and intuitive, and their tools are crafted from natural materials.

Playstyle: A highly resourceful ranger focused on tracking, ambushes, and survival. Excel in hostile terrain and use cunning traps and tools to control the battlefield and overwhelm foes.

Paleolithic people survived by hunting and gathering. The search for food was their main activity, and it was often difficult. They had to learn which animals to hunt and which plants to eat. Paleolithic people hunted buffalo, bison, wild goats, reindeer, and other animals, depending on where they lived.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 46 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Primal Hunter (Stone Age Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain Proficiency in Survival and Nature, and you can add double your Proficiency Bonus to checks made to track creatures or locate natural resources.
	While in Difficult Terrain, your Speed is not reduced.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 46 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Primitive Weaponry (Stone Age Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>You can craft primitive weapons using natural materials during a Short or Long Rest. These include:

	Barbed Spear. When you hit a creature with this weapon, it cannot take Reactions until the end of your next turn.

	Stone Net. A thrown weapon with a range of 15/30 feet. A Large or smaller creature hit by the net must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Strength modifier). Failure: Restrained condition. The target can use its Action to make another Strength saving throw to ending the condition on itself.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 46 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Ambush Predator (Stone Age Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>When you hit a creature that hasn't taken a turn yet, you deal an additional 2d8 damage.
	Additionally, when you roll Initiative, you can move up to half your Speed without provoking Opportunity Attacks.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 46 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Extra Damage">2d8</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Master Trapper (Stone Age Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>You can create traps as part of your preparation for combat. When you finish a Short or Long Rest, you can prepare up to two traps in a 10-foot square area. These include:

	Pitfall Trap. A creature entering the area must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Wisdom modifier). Failure: Prone condition and 3d8 Bludgeoning damage.

	Snare Trap. A creature entering the area must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Wisdom modifier). Failure: Restrained condition until the end of its next turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 46 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Apex Survivalist (Stone Age Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>You can no longer be surprised and you gain Resistance to all damage types.
	Additionally, as a Bonus Action, you can grant yourself Blindsight up to 30 feet until the end of your next turn.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 46 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Apex Survivalist</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Stone Age Tracker (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Apex Survivalist</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Stone Age Tracker (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Ranger Subclass: Valkyrie Scout (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Subclass: Valkyrie Scout (HB)</name>
        <text>Bring fate and ultimate doom upon enemies

"I ride with the wind and strike with the storm. No warrior dies unmarked beneath my gaze"

Theme: Emulating the legendary Valkyries of Norse mythology, these rangers act as battlefield guides and emissaries of fate. They excel in marking foes for judgment, inspiring allies, and controlling the flow of combat.

Playstyle: A support and control ranger.

Valkyrie, in Norse mythology, are of a group of maidens who served the god Odin and were sent by him to the battlefields to choose the slain who were worthy of a place in Valhalla. These foreboders of war rode to the battlefield on horses, wearing helmets and shields; in some accounts, they flew through the air and sea. Some Valkyries had the power to cause the death of the warriors they did not favour; others, especially heroine Valkyries, guarded the lives and ships of those dear to them. Old Norse literature made references to purely supernatural Valkyries and also to human Valkyries with certain supernatural powers. Both types of beings were associated with fairness, brightness, and gold, as well as bloodshed.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 43 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Judgment of the Fallen (Valkyrie Scout (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can mark a creature that you can see within 60 feet as Fated. You and your allies have advantage on attack rolls against Fated creatures for 1 minute.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 43 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Judgment of the Fallen</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Valkyrie Scout (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Shield of Fate (Valkyrie Scout (HB))</name>
        <text>When a creature that you can see within 10 feet of you is hit by an attack, you can use your Reaction to reduce the damage by 1d10 + your Wisdom modifier.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 43 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Damage Reduction">1d10+%5</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Shield of Fate</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Valkyrie Scout (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Shield of Fate</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Valkyrie Scout (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Wings of the Valkyrie (Valkyrie Scout (HB))</name>
        <text>You sprout spectral wings as a Bonus Action for 1 minute. You gain a Fly Speed 30 feet.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 43 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Wings of the Valkyrie</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Valkyrie Scout (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Shield of Fate</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Valkyrie Scout (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Valorous Resolve (Valkyrie Scout (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action you can grant to you and to each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you Temporary Hit Points equal to your Ranger level + your Wisdom modifier.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 43 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Valorous Resolve</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Valkyrie Scout (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Shield of Fate</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Valkyrie Scout (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Ranger Subclass: Wild Hunt Tracker (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Subclass: Wild Hunt Tracker (HB)</name>
        <text>Chase Otherworldly creatures

"I do not chase beasts—I chase those who have become them. The hunt never ends"

Theme: Chosen by the spectral Wild Hunt, these rangers pursue supernatural creatures and enforce balance between realms. They are relentless trackers and hunters of fey, fiends, and undead.

Playstyle: Specializes in tracking and dispatching otherworldly creatures.

The Wild Hunt is a folklore motif occurring across various northern, western and eastern European societies, appearing in the religions of the Germans, Celts, and Slavs. Wild Hunts typically involve a chase led by a mythological figure escorted by a ghostly or supernatural group of hunters engaged in pursuit.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 44 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hunter's Boon (Wild Hunt Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>You don't need Concentration on your hunter's mark spell if the target is a Fey, Fiend, or Undead.
	You gain Proficiency in Arcana or Religion (your choice).

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 44 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Ghostly Pursuit (Wild Hunt Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>When you deal damage to a Fey, Fiend, or Undead marked by your Hunter's Mark, you can force it to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Wisdom modifier). Failure: Frightened condition until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 44 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Hounds of the Hunt (Wild Hunt Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>You can summon two spectral hounds as a Bonus Action. These hounds use the stats of dire wolves but are Immune to Necrotic and Poison and have Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage. They take their actions during your turn and follow your orders as a Bonus Action. They disappear after 1 minute or when reduced to 0 Hit Points.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 44 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Hounds of the Hunt</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Wild Hunt Tracker (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Master of the Hunt (Wild Hunt Tracker (HB))</name>
        <text>Fey, Fiend, or Undead creatures marked by your Hunter's Mark cannot teleport or have the Invisible condition while within 60 feet of you. Additionally, attacks you make against these creatures deal an extra 2d6 damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 44 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Extra Damage">2d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
