<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Sorcerer [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Sorcerer Subclass: Oracle Sorcery (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerer Subclass: Oracle Sorcery (HB)</name>
        <text>Foresee events and change them through visions and prophecies

"The stars whisper, the bones tremble, and the future bends at my call—yet even I cannot see my own fate"

Theme: You are descended from the ancient oracles who communed with gods and fate itself. Your magic manifests through visions of the future and divine inspiration, allowing you to foresee danger and influence outcomes.

Playstyle: A highly tactical sorcerer who manipulates initiative, rerolls dice, and provides knowledge and advantages to allies while debuffing enemies.

During ancient Greece, the Oracle of Delphi served as a source of divine wisdom, nestled within the rough terrain of Mount Parnassus. This hallowed location acted for millennia as a medium between humans and the gods, providing enigmatic forecasts that influenced the path of human history. The Pythia, a priestess who acted as a medium for the deity of prophecy, Apollo, was located at the center of the Delphi sanctuary. Perched on a holy tripod in the inner sanctuary, or adyton, she breathed in the mist rising from a hole in the ground that was said to be the god himself. In a state of trance, the Pythia spoke in a language full of symbolism, her prophecies difficult for petitioners to understand without the assistance of translators.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 52 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oracle's Sight (Oracle Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can channel fate, imposing Advantage or Disadvantage on its next Test in the next minute on a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 52 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Oracle's Sight</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <counter>
        <name>Oracle's Sight</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Prophetic Echoes (Oracle Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>You can enter a trance-like state for 1 minute. While in this state, you can take the Dodge Action as a Bonus Action.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.
	Additionally, you can cast the Detect Thoughts spell once per Long Rest without expending a spell slot.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 52 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Prophetic Echoes</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Oracle's Sight</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Divine Insight (Oracle Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.
	You can cast the Commune and Divination spells once per Long Rest without expending a spell slot.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 52 (Homebrew)</text>
        <modifier category="saving throw">wisdom save +%0</modifier>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Divine Insight</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Oracle's Sight</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Divine Insight</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Visionary's Presence (Oracle Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain Truesight 60 feet.
	When you cast a spell, you can choose one creature within 30 feet. That creature cannot attack you until the start of your next turn unless it succeeds on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 52 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Oracle's Sight</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Divine Insight</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oracle Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Sorcerer Subclass: Runestone Sorcery (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerer Subclass: Runestone Sorcery (HB)</name>
        <text>Use your gift in the power of Runes for divination and combat

Beer I bring thee, tree of battle,
Mingled of strength and mighty fame;
Charms it holds and healing signs,
Spells full good, and gladness-runes.
— Edda, Sigrdrífumál, Stanze 5

Theme: Your bloodline is tied to the ancient runes of the Norse, where mystic symbols hold the power of creation, protection, and destruction. Your magic manifests through carving runes into the fabric of reality.

Playstyle: A strategic sorcerer who places rune-like effects on the battlefield, enhancing allies or hindering enemies. Offers defensive and utility options alongside steady damage.

There is some evidence that, in addition to being a writing system, runes historically served purposes of magic. This is the case from the earliest epigraphic evidence of the Roman to the Germanic Iron Age, with non-linguistic inscriptions and the alu word. An erilaz appears to have been a person versed in runes, including their magic applications. In medieval sources, notably the Poetic Edda, the Sigrdrífumál mentions "victory runes" to be carved on a sword, "some on the grasp and some on the inlay, and name Tyr twice."

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 54 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Rune-Carved Magic (Runestone Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>When you finish a Long Rest rest, choose one of the following runes to empower yourself:

	Isa (Ice Rune). Gain Resistance to Cold damage and deal additional Cold damage equal to your Charisma modifier with spells.

	Thurisaz (Destruction Rune). Once per turn, add your Charisma modifier to damage dealt to a creature when you hit it with a spell.

	Algiz (Protection Rune). You and your Allies within 10 feet of you gain a +1 bonus to AC.

A rune lasts for 8 hours.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 54 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Mystic Runes (Runestone Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>You can inscribe temporary runes on weapons and armor during a Long Rest. Weapons gain +1 to attack and damage rolls, and armor grants a +1 AC bonus.
	You can inscribe a number of weapons and armor equal to your Proficiency Bonus.

The runes last for 8 hours.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 54 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Eternal Inscription (Runestone Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>You can cast the Glyph of Warding spell once per Long Rest without expending a spell slot.

Your runes last for 24 hours.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 54 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Master of the Runes (Runestone Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain Resistance to any type of damage while within 10 feet of a rune you've created.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 54 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Sorcerer Subclass: Siren Sorcery (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerer Subclass: Siren Sorcery (HB)</name>
        <text>Enchant creatures through the blood of the Siren

"Così dissero, cantando con bella voce: e il mio cuore
voleva ascoltare e ordinai ai compagni di sciogliermi,
facendo segno cogli occhi: ma essi curvi remavano"
— Odissea, Canto XII, 192-194

Theme: You are descended from the mythical sirens of legend, whose enchanting voices could bend the will of mortals. Your magic calls to the hearts of others, luring them to their fate or guiding them to safety.

Playstyle: A charm and enchantment specialist who excels at social interactions and subterfuge.

In Greek mythology, sirens (Ancient Greek: singular: Σειρήν, Seirḗn; plural: Σειρῆνες, Seirênes) are female humanlike beings with alluring voices; they appear in a scene in the Odyssey in which Odysseus saves his crew's lives. Roman poets place them on some small islands called Sirenum scopuli. In some later, rationalized traditions, the literal geography of the "flowery" island of Anthemoessa, or Anthemusa, is fixed: sometimes on Cape Pelorum and at others in the islands known as the Sirenuse, near Paestum, or in Capreae. All such locations were surrounded by cliffs and rocks. Sirens continued to be used as a symbol of the dangerous temptation embodied by women regularly throughout Christian art of the medieval era. "Siren" can also be used as a slang term for a woman considered both very attractive and dangerous.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 53 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Magic of the Siren (Siren Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain proficiency in Persuasion. When you cast a spell that causes the Charmed or Frightened condition, you can expend 1 Sorcery Point to impose Disadvantage on the target's saving throw.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 53 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Alluring Presence (Siren Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>Creatures with the Charmed condition by you have Disadvantage on attack rolls against you and saving throws against your spells.
	You can cast the Suggestion spell without expending a spell slot once per Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 53 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Alluring Presence</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Siren Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Siren's Song (Siren Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you sing a haunting melody. Creatures of your choice within 60 feet that can hear you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Charmed condition and can't take actions or bonus actions and must use their Speed to move towards you until the start of your next turn.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 53 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Siren's Song</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Siren Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Siren's Song</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Siren Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Siren's Command (Siren Sorcery (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you sing a hypnotic melody. All creatures of your choice that can hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Charmed and Incapacitated condition for 1 minute. Targets can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of their turns, ending the conditions on a success.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 53 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Siren's Song</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Siren Sorcery (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
