<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Barbarian [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Barbarian Subclass: Path of the Celts (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Barbarian Subclass: Path of the Celts (HB)</name>
        <text>Fight according to traditions and nature

"Blood and earth, iron and fire, this is the warrior's path."

Theme: Barbarians who embody the mysticism, warrior traditions, and fierce independence of the ancient Celts. They draw strength from nature, channeling primal energies to protect allies and devastate foes.

Playstyle: A hybrid of offensive ferocity and primal magic, focusing on battlefield control, mystic resistance, and empowering allies.

The Celts were a collection of tribes which originated in central Europe. Although separate tribes, they had similar culture, traditions, religious beliefs and language in common. First mention of the Celts was made by the Greeks authors between 540 and 424BC. But the most valuable insights are provided by Roman authors — as the Roman world was expanding, they came in direct contact with the Celts on their northern borders.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Primal Battle Frenzy (Path of the Celts (HB))</name>
        <text>When you enter a Rage, you enhance it with ancient primal energy. While raging, you gain the following benefits:

	• When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can deal an additional 1d6 Force damage.

	• You and your Allies within 10 feet of you are Immune to the Frightened condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Additional Force Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Mystical Ward (Path of the Celts (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to nature grants you protective magic. As a Reaction, when you or one of your Allies within 30 feet of you is hit by an attack, you can reduce the damage by 1d10 + your Barbarian level.
	You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Damage Reduction">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Wrath of the Ancestors (Path of the Celts (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you call for help from your ancestors that appear as spectral Celtic warriors around you in a 15-foot Emanation for 1 minute. The Emanation provides the following effects:

	• Hostile Creatures within the Emanation have Disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you.

	• Your Allies within the Emanation gain a bonus to saving throws equal to your Rage Damage Bonus.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Wrath of the Ancestors</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Path of the Celts (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Oath of the Ancestors (Path of the Celts (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to your ancestors allows you to shield your allies even further. When a creature Allied to you within 30 feet of you drops to 0 hit points but isn't outright killed, you can use your Reaction to have them drop to 1 hit point instead.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Oath of the Ancestors</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Path of the Celts (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Barbarian Subclass: Path of the Highlanders (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Barbarian Subclass: Path of the Highlanders (HB)</name>
        <text>Dominate the battlefield with might and inspiring the others

"From the cliffs to the glens, I fight for my land and my kin!"

Theme: Inspired by the fierce clansmen of the Scottish Highlands, Highlander Barbarians blend endurance, skill with great weapons, and rousing battle cries to dominate the battlefield.

Playstyle: Tough and disciplined warriors with an emphasis on heavy weapons, resilience, and rallying allies in the heat of battle.

In Scotland, by the 13th century, a distinctive culture was indeed evolving in the Highlands, where clan chiefs would confer lands upon warriors in exchange for their services. By the 17th century the stronger clans had overwhelmed the weaker and were able to defy efforts by the monarchs in the Lowlands (who had become monarchs of England as well) to assert control. Highland warriors had become renowned for expertise using sword, shield, and a shorter sword known as a dirk.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Clanblade Tactics (Path of the Highlanders (HB))</name>
        <text>Your skill with heavy weapons is unparalleled. While raging, when you wield a melee weapon with the Heavy property, on a successful hit you deal an additional damage equal to your Proficiency Bonus.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Rallying Cry (Path of the Highlanders (HB))</name>
        <text>You can inspire your allies with your booming voice. As a Bonus Action, you can let out a cry that grants Temporary hit points equal to 1d10 + your Barbarian level to a number of creatures that can hear you equal to your proficiency bonus within 30 feet of you.
	You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Temporary Hit Points">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Rallying Cry</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Path of the Highlanders (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Rallying Cry</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Path of the Highlanders (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Fortitude of the Highlands (Path of the Highlanders (HB))</name>
        <text>Your body is as unyielding as the highlands you defend. While raging, you gain Resistance to Cold, Fire, and Lightning damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Rallying Cry</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Path of the Highlanders (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Unbreakable Charge (Path of the Highlanders (HB))</name>
        <text>You can charge through enemy lines with unstoppable force. As a Bonus Action, you can move up to 30 feet in a straight line without provoking Opportunity Attacks. Each creature of Large or smaller Size in your path must make a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your Strength modifier + your proficiency bonus).

	• Failure: 4d10 Bludgeoning damage and Prone condition.
	• Success: Half as much damage.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage">4d10</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Unbreakable Charge</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Path of the Highlanders (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <counter>
        <name>Rallying Cry</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Path of the Highlanders (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
