<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Black Death Domain (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Black Death Domain (HB)</name>
        <text>Spread and retain disease at your will

"To cure or to cull, to heal or to harm—faith and pestilence are two hands of the same god."

Theme: Masters of life and death, these clerics wield plague magic to heal and harm in equal measure.

Playstyle: Poison-based abilities, battlefield control, and resilience.

The Black Death was a devastating global epidemic of bubonic plague that struck Europe and Asia in the mid1300s. The plague arrived in Europe in October 1347, when 12 ships from the Black Sea docked at the Sicilian port of Messina. People gathered on the docks were met with a horrifying surprise: Most sailors aboard the ships were dead, and those still alive were gravely ill and covered in black boils that oozed blood and pus. Sicilian authorities hastily ordered the fleet of "death ships" out of the harbor, but it was too late: Over the next five years, the Black Death would kill more than 20 million people in Europe—almost one-third of the continent's population.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 22 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Toxic Cloud (Black Death Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>When you deal Poison damage to a creature, you can reduce its Speed by 10 feet until the end of its next turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 22 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Miasma of Decay (Black Death Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you present your Holy Symbol and expend one use of your Channel Divinity to create a 15-foot radius Sphere of toxic gas centered at a point that you can see within 60 feet of you. Creatures of your choice in the area must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: 3d6 Poison damage and the Poisoned condition until the end of your next turn. Success: Half damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 22 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Poison Damage">3d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Black Death Spells (Black Death Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Black Death Spells:
Level | Spell
3rd | Ray of Sickness, False Life, Protection from Poison
5th | Animate Dead, Stinking Cloud
7th | Blight, Death Ward
9th | Cloudkill, Contagion

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 22 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Epidemic Aura (Black Death Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>When a creature Hostile within 60 feet of you starts its turn and has the Poisoned condition, it takes 2d6 Poison damage.
	Additionally, you are Immune to Poison damage and to the Poisoned condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 22 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Poison Damage">2d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Master of Plagues (Black Death Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your spells and abilities ignore Resistance and Immunity to Poison damage and Poisoned condition.
	Additionally, when you cause Poison damage, you can deal a double amount of that damage. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 22 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Master of Plagues</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Black Death Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Cathedral Domain (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Cathedral Domain (HB)</name>
        <text>Draw power through majestic city cathedrals

"Stone endures longer than empires—let faith rise as high as the spires above."

Theme: A bastion of faith and order, who channels the divine majesty and awe of grand places of worship, and channel the grandeur and discipline of their church, turning devotion into undeniable might.

Playstyle: Radiant damage, auras, and support.

The building of monumental cathedrals in the middle ages was a reflection of faith and the channel for much of the creative energy of medieval European society. Although cathedral building was driven by religious figures or institutions, it was often a community effort. The Cathedral was a place of Catholic worship and the seat of the Bishop of the diocese, but it was also a symbol of Paradise. In Medieval times, it was the centerpiece of the community, representing hope and refuge. Refuge from the struggles and difficulties of human life; hope of the promise of Heaven while in the presence of God. Its very structure should make men yearn for Heaven. Cathedrals were built to evoke that feeling through their structure and art, both rich in symbolism.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Divine Awe (Cathedral Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Hostile creatures within 10 feet of you have Disadvantage on saving throws against the Frightened condition and your Allies have Advantage on saving throws against the Frightened condition.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Holy Aura (Cathedral Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you present your Holy Symbol and expend one use of your Channel Divinity to emit a divine aura that reaches up to six creatures of your choice within 30 feet of you. For 1 minute, target creatures gain Temporary Hit Points equal to 1d8 + your Cleric level at the start of each of their next turns and deal an extra 1d6 radiant damage on their attacks.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Temporary Hit Points">1d8</roll>
        <roll description="Radiant Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Cathedral Domain Spells (Cathedral Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Cathedral Domain Spells:
Level Spell
3rd | Bless, Command, Shield of Faith, Sanctuary
5th | Beacon of Hope, Spirit Guardians
7th | Aura of Life, Stone Shape
9th | Greater Restoration, Wall of Stone

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Pillar of Light (Cathedral Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>When you cast a spell that deals Radiant damage, you can force one creature affected by the spell to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Blinded condition until the end of your next turn.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Pillar of Light</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Cathedral Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Pillar of Light</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Cathedral Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Pillar of Light</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Cathedral Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Divine Ground (Cathedral Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you evoke a 30-foot radius, 60-foot-high Cylinder of divine light centered on a point that you can see within 60 feet of you. The Cylinder lasts for 1 minute. Each creature that starts its turn in the Cylinder gains 3d6 hit points up to its maximum or takes 3d6 Radiant damage (your choice). On each of your subsequent turns, you can use your Bonus Action to move the Cylinder up to 30 feet in any direction.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 23 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Hit Points">3d6</roll>
        <roll description="Radiant Damage">3d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Pillar of Light</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Cathedral Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB)</name>
        <text>Protect the others through the power of hearth

"Where the fire burns, so too does hope. My faith is not in walls or gods—it is in the warmth that binds us together."

Theme: Protectors and nurturers, clerics of the Hearth create sanctuaries of warmth and safety, bolstering allies and defending them from harm.

Playstyle: Healing, defensive utility, and area control.

Hearth was a common topic and icon in many ancient European religions. The hearth also served as a communal and ritualistic space, where stories were told, and bonds strengthened. This reverence for the hearth can be seen in burial practices and household rituals, with fire representing life and death cycles. Even in folklore, the hearth was immensely symbolic.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Warming Embrace (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>Each creature Allied to you within 10 feet of you gains Resistance to Cold and Fire damage.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Hearth Domain Spells (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Hearth Domain Spells:
Level | Spell
3rd | Sanctuary, Cure Wounds, Shield of Faith, Calm Emotions
5th | Beacon of Hope, Leomund's Tiny Hut
7th | Aura of Purity, Guardian of Faith
9th | Hallow, Mass Cure Wounds

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Guardian's Flame (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you present your Holy Symbol and expend one use of your Channel Divinity to summon protective flames around up to three creatures of your choice within 30 feet of you. Each creature gains temporary hit points equal to 2d8 + your Cleric level and has Advantage on Tests until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Temporary Hit Points">2d8</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Hearth of Safety (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>When one creature that you can see within 30 feet takes damage, you can use your Reaction to teleport it to an unoccupied space within 10 feet of you, reducing the damage it takes by 2d8 + your Wisdom modifier.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Damage Reduction">2d8</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Eternal Hearth (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>Your Warming Embrace radius expands to 30 feet. Each creature Allied to you within 30 feet of you is also Immune to the Frightened and Charmed conditions, and creatures Hostile within 30 feet of you can't be surprised con have Advantage on Initiative rolls.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 20 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Heresy Domain (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Heresy Domain (HB)</name>
        <text>Inspire others defying the established divine order

"The truth is not written in stone, but in the whispers of the doubters, the fire of the condemned, and the revelations of those who dare to question."

Theme: Inspired by the real-world heresies of medieval Europe (such as the Cathars, Hussites, and Lollards), this domain represents faith as rebellion.

The gods may grant power, but the Heretic dares to question their authority.

Playstyle: Blend divine magic with cunning defiance, gaining powers that fuel rebellion, protect outcasts, and challenge the authority of the gods themselves.

Heresy was an opinion about the teaching of the Catholic church, which was condemned by the church as inconsistent with it. First heretics groups started in XI century and lasted until XVI century. Heretics were religious groups whose beliefs did not wholly conform with the medieval Church's doctrines. While the groups themselves ranged in beliefs, their commonality was their rejection of and persecution by the Church. Many of the groups still thought of themselves as Christians despite the Church's rejection. Some felt that the Church had changed too much and that it, in fact, was heretical. In this way, heretics were both within and outside the Church. It is often hard to determine whose beliefs were truly heretical.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Profane Revelation (Heresy Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you expend one use of your Channel Divinity to unleash a blasphemous truth that undermines divine power. You force creatures of your choice within 30 feet that relies on divine magic (including Clerics, Paladins, and Celestials) to make a Wisdom saving throw. Failure: Incapacitated condition until the end of your next turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Inquisition's Bane (Heresy Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your faith is tempered by hardship. You gain Resistance to Radiant and Necrotic damage, and you have Advantage on saving throws against spells or other magical effects that detect truth or compel honesty (such as Zone of Truth).

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Heresy Domain Spells (Heresy Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Heresy Domain Spells:
Level Spell
3rd | Cause Fear, Detect Magic, Disguise Self, Hellish Rebuke
5th | Suggestion, Silence
7th | Blight, Counterspell
9th | Dispel Evil and Good, Greater Invisibility

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Martyr's Fire (Heresy Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>You can endure suffering to fuel your cause. When you take damage from an enemy, you can use your Reaction to bestow to a creature that you can see within 30 feet to gain Temporary Hit Points equal to your Cleric level + your Wisdom modifier. Additionally, you can also immediately make a weapon attack or cast a cantrip.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Proficiency Bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Martyr's Fire</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Heresy Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Martyr's Fire</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Heresy Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Martyr's Fire</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Heresy Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Divine Schism (Heresy Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your presence warps the flow of divine power, severing the connection between the heavens and the battlefield. As a Magic Action, any creature of your choice within 30 feet of you has the following effects for 1 minute:

	• Loses Resistance and Immunity to Radiant and Necrotic damage.

	• Each time it wants to cast a spell, it must succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your spell save DC.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by expending a 5+ level spell slot (no action required).

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 24 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Martyr's Fire</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Heresy Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
      <counter>
        <name>Divine Schism</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Heresy Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB)</name>
        <text>Use divine law as instrument of judgment and purification

"Truth is a blade that must be wielded without hesitation. Doubt is a sickness that must be purged."

Theme: Unyielding hands of faith, wielding magic not for mercy, but to interrogate, expose, and eradicate falsehoods.

Playstyle: Specialized in investigation, coercion, and relentless pursuit of those who defy their faith. They control battlefields through fear and suppression, limiting enemy options while bolstering allies with unwavering certainty.

The Inquisition was a powerful office set up within the Catholic Church to root out and punish heresy throughout Europe and the Americas. Beginning in the 12th century and continuing for hundreds of years, the Inquisition is infamous for the severity of its tortures and its persecution of Jews and Muslims. Its worst manifestation was in Spain, where the Spanish Inquisition was a dominant force for more than 200 years, resulting in some 32,000 executions.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Unyielding Authority (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain Advantage on Insight and Intimidation checks.
	Additionally, you can cast the Zone of Truth spell without expending a spell slot. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Trial by Fire (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>You present your Holy Symbol and expend one use of your Channel Divinity to invoke divine authority to expose and punish transgressors. As a Magic Action, you mark a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you as a heretic. For 1 minute, the target suffers the following effects:

	• If it lies, it takes Radiant damage equal to your Cleric level and has the Incapacitated condition until the end of its next turn.

	• If it casts a spell, it must first make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: the spell doesn't have effect and is wasted.

	• If it attempts to use its movement, it must first make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Its Speed is halved until the start of its next turn.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Inquisition Domain Spells (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Inquisition Domain Spells:
Level Spell
3rd | Command, Detect Magic, Hunter's Mark, Zone of Truth
5th | Hold Person, See Invisibility
7th | Counterspell, Locate Creature
9th | Banishment, Dominate Person

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Unyielding Authority</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Chains of Repentance (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can force it to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. Failure: Restrained condition for 1 minute as divine chains bind them in place. It can repeat the save at the end of each of their next turns, ending the condition on itself on a success.
	Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you finish a Short or Long rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Chains of Repentance</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
        <subclass>Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Divine Tribunal (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</name>
        <text>You create a 30-foot radius aura of judgment for 1 minute. While within this aura:

	• As a Magic Action, you evoke a 30-foot radius, 60-foot-high Cylinder of divine light centered on a point that you can see within 60 feet of you. The Cylinder lasts for 1 minute. On each of your subsequent turns, you can use your Bonus Action to move the Cylinder up to 30 feet in any direction. In the Cylinder, the following effects apply:

	• Creatures of your choice can't have the Invisible condition nor can they magically teleport or move (such as through the misty step spell)

	• Spells or magical effects of the illusion or enchantment school automatically fail.
	• Creatures of your choice add your Wisdom modifier to their Tests.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by expending a 5+ level spell slot (no action required).

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 25 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Divine Tribunal</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Cleric Subclass: Mysteries Domain (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cleric Subclass: Mysteries Domain (HB)</name>
        <text>Keeper of hidden truths and powerful divine magic

"The divine is not to be known, but to be sought. Every question is a prayer, every answer another veil to be lifted."

Theme: Keepers of divine secrets, clerics of Mysteries serves the hidden gods, the cryptic prophecies, and the sacred rites known only to the initiated. They speak in riddles, guard lost truths, and wield magic that veils, reveals, or warps reality itself. They uncover hidden truths and wield arcane power through their divine insight.

Playstyle: Supportive, through divination, arcane magic, and knowledge.

The Eleusinian Mysteries (Greek: Ἐλευσίνια Μυστήρια, romanized: Eleusínia Mystḗria) were initiations held every year for the cult of Demeter and Persephone based at the Panhellenic Sanctuary of Eleusis in ancient Greece. They are considered the "most famous of the secret religious rites of ancient Greece". Their basis was a Bronze Age agrarian cult, and there is some evidence that they were derived from the religious practices of the Mycenean period. The Mysteries represented the myth of the abduction of Persephone from her mother Demeter by the king of the underworld Hades. The rites, ceremonies, and beliefs were kept secret and consistently preserved from antiquity.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oracle's Insight (Mysteries Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>You start to understand the true secrets of the world. You gain the following benefits:

	• You are Proficient in Arcana. If you are already proficient, you gain Expertise.

	• You have Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects of the illusion and enchantment schools.

	• You learn the Minor Illusion cantrip. This cantrip is on top the number of cantrips you can normally learn, and Wisdom is your spellcasting ability to cast it.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Revelation (Mysteries Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Magic Action, you present your Holy Symbol and expend a use of your Channel Divinity to reveal hidden truths within a 30-foot radius. Invisible creatures and objects are revealed for 1 minute, and each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects of illusion and enchantment schools.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Mysteries Domain Spells (Mysteries Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>Your connection to this divine domain ensures you always have certain spells ready. When you reach a Cleric level specified in the table below, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Mysteries Domain Spells:
Level | Spell
3rd | Detect Magic, Identify, Augury, Mirror Image
5th | Clairvoyance, Dispel Magic
7th | Arcane Eye, Divination
9th | Scrying, Modify Memory

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Veil of Mystery (Mysteries Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Reaction, when an enemy targets you with an attack, you can impose Disadvantage on the roll and teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Veil of Mystery</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Mysteries Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <counter>
        <name>Veil of Mystery</name>
        <value>4</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Mysteries Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <counter>
        <name>Veil of Mystery</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Mysteries Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Oracle's Sight (Mysteries Domain (HB))</name>
        <text>You gain Truesight 120 feet. Additionally, you are Immune to Blinded condition and can't be surprised.

Source:	Old World's Might - Subclasses from Old Europe p. 21 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Veil of Mystery</name>
        <value>6</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Mysteries Domain (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Sanctuary</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB)), Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Beacon of Hope</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB)), Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Purity</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hallow</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cure Wounds</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shield of Faith</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB)), Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Calm Emotions</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Leomund's Tiny Hut</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Guardian of Faith</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mass Cure Wounds</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Hearth Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Detect Magic</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB)), Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB)), Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Identify</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Augury</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mirror Image</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Clairvoyance</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Magic</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Arcane Eye</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Divination</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Scrying</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Modify Memory</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Minor Illusion</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Mysteries Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ray of Sickness</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>False Life</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Protection from Poison</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Animate Dead</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Stinking Cloud</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blight</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB)), Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Death Ward</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cloudkill</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contagion</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Black Death Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bless</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Command</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB)), Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spirit Guardians</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Aura of Life</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Stone Shape</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Restoration</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Stone</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Cathedral Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cause Fear</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Disguise Self</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hellish Rebuke</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Suggestion</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Silence</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Counterspell</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB)), Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dispel Evil and Good</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Heresy Domain (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hunter's Mark</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Zone of Truth</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Hold Person</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>See Invisibility</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Locate Creature</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Banishment</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dominate Person</name>
    <classes>Cleric [5.5e] (Inquisition Domain (OWM) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
