<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<source>
  <name>The Old World's Might</name>
  <abbreviation>owm</abbreviation>
  <url>https://www.dmsguild.com/en/product/513310/the-old-world-s-might-subclasses-from-old-europe</url>
  <author>Marco Giulio Fossati</author>
  <publisher>Dungeon Master's Guild</publisher>
  <website>https://www.dmsguild.com/en/browse?author=%22Marco%20Giulio%20Fossati%22</website>
  <category>Homebrew [5.5e]</category>
  <pubdate>2025-02-23</pubdate>
  <description>The Old World's Might
Subclasses from Old Europe

A 70-page supplement featuring 45 new subclasses inspired by the legends, warriors, and mystics of Europe's past.

Step into a world shaped by the cultures, myths, and warriors of Old Europe. The Old World's Might brings 45 unique subclasses to your table, each drawing from historical and legendary traditions spanning from prehistory to the dawn of the industrial era. Whether you seek the wisdom of ancient druids, the resolve of knightly orders, or the cunning of legendary outlaws, this supplement expands your game with new possibilities.

What's Inside?

	• 45 brand-new subclasses for every core class, fully compatible with 2024 rules.
	• A rich tapestry of themes drawn from Celtic warriors, Renaissance duelists, Viking scouts, and more.
	• Deeply thematic abilities that bring each subclass to life with historically inspired mechanics.
	• Curated spell lists for clerics, paladins, druids, sorcerers, and warlocks, reflecting their sacred and mystical traditions.

Discover New Powers for Your Characters

	• Barbarian: Channel the battle rage of the Highlander or the sacred fury of the Celts.
	• Bard: Inspire with the epics of the Skald or the theatrical flair of the Cabaret.
	• Druid: Walk the mystic paths of the Stone or the Labyrinth.
	• Fighter: Master the disciplined formations of the Hoplite or the daring bravado of the Landsknecht.
	• Ranger: Hunt with the Wild Hunt Tracker or roam as an Outlaw of Sherwood.
	• Rogue: Embrace the masked intrigue of the Venetian spy or the ruthlessness of the Highwayman.
	• Paladin: Swear oaths of knighthood with the Templar, the Hospitaller, or the Varangian Guard.
	• Sorcerer: Wield the untamed power of the Oracle, the Siren, or the Runestone's magic.
	• Warlock: Serve the enigmatic Muse or one of the Four Horsemen.
	• Wizard: Delve into the arcane secrets of Renaissance Art, Illuminism, or Alchemy.

Why Choose This Supplement?

	• Authentically Inspired: Each subclass is grounded in European history, folklore, and tradition.
	• Balanced and Playable: Designed for seamless integration with official rules.
	• Expands Roleplaying Depth: Bring rich cultural themes to your game, whether in historical campaigns or fantasy worlds.</description>
  <collection>
    <doc href="class-barbarian-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-bard-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-cleric-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-druid-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-fighter-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-paladin-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-ranger-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-rogue-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-sorcerer-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-warlock-owm.xml"/>
    <doc href="class-wizard-owm.xml"/>
  </collection>
</source>
