<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Alchemist (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <hd>8</hd>
    <proficiency>Constitution, Intelligence, Arcana, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Sleight of Hand, Survival</proficiency>
    <numSkills>3</numSkills>
    <armor>Light Armor</armor>
    <weapons>Simple Weapons, Improvised Weapons</weapons>
    <tools>Alchemist's Supplies</tools>
    <wealth>5d4x10</wealth>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <trait>
      <name>Alchemist</name>
      <text>Often found cooped-up experimenting or scavenging for ingredients, the Alchemist is a student of the metaphysical essence of things, and is as curious as they are resourceful.

Playing an Alchemist
This class grants you features to create a low defense, high damage and utility martial blaster.

Action: Utilize
Bonus Action (Set-Up): Catalyze
Movement: Far from enemies, but within throw range.
Reaction: Defensive features, such as Mind Over Matter.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 1 (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Becoming An Alchemist As A Level 1 Character</name>
        <text>As a 1st-level Alchemist, you begin play with 8 + your Constitution modifier hit points.

Core Alchemist Traits
Primary Ability: Intelligence
Hit Point Die: D8 per Alchemist Level
Saving Throw Proficiencies: Constitution, Intelligence
Skill Proficiencies: Choose 3: Arcana, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Sleight of Hand, Survival
Weapon Proficiencies: Improvised and Simple weapons
Tool Proficiencies: Alchemist's Supplies
Armor Training: Light armor
Starting Equipment: Choose A or B: (A) Alchemist's Fire, 5 GP of raw materials, Light Crossbow, 20 Bolts, Case, Padded Armor, 5 Flasks, Alchemist's Supplies, and an Explorer's Pack, and 5 GP; or (B) 150 GP

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 1 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Becoming An Alchemist As A Multiclass Character</name>
        <text>Core Alchemist Traits
Hit Point Die: D8 per Alchemist level
Skill Proficiencies: one from Arcana, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Sleight of Hand, or Survival
Tool Proficiencies: Alchemist Supplies
Armor Training: Light armor

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 1 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 1: Alchemy</name>
        <text>Your practice of alchemical research has trained you to use and create devastating concoctions.

	Formulae: Formulae are the recipes to Craft Alchemical Items with Alchemist's Supplies. You know the Formulae listed below, as well as two other Alchemical Items of your choice.

Acid
Alchemist's Fire
Antitoxin
Candle
Component Pouch
Oil
Perfume
Potion of Healing

	Learning Formulae: Whenever you gain an Alchemist Level, you learn the Formula for another Alchemical Item of your choice. If you find Formulae during your adventures, you can add them to the Formulae you know. You can also research a Potion or Alchemical Item to learn its Formula. Either way takes 2 hours of time spent with a set of Alchemist's Supplies. If the Item has a rarity of Common, the time required is doubled, and doubles again for each rank above Common.

	Craft Discount: You only need to provide 5 GP worth of raw materials to Craft any item worth 50 GP or less that you know how to Craft with Alchemist's Supplies, and can Craft these items in 1 day, rather than their purchase price divided by 5.

	Item Attacks: Whenever you attack with Alchemical Items, you can use your Intelligence modifier for the DC instead of using Dexterity. Further, the range you can throw them is doubled and being within 5 feet of the target does not impose Disadvantage on the D20 Test.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 1 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 1: Catalyze</name>
        <text>On your turn, you can take one of the following actions as a Bonus Action: Study or Utilize to use an Item that normally calls for an Action.
	Whenever you take the Utilize Action while holding Alchemist's Supplies in-hand, you can create any of the items you can Craft with them, ignoring the Time requirement. Items created this way only last for 1 minute, then lose their potency.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 1 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 2: Methodical</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Experimentalist. Choose two of your skill proficiencies with which you lack Expertise. You gain Expertise in those skills.

	Fast Hands. You can draw or store two items during your Free Interaction, rather than one.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 1 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 3: Alchemist Subclass</name>
        <text>You gain an Alchemist Subclass of your choice, detailed after this class's description. A subclass is a specialization that grants you features at certain Alchemist levels.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 4: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify. You gain this feature again at Alchemist levels 8, 12, and 16.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 5: Eureka</name>
        <text>You can use the Bonus Action granted by Catalyze to Craft a Potion with a rarity of Common that you know the Formula for, which otherwise follows the same rules for Catalyze.
	Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a Long Rest. The rarity increases as you gain levels in this class, starting at 9th level (Uncommon) and again at 13th level (Rare).

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 5: Extra Attack</name>
        <text>You can attack twice instead of once whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Subclass Feature</name>
        <text>You gain a feature from your Alchemist Subclass.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 7: Mix</name>
        <text>While you have two Alchemical Items or Potions in hand and neither is the same item, you can use the Bonus Action granted by Catalyze to swiftly, and safely, combine them. When used, both effects occur simultaneously. Attempting to use this feature with an Item previously combined by this feature results in both items losing their potency and being destroyed.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 8: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 9: Eureka (Uncommon)</name>
        <text>The rarity of the Potion you can create with your Eureka feature increases to Uncommon.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 9: Mercurial Flux</name>
        <text>Items you Craft with Catalyze now last for 1 hour before losing their potency.
	Further, you can replace the raw materials to Craft Alchemical Items you know the Formula for with valuables (such as GP) of a value equal to or greater than the cost of the raw materials.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Subclass Feature</name>
        <text>You gain a feature from your Alchemist Subclass.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 11: Volatile Potency</name>
        <text>When a damage or healing roll is made with an Alchemical Item or Potion you Craft, you can roll 1d6 and add the result to the damage or healing of the item. This increases to 2d6 when you reach 17th level.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Extra Damage or Healing" level="11">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="Extra Damage or Healing" level="17">2d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 12: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 13: Eureka (Rare)</name>
        <text>The rarity of the Potion you can create with your Eureka feature increases to Rare.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Level 13: Mind Over Matter</name>
        <text>When you or a creature you can see within 30 feet of you fails an ability check or a saving throw, you can take a Reaction to add a bonus to the roll, potentially causing it to succeed. The bonus equals your Intelligence modifier.
	You can take this Reaction a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Mind Over Matter</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Subclass Feature</name>
        <text>You gain a feature from your Alchemist Subclass.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 15: Philosopher's Stone</name>
        <text>Your studies have revealed to you the mystic Formula for the legendary Philosopher's Stone, which you can create over the course of 7 days. If you create a new one, any of your previous Philosopher's Stones are destroyed and return to nothing. Your Philosopher's Stone grants you the following benefits.

	• You are Immune to Magical Contagions and Curses, and cannot be aged by natural or magical means.

	• Once per hour, you can use the Utilize Action to Craft an item worth 50 GP or less without materials.

	• You can allow it to replace any of the material components called for by a spell, which consumes the Philosopher's Stone in the casting.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 16: Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Volatile Potency Enhancement</name>
        <text>The damage and healing bonus from your Volatile Potency feature increases to 2d6.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 18: Lightning in a Bottle</name>
        <text>Once every 7 days, you can create a Potion with your Eureka feature with a rarity of Very Rare.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 19: Epic Boon</name>
        <text>You gain an Epic Boon feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Level 20: Big Bang</name>
        <text>When you roll for Initiative, you can use the Utilize and Attack action once (no Action required).

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Alchemist Subclass: Animator -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Subclass: Animator</name>
        <text>Crafter of Life

An Animator repurposes living matter to create living creatures that serve them. They are creators of constructs, often found with the animator serving as an assistant in their research.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 3 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Homunculus Companion (Animator)</name>
        <text>You can conduct a Ritual over the course of an hour, shaping a mixture of 25 GP worth of clay, ash, mandrake root, and blood to gain the service of an Alchemical Homunculus.
	Your Alchemical Homunculus is a faithful companion, and it dies if you die. You determine its appearance. See this creature's game statistics in the Alchemical Homunculus stat block.
	In combat, it shares your Initiative count, but takes its turn immediately after yours. It is Friendly to you and your companions, and it obeys your telepathic commands (no Action required by you). If you don't issue any, it takes the Dodge action and uses its move to avoid danger.
	If you are Incapacitated, it can take any action of its choice, not just Dodge.
	You can't have more than one Homunculus from this feature at a time. If you attempt to create another, the creation fails.

Alchemical Homunculus:
Tiny Construct, Shares Your Alignment
AC 12 + your Intelligence modifier
HP 5 plus 5 times your Alchemist Level (it has a number of Hit Point Dice [d4s] equal to your Alchemist Level)
Speed 30 ft.
Str 14 (+2), Dex 14 (+2), Con 15 (+2), Int 10 (+0), Wis 12 (+1), Cha 10 (+0)
Immunities Poison; Exhaustion, Poisoned
Senses Darkvision 60 ft.; Passive Perception 10
Languages Understands the languages you know; telepathy 30 ft.

Traits:
Evasion. If the homunculus is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, the homunculus instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the save and only half damage if it fails. It can't use this trait if it has the Incapacitated condition.

Actions:
Bite. Melee Attack Roll: +2 plus your Intelligence modifier, reach 5 ft. Hit: 1 Piercing damage, and the target is Poisoned for 1 minute. If the attack roll exceeds the target's Consitution score by 5 or more, the target falls Unconscious until it takes damage or another creature uses an Action to shake it awake.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 3 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Zoetic Theory (Animator)</name>
        <text>You can give your Homunculus materials of a value of at least 5 GP to absorb into its body during a Short or Long Rest. For each component used, the Alchemical Homunculus gains a benefit.

	Adder's Stomach. It gains a Spit Acid attack, a ranged weapon with a range of 30 feet that deals 1d6 + your Intelligence modifier Acid damage.

	Eagle's Eye. It gains proficiency with Perception checks and has Advantage on sight-based Wisdom (Perception) checks.

	Fur of Bat. While it doesn't have the Deafened condition, it has 30 feet of Blindsight.

	Leech. Its Bite attack damage increases to 1d4 + your Intelligence modifier and, when it hits a creature that is not a Construct or Undead, it can spend and roll one of its Hit Dice to regain Hit Points equal to the number rolled.

	Spiderwebs. It gains a Climb Speed equal to its Walking Speed and can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 3 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Acid Damage">1d6+%4</roll>
        <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d4+%4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Anima Profane (Animator)</name>
        <text>You gain the ability to cast the Animate Dead spell, but only as a Ritual. The Skeleton or Zombie created through this Ritual has the following changes:

	• It is a Construct rather than an Undead.

	• Its Hit Point Maximum is increased by an amount equal to your Alchemist level.

	• It gains the Telepathic Bond feature of your Alchemical Homunculus.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Life Stitcher (Animator)</name>
        <text>Your Zoetic Theory is enhanced.

	Adder's Stomach. Its Spit Acid damage increases to 2d6 + your Intelligence modifier.

	Eagle's Eye. It has Expertise in Perception checks while it doesn't have the Blinded condition.

	Fur of Bat. It does not provoke Opportunity Attacks while using its Fly Speed.

	Leech. Its Bite attack damage increases to 2d4 + your Intelligence modifier.

	Spiderwebs. Its Climb Speed increases by 10 feet.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Acid Damage">2d6+%4</roll>
        <roll description="Piercing Damage">2d4+%4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Contemptible Chimera (Animator)</name>
        <text>If your Homunculus and a Construct created with Anima Profane are within 5 feet of each other, you can use an Action to command them to merge, creating a Flesh Golem that you control, with the following changes:

	• It gains the Homunculus' Fly, Bite, Telepathic Bond, and any Traits and Actions through Zoetic Theory.

	• Its Hit Point Maximum is increased by an amount equal to your Alchemist level.

	• The Flesh Golem dies immediately if you die or create a new Construct from your Alchemist features.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Alchemist Subclass: Apothecary -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Subclass: Apothecary</name>
        <text>Practitioner of Natural Medicine

While laughter might be the best medicine, it never cured Filth Fever. Apothecaries are medical practitioners, creating potent potions to cure what ails.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Holistic Medicine (Apothecary)</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Natural Medicine. You gain proficiency in the Medicine, Nature, or Survival skill (your choice), and you have advantage on any ability check you make to stabilize a creature with 0 Hit Points and to forage.

	Doctor's Tonic. You learn the Formula for Healing Draught or one Alchemical Item of your choice if you already know it.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Spagyric Theory (Apothecary)</name>
        <text>When you create an item that restores Hit Points, you can infuse the item with at least 5 GP of any of the following materials to enhance it.

	Honeycomb. The consumer gains a bonus on Wisdom (Animal Handling) and Charisma checks made against Beasts equal to your Intelligence modifier for 1 hour.

	Powdered Gems. If the consumer has the Poisoned condition from an effect that a successful saving throw would end, it can immediately attempt the saving throw (no Action required).

	Powdered Silver. The consumer gains a d4 bonus to the next saving throw they make within the next minute.

	Troll's Blood. The consumer regains 1 Hit Point at the start of each of its turns for 1 minute, or until they take Acid or Fire damage (whichever comes first).

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Add to Saving Throw">1d4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Sweet Succor (Apothecary)</name>
        <text>When a creature consumes an Alchemical Item or Potion you administer or Craft that restores Hit Points, the item's first healing roll gains a bonus equal to your Intelligence modifier.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Panacea (Apothecary)</name>
        <text>Your Spagyric Theory is enhanced.

	Honeycomb. The item causes subtle changes in the consumer's scent. Animals are put at ease by the scent, granting the consumer a bonus on Wisdom (Animal Handling) and Charisma checks made against beasts equal to your Intelligence modifier for 1 hour and advantage on these checks.

	Powdered Gems. If the consumer is afflicted by any condition that a successful saving throw would end, it can immediately attempt the saving throw when the item restores its Hit Points (no Action required).

	Powdered Silver. The next time the consumer makes a saving throw within the next minute, they can roll a 2d4 and add the result rolled to the saving throw.

	Troll's Blood. The consumer regains 2 Hit Points at the start of each of its turns for 1 minute, and their severed body members (fingers, legs, tails, and so on) are restored after 2 minutes if the severed part is held to the stump.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 4 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Add to Saving Throw">2d4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Miracle Elixir (Apothecary)</name>
        <text>When you create a Healing Draught or Potion of Healing of any type, you can infuse it with 300 GP worth of diamond dust. If you administer the draught to a creature that has died within the last hour, the creature returns to life with 1 Hit Point. Doing so can't return to life a creature that has died of old age, nor can it restore any missing body parts.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Alchemist Subclass: Crystallographer -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Subclass: Crystallographer</name>
        <text>Maker of Matter

Crystallography is the study of crystalline structures and the creation of matter from chemical compounds.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Crystalizer (Crystallographer)</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Jeweled Alchemy. You gain proficiency with Jeweler's Tools and learn the Formula for Frigid Azote, or another Alchemical Item if you already know it.

	Paralyzer. Whenever a creature makes an ability check or saving throw to end an effect caused by one of your Alchemical Items that reduced its speed, the creature must roll 1d4 and subtract the number rolled from the d20 roll.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Vitreus Theory (Crystallographer)</name>
        <text>When you create an item that reduces Speed or that creates an object or structure (such as an Instant Wall), you can infuse the item with at least 5 GP of any of the following materials to enhance it.

	Banded Agate. The form of any structure created by using the item expands by 5 feet in one direction of your choice, provided the space it would enter is unoccupied.

	Carbon. Any object or structure created by using the item is hardened, giving it an AC equal to your Alchemy save DC and additional Hit Points equal to your Alchemist level.

	Cicada. For 1 minute, the target must make a Constitution saving throw at the start of each of its turns. On a failure, the creature must spend 2 feet of speed for every 1 foot it attempts to use a Walk or Climb speed. On a success, this effect ends.

	Obsidian. Each time the creature makes an ability check or saving throw against the Alchemical item or comes into contact for the first time on its turn with an object or structure created by the item, it takes 1d6 Piercing damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Piercing Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Sterner Stuff (Crystallographer)</name>
        <text>You can use your Eureka feature to create a nonmagical crystal or gem of your choice. You can create this item using valuables (such as gold pieces) of a value equal to half the value of the item. The value of the item can't be more than 50 times your alchemist level, and disappears after a number of hours equal to your proficiency bonus.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Matter Maker (Crystallographer)</name>
        <text>Your Vitreous Theory is enhanced.

	Banded Agate. The form expands by 10 feet instead.

	Carbon. Any object or structure created is Immune to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage other than from magic or Adamantine weapons.

	Cicada. The item also affects a creature's Fly and Swim speeds.

	Obsidian. The Piercing damage increases to 2d6.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Piercing Damage">2d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Prima Materia (Crystallographer)</name>
        <text>Any item you create with Sterner Stuff no longer disappears, and you can use Eureka to Craft a Spark of Creation and only need to provide 500 GP to do so.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Alchemist Subclass: Fulminare -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Subclass: Fulminare</name>
        <text>Philosophers of Destruction

The process of creation must have its opposite, and Fulminares are the specialists of chaos and combustion.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Student of Destruction (Fulminare)</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Combuster's Vessels. You gain proficiency with Potter's Tools and you learn the Formula for Thunderstone, or another Alchemical Item if you already know it.

	Exploding Damage. Whenever you roll the highest value on any of the damage dice of an Alchemical Item, it deals one extra die of damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Phlogiston Theory (Fulminare)</name>
        <text>When you create an item that deals damage, you can infuse the item with at least 5 GP of any of the following materials to enhance it.

	Nut Shells. The item sends a seismic shock, causing the ground within 10 feet of the area the item was thrown to become Difficult Terrain.

	Quartz. When a creature takes damage from the item, it becomes Dazed until the end of the turn. While Dazed, the creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw before it makes an attack, or the attack misses. On a success, the target is no longer Dazed.

	Saltpeter. If it only targets a single creature, you can instead target a point within the same range. All creatures within 10 feet of the point are targeted by it.

	Powdered Arcane Focus. When it deals damage, roll a d6 and consult the following table to determine its Damage Type.

Powdered Arcane Focus:
d6 | Damage Type
1 | Cold
2 | Lightning
3 | Necrotic
4 | Psychic
5 | Radiant
6 | Force

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 5 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Damage Type">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Hit the Deck (Fulminare)</name>
        <text>When you are forced to make a Dexterity saving throw against an effect you can see and hear, you can use your Reaction to move up to half your Speed immediately before the effect occurs, potentially moving out of the area of danger.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Chemical Warfare (Fulminare)</name>
        <text>Your Phlogiston Theory is enhanced.

	Nut Shells. The area of the effect increases to 15 feet and deals double damage to objects and structures.

	Quartz. The creature has Disadvantage on the Constitution saving throw to end the Dazed condition.

	Saltpeter. The area of the effect increases to 15 feet.

	Powdered Arcane Focus. When you roll on the table, roll 3d6 and choose one of the dice to use for the result instead.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Damage Type">3d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Spontaneous Combustion (Fulminare)</name>
        <text>Your Exploding Damage benefit of Student of Destruction is enhanced in the following way.

	Exploding Damage. Whenever you roll the highest value on any of the damage dice of an Alchemical Item, you can roll those dice an additional time and add the number rolled to the damage until that die doesn't roll its highest value.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Alchemist Subclass: Salbenist -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Subclass: Salbenist</name>
        <text>Anointed Warriors of Oil

The title of Salbenist (literally "oil-user") is used by alchemists who wield blades coated in alchemical oil.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oleic Arms (Salbenist)</name>
        <text>You have the following benefits.

	Martial Training. You gain proficiency with Martial weapons that lack the Heavy or Two-Handed properties and training with Medium armor.

	Burning Blades. You learn the Formula for Bladefire Oil, or another Alchemical Item if you already know it.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Anointed Blade (Salbenist)</name>
        <text>You can perform a Ritual over the course of 1 hour with a weapon you are proficient with and coat it with an oil. The oil is absorbed into the weapon, anointing it and granting you the following benefits until you perform this Ritual again.

	• Whenever you attack with the weapon, you can use your Intelligence modifier for the attack and damage rolls instead of using Strength or Dexterity; and you can use its Mastery Property.

	• As part of making an attack with it, you can will the oil absorbed into it to coat it. Doing so does not consume the oil, and the weapon remains coated until you dismiss it, it leaves your hand, or until you coat it with another oil.

	• Whenever you make a damage roll with it and roll the highest value on one of the damage dice, you can roll that die one additional time and add the number rolled to the damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: All-Consuming Flame (Salbenist)</name>
        <text>Whenever you take damage of the same type dealt by the oil anointing your weapon, you can use a Reaction to reduce the damage you take to 0. If you do, you regain a number of Hit Points equal to the total damage reduced. If these Hit Points would exceed your Hit Point maximum, you can choose to instead gain the remainder as Temporary Hit Points.
	You can use this Reaction a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1), and you cannot do so again until you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>All-Consuming Flame</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Salbenist</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Hallowed Warrior (Salbenist)</name>
        <text>When you will the oil absorbed into your Anointed Blade to coat it, you can choose another Weapon Mastery Property. The weapon gains this other Weapon Mastery Property until you dismiss it, it leaves your hand, or until you coat it with another oil.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Soul of Cinder (Salbenist)</name>
        <text>Whenever you make a damage roll for damage dealt with your Anointed Blade and roll the highest value on any of the dice, the attack's damage ignores Resistance and Immunity.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Alchemist Subclass: Toxicologist -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Subclass: Toxicologist</name>
        <text>Insidious Poisoners and Pathologists

A reviled trade in most societies, Toxicologists are alchemists that specialize in disease and poison.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Adulterated Alchemy (Toxicologist)</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Poisoner. You gain proficiency with the Poisoner's Kit and treat Poisons you create as Alchemical Items for the purposes of your Alchemist class features.

	Substance Savant. You have Advantage on ability checks to handle, harvest, or identify Poisons, and diagnose Magical Contagions.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Fel Theory (Toxicologist)</name>
        <text>When you Craft an item that inflicts the Poisoned condition or deals Poison or Necrotic damage, you can infuse it with at least 5 GP of any of the following materials to enhance it.

	Desecrated Water. Poison damage dealt by it becomes Necrotic damage.

	Eye of Newt. While the target is poisoned in this way, the target takes 1d6 Poison damage the first time it is hit with an attack each turn.

	Powdered Lead. The Poison becomes a powder that takes effect when inhaled.

	Valerian Root. Whenever the target Poisoned this way makes a Constitution saving throw to maintain Concentration, it must subtract a d4 from the number rolled.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Poison Damage">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="Subtract from Concentration Roll">1d4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Mithridatism (Toxicologist)</name>
        <text>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Poisoned condition on yourself, and you have Resistance to Poison damage.
	If another feature, item, or spell gives you Resistance to Poison damage, you can choose instead to gain one of the following benefits, which lasts for the duration listed in the effect (you choose when the effect takes place).

	• You are Immune to Poison damage.

	• You have Resistance to either Acid or Necrotic damage (choose one).

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Malediction (Toxicologist)</name>
        <text>Your Fel Theory is enhanced.

	Desecrated Water. Damage dealt by the item ignores Resistance to Necrotic damage.

	Eye of Newt. The damage increases to 2d6 Poison.

	Powdered Lead. The inhaler has a d4 penalty to the saving throw forced by the Poison.

	Valerian Root. The penalty increases to 2d4.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Poison Damage">2d6</roll>
        <roll description="Subtract from Saving Throw">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Subtract from Concentration Saving Throw">2d4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Demon Core (Toxicologist)</name>
        <text>Poisons you create have the following benefits.

	• They ignore Resistance to Poison damage.

	• Creatures with Immunity to Poison damage instead take half damage from the item instead of none.

	• They ignore Immunity to the Poisoned condition, with these creatures instead making the saving throw with Advantage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
