<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <!-- Adventuring Gear -->
  <item>
    <name>Alembic [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>12</value>
    <text>An airtight, glass distillation device.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Astrolobe [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>2</value>
    <text>An astrolabe can be used as a part of making an ability check to navigate at night while stars or other planetary bodies are visible. If you do, the check is made with advantage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Astronomer's Pack [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>40</value>
    <text>An Astronomer's Pack contains the following items:

	• Backpack
	• Bedroll
	• Astrolabe
	• a Bottle of Ink
	• Ink Pen
	• Telescope
	• a Scroll Case
	• 10 sheets of Parchment
	• 10 days of Rations
	• a Waterskin

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bellows [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>A device used to furnish a strong, short blast of air through a nozzle.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Brazier [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>50</weight>
    <value>10</value>
    <text>A portable container used to burn charcoal or fuel.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle Mold [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>1.2</value>
    <text>A mold is required, in addition to any wax, to make any candle with a weight of 1 pound or less.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Coffee Grounds [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>Boiling water can be poured through coffee grounds and filtered to make a cup of coffee.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Crucible [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>1</value>
    <text>A small ceramic or metal container that can hold molten substances without breaking.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Demolitioner's Pack [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>15</value>
    <text>A Demolitioner's Pack contains the following items:

	• Backpack
	• Bedroll
	• 3 Flasks
	• 4 Clay Pots
	• Earplugs
	• a Hooded Lantern
	• a vial of Gunpowder
	• 10 days of Rations
	• a Waterskin

The pack also has 30 feet of fuse packed within the chest.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Detective's Pack [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>15</value>
    <text>A Detective's Pack includes the following items:

	• Backpack
	• Bedroll
	• Magnifying Glass
	• a mask
	• Tongs
	• a Test Kit
	• 10 days of Rations
	• a Waterskin

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Earplugs [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>0.3</value>
    <text>Made from solid sponge or cork, a creature wearing these earplugs is effectively Deafened.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Glass Cutter [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>2</value>
    <text>It can cut through glass as thick as a half-inch, creating a circular hole between 3 to 16 inches wide.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Glass Tubing [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>1 SP per ft.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Hammock [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>A Hammock sleeps one Small or Medium creature. It can be hung between two supports to create a comfortable, elevated sleeping area.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Heat Mat [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>A 1 square foot mat made of heat-absorbing materials. The mat can withstand temperatures of up to 1,200 degrees Fahrenheit without catching fire. It can be used to handle flaming hot objects for short periods of time without burning the creature carrying it.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Heatsuit Outfit [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>15</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>Clothing designed to protect the wearer against the effects of Extreme Heat.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Magnet, Small [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>1</value>
    <text>Can be used to attract loose metal items or stick to ferrous objects. It is only powerful enough to attract metal that weighs 3 ounces or less.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Mediciner's Pack [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>22</value>
    <text>A Mediciner's Pack includes the following items:

	• Backpack
	• Hammock
	• 3 Flasks
	• 5 Glass Bottles
	• 10 days of Rations
	• a Waterskin
	• a Healer's Kit
	• a Herbalism Kit

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Mortar and Pestle [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>1</value>
    <text>A bowl and crusher used to grind material to powder.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Periscope [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>Handheld periscope roughly 1 foot long. If you use a periscope while behind Cover, you can look over obstacles and around corners without exposing yourself.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Shriek Rock [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>Flat stones with drilled holes that cause a loud, high-pitched "shriek" as loud as a shrill human scream when thrown.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Telescope [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>30</value>
    <text>An instrument used to view planetary bodies

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Test Kit [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>This kit contains various materials for the testing of unknown magical and mundane fluids. A single kit typically contains leather gloves, clippers, five glass vials, strips of alchemical testing paper, and a flask of alcohol. The kit has 10 uses, one of which you can spend to gain advantage on an applicable Intelligence (Investigation) check.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Tongs [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <value>0.3</value>
    <text>1-foot-long metal Tongs that can pick up objects that weigh as much as 1 pound.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <!-- Alchemical Items -->
  <item>
    <name>Acid, Basic (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a vial of Acid. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d6 Acid damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">2d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Acid, Oxidizeding Agent (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a vial of Acid. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d6 Acid damage.

	• Its damage is increased to 2d10 if the target is a Construct made of metal.

	• If the target is a nonmagical metal object, the object takes a -1 penalty to the AC it offers (armor) or to its attack rolls (weapon). Armor is destroyed if the penalty reduces its AC to 10, and a weapon is destroyed if its penalty reaches -5. The penalty can be removed by casting the Mending spell on the item.

	• If the target is a nonmagical metal object that isn't being worn or carried, a 1-foot Cube of the object is destroyed.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">2d6</roll>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">2d10</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Adhesive (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>0.5</value>
    <text>A sticky substance used to adhere materials together.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Alkahest (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When poured on or within an Alchemical Item, the item is reduced back to its raw materials after 1 minute. The alkahest is lost in the process.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle, Basic [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.01</value>
    <text>For 1 hour, a lit Candle sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle, Focusing [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>For 1 hour, a lit Candle sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.
	Those within 20 feet of a burning Focusing Candle have a +1 bonus to any ability check made with artisan's tools.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle, Insectbane [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>For 1 hour, a lit Candle sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.
	Insects and insectoid-like creatures (DM's discretion) within 20 feet of a burning Insectbane Candle have the Frightened condition.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle, Restful [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>10</value>
    <text>For 1 hour, a lit Candle sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.
	Creatures within 20 feet of a burning Restful Candle regain twice as many Hit Points from spent Hit Points Dice during a Short Rest.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Clearbreath (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>As a Bonus Action, you can inhale it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that inhales this concoction gains a +2 bonus to smell-based Constitution saving throws for 1 hour.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Darkvision Powder (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.0625</weight>
    <value>10</value>
    <text>This powder glows brightly when viewed by creatures with Darkvision, but otherwise appears to be a plain gray dust. A vial contains enough powder to write a short message (up to 25 words).

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Defoliator (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Defoliator. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. All Plant creatures within 10 feet of the point must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d4 Poison damage. Medium or smaller natural plants in the area wither and die, and wooden objects and structures take double the damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Poison Damage">2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Dwarfblind Stone [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Dwarfblind Stone. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. All creatures with Darkvision within 20 feet of the target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or gain the Blinded condition. A creature Blinded this way makes a Constitution saving throw at the start of its turns, ending the Blinded condition on a success.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Poison Damage">2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Fleetfoot (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the contents of this vial has their Walking Speed and jump distance increased by 10 feet.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Poison Damage">2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Frigid Azote (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Frigid Azote. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d6 Cold damage and its speed is halved until the end of its next turn.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Cold Damage">2d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Green Slime (Pot) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>7</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a pot of Green Slime. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 1d10 Acid damage and 1d10 Acid damage at the start of each of its turns until a creature uses its action to scrape or wash the slime off. Sunlight and effects that end the Poisoned condition (such as the Lesser Restoration spell) immediately kill the slime.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">1d10</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Healing Draught (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the contents of this flask can spend and roll its Hit Dice and regain a number of Hit Points equal to the roll. The maximum number of Hit Dice it can spend by consuming the contents is equal to their Constitution modifier (minimum of 1).

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Holy Water (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Holy Water. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d8 Radiant damage if it is a Fiend or an Undead.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Insect Repellent-Salve (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>Over the course of 1 minute, you can apply this grease to protect the wearer against normal insects for 24 hours. There are 20 applications.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Instant Rope (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>As an Action, you can pour the liquid from this flask to form a long cord that functions as a 50-foot-long Hemp Rope. After an hour, it crumbles into dust.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Instant Wall (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Instant Wall. Target one point you can see within 20 feet of yourself. A 10-foot-square, 1-foot-thick panel of stone-like matter erupts on the point with the wall facing you. The wall lasts until the end of your next turn, then it crumbles into dust. The panel is an object with AC 12 and 10 Hit Points, and is Vulnerable to Bludgeoning and Thunder damage.
	If the panel cuts through a creature's space when it erupts, that creature must make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (its choice, DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 1d8 Bludgeoning damage and be forced to the side of the wall of your choice.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage">1d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Levin Shell (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Levin Shell. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 1d6 Lightning damage and have Disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws until the end of its next turn.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Lightning Damage">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Longbreath (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>As a Bonus Action, you can inhale it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that inhales this concoction can hold its breath indefinitely for the next hour.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Motelight (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Motelight. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or become surrounded by rapidly moving, harmless sparks that follow it until the start of your next turn. If the creature attempts to take the Magic action, it must succeed on a Concentration check before doing so. If it fails, the action has no effect and the Spell Slot or use of the action is expended.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil, Basic (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>You can douse a creature, object, or space with Oil or use it as fuel, as detailed below.

	Dousing a Creature or an Object. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing an Oil flask. Target one creature or object within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be covered in oil. If the target takes Fire damage before the oil dries (after 1 minute), the target takes an extra 5 Fire damage from burning oil.

	Dousing a Space. You can take the Utilize action to pour an Oil flask on level ground to cover a 5-footsquare area within 5 feet of yourself. If lit, the oil burns until the end of the turn 2 rounds from when the oil was lit (or 12 seconds) and deals 5 Fire damage to any creature that enters the area or ends its turn there. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.

	Fuel. Oil serves as fuel for Lamps and Lanterns. Once lit, a flask of Oil burns for 6 hours in a Lamp or Lantern. That duration doesn't need to be consecutive; you can extinguish the burning Oil (as a Utilize action) and rekindle it again until it has burned for a total of 6 hours.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil, Anointing (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>You can douse a creature, object, or space with Oil or use it as fuel, as detailed below.

	Dousing a Creature or an Object. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing an Oil flask. Target one creature or object within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be covered in oil. If the target takes Fire damage before the oil dries (after 1 minute), the target takes an extra 5 Fire damage from burning oil.

	Dousing a Space. You can take the Utilize action to pour an Oil flask on level ground to cover a 5-footsquare area within 5 feet of yourself. If lit, the oil burns until the end of the turn 2 rounds from when the oil was lit (or 12 seconds) and deals 5 Fire damage to any creature that enters the area or ends its turn there. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.

	Fuel. Oil serves as fuel for Lamps and Lanterns. Once lit, a flask of Oil burns for 6 hours in a Lamp or Lantern. That duration doesn't need to be consecutive; you can extinguish the burning Oil (as a Utilize action) and rekindle it again until it has burned for a total of 6 hours.

	Anointing. One vial of this oil can coat one Melee weapon or twenty pieces of ammunition, but only ammunition and Melee weapons that deal Slashing or Piercing damage are affected. Applying the oil takes 1 minute, after which the oil seeps into whatever it coats. When you hit a Fiend or Undead with the coated item, the attack deals an extra 1d6 Radiant damage. If you apply another oil to the coated weapon, it loses these effects.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Radiant Damage">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil, Bladefire (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>You can douse a creature, object, or space with Oil or use it as fuel, as detailed below.

	Dousing a Creature or an Object. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing an Oil flask. Target one creature or object within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be covered in oil. If the target takes Fire damage before the oil dries (after 1 minute), the target takes an extra 5 Fire damage from burning oil.

	Dousing a Space. You can take the Utilize action to pour an Oil flask on level ground to cover a 5-footsquare area within 5 feet of yourself. If lit, the oil burns until the end of the turn 2 rounds from when the oil was lit (or 12 seconds) and deals 5 Fire damage to any creature that enters the area or ends its turn there. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.

	Fuel. Oil serves as fuel for Lamps and Lanterns. Once lit, a flask of Oil burns for 6 hours in a Lamp or Lantern. That duration doesn't need to be consecutive; you can extinguish the burning Oil (as a Utilize action) and rekindle it again until it has burned for a total of 6 hours.

	Bladefire. One vial of this oil can coat one Melee weapon or twenty pieces of ammunition, but only ammunition and Melee weapons that deal Slashing or Piercing damage are affected. Applying the oil takes 1 minute, after which the oil seeps into whatever it coats. The coated item burns as if it were a Torch and deals an extra 1d4 Fire damage on a hit. If you apply another oil to the coated items), it loses these effects.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Fire Damage">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil, Crone's Ire (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>You can douse a creature, object, or space with Oil or use it as fuel, as detailed below.

	Dousing a Creature or an Object. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing an Oil flask. Target one creature or object within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be covered in oil. If the target takes Fire damage before the oil dries (after 1 minute), the target takes an extra 5 Fire damage from burning oil.

	Dousing a Space. You can take the Utilize action to pour an Oil flask on level ground to cover a 5-footsquare area within 5 feet of yourself. If lit, the oil burns until the end of the turn 2 rounds from when the oil was lit (or 12 seconds) and deals 5 Fire damage to any creature that enters the area or ends its turn there. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.

	Fuel. Oil serves as fuel for Lamps and Lanterns. Once lit, a flask of Oil burns for 6 hours in a Lamp or Lantern. That duration doesn't need to be consecutive; you can extinguish the burning Oil (as a Utilize action) and rekindle it again until it has burned for a total of 6 hours.

	Crone's Ire. As an Action, you can coat one weapon or up to 5 pieces of ammunition with a flask of Crone's Ire Oil, which remains for 1 hour. During this time, the coated item sheds Dim Light out to 5 feet and deals an extra 1d4 Necrotic damage on a hit. If the target of the attack has to make a Concentration check from taking the attack's damage, they subtract the Necrotic damage from the roll. If you apply another oil to the coated weapon, it loses these effects.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Necrotic Damage">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil, Dragonwound (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>You can douse a creature, object, or space with Oil or use it as fuel, as detailed below.

	Dousing a Creature or an Object. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing an Oil flask. Target one creature or object within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be covered in oil. If the target takes Fire damage before the oil dries (after 1 minute), the target takes an extra 5 Fire damage from burning oil.

	Dousing a Space. You can take the Utilize action to pour an Oil flask on level ground to cover a 5-footsquare area within 5 feet of yourself. If lit, the oil burns until the end of the turn 2 rounds from when the oil was lit (or 12 seconds) and deals 5 Fire damage to any creature that enters the area or ends its turn there. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.

	Fuel. Oil serves as fuel for Lamps and Lanterns. Once lit, a flask of Oil burns for 6 hours in a Lamp or Lantern. That duration doesn't need to be consecutive; you can extinguish the burning Oil (as a Utilize action) and rekindle it again until it has burned for a total of 6 hours.

	Dragonwound. As an Action, you can coat one metal weapon or up to 5 pieces of metal ammunition with a flask of Dragonwound Oil, which remains for 1 hour. When you hit a Dragon with the coated item, the attack deals an extra 1d6 Force damage and the target's Fly Speed is reduced by half until the start of your next turn. If you apply another oil to the coated weapon, it loses these effects.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Force Damage">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil, Farflame (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>You can douse a creature, object, or space with Oil or use it as fuel, as detailed below.

	Dousing a Creature or an Object. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing an Oil flask. Target one creature or object within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be covered in oil. If the target takes Fire damage before the oil dries (after 1 minute), the target takes an extra 5 Fire damage from burning oil.

	Dousing a Space. You can take the Utilize action to pour an Oil flask on level ground to cover a 5-footsquare area within 5 feet of yourself. If lit, the oil burns until the end of the turn 2 rounds from when the oil was lit (or 12 seconds) and deals 5 Fire damage to any creature that enters the area or ends its turn there. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.

	Fuel. Oil serves as fuel for Lamps and Lanterns. Once lit, a flask of Oil burns for 6 hours in a Lamp or Lantern. That duration doesn't need to be consecutive; you can extinguish the burning Oil (as a Utilize action) and rekindle it again until it has burned for a total of 6 hours.

	Farflame. When used as a Fuel, the Light it sheds is doubled and can last for up to 3 hours.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 12 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil, Ghostflame (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>You can douse a creature, object, or space with Oil or use it as fuel, as detailed below.

	Dousing a Creature or an Object. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing an Oil flask. Target one creature or object within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be covered in oil. If the target takes Fire damage before the oil dries (after 1 minute), the target takes an extra 5 Fire damage from burning oil.

	Dousing a Space. You can take the Utilize action to pour an Oil flask on level ground to cover a 5-footsquare area within 5 feet of yourself. If lit, the oil burns until the end of the turn 2 rounds from when the oil was lit (or 12 seconds) and deals 5 Fire damage to any creature that enters the area or ends its turn there. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.

	Fuel. Oil serves as fuel for Lamps and Lanterns. Once lit, a flask of Oil burns for 6 hours in a Lamp or Lantern. That duration doesn't need to be consecutive; you can extinguish the burning Oil (as a Utilize action) and rekindle it again until it has burned for a total of 6 hours.

	Ghostflame. As an Action, you can coat one metal weapon or up to 5 pieces of metal ammunition with a flask of Ghostflame Oil, which remains for 1 hour. During this time, attacks made with the weapon ignore Resistance and Immunity to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage if the target has the Incorporeal Movement trait or if it gained them through the Gaseous Form spell. If you apply another oil to the coated weapon, it loses these effects.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Oil, Dicious Bleeder (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>You can douse a creature, object, or space with Oil or use it as fuel, as detailed below.

	Dousing a Creature or an Object. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing an Oil flask. Target one creature or object within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be covered in oil. If the target takes Fire damage before the oil dries (after 1 minute), the target takes an extra 5 Fire damage from burning oil.

	Dousing a Space. You can take the Utilize action to pour an Oil flask on level ground to cover a 5-footsquare area within 5 feet of yourself. If lit, the oil burns until the end of the turn 2 rounds from when the oil was lit (or 12 seconds) and deals 5 Fire damage to any creature that enters the area or ends its turn there. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.

	Fuel. Oil serves as fuel for Lamps and Lanterns. Once lit, a flask of Oil burns for 6 hours in a Lamp or Lantern. That duration doesn't need to be consecutive; you can extinguish the burning Oil (as a Utilize action) and rekindle it again until it has burned for a total of 6 hours.

	Dicious Bleeder. As an Action, you can coat one metal weapon or up to 5 pieces of metal ammunition with a flask of Ghostflame Oil, which remains for 1 hour. During this time, attacks made with the weapon against Constructs, Elementals, and Oozes deal an additional 1d6 damage and grants Advantage on ability checks made to track it for the next hour. If you apply another oil to the coated weapon, it loses these effects.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Damage">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Perfume (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>Perfume comes in a 4-ounce vial. For 1 hour after applying Perfume to yourself, you have Advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to influence an Indifferent Humanoid within 5 feet of yourself.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Damage">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Polar Skin (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>Over the course of 1 minute, you can apply this grease to protect the wearer against Extreme Cold for 24 hours. There are 20 applications.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Extra Damage">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Potion of Healing, Generic (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>This potion is a magic item. As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the magical red fluid in this vial regains a number of Hit Points determined by the potion's rarity, as shown in the table below.

Potion:
HP | Regained | Rarity
Potion of Healing | 2d4+2 | Common
Potion of Healing (greater) | 4d4+4 | Uncommon
Potion of Healing (superior) | 8d4+8 | Rare
Potion of Healing (supreme) | 10d4+20 | Very Rare

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Common Heal">2d4+2</roll>
    <roll description="Uncommon Heal">4d4+4</roll>
    <roll description="Rare Heal">8d4+8</roll>
    <roll description="Very Heal">10d4+20</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Basic Potion of Healing (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>This potion is a magic item. As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the magical red fluid in this vial regains 2d4+2 Hit Points.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Heal">2d4+2</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Greater Potion of Healing (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, uncommon</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>200</value>
    <text>This potion is a magic item. As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the magical red fluid in this vial regains 4d4+4 Hit Points.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Heal">4d4+4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Superior Potion of Healing (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>2000</value>
    <text>This potion is a magic item. As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the magical red fluid in this vial regains 8d4+8 Hit Points.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Heal">8d4+8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Supreme Potion of Healing (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, very rare</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20000</value>
    <text>This potion is a magic item. As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the magical red fluid in this vial regains 10d4+20 Hit Points.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Heal">10d4+20</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Shriek Paste (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>15</value>
    <text>When smeared on a surface, it retains its same consistency almost indefinitely. When Bright Light is within 30 feet of the paste, the paste rapidly crystallizes and emits a shriek audible within 300 feet of it for 1 minute. If the Bright Light moves out of range, the shriek ends after 1d4 rounds. Afterward, the paste dries up and is rendered inert.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Rounds">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Spark of Creation (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, very rare</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20000</value>
    <text>This Alchemical Item is a magic item. When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Spark of Creation. Target one point you can see within 20 feet of yourself. Eight 5-foot diameter crystalline spires burst forth at points of your choice within 30 feet of the point. Each spire has a height of up to 30 feet, with AC 5 and 30 Hit Points. When reduced to 0 Hit Points, a spire crumbles to rubble, which creates an area of Difficult Terrain with a 5-foot radius that lasts until the rubble is cleared. Each 5-foot diameter portion of the area requires at least 1 minute to clear by hand.
	If the spire is created under a creature, that creature must make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (its choice, DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 6d6 Piercing damage and is Restrained if it is pinned between the spire and an obstacle. The Restrained creature can use an action to make a DC 16 Strength or Dexterity check (the creature's choice). On a success, the creature is no longer Restrained and must either move off the pillar or fall off of it.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew)</text>
    <roll description="Rounds">1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Splash Catalyst (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>As an Action, you can combine a vial of Splash Catalyst with an Alchemical Item to increase its volatility. If the item only targets a single creature, you can instead target a point within the same range. Creatures within 5 feet of the point must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (which they can choose to fail, DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or be subjected to the item's effects as if they had been hit by an attack made using the item.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Soap [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.02</value>
    <text>A commodity used for bathing.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Sparkstone [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Sparkstone. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 1d6 Lightning damage and it can't make Opportunity Attacks until the start of your next turn.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Lightning Damage">1d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Smelling Salts [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>0.3</value>
    <text>As a Bonus Action, you can administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. If the creature can smell and has the Unconscious condition by an effect that put it to sleep, it immediately wakes up.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Smokestick, Basic [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>2</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Basic Smokestick at a point you can see within 20 feet of yourself. A 10-foot-radius dome area centered on the point fills with smoke for the next minute, which may be dispersed by strong winds. This smoke Heavily Obscures the area and blocks vision, including Darkvision.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Smokestick, Gravebane (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Basic Smokestick at a point you can see within 20 feet of yourself. A 10-foot-radius dome area centered on the point fills with smoke for the next minute, which may be dispersed by strong winds. This smoke Heavily Obscures the area and blocks vision, including Darkvision.
	Undead that try to enter the smoke for the first time on a turn must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or it must spend the next 1 minute trying to move as far away from the area of smoke as it can. During this time, it can't willingly move to a space nearer to the smoke or make Opportunity Attacks.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Smokestick, Verminbane (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Basic Smokestick at a point you can see within 20 feet of yourself. A 10-foot-radius dome area centered on the point fills with smoke for the next minute, which may be dispersed by strong winds. This smoke Heavily Obscures the area and blocks vision, including Darkvision.
	Rodent-like creatures (DMs discretion) that try to enter the smoke for the first time on a turn must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or gain the Frightened condition for the next minute, and it must spend its turns trying to move further than 30 feet away from the area of smoke. It also can't make Opportunity Attacks.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Sunrod [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>2</value>
    <text>As an Action, you can strike a Sunrod, causing it to provide Bright Light in a 30-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 30 feet. It glows for 6 hours, then crumbles to ash.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Tanglefoot Bag (Sack) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing or bursting open a Tanglefoot Bag. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or become Grappled escape DC 10) by the Tanglefoot Bag, which gives it the Restrained condition while grappled this way. This item does not work underwater, and becomes brittle and breaks after 1 hour.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Thunderstone [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Thunderstone. Target a point you can see within 20 feet of yourself. Each creature within 10 feet of the point to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take ld8 Thunder damage and be Deafened until the end of your next turn. A creature Deafened in this way also has Disadvantage on Initiative checks.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Torch, Basic [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>0.01</value>
    <text>A Torch burns for 1 hour, casting Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet. When you take the Attack action, you can attack with the Torch, using it as a Simple Melee weapon. On a hit, the target takes 1 Fire damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Torch, Beast-Repellent [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>A Torch burns for 1 hour, casting Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet. When you take the Attack action, you can attack with the Torch, using it as a Simple Melee weapon. On a hit, the target takes 1 Fire damage.
	A Beast within 30 feet of a burning Beast-Repellent Torch that can see it must succeed on a DC 10 Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened of the torch until it is attacked or takes damage. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature's saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature cannot be Frightened by Beast-Repellent Torches for 24 hours.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Torch, Frigidflame [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>1</value>
    <text>A Frigidflame Torch burns for 1 hour, casting Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet. When you take the Attack action, you can attack with the Torch, using it as a Simple Melee weapon. On a hit, the target takes 1 Cold damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Torch, Sentry [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>A Torch burns for 1 hour, casting Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet. When you take the Attack action, you can attack with the Torch, using it as a Simple Melee weapon. On a hit, the target takes 1 Fire damage.
	Invisible creatures and objects within the Bright Light are visible.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Torch, Tindertwig [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>A Torch burns for 1 hour, casting Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet. When you take the Attack action, you can attack with the Torch, using it as a Simple Melee weapon. On a hit, the target takes 1 Fire damage.
	Flame does not harm this torch, and it can burn indefinitely.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 14 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Toothpaste (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.5</value>
    <text>A commodity used for cleaning ones teeth.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 13 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
</compendium>
