<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <!-- Adventuring Gear -->
  <item>
    <name>Alembic [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>12</value>
    <text>An airtight, glass distillation device.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Astrolobe [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>2</value>
    <text>An astrolabe can be used as a part of making an ability check to navigate at night while stars or other planetary bodies are visible. If you do, the check is made with advantage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Astronomer's Pack [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>40</value>
    <text>An Astronomer's Pack contains the following items:

	• Backpack
	• Bedroll
	• Astrolabe
	• a Bottle of Ink
	• Ink Pen
	• Telescope
	• a Scroll Case
	• 10 sheets of Parchment
	• 10 days of Rations
	• a Waterskin

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bellows [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>A device used to furnish a strong, short blast of air through a nozzle.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Brazier [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>50</weight>
    <value>10</value>
    <text>A portable container used to burn charcoal or fuel.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle Mold [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>1.2</value>
    <text>A mold is required, in addition to any wax, to make any candle with a weight of 1 pound or less.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Coffee Grounds [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>Boiling water can be poured through coffee grounds and filtered to make a cup of coffee.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Crucible [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>1</value>
    <text>A small ceramic or metal container that can hold molten substances without breaking.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 8 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Demolitioner's Pack [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>15</value>
    <text>A Demolitioner's Pack contains the following items:

	• Backpack
	• Bedroll
	• 3 Flasks
	• 4 Clay Pots
	• Earplugs
	• a Hooded Lantern
	• a vial of Gunpowder
	• 10 days of Rations
	• a Waterskin

The pack also has 30 feet of fuse packed within the chest.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Detective's Pack [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>15</value>
    <text>A Detective's Pack includes the following items:

	• Backpack
	• Bedroll
	• Magnifying Glass
	• a mask
	• Tongs
	• a Test Kit
	• 10 days of Rations
	• a Waterskin

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Earplugs [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>0.3</value>
    <text>Made from solid sponge or cork, a creature wearing these earplugs is effectively Deafened.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Glass Cutter [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>2</value>
    <text>It can cut through glass as thick as a half-inch, creating a circular hole between 3 to 16 inches wide.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Glass Tubing [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>1 SP per ft.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Hammock [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>A Hammock sleeps one Small or Medium creature. It can be hung between two supports to create a comfortable, elevated sleeping area.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Heat Mat [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>A 1 square foot mat made of heat-absorbing materials. The mat can withstand temperatures of up to 1,200 degrees Fahrenheit without catching fire. It can be used to handle flaming hot objects for short periods of time without burning the creature carrying it.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Heatsuit Outfit [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>15</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>Clothing designed to protect the wearer against the effects of Extreme Heat.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Magnet, Small [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>1</value>
    <text>Can be used to attract loose metal items or stick to ferrous objects. It is only powerful enough to attract metal that weighs 3 ounces or less.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Mediciner's Pack [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>22</value>
    <text>A Mediciner's Pack includes the following items:

	• Backpack
	• Hammock
	• 3 Flasks
	• 5 Glass Bottles
	• 10 days of Rations
	• a Waterskin
	• a Healer's Kit
	• a Herbalism Kit

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Mortar and Pestle [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>1</value>
    <text>A bowl and crusher used to grind material to powder.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Periscope [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>Handheld periscope roughly 1 foot long. If you use a periscope while behind Cover, you can look over obstacles and around corners without exposing yourself.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Shriek Rock [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>Flat stones with drilled holes that cause a loud, high-pitched "shriek" as loud as a shrill human scream when thrown.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Telescope [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>30</value>
    <text>An instrument used to view planetary bodies

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Test Kit [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>This kit contains various materials for the testing of unknown magical and mundane fluids. A single kit typically contains leather gloves, clippers, five glass vials, strips of alchemical testing paper, and a flask of alcohol. The kit has 10 uses, one of which you can spend to gain advantage on an applicable Intelligence (Investigation) check.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Tongs [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <value>0.3</value>
    <text>1-foot-long metal Tongs that can pick up objects that weigh as much as 1 pound.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <!-- Alchemical Items -->
  <item>
    <name>Acid, Basic (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a vial of Acid. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d6 Acid damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">2d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Acid, Oxidizeding Agent (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a vial of Acid. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d6 Acid damage.

	• Its damage is increased to 2d10 if the target is a Construct made of metal.

	• If the target is a nonmagical metal object, the object takes a -1 penalty to the AC it offers (armor) or to its attack rolls (weapon). Armor is destroyed if the penalty reduces its AC to 10, and a weapon is destroyed if its penalty reaches -5. The penalty can be removed by casting the Mending spell on the item.

	• If the target is a nonmagical metal object that isn't being worn or carried, a 1-foot Cube of the object is destroyed.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">2d6</roll>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">2d10</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Adhesive (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>0.5</value>
    <text>A sticky substance used to adhere materials together.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 9 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Alkahest (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When poured on or within an Alchemical Item, the item is reduced back to its raw materials after 1 minute. The alkahest is lost in the process.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 10 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle, Basic [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <value>0.01</value>
    <text>For 1 hour, a lit Candle sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 10 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle, Focusing [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>For 1 hour, a lit Candle sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.
	Those within 20 feet of a burning Focusing Candle have a +1 bonus to any ability check made with artisan's tools.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 10 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle, Insectbane [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <value>0.1</value>
    <text>For 1 hour, a lit Candle sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.
	Insects and insectoid-like creatures (DM's discretion) within 20 feet of a burning Insectbane Candle have the Frightened condition.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Candle, Restful [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>10</value>
    <text>For 1 hour, a lit Candle sheds Bright Light in a 5-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 5 feet.
	Creatures within 20 feet of a burning Restful Candle regain twice as many Hit Points from spent Hit Points Dice during a Short Rest.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cleatbreath (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>As a Bonus Action, you can inhale it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that inhales this concoction gains a +2 bonus to smell-based Constitution saving throws for 1 hour.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Darkvision Powder (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>0.0625</weight>
    <value>10</value>
    <text>This powder glows brightly when viewed by creatures with Darkvision, but otherwise appears to be a plain gray dust. A vial contains enough powder to write a short message (up to 25 words).

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Defoliator (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Defoliator. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. All Plant creatures within 10 feet of the point must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d4 Poison damage. Medium or smaller natural plants in the area wither and die, and wooden objects and structures take double the damage.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Poison Damage">2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Dwarfblind Stone [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a Dwarfblind Stone. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. All creatures with Darkvision within 20 feet of the target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or gain the Blinded condition. A creature Blinded this way makes a Constitution saving throw at the start of its turns, ending the Blinded condition on a success.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Poison Damage">2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Fleetfoot (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the contents of this vial has their Walking Speed and jump distance increased by 10 feet.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Poison Damage">2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Frigid Azote (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>50</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Frigid Azote. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d6 Cold damage and its speed is halved until the end of its next turn.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Cold Damage">2d6</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Green Slime (Pot) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>7</weight>
    <value>100</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a pot of Green Slime. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 1d10 Acid damage and 1d10 Acid damage at the start of each of its turns until a creature uses its action to scrape or wash the slime off. Sunlight and effects that end the Poisoned condition (such as the Lesser Restoration spell) immediately kill the slime.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Acid Damage">1d10</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Healing Draught (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>As a Bonus Action, you can drink it or administer it to another creature within 5 feet of yourself. The creature that drinks the contents of this flask can spend and roll its Hit Dice and regain a number of Hit Points equal to the roll. The maximum number of Hit Dice it can spend by consuming the contents is equal to their Constitution modifier (minimum of 1).

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Holy Water (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Holy Water. Target one creature or object you can see within 20 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 2d8 Radiant damage if it is a Fiend or an Undead.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Insect Repellent-Salve (Vial) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>20</value>
    <text>Over the course of 1 minute, you can apply this grease to protect the wearer against normal insects for 24 hours. There are 20 applications.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Instant Rope (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>5</value>
    <text>As an Action, you can pour the liquid from this flask to form a long cord that functions as a 50-foot-long Hemp Rope. After an hour, it crumbles into dust.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage">2d8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Instant Wall (Flask) [5.5e]</name>
    <detail>alchemical item, common</detail>
    <type>P</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <value>25</value>
    <text>When you take the Attack action, you can replace one of your attacks with throwing a flask of Instant Wall. Target one point you can see within 20 feet of yourself. A 10-foot-square, 1-foot-thick panel of stone-like matter erupts on the point with the wall facing you. The wall lasts until the end of your next turn, then it crumbles into dust. The panel is an object with AC 12 and 10 Hit Points, and is Vulnerable to Bludgeoning and Thunder damage.
	If the panel cuts through a creature's space when it erupts, that creature must make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (its choice, DC 8 plus your Dexterity modifier and Proficiency Bonus) or take 1d8 Bludgeoning damage and be forced to the side of the wall of your choice.

Source:	The Alchemist Class p. 11 (Homebrew [5.5e])</text>
    <roll description="Bludgeoning Damage">1d8</roll>
  </item>
</compendium>
