<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <monster>
    <name>Ashsnake</name>
    <size>H</size>
    <type>monstrosity</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>14</ac>
    <hp>67 (7d12 + 21)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft., burrow 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>16</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>16</con>
    <int>4</int>
    <wis>12</wis>
    <cha>4</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>11</passive>
    <languages>Understands Ignan, but can't speak</languages>
    <cr>4</cr>
    <exp>1100</exp>
    <resist>Fire</resist>
    <immune/>
    <vulnerable>Cold</vulnerable>
    <conditionImmune/>
    <senses>blindsight 30 ft. (blind beyond this radius), tremorsense 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
    <name>Ash Cover</name>
    <text>
The ashsnake has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made when it is burrowing in ash, as well as a +4 bonus to its armor class.</text>
</trait>
    <trait>
    <name>Eruption</name>
    <text>
When the ashsnake emerges from burrowing, any creature within 5 feet of it that is at least one size smaller than the ashsnake must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
</trait>
    <action>
    <name>Multiattack</name>
    <text>
The Ashsnake can make one bite attack and either one Constrict or Crush attack each round.</text>
</action>
    <action>
    <name>Bite</name>
    <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d10 + 3) piercing damage.</text>
    <attack>Bite|+5|1d10+3</attack>
</action>
    <action>
    <name>Constrict</name>
    <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d8 + 3) bludgeoning damage and the target is grappled (escape DC 14). Until the grapple ends the target is restrained and the ashsnake cannot constrict or crush another target. The ashsnake can release the target at any time during its turn.</text>
    <attack>Constrict|+5|2d8+3</attack>
</action>
    <action>
    <name>Crush</name>
    <text>
The ashsnake crushes its grappled target, dealing 11 (2d8 + 3) bludgeoning damage.</text>
    <attack>Crush||2d8+3</attack>
</action>
    <action>
    <name>Ashen Breath (Recharge 5-6)</name>
    <text>
The ashsnake breathes out a cloud of superheated ash in a 15-foot cone. Each creature in the area must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw, taking 11 (2d10) fire damage on a failed save, or half as much on a success.</text>
    <attack>Ashen Breath (Recharge 5-6)||2d10</attack>
</action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>Ashsnakes are huge monstrosities which resemble snakes molded from volcanic magma. Their bodies seeth with an internal heat below the charcoal-gray scales that cover their forms. While the blazing light emanating from their empty eye sockets makes it appear as though ashsnakes can see, they rely entirely on vibrations to assess their surroundings.

Mysterious Origins:
Little is known about the origins of the ashsnake. They recently emerged from beneath the ashen plains of the Scorched Grove and appear to have an insatiable hunger. Ashnakes use the mounds of ash and dust in the Grove to conceal their presence, allowing them to close in on unwary prey and ambush them. While not particularly intelligent, ashsnakes possess predatorial cunning and survival instincts eerily reminiscent of the fauna that inhabited the Grove before its burning.

Sightless Worms:
Ashsnakes have no ability to detect sights and sounds in a traditional sense. They are, however, adept at sensing even the smallest vibration, and the slightest footfall is enough to draw their attention. Some scholars believe it may be possible to "disappear" from an ashsnakes "vision" by standing perfectly still, but finding volunteers to confirm this theory has understandably proven difficult.

“Beneath the ash it lies in wait. A hiss, a snap, and it’s too late.”
- From The Epic of Fire, a centuries old poem.

Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 177</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Aspect of Fire</name>
    <size>G</size>
    <type>elemental</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>15</ac>
    <hp>174 (12d20 + 48)</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <str>21</str>
    <dex>13</dex>
    <con>18</con>
    <int>6</int>
    <wis>15</wis>
    <cha>14</cha>
    <save>Wis +6</save>
    <skill/>
    <passive>12</passive>
    <languages>Ignan</languages>
    <cr>12</cr>
    <exp>8400</exp>
    <resist>Bludgeoning, Piercing or Slashing damage from non-magical weapons</resist>
    <immune>fire, poison</immune>
    <vulnerable/>
    <conditionImmune>exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, restrained, unconscious</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
    <name>Legendary Resistance (3/day)</name>
    <text>
If the aspect of fire fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
</trait>
    <trait>
    <name>Molten Skin</name>
    <text>
Any creature who touches, makes a melee attack within 5 feet of, or ends their turn within 5 feet of the aspect takes 11 (2d10) fire damage. Flammable objects within 5 feet of the aspect burst into flames.</text>
    <roll>2d10</roll>
</trait>
    <trait>
    <name>Natural Light</name>
    <text>
The aspect gives off bright light in a 60-foot-radius and dim light for an additional 60 feet.</text>
</trait>
    <trait>
    <name>Cooling</name>
    <text>
If the aspect of fire takes 50 or more cold damage in one round, its speed is reduced to 0 until the end of its next turn.</text>
</trait>
    <trait>
    <name>Fuel for the Fire</name>
    <text>
The aspect of fire doesn't treat plant life as difficult terrain. Whenever the aspect begins its turn in a space of plant life that provides cover, it burns the plant life away from all spaces it is currently occupying, healing 1d4 hit points for each 5-foot square of such plant life it has consumed. If it heals for 17 or more damage in this way, it flares up, recharging its magma throw action.</text>
    <roll>1d4</roll>
</trait>
    <action>
    <name>Multiattack</name>
    <text>
The aspect makes two molten fist attacks</text>
</action>
    <action>
    <name>Molten Fist</name>
    <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 16 (2d10 + 5) fire damage.</text>
    <attack>Molten Fist|+9|2d10+5</attack>
</action>
    <action>
    <name>Stomp</name>
    <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 20 (3d10 + 5) fire damage. The target must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
    <attack>Stomp|+9|3d10+5</attack>
</action>
    <action>
    <name>Magma Throw (Recharge 5-6)</name>
    <text>
The aspect hurls a ball of molten rock. Choose a location within 60 feet of the aspect. All creatures within 15 feet of the target location must make a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 22 (4d10) fire damage. On a success, the creature takes half as much damage.</text>
    <attack>Magma Throw (Recharge 5-6)||4d10</attack>
</action>
    <legendary>
    <text>
The aspect of fire can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time, and only at the end of another creature's turn. The aspect regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</text>
</legendary>
    <legendary>
    <name>Detect</name>
    <text>
The aspect makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
</legendary>
    <legendary>
    <name>Molten Fist</name>
    <text>
The aspect makes a molten fist attack.</text>
</legendary>
    <legendary>
    <name>Magma Barrage (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
    <text>
The aspect of fire uses its magma throw action. It may use this ability if it has not yet been recharged by dealing 17 points of cold damage to itself.</text>
</legendary>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>The aspect of fire is an elemental creature of fire and molten rock, whose gargantuan frame could easily be mistaken for a small mountain. The aspect is not only a creature of heat and energy, but also of destruction and rage, and it appears to draw strength from the forests its flames consume.

Primal Incarnation:
A creature of legend, it is believed by some that this was the "being of fire and destruction" said to have caused the Great Calamity that created the Scorched Grove many centuries ago. The aspect possesses frightening power, enough to cause serious harm to the Wood and all those who inhabit it. Long has it been forgotten that the creature was conjured in a lost ritual. Shortly afterwards, it was sealed away beneath the Scorched Grove where its presence has continued to affect the region. Centuries of dormancy have weakened the aspect, as its essence has seeped into the surrounding land. Since being released, it has begun to amass power for itself by consuming plants, trees, and other living beings in flame. Once it attains enough energy to completely break the mystical fetters that tie it to the Scorched Grove, it will be an unstoppable force that could very well bring fiery ruin to all of Humblewood.

Stirring in its Slumber:
The strange occurrences of late have many prominent scholars baffled: unusually aggressive emberbats, the appearance of ashsnakes, the increased frequency of forest fires, and many other phenomena which have never been seen before in Humblewood. More than mere legend, the aspect is the reason for all of these. As a creature of primordial fire, it is inextricably bound to the plane of its element. Even as it slumbered beneath the Grove for generations, the aspect has stirred, its presence causing a weakening in the barrier which keeps the material plane separate from the plane of fire, allowing for weaker creatures to slip through.

The aspect's essence has also seeped into the Scorched Grove, causing the landscape to take on far stronger elemental properties than before. The fundamental shift in the Grove's nature has effectively thwarted the efforts of the Tenders, who have for so long sought to heal this burned land. As the aspect continues to grow in power, more of this harmful elemental energy will be released, and even more powerful creatures will arise from the flames. If this otherworldly power spreads across the forest unchecked, all of Humblewood might suffer the fate of the Scorched Grove.

Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 179</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster>
  <monster>
    <name>Birdfolk Skeleton</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>undead</type>
    <alignment>Lawful Evil</alignment>
    <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>12 (2d8 + 4)</hp>
    <speed>30 ft.</speed>
    <str>11</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>7</int>
    <wis>8</wis>
    <cha>4</cha>
    <save/>
    <skill/>
    <passive>9</passive>
    <languages>understands Auran and Birdfolk, but can't speak</languages>
    <cr>1/4</cr>
    <exp>50</exp>
    <resist/>
    <immune>poison</immune>
    <vulnerable>Bludgeoning</vulnerable>
    <conditionImmune>exhaustion, poisoned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
    <trait>
    <name>Talons</name>
    <text>
The birdfolk skeleton has advantage on Strength (Athletics) checks made to climb any surface its talons could reasonably grip.</text>
</trait>
    <action>
    <name>Shortsword</name>
    <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage.</text>
    <attack>Shortsword|+4|1d6+2</attack>
</action>
    <action>
    <name>Talons</name>
    <text>
Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) piercing damage.</text>
    <attack>Talons|+4|1d4+2</attack>
</action>
    <spells/>
    <slots/>
    <description>Deceased birdfolk granted a semblance of life through necromantic spells don't have memory per se, but their skeletal bodies retain familiarity with tasks they performed in life. They also remain skilled with weapons they wielded in life, making them useful guards or servants.

Unnatural Life
Animated skeletons are common among the practitioners of the necromantic arts. Even at the Avium, where necromancy is forbidden in practice, it is taught in theory. A common exception is the use of animated skeletons for menial tasks around the college. The reanimation of birdfolk who did not give their express consent in life is seen as a violation of their memory, so these skeletons usually consist of former college staff who desired to stay and help long past their own time. Not all scholars agree that even this relatively benign form of necromancy should be allowed, while others don't see why permission from the dead should be necessary, believing that "dead is dead". Though the consent policy remains in place, heady debates over the ethics of certain forms of necromancy have resulted in the shunning of more morally flexible scholars.

Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 180</description>
    <environment/>
</monster>
</compendium>
