<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <item>
    <name>Blade of the Wood (Shortsword)</name>
    <detail>Shortsword, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <type>M</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <value>10.0</value>
    <property>F,L,M</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <text>A finely crafted sword with delicate etchings, it resonates with a faint hum of life.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The sword has 2 charges. You can expend a charge and speak the command word to cast spike growth (save DC 16) centered on yourself. You can pass through this terrain unaffected.

The sword regains one charge each day at dawn.

Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Proficiency: martial, shortsword
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 213</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Damage +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Blade of the Wood (Longsword)</name>
    <detail>Longsword, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <type>M</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <value>15.0</value>
    <property>V,M</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>A finely crafted sword with delicate etchings, it resonates with a faint hum of life.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The sword has 2 charges. You can expend a charge and speak the command word to cast spike growth (save DC 16) centered on yourself. You can pass through this terrain unaffected.

The sword regains one charge each day at dawn.

Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property—the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee Attack.

Proficiency: martial, longsword
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 213</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Damage +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Blade of the Wood (Greatsword)</name>
    <detail>Greatsword, rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <type>M</type>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <value>50.0</value>
    <property>H,2H,M</property>
    <dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>A finely crafted sword with delicate etchings, it resonates with a faint hum of life.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The sword has 2 charges. You can expend a charge and speak the command word to cast spike growth (save DC 16) centered on yourself. You can pass through this terrain unaffected.

The sword regains one charge each day at dawn.

Heavy: Creatures that are Small or Tiny have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small or Tiny creature to use effectively.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Proficiency: martial, greatsword
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 213</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Damage +1</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>The Borealus</name>
    <detail>Staff, spellcasting focus, artifact (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>ST</type>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <value>5.0</value>
    <property/>
    <text>This legendary artifact was created by a powerful wizard, crafted from the finger of a towering, ancient elemental aspect of frost. It is so cold to the touch that it numbs any skin it comes into contact with, although an attuned character is immune to this effect.

Gifts of the Rime:
As long as you are attuned to the Borealus, you gain the following benefits:

	• You are resistant to fire damage
	• You are immune to cold damage
	• You learn the ray of frost cantrip

Breath of Winter:
While holding the staff you can use your action to unleash an icy-cold blizzard from your open mouth. A 100-foot-cone of hoarfrost blasts forth in a direction of your choice, dealing 9d8 cold damage to all creatures within the cone if they fail a DC 18 Constitution saving throw, or half as much on a success. You can't use this property again until the next dawn.

Glacial Prison:
By using your action to touch the staff to a surface, you can cause a barrier of ice to spring into existence from a point you can see along this surface within 200 feet of you. This effect is otherwise identical to a wall of ice spell cast at 6th level, with a DC 18 for all saving throws related to the effect. You can't use this property again until 3 days have passed.

Cruel Winds:
Wherever the staff goes, a bitterly cold boreal wind accompanies it. The wind gusts intermittently within 30 feet of the attuned character and extinguishes all non-magical flames it comes into contact with.

Destroying the Staff:
The staff can be destroyed through exposure to flames from a fire elemental of equal power to the being it was crafted from. After centuries of exposure, it will melt away into nothing.

Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 213</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Feathered Helm</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>The helm itself is simple leather, hide, scale, or plate, but the magic imbued into it comes from the feather. The birdfolk races of Humblewood consider the giving of a feather to be one of the highest honors one can bestow, and it represents an eternal bond or deep appreciation.

The helm has 3 charges that, while wearing it, you can use to activate its abilities. The helm has different properties based on the race of the birdfolk who gifted the feather.

Corvum:
You can use a charge to cast hideous laughter (save DC 16) and two charges to cast detect thoughts (save DC 16).

Gallus:
You can use a charge to cast bless and two charges to cast aid.

Luma:
You can use a charge to cast a random 1st-level spell from the sorcerer spell list, then roll a d20. On a roll of 20, you may use this ability again without expending a charge. On a roll of 1, the spell also targets you, unless you are its only target, in which case the spell fizzles to no effect. Any spell cast using this helm that requires a saving throw has a save DC of 16.

Raptor:
You can use a charge to cast hunter's mark and two charges to cast magic weapon.

Strig:
You can use a charge to cast divine favor and two charges to cast pass without trace.

The helm regains 1d3 charges each day at dawn.

Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 213</text>
    <roll>1d20</roll>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Necronomicon Ex Corvis</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <detail>rare (requires attunement by a wizard)</detail>
    <text>This legendary tome of dark necromancy was penned by the mad corvum necromancer Lathrus, of the Night's Call. The book is one of a kind and contains terrible necromantic secrets.

The Necronomicon Ex Corvis is a spellbook, and as such only wizards can truly benefit from studying the dark secrets within.

Abyssal Secrets:
By spending a full week studying the dark secrets in this tome, your Intelligence score increases by 2. These secrets gnaw at your mind, however, and your Wisdom score decreases by 1.

Grasp of Shadows:
By spending at least a minute reciting a ritual listed in this book, you can summon forth 1d4 + 2 shadows. These creatures are loyal to you and can understand any instructions you give them. They will carry out these instructions to the best of their ability. This property can only be used once per week.

Knowledge Beyond Reason:
You may add the spells listed below into your spellbook. However, the tome removes the restriction that requires you to be able to prepare and cast these spells. In effect, you can copy these spells to your spellbook now, though they will only be available to prepare once you reach a level at which you can cast them. Additionally, rather than pay gold pieces to copy any spell within into your spellbook, you may deal one point of damage to yourself and take one level of exhaustion to scribe the spell in your own blood.

Level | Spell
3rd | animate dead, bestow curse, vampiric touch
4th | blight
6th | circle of death, magic jar
7th | finger of death

The Corvum's Curse:
After copying at least one spell from this tome into your spellbook, you must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or become cursed (as bestow curse), with the effect of the curse being decided by the GM. The curse persists for 2d4 days, but its duration resets anytime you copy a spell from this book. Otherwise, only a remove curse spell cast using a 5th level or higher spell slot can rid you of this effect.

Destroying the Book:
Unlike other artifacts, the book is not immune to damage. Pages removed from the book will lose their magic within a day. Additionally, exposing the book to direct sunlight for at least 8 hours will cause the dark magic within to dissipate, rendering it useless.

Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 213</text>
    <roll>1d4+2</roll>
    <roll>2d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Nest Charm</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>W</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <text>This charm is a sphere of intricate metal branches, interwoven to form a sort of nest.

By placing the charm on the ground and speaking its command word, you can cause it to unfold, creating a 30-foot-diameter circular platform of interwoven branches. Once the platform has reached its full size, a magical tree grows beneath it, lifting the platform 50 feet into the air, carrying any passengers and items along with it.

This perch lasts up to 8 hours, at which point the tree will retreat into the ground and the platform will shrink, eventually curling back into the small charm. At any time the command word can be spoken again to dismiss the perch in a similar fashion. Once the nest charm's power has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.

Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 214</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Red-Feather Hand Crossbow</name>
    <detail>Hand Crossbow, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <value>75.0</value>
    <property>A,L,LD,M</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>30/120</range>
    <text>A prized hunting weapon among mistral raptors, this bow is imbued with magic to help the wielder see their prey from afar.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The bow has 3 charges. When you fire an arrow from this bow, you can speak the command word and use a charge to see through the arrow as a bonus action. You can see from the point your arrow lands as if you were there for 1 minute. If the arrow strikes a creature, you see what they see for the same duration.

The bow regains 1d3 charges each day at dawn.

Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack (you need a free hand to load a one-handed weapon). At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons").

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Loading: Because of the time required to load this weapon, you can fire only one piece of ammunition from it when you use an action, bonus action, or reaction to fire it, regardless of the number of attacks you can normally make.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Proficiency: martial, hand crossbow
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 214</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Damage +1</modifier>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Red-Feather Heavy Crossbow</name>
    <detail>Heavy Crossbow, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <weight>18</weight>
    <value>50.0</value>
    <property>A,H,LD,2H,M</property>
    <dmg1>1d10</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>100/400</range>
    <text>A prized hunting weapon among mistral raptors, this bow is imbued with magic to help the wielder see their prey from afar.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The bow has 3 charges. When you fire an arrow from this bow, you can speak the command word and use a charge to see through the arrow as a bonus action. You can see from the point your arrow lands as if you were there for 1 minute. If the arrow strikes a creature, you see what they see for the same duration.

The bow regains 1d3 charges each day at dawn.

Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack (you need a free hand to load a one-handed weapon). At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons").

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Loading: Because of the time required to load this weapon, you can fire only one piece of ammunition from it when you use an action, bonus action, or reaction to fire it, regardless of the number of attacks you can normally make.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.

Proficiency: martial, heavy crossbow
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 214</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Damage +1</modifier>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Red-Feather Light Crossbow</name>
    <detail>Light Crossbow, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <value>25.0</value>
    <property>A,LD,2H</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>80/320</range>
    <text>A prized hunting weapon among mistral raptors, this bow is imbued with magic to help the wielder see their prey from afar.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The bow has 3 charges. When you fire an arrow from this bow, you can speak the command word and use a charge to see through the arrow as a bonus action. You can see from the point your arrow lands as if you were there for 1 minute. If the arrow strikes a creature, you see what they see for the same duration.

The bow regains 1d3 charges each day at dawn.

Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack (you need a free hand to load a one-handed weapon). At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons").

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Loading: Because of the time required to load this weapon, you can fire only one piece of ammunition from it when you use an action, bonus action, or reaction to fire it, regardless of the number of attacks you can normally make.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Proficiency: simple, light crossbow
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 214</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Damage +1</modifier>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Red-Feather Light Repeating Crossbow</name>
    <detail>Light Repeating Crossbow, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <property>A,2H</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>40/160</range>
    <text>A prized hunting weapon among mistral raptors, this bow is imbued with magic to help the wielder see their prey from afar.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The bow has 3 charges. When you fire an arrow from this bow, you can speak the command word and use a charge to see through the arrow as a bonus action. You can see from the point your arrow lands as if you were there for 1 minute. If the arrow strikes a creature, you see what they see for the same duration.

The bow regains 1d3 charges each day at dawn.

This crossbow is fitted with a cartridge that can hold up to six crossbow bolts. It automatically reloads after firing until the cartridge runs out of ammunition. Reloading the cartridge takes an action.

Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack (you need a free hand to load a one-handed weapon). At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons").

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Proficiency: simple, light repeating crossbow
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 214</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Damage +1</modifier>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Red-Feather Longbow</name>
    <detail>Longbow, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <value>50.0</value>
    <property>A,H,2H,M</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>150/600</range>
    <text>A prized hunting weapon among mistral raptors, this bow is imbued with magic to help the wielder see their prey from afar.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The bow has 3 charges. When you fire an arrow from this bow, you can speak the command word and use a charge to see through the arrow as a bonus action. You can see from the point your arrow lands as if you were there for 1 minute. If the arrow strikes a creature, you see what they see for the same duration.

The bow regains 1d3 charges each day at dawn.

Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack (you need a free hand to load a one-handed weapon). At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons").

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.

Proficiency: martial, longbow
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 214</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Damage +1</modifier>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Red-Feather Shortbow</name>
    <detail>Shortbow, uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <value>25.0</value>
    <property>A,2H</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>80/320</range>
    <text>A prized hunting weapon among mistral raptors, this bow is imbued with magic to help the wielder see their prey from afar.

You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.

The bow has 3 charges. When you fire an arrow from this bow, you can speak the command word and use a charge to see through the arrow as a bonus action. You can see from the point your arrow lands as if you were there for 1 minute. If the arrow strikes a creature, you see what they see for the same duration.

The bow regains 1d3 charges each day at dawn.

Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack (you need a free hand to load a one-handed weapon). At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons").

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Proficiency: simple, shortbow
Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 214</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Attacks +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Damage +1</modifier>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wing Crest Shield</name>
    <detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>S</type>
    <weight>6</weight>
    <value>10.0</value>
    <property/>
    <ac>2</ac>
    <text>While wielding this shield, you gain a +1 bonus to your AC.

As an action, you can speak the command word to cast gust of wind (save DC 15). Once the shield has been used to cast this spell, it can't be used to cast this spell again until the next dawn.

A shield is made from wood or metal and is carried in one hand. Wielding a shield increases your Armor Class by 2. You can benefit from only one shield at a time.

Source:	Humblewood Campaign Setting p. 214</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
  </item>
</compendium>