<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Bard [2024]</name>
    <!-- Bard Subclass: College Of The Moon (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard Subclass: College Of The Moon (UA)</name>
        <text>Inspire Allies with Primal Tales

The College of the Moon traces its origins to the ancient druidic circles of the Moonshae Isles, who entrusted the first Bards of this tradition with chronicling the stories of the islands and their people. Bards of this college draw from the isles' Fey magic and the primal power of the moonwells to bolster their allies, protect the natural world, and inspire their bardic works. Such works tend to be based on well-known Moonshae myths such as the whimsy of fairy pranksters, the viciousness of the Beast, and the mysteries of the moonwells.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Moonshae Folktales (College Of The Moon (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Magic action, you can invoke the power of a folktale, imbuing yourself with primal magic until you use this feature again. When you use this feature, choose which of the following folktales you invoke; your choice gives you certain benefits while this magic is active.

Tale of Life. You invoke a tale of vitality and thriving earth. When you restore Hit Points to a creature with a spell, you can expend a Bardic Inspiration die and increase the amount of Hit Points restored by a number equal to a roll of the Bardic Inspiration die. You can do this only once per turn.

Tale of Gloam. You invoke a tale of mystery and secrets. When you use a Bonus Action to give a creature a Bardic Inspiration die, you can take the Disengage or Hide action as part of that Bonus Action.

Tale of Mirth. You invoke a tale of merriment and fey guile. When an enemy you can see within 60 feet of yourself succeeds on a saving throw, you can take a Reaction to expend a Bardic Inspiration die. The creature then must roll the Bardic Inspiration die and subtract the number rolled from the save's total, possibly causing the save to fail.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 1</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Primal Lorist (College Of The Moon (UA))</name>
        <text>You learn Druidic and one cantrip from the Druid spell list. It counts as a Bard spell for you but doesn't count against the number of cantrips you know.

Additionally, choose one of the following skills: Animal Handling, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Perception, or Survival. You have proficiency in that skill.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Blessing Of The Moonwells (College Of The Moon (UA))</name>
        <text>You always have the Moonbeam spell prepared.

As a Bonus Action, you can cast Moonbeam without expending a spell slot. When you cast it using this feature, you glow faintly while you maintain Concentration on the spell. While glowing, you shed Dim Light out to 5 feet, and whenever a creature fails its saving throw against the effects of this Moonbeam, another creature of your choice that you can see within 60 feet of you regains 2d4 Hit Points.

Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by expending a level 3+ spell slot (no action required).

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Bolstered Folktales (College Of The Moon (UA))</name>
        <text>The power of your Moonshae Folktales improves. When you use your Tale of Life or Tale of Mirth, you can roll 1d6 and use the number rolled in place of expending a Bardic Inspiration die, and when you use your Tale of Gloam, you can also teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see as part of that Bonus Action.

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Forgotten Realms Subclasses p. 2</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
