<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Barbarian</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Primal Path: Path of the Blighted</name>
        <text>The Path of the Blighted is a path of unholy origin, traced back to the same origin of the Blights: the Gulthias Tree. By gaining power from this evil source, you can channel your rage to shift your physical form, becoming a monstrous abomination of vines and branches. While transformed, you engulf and constrict your enemies as you tear them apart.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Path of the Blighted: Demoralizing Blow</name>
        <text>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, you become a blighted monster when you rage. For the duration of your rage, whenever you successfully grapple a creature you can choose to constrict them with vines, causing them to be restrained for the duration of the grapple.

Whenever you take damage while restraining a creature in this manner, you must succeed on a Constitution saving throw to maintain the restrained condition. The DC equals 10 or the damage you take, whichever number is higher. On a failed save, the restrained condition ends until the end of the creature's next turn, though they still remain grappled.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Path of the Blighted: False Appearance</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, your body is now able to become temporarily plantlike. As an action, you can camouflage yourself against the surface of a plant, such as the bark of a tree, a large bush, or an area of thick vines. When you do so, you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check with advantage, remaining camouflaged until you move or take an action.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Path of the Blighted: Blighted Veins</name>
        <text>At 10th level, whenever you rage you can cast the thorn whip cantrip as a bonus action on your turn. Constitution is your spellcasting ability for this spell.

Additionally, you no longer have to make Constitution saving throws to avoid ending the restrained condition from your Blighted Transformation feature. The restrained condition now lasts for the duration of the grapple.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Path of the Blighted: Reactive Tendrils</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, whenever you take damage from a creature within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to release grasping vines at the attacker, attempting to grapple the target.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <class>
    <name>Bard</name>
    <!--  Ancients  -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bard College: College of the Ancients</name>
        <text>Bards of the College of Ancients have deep knowledge in the area of nature magic, and they often wander the wilderness, collecting knowledge on the magic of the earth. They are most often wandering singers and skalds, traveling through ancient forests and long abandoned roads, often singing to nobody at all. They wish, first and foremost, to protect and honor nature. They tell tales of great floods and good harvests, tremendous storms and frightening gales. They learn to be one with nature.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Ancients: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
        <text>When you join the College of Ancients at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor, shields, and the Nature skill.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Ancients: Words of the Ancients</name>
        <text>Also at 3rd level, you learn how to command plants to grasp at the heels of your foes, impeding their movement. When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you begins moving, you can use your reaction to expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration, rolling a Bardic Inspiration die and reducing the creature's speed by a number of feet equal to the number rolled x 5 until the end of their turn. This cannot reduce a creature's speed below 5 feet.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Ancients: Hand of the Ancients</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, you can cast Gaea's Hand at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>College of the Ancients: Song of Awakening</name>
        <text>At 14th level, you learn an ancient melody that can awaken a small non-magical shrub. While standing next to a shrub, you may sing for 1 minute and roll a Bardic Inspiration die, awakening the shrub and adding the number rolled as temporary hit points for the creature, which uses the statistics for the awakened shrub. The shrub remains awakened and under your command until you complete a long rest, at which point it returns to being a normal plant.

As a bonus action on your turn, you can command the shrubs to move and use their actions. Additionally, whenever you cast a spell, an awakened shrub can deliver the spell as if it had cast the spell. The shrub must be within 60 feet of you, and it must use its reaction to deliver the spell when you cast it. If the spell requires an attack roll, you use your attack modifier for the roll.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <class>
    <name>Druid</name>
    <!--  Seedling  -->
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Druid Circle: Circle of the Seedling</name>
        <text>Druids of the Circle of the Seedling delve more completely into the ancient rituals and hidden knowledge of plant magic. These druids meet together in their Plant Wild Shape, sharing their wisdom and arcane secrets with each other in Druidic, while appearing to just be a small bunch of shrubs and trees. As a member of this circle, your magic allows you to be one with your surroundings, gaining intricate control over the plants around you.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Circle of the Seedling: Plant Wild Shape</name>
        <text>When you choose this circle at 2nd level, you gain the ability to use Wild Shape to assume the shape of a plant creature.

When you transform into a plant creature, the Max CR that you can transform into is increased to 1. Starting at 6th level, you can transform into a Plant with a challenge rating as high as your druid level divided by 3, rounded down.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Circle of the Seedling: Plantspeaker</name>
        <text>Also at 2nd level, when you are transformed into a plant creature you gain the ability to command nearby mundane plants. As an action, you can turn difficult terrain caused by plant growth into ordinary terrain in a 5 foot radius centered on you, or you can turn ordinary terrain where plants are present into difficult terrain in a 5 foot radius centered on you. After a 10 minute duration, the plants return to their original condition.

Additionally, while you are transformed into a plant creature you ignore difficult terrain caused by plants.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Circle of the Seedling: Take Root</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, you gain the ability to root yourself in the ground while in your normal form, forming a protective armor of bark around yourself. As an action on your turn, you can root yourself in the ground, reducing your speed to 0 and granting you advantage on checks made to avoid being moved.

Until you end this effect using your bonus action or fall unconscious, you have a +1 bonus to AC and resistance to slashing, bludgeoning and piercing damage from non-magical weapons.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Circle of the Seedling: Spore Sovereign</name>
        <text>At 10th level, you gain the ability to release spores while in your normal form. You gain 2 different types of spores, detailed below.

Rapport Spores: As an action, you create a 30-foot radius of spores which extends from your position. These spores can go around corners and affect only creatures with an Intelligence of 2 or higher that aren't undead, constructs, or elementals. Affected creatures can communicate telepathically with one another while they are within 30 feet of each other. The effect lasts for 1 hour.

Poison Spores: As an action, you eject spores at a creature within 5 feet of you. The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be poisoned for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the condition on a success. Once the creature succeeds on its saving throw, it becomes immune to these spores for 1 minute.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Circle of the Seedling: One with the Forest</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, you gain the ability to cast barkskin, speak with plants, and arm of the wild without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <class>
    <name>Monk</name>
    <!--  Way of Thorns  -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of Thorns</name>
        <text>You follow a monastic tradition that teaches you to harness the power of nature. Nature has become an extension of yourself, and you have learned to use it to great effect. By following this Way, you learn techniques to manipulate plants, allowing them to bend to your will and aid you both in combat and out of it.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Way of Thorns: Disciple of the Wilds</name>
        <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you learn magical disciplines that harness the power of nature. A discipline requires you to spend ki points each time you use it.

You know the Natural Attunement discipline and one other nature discipline of your choice, which are detailed in the "Nature Disciplines" section below. You learn one additional nature discipline of your choice at 6th, 11th.and 17th level.

Whenever you learn a new natural discipline, you can also replace one nature discipline that you already know with a different discipline.

Casting Nature Spells: Some nature disciplines allow you to cast spells. To cast one of these spells, you use its casting time and other rules, but you don't need to provide material components for it.

Once you reach 5th level in this class, you can spend additional ki points to increase the level of a nature discipline spell that you cast, provided that the spell has an enhanced effect at a higher level, as slicing leaves does. The spell's level increases by 1 for each additional ki point you spend. For example, if you are a 5th-level monk and use Nature's Weapon to cast slicing leaves, you can spend 3 ki points to cast it as a 2nd-level spell (the discipline's base cost of 2 ki points plus 1).

The maximum number of ki points you can spend to cast a spell in this way(including its base ki point cost and any additional ki points you spend to increase its level) is determined by your monk level. as shown in the Spells and Ki Points table.

5th-8th: 3
9th-12th: 4
13th-16th: 5
17th-20th: 6</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Way of Thorns: Nature Disciplines</name>
        <text>The nature disciplines are presented in alphabetical order. If a discipline requires a level, you must be that level in this class to learn the discipline.

Breath of Pain (6th Level Required): You can spend 3 ki points to cast spray of thorns.

Bridge of Spring: You can spend 2 ki points to cast bridge of branches.

Earthen Restraints: You can spend 2 ki points to cast entangle.

Fang of the Earth (6th Level Required): You can spend 3 ki points to cast explosive seed.

Felling Strike (11th Level Required): You can spend 4 ki points to cast fell.

Hidden Grove: You can spend 2 ki points to cast overgrowth.

Natural Attunement:
You can use your action to briefly control the natural world, causing one of the following effects of your choice:

	• Create a harmless, instantaneous sensory effect related to nature, such as the smell of flowers, a rumbling of tree branches, or the brush of falling leaves.
	• Cause a plant's flowers to blossom or fruits to ripen.
	• Change the color of a plant for 1 minute, choosing a portion of the plant that can fit in a 5 ft. cube.
	• Cause a plant that can fit within a 5 ft. cube to shape itself into a crude form you designate for 1 minute.

Nature's Commune: You can spend 2 ki points to cast rapport spores.

Nature's Weapon: You can spend 2 ki points to cast slicing leaves.

Skewering Fist (11th Level Required): You can spend 4 ki points to cast skewering branch.

Stride of the Dryad (17th Level Required): You can spend 6 ki points to cast tree stride.

Striking Vine (6th Level Required): You can spend 3 ki points to cast arm of the wild.

Treant's Fist (17th Level Required): You can spend 5 ki points to cast tree strike.

Wave of Thorns (11th Level Required): You can spend 4 ki points to cast engulfing thorns.

Verdant Grasp (17th Level Required): You can spend 5 ki points to cast grasping vine.

Verdant Hand: You can spend 2 ki points to cast gaea's hand. The hand uses your unarmed strike damage as its damage die.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Way of Thorns: Additional Natural Discipline</name>
        <text>You learn one additional nature discipline of your choice at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Way of Thorns: Additional Natural Discipline</name>
        <text>You learn one additional nature discipline of your choice at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Way of Thorns: Additional Natural Discipline</name>
        <text>You learn one additional nature discipline of your choice at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>

  <class>
    <name>Ranger</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ranger Archetype: Seedmaster</name>
        <text>The Seedmaster archetype serves as an alternate path to the Beastmaster archetype, instead growing a bond between a small plant creature and the ranger. The ranger and the plant work as one to fight off forces of evil and destruction. Seedmaster rangers lovingly cultivate their magic seedlings, forming an almost pet-like bond between themselves and the animated plant.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Seedmaster: Magic Seedling</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you learn a ritual that creates a magical bond between yourself and a small seedling. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. At the conclusion of this ritual, the seedling gains magical powers that you can activate.

As a bonus action, you may throw the seedling up to 30 feet, which then roots itself into the ground where it lands. The seedling has 10 + your proficiency bonus AC and hit points equal to 10 + your ranger level, and cannot move until you safely unroot it using a 1 minute ritual. If the seedling is reduced to 0 hit points, it withers back into a small seed which cannot be deployed again until you complete a long rest. Once the seedling is planted, you learn the following commands:

Thorn Strike: As a bonus action, you can command the seedling to shoot a thorn at an enemy within 30 feet of it that you can see. Make a ranged spell attack against that enemy. On a hit, the target takes 1d4 piercing damage.

This damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4)

Trip Attack: When a creature that you can see moves within 5 feet of the seedling, you may use your reaction to command the seedling to trip that creature. The creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or fall prone.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Seedmaster: Power of the Seed</name>
        <text>At 7th level, you can either upgrade the seedling's Thorn strike or Trip attack feature.

Thorn Strike Upgrade: Whenever Thorn St	rike hits an enemy, your next attack against that enemy is made with advantage.

Trip Attack Upgrade: Trip Attack's range increases to 15 feet.</text>

      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Seedmaster: Uncanny Strikes</name>
        <text>Beginning at 11th level, your seedling has advantage on all of its Thorn Strikes, and creatures have disadvantage on the saving throw against Trip Attack.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Seedmaster: Nature's Bond</name>
        <text>Starting at 15th level, you can use your action to see and hear out of your seedling as long as you are on the same plane of existence until the end of your next turn.

Additionally, you may perform the unrooting ritual from anywhere on the same plane of existence as your Seedling, teleporting the seed back to your hand.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>