<?xml version="1.0"?>
<compendium xmlns:exsl="http://exslt.org/common" version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <spell>
    <name>Arm of the Wild</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <castingtime>1 bonus action</castingtime>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <text>You transform one of your arms into an extendable vine whose end sticks to any surface that it touches. The arm cannot be used to wield any objects or weapons. As you cast the spell and on every turn within the duration, you can make either of the following actions:

Grab Creature. As a bonus action, you extend your vine arm forward, attempting to pull one creature you choose within 20 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be pulled 10 feet directly towards you.

Grab Surface. As either a bonus action on your turn or a reaction to when you fall, you extend your vine arm forward, pulling yourself to a hard surface such as a wall or ceiling within 20 feet of you. If this movement would cause you to be suspended off the ground, you remain so until you take an action or the concentration ends.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
    <classes>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bonding Vine</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 bonus action</time>
    <range>20 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a small twig)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>Choose one creature you can see within range. That creature must succeed on a Dexterity Saving throw or become connected to you with a magical vine. A creature that you are connected with must make a Strength saving throw whenever they attempt to move to a point more than 20 feet away from you. On a failed save, their speed is reduced to zero until the start of their next turn and they are knocked prone. On a successful save, the vine snaps, and they are freed.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bridge of Branches</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>YES</ritual>
    <time>1 minute</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S, M (the branch of a tree)</components>
    <duration>1 hour</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You cause large branches to sprout from a surface, creating a makeshift bridge up to 20 feet in length. The bridge can hold up to 600 pounds at once. The bridge has AC 10 and 50 hit points. If the bridge is reduced to zero hit points, the entire bridge collapses and immediately withers away.

At Higher Levels:
When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the bridge's length increases by 10 feet, its weight limit increases by 100 pounds, and its hit points increase by 25 for each slot level above 1st.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cloud of Spores</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a fungal spore)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You conjure a cloud of hallucination spores in a 10-foot cube within range. Each creature within the cube must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 3d8 poison damage and become poisoned for 1 minute. A poisoned target is incapacitated while it hallucinates. A target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.

At Higher Levels:
When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Conjure Plant Creature</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 minute</time>
    <range>90 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a branch with leaves)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
    <classes>Druid, Ranger, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You call forth a plant creature to serve you. Choose an area of plant life that fills a 10-foot cube within range. A plant creature of challenge rating 5 or lower appears in an unoccupied space within 10 feet of it. The creature is friendly to you and your companions for the duration. Roll initiative for the creature, which has its own turns. lt obeys any verbal commands that you issue to it (no action required by you). If you don't issue any commands to the creature, it defends itself from hostile creatures but otherwise takes no actions.

If your concentration is broken, the plant creature doesn't disappear. Instead, you lose control of it, it becomes hostile toward you and your companions, and it might attack. An uncontrolled creature can't be dismissed by you, and it disappears 1 hour after you summoned it.

The DM has the elemental's statistics.

At Higher Levels:
When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the challenge rating increases by 1 for each slot level above 5th.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dryad's Leap</name>
    <level>6</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>400 feet</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
    <classes>Druid</classes>
    <text>You choose up to 10 Large or larger inanimate plants that you can see within range. For the duration, you and up to 10 other creatures of your choice within range can step into one of these plants and exit from any of the other plants targeted by this spell by using 5 feet of movement. Each creature may only use this ability once per round.

At Higher Levels:
When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the range increases by 200 feet and the maximum number of plants and creatures chosen increases by 2 for each slot level above 6th.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Engulfing Thorns</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>10 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a rose thorn)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You conjure thorny vines which grow along a line 5 feet wide and 10 feet long emanating from you in a direction you choose, engulfing everything they touch. At the start of each of your turns, the length of the line increases by 5 feet in the same direction. For the duration, these vines turn the ground in that area to difficult terrain.

When a creature enters the affected area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, the creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 2d6 piercing damage and be restrained by the vines until the spell ends. A creature that starts its turn in the area and is already restrained by the vines takes 2d6 piercing damage and is pulled 5 feet in the direction that the vines are growing.

A creature restrained by the vines can use its action to make a Strength or Dexterity check (its choice) against your spell save DC. On a success, it frees itself.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Explosive Seed</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You conjure an explosive seed and then throw it a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 4d4 fire damage. On both a hit or a miss, the seed drops to the ground and sizzles violently. At the start of your next turn, the seed explodes. Each creature in a 10-foot radius must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d4 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.

At Higher Levels:
When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the initial damage and the explosion damage each increase by 1d4 for each slot level above 2nd.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fell</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>Cleric, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You cause a non-magical tree to fall, damaging all creatures in its path. You choose the direction that the tree falls, and the area that it effects changes depending on the height of the tree. You cannot target a tree with a diameter greater than 5 feet. Each creature within the line of the trunk must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 7d8 bludgeoning damage. The tree then remains on the ground, providing partial cover for those behind it.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Gaea's Hand</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a vial of water)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Druid, Ranger, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You conjure a makeshift arm made of weeds and branches, which sprouts out of a point within range. As you cast the spell, you may give a melee weapon to the arm for it to fight with. The weapon given to it must be a weapon of a size you could wield. Otherwise, it deals 1d4 damage on its attacks.

As a bonus action on your turn, you may command the arm to strike a foe within 10 feet of it. Make a melee spell attack. On a hit, the target takes 1d4+your spellcasting ability modifier bludgeoning damage. If a weapon was given to the arm, it instead uses that weapon's damage die and damage type.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Grasping Sprout</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 bonus action</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a seedling)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Druid, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You conjure a small vine with a reach of 5 feet. Whenever a creature enters its reach, you may use your reaction to have the sprout attempt to grasp at its heels, stopping its movement. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or have their speed reduced to zero until the start of their next turn.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mind Spore</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Until dispelled</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You place a magical spore in someone's brain. The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or become affected by a Mind Spore. On a successful save, the creature knows that it has been targeted by a spell. On a failed save, it is completely oblivious. 

After 10 days: You always know the general location of the infected creature as long as you are on the same plane of existence, though you do not know any specific information about that location. 

After 30 days: As a bonus action, you can read the infected creature's surface thoughts (those foremost in its mind, reflecting its current emotions and what it is actively thinking about) as long as you are on the same plane of existence. If you perform a 1 hour ritual, you instead gain access to any of that creature's thoughts since your initial casting of the spell. If the spell is dispelled at this point, the creature takes 5d10 psychic damage, as the spore has partially melded with their brain.

After 1 year: You gain the ability to cast suggestion on the infected creature, without expending a spell slot or material components, as long as you are on the same plane of existence. The creature automatically fails the saving throw. If the spell is dispelled at this point, the creature takes 10d10 psychic damage, as the spore has near completely melded with their brain.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mold Plant</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>S</components>
    <duration>1 hour</duration>
    <classes>Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You choose a non-magical plant that you can see within range and that	fits within a 10-foot cube. You manipulate it in one of the following ways:

	• Change the color of the plant for 1 hour

	• Cause the plant to shape itself into a form you designate. The plant's branches and leaves may twist into words, create images, or shape into patterns. The changes last for 1 hour.

	• If the plant you target is on the ground, you cause it to become difficult terrain. Alternatively, you can cause the plant to become normal terrain if it is already difficult terrain. This change lasts for 1 hour.

If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have no more than two ofits effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Overgrowth</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>90 feet</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You create a 10-foot-radius area of thick overgrowth centered on a point within range. The sphere spreads around corners, and its area is heavily obscured and difficult terrain. It lasts for the duration or until it is destroyed.

If the overgrowth is lit on fire, it burns away immediately. Each creature in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 fire damage, or half damage on a success.

At Higher Levels:
When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the radius of the overgrowth increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 1st.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Piercing Thorn</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a rose thorn)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You hurl a magical piercing thorn at a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d6 piercing damage, and the thorn lodges itself into the creature for 1 minute or until the thorn explodes.

If the creature is hit by a spell of 1st level or higher, the thorn absorbs some of the spell's magical power and explodes into a rain of thorns, dealing 1d6 piercing damage to the creature. All creatures within a 5 ft radius of the creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 piercing damage as well.

This spell's initial damage and explosion damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Rapport Spores</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a fungal spore)</components>
    <duration>8 hours</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You conjure a 30-foot radius of spores extending from your position. These spores can go around corners and affect only creatures with an Intelligence of 2 or higher that aren't undead, constructs, or elementals.

Affected creatures can communicate telepathically with one another while they are within 60 feet of each other.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Skewering Branch</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>30 feet</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You cause a thick branch to shoot out of the ground along a line 5 feet wide and 30 feet long. Each creature in the line must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be pushed along the length of the branch as it grows in a direction of your choice. If the branch impacts a hard surface, such as a wall, it immediately stops and skewers all creatures that were pushed against that wall. Each creature takes 3d4 piercing damage and is restrained, skewered to the surface. A restrained creature can use an action to make a Strength or Dexterity check (the creature's choice) against the spell's saving throw DC. On a success, the creature is no longer restrained.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Slicing Leaves</name>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You touch up to 6 leaves and imbue them with magic, hardening them and making their edges razor sharp. You or someone else can make a ranged spell attack with one of the leaves by throwing it with a range of 60 feet. If someone else attacks with a leaf, that attacker adds your spellcasting ability modifier, not the attacker's, to the attack roll. On a hit, the target takes slashing damage damage equal to 3d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. Hit or miss, the spell then ends on the leaf.

At Higher Levels:
When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the number of leaves you can effect with this spell increases by 3 for each slot level above 1st.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sporecaller's Smite</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 bonus action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Paladin</classes>
    <text>The next time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack during this spell's duration, your weapon is followed by a trail of spores, and the attack deals an extra 2d4 psychic damage damage to the target. Additionally, the target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of their next turn as pacifying spores enter their body.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spray of Thorns</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>15-foot cone</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a rose thorn)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Ranger, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You shoot forth a burst of thorns from your hands which pierce through your enemy's defenses. Each creature in a 15-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 piercing damage and then has vulnerability to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage until the start of their next turn. On a successful save, a creature takes half damage and suffers no other effect.

At Higher Levels:
When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Thorn Shield</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Cleric, Druid, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You conjure a wooden shield covered in thorns in one of your hands. You are considered proficient in wielding this shield, which provides the same bonuses as a normal shield. Whenever you successfully shove a creature with your thorn shield, that creature takes 1d8 piercing damage. If you let go of the shield, it wilts away.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tree Strike</name>
    <level>4</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a vial of water)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer</classes>
    <text>You cause a tree to grasp at a creature within 10 feet of it with its branches, pulling and constricting that creature. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 6d8 bludgeoning damage, be pulled to the tree, and become restrained. At the start of each of its turns, the restrained creature takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage. A restrained creature can use an action to make a Strength or Dexterity check (the creature's choice) against the spell's saving throw DC. On a success, the creature is no longer restrained.

Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
  </spell>

  <race>
    <name>Silva</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Wis 2, Con 1</ability>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Living in grand cities atop the tallest forests, the Silva, often misnamed as "Green Elves," are an ancient race that look like tall, humanoid halfplant, half-elves. In actuality, they are far more similar to the former than the latter. They hail from only the greatest forests and jungles - the only places that can support their Mother Trees.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Photosynthesis</name>
      <text>You do not need to sleep while in sunlight. Instead, you can choose to sunbathe for 4 hours a day. While sunbathing, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep, and you are considered fully nourished for the rest of the day. If you do not get the opportunity to sunbathe, you can still sleep and eat normally. When you do so, you consume the same amount of food and sleep for the same length as a human.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>Accustomed to the dark canopies of your homeland, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Call of the Forest</name>
      <text>You know the druidcraft cantrip. Once you reach 3rd level, you can cast the entangle spell once per day. Once you reach 5th level, you can also cast the plant growth spell once per day. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Awakened Blight</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Con 2, Str 1</ability>
    <spellAbility/>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Awakened plants gifted with the powers of intelligence and mobility, blights plague lands contaminated by darkness. "Awakened" Blights are those blights which have ascended to even greater intelligence and power. Although most still follow their evil masters, the awakened ones are able to stray from that path if they so desire. Although they are not necessarily evil, an Awakened Blight is still feared and hunted wherever they go. Most races of the world do not consider awakened blights a race, but instead consider them monstrosities.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Source:	Player's Companion - Sprouting Chaos (Third Party)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Blindsight</name>
      <text>Possessing no real eyes, Awakened Blights have adapted to see without them. You gain Blindsight with a radius of 120 feet. However, you are blind beyond this radius.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Constricting Vines</name>
      <text>You know the thorn whip cantrip. Whenever you cast this cantrip and use it to bring a creature within 5 feet of you, you can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Natural Armor</name>
      <text>Your skin is made of thick bark and vines. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is equal to 12 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>