<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric</name>
    <hd>8</hd>
    <proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma, History, Insight, Medicine, Persuasion, Religion</proficiency>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>
    <armor>Light Armor, Medium Armor, Shields</armor>
    <weapons>Simple Weapons</weapons>
    <tools>None</tools>
    <wealth>5d4x10</wealth>
    <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
    <slotsReset>L</slotsReset>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <slots>3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <slots>3,3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <slots>3,4,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4">
      <slots>4,4,3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <slots>4,4,3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <slots>4,4,3,3</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
      <slots>4,4,3,3,3,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,2</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="13">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Starting Cleric</name>
        <text>As a 1st-level Cleric, you begin play with 8 + your Constitution modifier hit points.

You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.

	• Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields
	• Weapons: simple weapons
	• Tools: none
	• Skills: Choose 2 from History, Insight, Medicine, Persuasion, Religion

You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.

	• (a) a mace or (b) a warhammer (if proficient)
	• (a) scale mail, (b) leather armor, or (c) chain mail (if proficient)
	• (a) a light crossbow and Crossbow Bolts (20) or (b) any simple weapon
	• (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack
	• A shield and a holy symbol

If you forgo this starting equipment, as well as the items offered by your background, you start with 5d4 × 10 gp to buy your equipment.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Cleric</name>
        <text>If your group uses the optional rule on multiclassing in the Player's Handbook, here's what you need to know if you choose cleric as one of your classes.

Ability Score Minimum:
As a multiclass character, you must have at least the following ability score(s) to take a level in this class, or to take a level in another class if you are already a cleric.

	• Wisdom 13

Proficiencies Gained:
When you gain your first level in a class other than your initial class, you gain only some of your new class's starting proficiencies, here are the proficiencies you gain when you take your first level as a cleric.

	• Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields
	• Weapons: none
	• Tools: none

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Multiclass Features</name>
        <text>When you gain a new level in a class, you get its features for that level. You don't, however, receive the class's starting equipment, and a few features have additional rules when you're multiclassing: Channel Divinity, Extra Attack, Unarmored Defense, and Spellcasting.

Channel Divinity:
If you already have the Channel Divinity feature and gain a level in a class that also grants the feature, you gain the Channel Divinity effects granted by that class, but getting the feature again doesn't give you an additional use of it. You gain additional uses only when you reach a class level that explicitly grants them to you. For example, if you are a cleric 6/paladin 4, you can use Channel Divinity twice between rests because you are high enough level in the cleric class to have more uses. Whenever you use the feature, you can choose any of the Channel Divinity effects available to you from your two classes.

Extra Attack:
If you gain the Extra Attack class feature from more than one class, the features don't add together. You can't make more than two attacks with this feature unless it says you do (as the fighter's version of Extra Attack does).
	Similarly, the warlock's eldritch invocation Thirsting Blade doesn't give you additional attacks if you also have Extra Attack.

Unarmored Defense:
If you already have the Unarmored Defense feature, you can't gain it again from another class.

Spellcasting:
Your capacity for spellcasting depends partly on your combined levels in all your spellcasting classes and partly on your individual levels in those classes. Once you have the Spellcasting feature from more than one class, use the rules below. If you multiclass but have the Spellcasting feature from only one class, you follow the rules as described in that class.

Spells Known and Prepared:
You determine what spells you know and can prepare for each class individually, as if you were a single-classed member of that class. If you are a ranger 4/wizard 3, for example, you know three 1 st-level ranger spells based on your levels in the ranger class. As a 3rd-level wizard, you know three wizard cantrips, and your spellbook contains ten wizard spells, two of which (the two you gained when you reached 3rd level as a wizard) can be 2nd-level spells. If your Intelligence is 16, you can prepare six wizard spells from your spellbook.
	Each spell you know and prepare is associated with one of your classes, and you use the spell casting ability of that class when you cast the spell. Similarly, a spellcasting focus, such as a holy symbol, can be used only for the spells from the class associated with that focus.
	If a cantrip of yours increases in power at higher levels, the increase is based on your character level, not your level in a particular class.

Spell Slots:
You determine your available spell slots by adding together all your levels in the bard, cleric, druid, sorcerer, and wizard classes, half your levels (rounded down) in the paladin and ranger classes, and a third of your fighter or rogue levels (rounded down) if you have the Eldritch Knight or the Arcane Trickster feature. Use this total to determine your spell slots by consulting the Multiclass Spellcaster table.
	If you have more than one spellcasting class, this table might give you spell slots of a level that is higher than the spells you know or can prepare. You can use those slots, but only to cast your lower-level spells. If a lower level spell that you cast, like burning hands, has an enhanced effect when cast using a higher-level slot, you can use the enhanced effect, even though you don't have any spells of that higher level.
	For example, if you are the aforementioned ranger 4/ wizard 3, you count as a 5th-level character when determining your spell slots: you have four 1st-level slots, three 2nd-level slots, and two 3rd-level slots. However, you don't know any 3rd-level spells, nor do you know any 2nd-level ranger spells. You can use the spell slots of those levels to cast the spells you do know-and potentially enhance their effects.

Pact Magic:
If you have both the Spellcasting class feature and the Pact Magic class feature from the warlock class, you can use the spell slots you gain from the Pact Magic feature to cast spells you know or have prepared from classes with the Spellcasting class feature, and you can use the spell slots you gain from the Spellcasting class feature to cast warlock spells you know.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Spellcasting</name>
        <text>As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for a selection of cleric spells.

	Cantrips. At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn additional cleric cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Cleric table.

	Preparing and Casting Spells. The Cleric table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your cleric spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of cleric spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.

	Spellcasting Ability. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells. The power of your spells comes from your devotion to your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.

	Spell save DC = 8 + Wisdom modifier + Proficiency Bonus

	Spell attack modifier = Wisdom modifier + Proficiency Bonus

	Ritual Casting. You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.

	Spellcasting Focus. You can use a holy symbol as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Divine Domain</name>
        <text>Choose one domain related to your deity from the list of available domains. Each domain is detailed in their own feature, and each one provides examples of gods associated with it. Your choice grants you domain spells and other features when you choose it at 1st level. It also grants you additional ways to use Channel Divinity when you gain that feature at 2nd level, and additional benefits at 6th, 8th, and 17th levels.

Domain Spells:
Each domain has a list of spells—its domain spells—that you gain at the cleric levels noted in the domain description. Once you gain a domain spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.
	If you have a domain spell that doesn't appear on the cleric spell list, the spell is nonetheless a cleric spell for you.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Channel Divinity (1/rest)</name>
        <text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as noted in the domain description.
	When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.
	Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell save DC.
	Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests, and beginning at 18th level, you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain Feature</name>
        <text>At 2nd level, you gain a feature from your Divine Domain.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead</name>
        <text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.
	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Channel Divinity</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
      <feature>
        <name>Destroy Undead (CR 1/2)</name>
        <text>Starting at 5th level, when an undead of CR 1/2 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature>
        <name>Channel Divinity (2/rest)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain Feature</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you gain a feature from your Divine Domain.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Channel Divinity</name>
        <value>2</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 8th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Destroy Undead (CR 1)</name>
        <text>Starting at 8th level, when an undead of CR 1 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain Feature</name>
        <text>At 8th level, you gain a feature from your Divine Domain.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature>
        <name>Divine Intervention</name>
        <text>Beginning at 10th level, you can call on your deity to intervene on your behalf when your need is great.
	Imploring your deity's aid requires you to use your action. Describe the assistance you seek, and roll percentile dice. If you roll a number equal to or lower than your cleric level, your deity intervenes. The DM chooses the nature of the intervention; the effect of any cleric spell or cleric domain spell would be appropriate.
	If your deity intervenes, you can't use this feature again for 7 days. Otherwise, you can use it again after you finish a long rest.
	At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Destroy Undead (CR 2)</name>
        <text>Starting at 11th level, when an undead of CR 2 or lower or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 12th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature>
        <name>Destroy Undead (CR 3)</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, when an undead of CR 3 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 16th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature>
        <name>Destroy Undead (CR 4)</name>
        <text>Starting at 17th level, when an undead of CR 4 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain Feature</name>
        <text>At 17th level, you gain a feature from your Divine Domain.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Channel Divinity (3/rest)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 18th level, you can use your Channel Divinity three times between rests.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Channel Divinity</name>
        <value>3</value>
        <reset>S</reset>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
        <text>When you reach 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.

If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Divine Intervention Improvement</name>
        <text>At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Divine Domain: Life Domain -->
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain: Life Domain</name>
        <text>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy—one of the fundamental forces of the universe—that sustains all life. The gods of life promote vitality and health through healing the sick and wounded, caring for those in need, and driving away the forces of death and undeath. Almost any non-evil deity can claim influence over this domain, particularly agricultural deities (such as Chauntea, Arawai, and Demeter), sun gods (such as Lathander, Pelor, and Re-Horakhty), gods of healing or endurance (such as Ilmater, Mishakal, Apollo, and Diancecht), and gods of home and community (such as Hestia, Hathor, and Boldrei).

Domain Spells:
At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.

Life Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
1st | bless, cure wounds
3rd | lesser restoration, spiritual weapon
5th | beacon of hope, revivify
7th | death ward, guardian of faith
9th | mass cure wounds, raise dead

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiency (Life Domain)</name>
        <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Disciple of Life (Life Domain)</name>
        <text>Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2 + the spell's level.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Channel Divinity: Preserve Life (Life Domain)</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to heal the badly injured.
	As an action, you present your holy symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore a number of hit points equal to five times your cleric level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. You can't use this feature on an undead or a construct.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Blessed Healer (Life Domain)</name>
        <text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others heal you as well. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hit points to a creature other than you, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the spell's level.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Strike (Life Domain)</name>
        <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Supreme Healing (Life Domain)</name>
        <text>Starting at 17th level, when you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hit points to a creature, you restore 12.

Source:	System Reference Document 5.0</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Bless</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cure Wounds</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Lesser Restoration</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Spiritual Weapon</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Beacon of Hope</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Revivify</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Death Ward</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Guardian of Faith</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Mass Cure Wounds</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Raise Dead</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Life Domain)</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
