<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Blood Hunter</name>
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Martial Archetype: Order of the Mosquito (HB)</name>
        <text>The Order of the Mosquito Blood Hunter specializes in using a spectral swarm to leech life from their enemies and protect themselves. They can summon a necrotic mosquito swarm that not only deals damage to nearby foes but also provides cover, with the ability to heal themselves or an ally by siphoning life from those harmed those harmed by the swarm.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Order of the Mosquito (HB): Swarm Affinity</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to call forth a swarm of spectral mosquitoes that aid you in battle.

As a bonus action, you can summon a swarm to surround you for 1 minute, or until you dismiss them as a bonus action. While the swarm is active, any enemy that starts its turn within 5 feet of you or hits you with a melee attack takes necrotic damage equal to your Hemocraft die. The swarm provides half cover against ranged attacks from more than 5 feet away. When you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you take a long rest.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Order of the Mosquito (HB): Blood Curse of the Draining Cloud</name>
        <text>At 3rd level, you learn a blood curse that can sap the vitality of your enemies to replenish your own. You gain the Blood Curse of the Draining Cloud for your Blood Maledict feature. This blood curse is not counted against your total number of blood curses known.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Order of the Mosquito (HB): Annoying Buzz</name>
        <text>At 7th level, your swarm becomes more distracting to your enemies. When the swarm is active, you gain advantage on attack rolls against any creature that has taken damage from your swarm within since your last turn. Additionally, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on attack rolls on a creature that takes damage from the swarm. You can now use Swarm Affinity twice per long rest.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Order of the Mosquito (HB): Persistent Harassment</name>
        <text>At 11th level, you learn to harness the relentless nature of the mosquito. 

As a reaction, you may siphon the vitality of any creature damaged by Swarm Affinity to heal yourself or an ally within 30 feet for the amount of necrotic damage dealt. The healing feels incredibly gross. You can do this a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier, regaining all uses after a long rest.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Order of the Mosquito (HB): Blood Curse of the Mosqo</name>
        <text>At 15th level, you master the art of hemocraft to invoke a curse that summons a large spectral mosquito to torment your foes. You gain the Blood Curse of the Mosqo for your Blood Maledict feature. This curse does not count against the number of blood curses you know.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Order of the Mosquito (HB): Master of the Swarm</name>
        <text>At 18th level, you can now summon or dismiss the swarm an unlimited number of times. Once per turn, when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can choose to release a burst of necrotic energy that deals an additional 2d12 necrotic damage to the target and heals you for half the amount of necrotic damage dealt.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 6 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Blood Curse of the Draining Cloud</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <time/>
    <range/>
    <components/>
    <duration/>
    <classes>Blood Curses</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: Order of the Mosquito

As a bonus action, you can mark one creature you can see within 30 feet of you to become the nexus of a life-draining swarm for the duration of the curse. The first time the marked creature deals damage with an attack, the attack inflicts additional Necrotic damage equal to your Hemocraft die roll. Simultaneously, you regain hit points equal to the necrotic damage dealt.

Amplify: When you choose to amplify this blood curse, the creature gains vulnerability to necrotic damage for the duration of the curse. Additionally, the radius of the draining swarm's influence expands to 10 feet around the cursed target. The amplified curse concludes when any creature takes necrotic damage from the Draining Cloud.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blood Curse of the Mosqo</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <time/>
    <range/>
    <components/>
    <duration/>
    <classes>Blood Curses</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: 15th level, Order of the Mosquito

As a bonus action, you can target one creature you can see within 30 feet of you. A giant spectral mosquito attaches itself to the target, causing it to have disadvantage on attack rolls against anyone except you. Furthermore, any damage the cursed creature takes heals the attacker by an amount equal to half of the damage dealt.

The curse lasts until the end of your next turn.

Amplify: When you amplify this blood curse, the spectral mosquito drains the very essence of the target. After the curse ends, the target suffers one level of exhaustion as a result of the draining torment.

Source:	Subclasses That Shouldn't Exist v1 p. 7 (Homebrew)</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>
