<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Thri-Kreen [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>History</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Thri-Kreen are insectoid nomads, bound by a deep connection to their clutch—the small group they hatch and grow alongside. While individualistic in nature, they retain strong communal instincts, often perceiving their allies as an extension of their own clutch. Their alien physiology grants them unique advantages, including natural camouflage, additional limbs, and the ability to communicate telepathically with those who do not understand their spoken language.
	Though they are skilled hunters and survivalists, Thri-Kreen possess a rich oral history passed down through generations. Their clutches share knowledge instinctively, leading them to recall ancient lore as if it were their own lived experience.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Monstrosity</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small or Medium</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiency</name>
      <text>History</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Languages</name>
      <text>Thri-Kreen (see Limited Telepathy)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Chameleon Carapace</name>
      <text>While you aren't wearing armor, your carapace gives you a base Armor Class of 13 + your Dexterity modifier. As an action, you can change the color of your carapace to match the color and texture of your surroundings, giving you advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide in those surroundings. Additionally, until you move, or take the Attack or Spell Attack action, directly after you have changed your carapace, you can attempt the hide action as if you were heavily obscured.</text>
      <special>Unarmored Defense: Dexterity</special>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Secondary Arms</name>
      <text>You have two slightly smaller secondary arms below your primary pair. These secondary arms can manipulate an object, open or close a door or container, pick up or set down a Tiny object, or wield a weapon with the light property. You only gain the benefits of a weapon's mastery property (if applicable) if the weapon is wielded in one of your primary arms.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Limited Telepathy</name>
      <text>You can only speak the Thri-Kreen language aloud, but you can communicate telepathically in any other languages you know with creatures within 90 feet. This communication is one-way; you can send thoughts, but you cannot receive them telepathically.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Clutch Recall</name>
      <text>The shared knowledge of your clutch lingers in your mind, allowing you to instinctively recall important information. You can automatically succeed on a History check to recall knowledge. Once you use this trait, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <item>
    <name>Grythka [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <property>M,2H</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmgType>S</dmgType>
    <text>Damage Type: Slashing or Piercing

A Grythka is a sturdy, dual-bladed polearm traditionally wielded by Thri-Kreen marauders, crafted from chitin and sharpened to a deadly edge. Designed for both slashing and piercing attacks, this weapon excels in close-quarters combat, allowing its wielder to deliver swift, sweeping strikes while maintaining defensive versatility.

Topple (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, you can force the creature to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 plus the ability modifier used to make the attack roll and your Proficiency Bonus). On a failed save, the creature has the Prone condition.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use. This property is relevant only when you attack with the weapon, not when you simply hold it.

Proficiency: martial, grythka
Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Chatkcha [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <detail>common</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <property>M,F,L,T</property>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>20/270</range>
    <text>A Chatkcha is a lightweight, three-bladed throwing weapon crafted from hardened crystalline material, traditionally used by Thri-Kreen hunters and marauders. Designed for precision and lethality, it is expertly balanced for both melee and ranged combat, capable of slicing through foes before returning to its wielder's hand with practiced skill.

Sap (Mastery): If you hit a creature with this weapon, that creature has Disadvantage on its next attack roll before the start of your next turn.

Thrown: If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the Finesse property.

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Proficiency: martial, grythka
Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
  </item>
</compendium>
