<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Githzerai (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <resist>psychic</resist>
    <proficiency>Insight</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Githzerai are ascetic warriors and psionic adepts, shaped by a history of survival and self-mastery. Once enslaved by the mind flayers, they freed themselves not through conquest but through sheer discipline, retreating to the chaos of Limbo to build order from within. Through rigorous training of the mind and body, Githzerai have honed their psionic abilities to shield themselves from external influence. While many remain within their monasteries, perfecting their craft, some venture into the Material Plane in pursuit of enlightenment, balance, or a mission known only to them.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Aberration</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 5 to 7 feet)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Insight</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Resistances</name>
      <text>Psychic Damage</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Githzerai Psionics</name>
      <text>Your affinity with psionic energy grants you certain magical gifts:

	• You know the Mage Hand cantrip, which you can cast at will. When you do, the hand is invisible.
	• At 3rd level, you learn Shield.
	• At 5th level, you learn See Invisibility.

You always have these spells prepared. You can cast each of them once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast a spell using this trait, you choose Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma as your spellcasting ability (choose when you create your Githzerai).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Mental Discipline</name>
      <text>You have trained your mind to resist outside influence. You have advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Charmed and Frightened conditions on yourself. Additionally, if you successfully resist the Charmed condition, you can attempt to deceive the creature that tried to charm you. Make a DC 15 Charisma (Deception) check. If successful, the creature believes you are charmed. If they suspect otherwise, they can attempt a DC 15 Wisdom (Insight) check to see through the deception.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Mind and Body</name>
      <text>You have mastered the unity of physical movement and mental clarity. You can take the Dodge action as a bonus action. When you do, you gain advantage on Wisdom saving throws until the start of your next turn.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
