<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <!-- Lost Castle of Dreams -->
  <monster>
    <name>Zeek, The Chicken Lich</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <type>beast</type>
    <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
    <ac>12 (15 with mage armor)</ac>
    <hp>99 (18d8+18)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>2</str><dex>14</dex><con>12</con><int>20</int><wis>15</wis><cha>16</cha>
    <save>Int +9, Wis +6</save>
    <skill>Arcana +13, History +13</skill>
    <resist>damage from spells; nonmagical bludgeoning, piercing, slashing (from stoneskin)</resist>
    <senses/><passive>12</passive>
    <languages>any six languages</languages>
    <cr>12</cr>
    <trait>
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>The archmage has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Variant: Familiars</name>
      <text>Any spellcaster that can cast the find familiar spell (such as an archmage or mage) is likely to have a familiar. The familiar can be one of the creatures described in the spell (see the Player's Handbook) or some other Tiny monster, such as a crawling claw, imp, pseudodragon, or quasit.</text>
    </action>
    <trait>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The archmage is an 18th-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Intelligence (spell save DC 17, +9 to hit with spell attacks). The archmage can cast disguise self and invisibility at will and has the following wizard spells prepared:</text>
      <text/>
      <text>At will: disguise self, invisibility.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>Cantrips (at will): fire bolt, light, mage hand, prestidigitation, shocking grasp</text>
      <text>1st level (4 slots): detect magic, identify, mage armor*, magic missile</text>
      <text>2nd level (3 slots): detect thoughts, mirror image, misty step</text>
      <text>3rd level (3 slots): counterspell, fly, lightning bolt</text>
      <text>4th level (3 slots): banishment, fire shield, stoneskin*</text>
      <text>5th level (3 slots): cone of cold, scrying, wall of force</text>
      <text>6th level (1 slots): globe of invulnerability</text>
      <text>7th level (1 slots): teleport</text>
      <text>8th level (1 slots): mind blank*</text>
      <text>9th level (1 slots): time stop</text>
      </text>
      <text>*The archmage casts these spells on itself before combat.</text>
    </trait>
    <spells>disguise self, invisibility, fire bolt, light, mage hand, prestidigitation, shocking grasp, detect magic, identify, mage armor, magic missile, detect thoughts, mirror image, misty step, counterspell, fly, lightning bolt, banishment, fire shield, stoneskin, cone of cold, scrying, wall of force, globe of invulnerability, teleport, mind blank, time stop</spells><slots>0,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
    <description>What Does Zeek Want? Ultimately, Zeek wants to be left alone to his own devices. Sometimes, his needs cause trouble—for example, he may require the blood of a virgin to complete a spell. And he's been known to accidentally open doors to the Other here and there. This events draw attention to adventurers.

      Source:	DMDave, Lost Castle of Dreams</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster> <!-- Zeek, The Chicken Lich -->
  <monster>
    <name>Chicken Disciple</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <type>beast</type>
    <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
    <ac>12 (15 with mage armor)</ac>
    <hp>40 (9d8)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>9</str><dex>14</dex><con>11</con><int>17</int><wis>12</wis><cha>11</cha>
    <save>Int +6, Wis +4</save>
    <skill>Arcana +6, History +6</skill>
    <senses/><passive>11</passive>
    <languages>any four languages</languages>
    <cr>6</cr>
    <action>
      <name>Variant: Familiars</name>
      <text>Any spellcaster that can cast the find familiar spell (such as an archmage or mage) is likely to have a familiar. The familiar can be one of the creatures described in the spell (see the Player's Handbook) or some other Tiny monster, such as a crawling claw, imp, pseudodragon, or quasit.</text>
    </action>
    <trait>
      <name>Spellcasting</name>
      <text>The mage is a 9th-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Intelligence (spell save DC 14, +6 to hit with spell attacks). The mage has the following wizard spells prepared:</text>
      <text>Cantrips (at will): fire bolt, light, mage hand, prestidigitation</text>
      <text>1st level (4 slots): detect magic, mage armor, magic missile, shield</text>
      <text>2nd level (3 slots): misty step, suggestion</text>
      <text>3rd level (3 slots): counterspell, fireball, fly</text>
      <text>4th level (3 slots): greater invisibility, ice storm</text>
      <text>5th level (1 slots): cone of cold</text>
    </trait>
    <spells>fire bolt, light, mage hand, prestidigitation, detect magic, mage armor, magic missile, shield, misty step, suggestion, counterspell, fireball, fly, greater invisibility, ice storm, cone of cold</spells><slots>0,4,3,3,3,1</slots>
    <description>What Do Zeek's Henchchickens Want? Overall, most of Zeek's henchchickens are okay with their current predicament. After all, the work is good and there's plenty of seeds to go around. However, some do long to become human again.
      
      Source:	DMDave, Lost Castle of Dreams</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster> <!-- Chicken Disciple -->
  <monster>
    <name>Zeek's Guardian</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <type>beast</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>10</ac>
    <hp>1 (1d4-1)</hp>
    <speed>walk 20 ft.</speed>
    <str>2</str><dex>11</dex><con>9</con><int>10</int><wis>10</wis><cha>4</cha>
    <senses>darkvision 30 ft.</senses><passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common</languages>
    <cr>0</cr>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>The chicken has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Peck</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +0 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 piercing damage.</text>
    </action>
    <description>What Do Zeek's Henchchickens Want? Overall, most of Zeek's henchchickens are okay with their current predicament. After all, the work is good and there's plenty of seeds to go around. However, some do long to become human again.
      
      Source:	DMDave, Lost Castle of Dreams</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster> <!-- Zeek's Chicken Guardian -->
  <monster>
    <name>Swarm of Zeek's Guardians</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>swarm of Medium beasts</type>
    <alignment>Unaligned</alignment>
    <ac>10</ac>
    <hp>24 (7d8-7)</hp>
    <speed>walk 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>9</str><dex>11</dex><con>9</con><int>10</int><wis>10</wis><cha>3</cha>
    <resist>bludgeoning, piercing, slashing</resist>
    <conditionImmune>charmed, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, prone, restrained, stunned</conditionImmune>
    <senses>darkvision 30 ft.</senses><passive>10</passive>
    <languages>Common</languages>
    <cr>1/4</cr>
    <trait>
      <name>Keen Smell</name>
      <text>The swarm has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Swarm</name>
      <text>The swarm can occupy another creature's space and vice versa, and the swarm can move through any opening large enough for a Tiny rat. The swarm can't regain hit points or gain temporary hit points.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Pecks</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 0 ft., one target in the swarm's space. 7 (2d6) piercing damage, or 3 (1d6) piercing damage if the swarm has half of its hit points or fewer.</text>
      <attack>Pecks|+2|2d6</attack>
    </action>
    <description>The Nature of Swarms.
      ------
      The swarms presented here aren't ordinary or benign assemblies of little creatures. They form as a result of some sinister or unwholesome influence. A vampire can summon swarms of bats and rats from the darkest corners of the night, while the very presence of a mummy lord can cause scarab beetles to boil up from the sand-filled depths of its tomb. A hag might have the power to turn swarms of ravens against her enemies, while a yuan-ti abomination might have swarms of poisonous snakes slithering in its wake. Even druids can't charm these swarms, and their aggressiveness is borderline unnatural.
      ------

      What Do Zeek's Henchchickens Want? Overall, most of Zeek's henchchickens are okay with their current predicament. After all, the work is good and there's plenty of seeds to go around. However, some do long to become human again.
      
      Source:	DMDave, Lost Castle of Dreams</description>
    <environment/>
  </monster> <!-- Swarm of Zeek's Chicken Guardians -->
</compendium>
