<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <item>
    <name>Demonbone Hooked Shortspear</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>L,M</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <text>On a hit with this weapon, the wielder can forgo dealing damage and attempt to trip the target, in which case the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or fall prone. The DC is 8 + the wielder's Strength modifier + the wielder's proficiency bonus.

You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, when you're damaged by a creature in reach, you may use your reaction to make one melee attack against it with this weapon.

Curse: You're unwilling to part with this weapon while attuned to it. While attuned, you have disadvantage on attack rolls with weapons other than this one.
	Whenever a hostile creature damages you, you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or go berserk. While berserk, you must use your action on each of your turns to attack the creature nearest to you with the weapon. If you can make extra attacks as part of the Attack action, you use those extra attacks, moving to attack the next nearest creature after you fell your current target. If you have multiple possible targets, you attack one at random. You're berserk until you start your turn with no creatures within 60 feet of you that you can see or hear. Alternatively, an ally can use an action to make a DC 15 Charisma (Persuasion) check and if successful, you're no longer berserk. Only the Remove Curse spell allows you to end attunement to this item.

Corrupting: This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Proficiency: martial, hooked shortspear
Source:	Chains of Asmodeus p. 267 (Third Party),
		Out of the Abyss p. 224</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Damage +2</modifier>
    <roll description="DC">8+%1+%8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Stygian Hooked Shortspear</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>L,M</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <text>On a hit with this weapon, the wielder can forgo dealing damage and attempt to trip the target, in which case the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or fall prone. The DC is 8 + the wielder's Strength modifier + the wielder's proficiency bonus.

You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you throw it, it deals one extra die of damage on a hit. After you throw it and it hits or misses, it flies back to your hand immediately.

Curse: You're unwilling to part with this weapon while attuned to it. In addition, you have disadvantage on attack rolls made with weapons other than this one.
	Whenever you roll a 1 on an attack roll using this weapon, your target changes to your closest ally. If there are multiple allies, randomly determine which is the target. Make a new attack roll with advantage against your ally. If the attack hits, in addition to the standard damage you deal an extra 2d6 poison damage. Only the Remove Curse spell allows you to end attunement to this item.

Corrupting: This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Proficiency: martial, hooked shortspear
Source:	Chains of Asmodeus p. 270 (Third Party),
		Out of the Abyss p. 224</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Attacks +2</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Damage +2</modifier>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Hooked Shortspear of Agonizing Paralysis</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>M</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <property>L,M</property>
    <dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <text>On a hit with this weapon, the wielder can forgo dealing damage and attempt to trip the target, in which case the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or fall prone. The DC is 8 + the wielder's Strength modifier + the wielder's proficiency bonus.

You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When this weapon reduces a creature to 0 hit points, the creature doesn't die. Instead, infernal runes appear as if carved into their flesh and they're healed to 1 hit point. They now have the paralyzed condition until the condition is removed by a Lesser Restoration spell or similar magic. When the condition is removed, the runes disappear. At the start of each of their turns while they're paralyzed, the creature suffers immense pain and gains a level of exhaustion.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Proficiency: martial, hooked shortspear
Source:	Chains of Asmodeus p. 271 (Third Party),
		Out of the Abyss p. 224</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Melee Damage +3</modifier>
    <roll description="DC">8+%1+%8</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Light Repeating Crossbow of Agonizing Paralysis</name>
    <detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <type>R</type>
    <magic>YES</magic>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <property>A,2H</property>
    <dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <range>40/160</range>
    <text>This crossbow is fitted with a cartridge that can hold up to six crossbow bolts. It automatically reloads after firing until the cartridge runs out of ammunition. Reloading the cartridge takes an action.

You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When this weapon reduces a creature to 0 hit points, the creature doesn't die. Instead, infernal runes appear as if carved into their flesh and they're healed to 1 hit point. They now have the paralyzed condition until the condition is removed by a Lesser Restoration spell or similar magic. When the condition is removed, the runes disappear. At the start of each of their turns while they're paralyzed, the creature suffers immense pain and gains a level of exhaustion.

Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. The ammunition of a firearm is destroyed upon use. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack (you need a free hand to load a one-handed weapon). At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.
	If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons").

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.

Proficiency: simple, light repeating crossbow
Source:	Chains of Asmodeus p. 271 (Third Party),
		Out of the Abyss p. 224</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Attacks +3</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">Ranged Damage +3</modifier>
  </item>
</compendium>
