<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <race>
    <name>Altmer (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Wisdom +1</ability>
    <resist>disease</resist>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Altmer, or self-titled "Cultured People", are a tall, golden-skinned race, hailing from Summerset Isle. They are also known as High Elves by the denizens of Tamriel. In the Empire, "High" is often understood to mean proud or snobbish, and as the Altmer generally personify these characteristics, the "lesser races" generally resent them. Altmer live two to three times as long as humans; with a 200-year-old Altmer being old and a 300-year-old Altmer being very, very old. Altmer consider themselves to be the most civilized culture of Tamriel; the common tongue of the continent is based on Altmer speech and writing, and most of the Empire's arts, crafts, laws, and sciences are derived from Altmer traditions.
	The Altmer are the most strongly gifted in the arcane arts of all the races. They are among the longest living and intelligent races of Tamriel, and they often become powerful magic users due to both their magical affinity and the many years they may devote to their studies.
	Their skin maintains a very pale golden hue, not quite the pale white of the northern human races such as Nords or Imperials, but far lighter than the Bosmer. They are slender, with prominently pointed ears and almond-shaped eyes.
	On average, Altmer are of smaller build than humans, and thus generally not as strong. Their tall stature also makes them less agile than their Bosmeri cousins. However, Altmer are among the most intelligent and magically-inclined races on Nirn, surpassing even the Bretons in magical aptitude.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Slender and Graceful</name>
      <text>With their elegant stature and beauty, high elves typically have healthy gaunt features. They are the tallest of all the races, usually well over 6 feet tall and sometimes above 7 feet. They are more slender than humans, weighing between 140 and 180 pounds. Males and females are about the same height, and males are only marginally heavier than females.
	Altmer have physical colorations that are very homogeneous in their nature. Their golden skin ranges from pale yellow tones to bronze, while their hair and eyes comes in similar shades, which sometimes makes it difficult to distinguish from long distances. Their hair color ranges from nearly white to blonde, to golden brown, while their almond shaped eyes are like pools of liquid gold. Altmer rarely have facial hair, either from genetics or from their favored cultured aesthetic. They favor elegant clothing and jewelry, usually in fabrics and materials that compliment their natural appearance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>A Timeless Perceptive</name>
      <text>Altmer, much like the other elves, can live for exceptional lengths of time, usually of spans two to three times as long as humans. An elf is considered old at 300 years of age, and typically reaches 400 years. Their natural resistance to disease allows them to live longer than the other races. It is even rumored that there are elves well over 4,000 year old, extending their lifespans by avoiding violence or mastering powerful restorative magic.
	Their extended lifespan allows Altmer to consider time as a luxury, mastering skills over long periods of research that their human counterparts would never be able to fathom. Societies of Altmer have been known to avoid war and violence, choosing to study their enemies, confident that they can easily wait for the most opportune time to strike quickly, or simply just outlive their nuisance.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Divine Decendents</name>
      <text>Altmer consider themselves to be the most direct descendants of the original Aldmer elves, the first elves of the Merethic Era. The Altmer believe that they resemble their Aldmer ancestors and take great pride in keeping a pure lineage, striving to emulate their ways with great reverence.
	Most Altmer live in beautifully appointed cities and towns that are populated mostly with other Altmer. Their architecture is strong and graceful, with pointed steeples to emphasize height, proudly reaching upwards towards the heavens. Truly, an visual echo to the High Elves themselves. Altmer are talented artisans, utilizing their long lifespans and mythic ancestry to hone their sophisticated crafts.
	Their societies are strongly regimented with deep discipline and are separated by a rigid hierarchy of classes. Teachers and priests are regarded as the highest rank, followed by artists, princes, warriors, landowners, merchants, workers, and finally their slaves.
	Outside of the Summerset Isles, the homeland of the Altmer, they are commonly scholars, artists, or sages. Human nobles compete for the services of Altmer to become court wizards, or as instructors of magic.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Exploration and Adventure</name>
      <text>Altmer that take up a life of adventure usually do so for the sake of discovery and exploration. Always curious and passionate for a deeper understanding of their interests, Altmer will commonly seek out careers that allow them to travel and study at their own pace. Naturally the most magically-inclined races of Tamriel, they enjoy gaining greater power, which adventuring allows them to do. Some might join with rebels fighting for social reform, while others might join militant groups that champion their moral cause.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Names</name>
      <text>The Altmer have only a single given name. They choose names that have the same elegance and nobility they see fit for their kind.

Male Names:
Aesmer, Arondil, Calanor, Cinnar, Cornor, Dandos, Eanor, Earran, Elikar, Erymil, Falion, Heldil, Iramo, Lermion, Miratar, Naarwe, Naemon, Ocando, Pircalmo, Quaranon, Rolancano, Sanyon, Tholbor, Valtir, Yancol

Female Names:
Alwaen, Areldur, Astorne, Cariel, Curwe, Earrona, Elanwe, Erille, Falen, Fistalle, Gathewen, Hildara, Inare, Karinnarre, Kirstar, Lamoline, Linwin, Malanie, Minique, Naire, Quen, Ruma, Sorcalin, Telandil, Valla, Vilva</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>The average Altmer can live for over 400 years, although they are known to be able to live for thousands of years. It is rumored that some Altmer on the Summerset Isles are over 4000 years old. They reach puberty at 18 years old and are considered an adult at 30. They mature similar to humans, but their advanced age means that they are still considered young until the age of 60.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Altmer set themselves on a higher standard and tend to be lawful neutral. They are very orderly and follow the traditions of their ancestors, while having a less generous attitude towards other races.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>High Elves are the tallest of the races of Tamriel, sometimes as tall as 7 feet, but they have slender, thin builds. Your size is Medium.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiency</name>
      <text>Your choice between alchemist's supplies, calligrapher's supplies, or jeweler's tools.

These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan's tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft. Each type of artisan's tools requires a separate proficiency.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Altmer Blood</name>
      <text>You have advantage on saving throws to resist diseases.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Highborn</name>
      <text>You have an innate well of magicka within you. You have 2 magicka points that you can use to cast spells, and you know one cantrip and one 1st level spell from mage spell list. You gain an additional magicka point when you reach 3rd level (3), 6th level (4), and 10th level (5).
	Additionally, when you reach 3rd level, you learn a 2nd level spell of your choice from the mage spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting attribute for these spells, you must expend magicka to cast them, and you can only cast them at their base level. You regain all expended magicka when you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Studious Nature</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency with two skills of your choice from Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and two other standard languages of your choice (Typically Altmeris).</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Argonian (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <resist>disease</resist>
    <weapons>Shortsword, Spear</weapons>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Argonians, also known as People of the Root, or Saxhleel in their native tongue of Jel, are the reptilian natives of the swampland known as the Black Marsh. The other races of Tamriel sometimes refer to them as 'lizards' or the 'Lizard Folk', which can be considered derogative. Argonians possess the most alien personalities in all of Tamriel, perceived by other races as to have no personality nor emotions.
	They are known as the foremost experts in guerrilla warfare throughout the Starry Heart, a reputation brought upon them by defending their borders from enemies for countless centuries. Argonians have a lifespan similar to that of humans. According to the First Era Scholar Brendan the Persistent "the Argonian people have, throughout Tamrielic history, been perhaps the most misunderstood, vilified, and reviled of all the sentient races. Yet, those who have taken the time to experience Argonian culture have gained a greater appreciation for this noble and beautiful people". However, it should be noted that he himself went missing in his final expedition into the deeper swamps of their homeland.
	Outside of Argonia, little is known of their homeland or native culture, and their alien physiology and customs are not well understood by scholars. They have been perhaps the most misunderstood of all the intelligent races.
	Despite their alien outlook, some Argonians make an effort to understand and, in their own manner, befriend people of other races. Such Argonians make faithful and skilled allies.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Alien Ancestry</name>
      <text>The Argonian's reptilian nature comes through not only in their appearance, but also in how they think and act. The other races mistake them to be cold and calculating, but that is mostly because their physiology lacks the ability to express emotions in a noticeable way to non-Argonians. They are, however, capable of displaying aggression and fear in an obvious manner by narrowing their eyes or showing their teeth.
	Although their physical appearance is reptilian, they are much more amphibious in reality. They have small gills behind their ears, instinctively swim in the same style as an eel, and are capable of growing feathers. Their females have mammalian breasts, although they lay eggs. Even their genders are confusing to humans and elves. It is rumored that an Argonian can change it's sex in a time of need.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Cautious and Loyal</name>
      <text>Because they are hard to understand, humans and elves treat Argonians as cold-blooded in nature. Although this is physically true, Argonians create deep and long lasting bonds with their own people and allies. Part of this misunderstanding is in part attributed to their emotionless demeanor, which makes them nearly impossible to get to know. They are also notoriously slow to trust outsiders.
	At their core, Argonians are fiercely loyal allies, making the difficulty of learning their ways and getting to know their tribes well worth the effort. Allied Argonians will fight to the death to protect anyone they deem to be family or friend.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Distrustful and Isolationists</name>
      <text>History has not always been kind to the Argonian people. The ancient Chimer of Morrowind first utilized the Lizard Folk as slaves centuries before their Dunmer ancestors would do the same. Imperial forces have made several attempts to break through the thick swamps and jungles of the Black Marsh and had set up bases around the coastlines, essentially annexing their culture from the rest of Tamriel.
	Over time, the Argonians fought back, largely through the use of guerrilla warfare, defending their borders across countless centuries. In recent years, they have broke free from their slavers and have claimed independence from the Empire.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Argonian Speech</name>
      <text>Argonian can master Common, but their mindset results in a speech pattern distinct from other humanoids. Argonians rarely use inflection in their speech, which can make their meaning difficult to interpret. Names confuse them, unless they are descriptive. They tend to apply their own naming conventions to other creatures using Common words. Argonians use active verbs to describe the world. An argonian in cold weather might say, "This wind brings cold" rather than "I feel cold." Argonians tend to define things in terms of actions, rather than effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Argonian Personality</name>
      <text>You can use the Argonian Quirks table to determine a personality quirk for an Argonian character or to inspire a unique mannerism.

Argonian Personality:
d8 | Quirk
1 | You hate waste and see no reason not to scavenge fallen enemies. Fingers are tasty and portable!
2 | You sleep best while mostly submerged in water.
3 | Money is meaningless to you.
4 | You love to sunbathe. If you aren't in the tropics, you wear socks filled with warm rocks on your tail. 
5 | You have learned how to laugh. You use this talent in response to all emotional situations to better fit in with your comrades.
6 | You still don't understand how metaphors work. That doesn't stop you from using them at every opportunity.
7 | You appreciate the soft humanoids who realize they need chain mail and swords to match the gifts you were born with.
8 | You enjoy eating your food while it's still wriggling.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Argonian Names</name>
      <text>Argonians take their names either from Jel, their native tongue, or from the common human language. They use simple descriptive names, usually based on an individual's notable deeds, actions, or appearance. For example, an Argonian traveler may be called Nhakik, which translates as "wander", or an Argonian who is a notable swimmer may be called Swims-with-haste, in Tamrielic. Both their Jel names and their common names are frequently hyphenated, but not always.

Male Jel Names:
Ah-Ra, Asheeus, Bar-Neeus, Chanka, Deeh, Geel, Jee-Tah, Motuu, Nexith, Oosh, Pad-Ei, Resari, Skeehei, Tanaka, Teeka, Uta-Ra, Vara-Zeen, Wanum-Neeus, Xal-Geh, Yelus

Female Jel Names:
Am-Eepa, Asska, Beek-Ja, Churasu, Dakee, Deel, Ei-Ei, Geeh, Heek-Sa, Jukka, Kal-Mei, Leetu, Meerana, Nam-Ja, Pekai-Vilax, Reesa, Sisar, Tulut, Wih-Jat, Xula

Tamrielic Names (gender neutral):
Black-Scale, Cuts-with-Words, Deepswimmer, Dusty-Claws, Eyeslike-Night, Follows-the-Sun, Juggles-Scorpions, Keen-Eyes, Purple Plumes, Sings-to-Lions, Walks-in-Ash</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>An Argonian's life is usually met with hardship and because of this, their lifespan is typically shorter than it should be. On average they live to 75 years, but living to 200 isn't unattainable.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Most Argonians are neutral good. They often see themselves as protectors and guardians.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Swimming</name>
      <text>As an Argonian, you are a naturally gifted swimmer which grants you a swimming speed of 40 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Tool Proficiency</name>
      <text>You ste proficient with alchemist supplies.

These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan's tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft. Each type of artisan's tools requires a separate proficiency.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Appearance</name>
      <text>Argonians have a wide variety of cranial features such as fins, feathers, ridges, spines, spikes, or horns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Argonian Combat Proficiency</name>
      <text>You have proficiency with Short Blades and Spears.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Argonian Resilience</name>
      <text>Your Argonian bloodline grants you advantage against saving throws to resist disease.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Bite</name>
      <text>Argonians have very sharp reptilian teeth lining their mouths which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with this attack, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
      <roll description="Unarmed Piercing Damage">1d6+%1</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Histskin</name>
      <text>You can invoke the power of the Hist to quickly recover your injuries. When your current hit points are less than half your hit point maximum, you can use an action to immediately expend any number of your Hit Dice and regain hit points equal to the result.
	Once you use this trait, you must complete a long rest before you are able to use it again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Protective Scales</name>
      <text>Your thick hide provides a natural armor. When you are unarmored, your AC is equal to 12 + your Agility modifier.</text>
      <special>Unarmored Defense: Dexterity</special>
      <modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Water-breathing</name>
      <text>Argonians are able to breath underwater indefinitely.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Jel.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Bosmer (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>35</speed>
    <ability>Dex +2, Wis +1</ability>
    <resist>poison, disease</resist>
    <proficiency>Acrobatics</proficiency>
    <weapons>Firearms</weapons>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Bosmer are the Elven clan-folk of Valenwood, a forested province in southwestern Tamriel. In the Empire, they are often referred to as Wood Elves, but Bosmer, Boiche, or the Tree-Sap people is what they call themselves. Bosmer rejected the stiff, formal traditions of Aldmeri high culture, preferring a more romantic, simple existence in harmony with the land and its wild beauty and creatures. They are relatively nimble and quick in body compared to their more "civilized" Altmeri cousins (who often look down upon the Bosmer as unruly and naive). Their agility makes them well-suited as scouts and thieves. However, they are also a quick-witted folk, and many pursue successful careers in scholarly pursuits or trading. Bosmer live two to three times as long as humans; with a 200-year-old Bosmer being old and a 300-year-old Bosmer being very, very old. Though they are considered less influential than some of their Elven brethren, the Bosmer are also relatively prone to producing offspring. As a result, they outnumber all other mer on Tamriel.
	The best archers in all of Tamriel, the Bosmer snatch and fire arrows in one continuous motion; they are even rumored to have invented the bow. They have many natural and unique abilities; notably, they can command simple-minded creatures and have a nearly chameleon-like ability to hide in forested areas. Many in the forests of Valenwood follow the tenets of the Green Pact. These "Green Pact Bosmer" are religiously carnivorous and cannibalistic and do not harm the vegetation of Valenwood, though they are not averse to using wooden or plant-derived products created by others.
	The Bosmer are one of the smallest races in Tamriel and are born with skin colors ranging from light brown to pale tan to light green. Biologically, the Bosmer are cousins of the Dunmer, or Dark Elves, and the Altmer, or High Elves. The Wood Elves lineage is less noble than that of the Altmer, but they have adapted well to Tamriel. After the Ayleids fled mainland Cyrodiil, they joined the Bosmer in seclusion, eventually being totally assimilated by the Bosmer. This probably significantly affected the biology of modern-day Bosmer.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Modest and Nimble</name>
      <text>Bosmer are one of the smallest races on Tamriel. They average around 5 feet tall and weigh between 100 and 130 pounds. This small frame grants the bosmer a natural proclivity for moving nimbly and stealthily. As with the other elves, they live two to three times as long as humans. Combined with their increased fertility and long lives, Bosmer are known to have large families and are one of the most populous races of Tamriel. Wood Elves, or Tree-Sap People, have skin tones in copper and bronze, and sometimes have traces of light green. Their hair tends toward browns and blacks, but occasionally red and copper colored. Their eyes are golden, brown, and sometimes solid black with no visible white.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Treaty of Frond and Leaf</name>
      <text>The ancestors of the Bosmer were some of the first to leave Old Ehlnofey, rejecting the formal traditions and high culture of the Aldmeri, instead preferring romantic ideas and a simple existence. They traveled to Valenwood to settle in the wild and untamed forests. Having to fight against lush jungles and savage creatures influenced the evolution of their society to make them who they are to this day. It is said that the Bosmer made a deal with Y'ffre, the God of Song and Forest, called the Green Pact. With this treaty, the Green would aid the bosmer, providing them with shelter and safe passage, and in exchange, the bosmer are forbidden from destruction of the forests. This brings great challenges that the Bosmer of Valenwood have adhered to for centuries. They are forbidden from eating any of the vegetation, so their diet is strictly meat, including some delicacies, such as beverages made from fermented pigs milk, called jagga, or fermented meat seasoned with insect organs, called rotmeth. The Bosmer are also notable pacifists. They have never instigated any of the major wars of Tamriel and aim to keep peace between their tribes. This may have something to do with an ancient tradition from the Green Pact called the Meat Mandate, which required the Bosmer to eat the bodies of their fallen enemies within three days. Before a great battle, the wood elves would prepare themselves by fasting. This cannibalistic ritual set the Bosmer apart from the other races, but this practice diminished during the Second Era and is now only observed in remote tribal villages.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Hidden Woodland Realms</name>
      <text>Most Wood Elves of Valenwood live in small villages hidden among the trees. Although the Green Pact prevents the bosmer from using lumber or hollowing out trees for shelter, they have been blessed with the ability to grow their shelter. Trees, branches, and vines weave together to suit the needs of the faithful. Bridges of vines and boughs knit as one, sometimes right before your eyes, to provide passage between homes and villages. Bone, resin, and sinew are also used in building construction, as well as for their art and weapons. Totems made from skulls and bones decorate many residences, and hides stretched across frames of bone create partitions for privacy. Bosmer bows, made from horns and sinew, are noted as the best bows in Tamriel. In fact, it is rumored that the bow was invented by the bosmer. These superior weapons, along with hides and bone charms, are the main exports to the neighboring nations. Many of the coastal villages, especially those founded by other races, are built on the forest floor and are typically constructed from traditional construction materials, like timber and stone. The Green Pact allows Bosmer to import timber to make their homes and doesn't apply to the other races.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Skilled Adventurers</name>
      <text>As some of the greatest hunters and scouts in all of Tamriel, many Bosmer leave their villages to seek out greater challenges. They are born warriors, excelling at martial combat, and they have a natural connection with beasts. Those who have ignored the Pact and turned their back on Y'ffre are expelled from their tribe. An exiled bosmer usually has no other option than to seek out adventure elsewhere.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Bosmer Names</name>
      <text>Most Bosmer have only their given name, but it is not unheard of to have a family name, which is typically descriptive of their skills or ancestry.

Male Names:
Aengvir, Athragar, Baenlin, Brenor, Calthindor, Deros, Drinlin, Elseer, Faenir, Fangaril, Filalmoth, Firras, Gelin, Hadran, Inluin, Lenor, Malgoth, Niden, Ording, Rollin, Saldir, Thranor, Urunil

Female Names:
Aerin, Althel, Belwen, Candel, Distel, Elphinia, Erwin, Evelie, Fangil, Ganwen, Glaras, Herdor, Indanas, Laen, Miniel, Nara, Pishna, Ralion, Sednel, Thralin, Uunril, Zifri

Family Names:
Arrow-Catcher, Blood-Letter, Daintyfoot, Flameheart, Greenwood, Longshot, Many-Legs, the bold, Tree-Killer, Woodwalker</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Like the Altmer, Bosmer mature the same way as humans do, but they can live up to 300 years or more.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Wood elves love their freedom from the more structured societies, but they also come from a history of strict tradition. Bosmer are neutral good more often than not, but those who ignore the pact might favor the gentler aspects of chaos.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 35 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Beast Tounge</name>
      <text>You know the spell speak with animals and can cast it once with this trait. You regain the ability to cast it again when you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Bosmer Blood</name>
      <text>Your Bosmer ancestry grants you advantage on saving throws against being poisoned or diseased, and you are resistant to poison damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Bosmer Combat Training</name>
      <text>You are proficient in the Acrobatics skill and with Marksman weapons.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Y'ffre's Gift</name>
      <text>You know one cantrip of your choice from the warden spell list. You also know the animal friendship spell and can cast it once with this trait. You regain the ability to cast it again when you finish a long rest. Willpower is your spellcasting attribute for these spells.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Bosmeri.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Breton (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Intelligence +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Bretons are the human descendants of the Aldmeri-Nedic Manmer of the Merethic Era and are now the inhabitants of the province of High Rock. They are united in culture and language, even though they are divided politically, for High Rock is a fractious region. Bretons make up the peasantry, soldiery, and magical elite of the feudal kingdoms that compete for power. Many are capable mages with innate resistance to magicka. They are known for proficiency in abstract thinking and unique customs. Bretons appear, by and large, much like other pale-skinned humans. They are usually slight of build and not as muscular as Nords or Redguards. Their Elvish ancestry is usually only detectable upon a closer inspection of their eyebrows, ears, or high cheekbones, though many individual Bretons appear to be more Nordic or Imperial than anything else. The great diversity in their appearance is to be expected from their politically fractured society, though their clothes, accents, customs, and names are fairly uniform.
	Bretons are the descendants of either an Aldmeri-Nedic or Aldmeri-Atmoran hybrid race of the 1st Era and are consequently termed as 'the mongrel race of Tamriel'. Their elven blood is heavily diluted due to their ancestors intermingling with the Nordic population in Skyrim and High Rock. Bretons are sometimes called "Manmeri" as a result of the interbreeding, literally translating to 'man-elf'. Although their Aldmeri ancestry is shadowed by their appearance, they still inherit the magical affinity of their elven blood. Their physical features resemble their Nedic ancestors, including their pale skin tone and the obvious physical resemblance to Imperials/Nords, but some still inherit the frail, sharp appearance of the elves, along with the arrogance, and some do have slight points in their ears.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Coupled Lineage</name>
      <text>Bretons are sometimes referred to as the mongrel race of Tamriel, being neither elven nor truly human. Sometimes, although usually only in a derogative manner, the Bretons are called Manmeri, literally 'man-elf', due to their history of crossbreeding. Their physical appearance is similar to their Nedic ancestors, giving them pale skin tones comparable to their Nord and Imperial cousins, along with the same range of hair color. Similar to the high elves, they maintain a slender form. This elven bloodline ensures that they are never quite as muscular as the other human races. A keen observer can also notice subtle elven lineaments, especially from their eyebrows, slightly pointed ears, and high cheekbones. Some Bretons even seem to adopt their elven arrogance, but paired with their human emotions, it usually comes off more graceful.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Curious and Inquisitive</name>
      <text>Although their Aldmeri ancestry is diluted, which shows in their physical appearance, they remain as capable mages with a strong resistance to magic. They are intellectual purists, known for their aptitude in abstract thinking, and are naturally drawn towards careers that favor logic and ordered complexity. Bretons are known to be skilled in many fields.
	Their friendly spirits and humorous demeanor lend themselves to writing, acting, and artistry. Their love of commerce leads them into banking, manufacturing, and trading, while their desire for order makes them well suited for the military and sailing.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>A Struggle for Sovereignty</name>
      <text>Breton society is divided into the many different regions of High Rock. The feudal kingdoms compete for power and enforce the strict hierarchy that splits its people from peasants and the elite. Despite this obvious rivalry, the Bretons are united in their culture, accents, customs, and language. Their villages are quaint, and although the architecture may change between the districts, they are usually functional in style and free of ornamentation.
	Bretons compete with the Orsimer, with their great city of Orsinium and the many small orcish strongholds, as well as the barbaric reachmen.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Born for Adventure</name>
      <text>Performing quests and services is a common way for Bretons to rise in the ranks of their society, which has created a unique form of enthusiasm. The younger Bretons are raised with a desire to find fortune and glory all over Tamriel</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Excellent Ambassadors</name>
      <text>Many Bretons learn at an early age to get along with everyone, defusing hostility and finding common ground. As a race, they have elven grace without elven aloofness and human energy without human boorishness. They often make excellent ambassadors and go-betweens.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Breton Names</name>
      <text>Bretons have both given names and family names.

Male Names:
Andre, Barnard, Blaise, Brandon, Clinton, Colin, Davide, Delacourt, Emmanual, Francois, Gregory, Hannibal, Jean, Louis, Marc, Mathieu, Philip, Roland, Samuel, Timothy, Vincent

Female Names:
Adeline, Alexia, Aren, Belle, Carena, Ciara, Dessire, Elain, Freyda, Gabrielle, Grace, Hester, Lexi, Maelle, Michelle, Nessa, Olivia, Pyn, Rianne, Saly, Sara, Taern, Veronica, Ysabeth, Zeli

Family Names:
Ashton, Beaufort, Celata, Dufont, Edette, Franc, Galien, LaRouche, Merchad, Panoit, Ronise, Serene, Talbot, Varin, Zurric</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Your elven lineage allows you to live slightly longer than your human counterparts. About 150 years.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment </name>
      <text>Their feudal governments lend them a mix of freedoms and laws, depending on their station in life. They tend to be Neutral Good.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Tool Proficiency</name>
      <text>You are proficient with Alchemist's Supplies. 

These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan's tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft. Each type of artisan's tools requires a separate proficiency.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Breton Ancestry</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in Willpower saving throws and the Arcana skill. You also know one cantrip of your choice from the mage spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting attribute for it.</text>
      <proficiency>Wisdom, Arcana</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Conjure Familiar</name>
      <text>You know the find familiar spell and can cast it once with this trait. You regain the ability to cast it again when you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Dragon Skin</name>
      <text>Your skin thickens to become that of a dragon when harmed. When you are hit by an attack or targeted by the magic missile spell, you can use your reaction to cast the shield spell. Once you use this trait, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Magic Resistance</name>
      <text>You have a natural ability to ward off the hazardous effects of magic. Whenever you are affected by a spell that deals damage, the total damage is reduced by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and one other standard language of your choice.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Dunmer (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +1, Intelligence +1, Strength +1</ability>
    <resist>fire</resist>
    <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
    <weapons>Longsword, Shortsword, Firearms</weapons>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Dunmer, also known as Dark Elves, are the ash-skinned, typically red-eyed elven peoples of Morrowind. "Dark" is commonly understood as meaning such characteristics as "dark-skinned", "gloomy", "ill-favored by fate" and so on. The Dunmer and their national identity, however, embrace these various connotations with enthusiasm. In the Empire, "Dark Elf" is the common usage, but among their Aldmeri brethren they are called "Dunmer". Their combination of powerful intellects with strong and agile physiques produce superior warriors and sorcerers. On the battlefield, Dunmer are noted for their skill with a balanced integration of the sword, the bow and destruction magic. Dunmer live two to three times as long as humans; with a 200-year-old Dunmer being old and a 300-year-old Dunmer being very, very old. In character, they are grim, aloof, and reserved, as well as distrusting and disdainful of other races.
	Dunmer distrust and are treated distrustfully by other races. They are often proud, clannish, ruthless, and cruel, from an outsider's point of view, but greatly value loyalty and family. Despite their powerful skills and strengths, the Dunmer's vengeful nature, age-old conflicts, betrayals, and ill-reputation prevent them from gaining more influence. Those born in their homeland of Morrowind before its devastation were known to be considerably less friendly than those who grew up in the Imperial tradition.
	Most Dunmer have red, glowing eyes with skin tones varying from somewhat greenish and the more common gray to the occasional light blue. They are known to be strong, intelligent, and quick, however, are also said to be ill favored by fate. Both male and female Dunmer have a height similar to most of the human races. This means that they are generally taller than their Bosmer cousins and shorter than the Altmer.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Skin of Twilight, Eyes of Sunlight</name>
      <text>The ashen skinned elves are typically the same size and shape as the human races, which makes them shorter than their Altmer cousins, but taller than the Bosmer. Their skin tone ranges from green, to varying shades of grey, to light blue, and their red glowing eyes make their appearance exceptionally unique. More often than not, their hair is jet black, but it can range in color from white, to grey, shades of dark brown, and on rare occasions, dark red.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>A Curse As a Reminder</name>
      <text>Before the dark elves were known as they are today, they were called the Chimer, or People of the North. They were a dissident tribe of Aldmeri who followed their prophet Veloth and worshiped the three 'good' daedra. They traveled to modern day Morrowind, where they warred with the Dwemer and Orcs.
	After the Battle of Red Mountain, the 'Living Gods' of the Tribunal betrayed their oath to Azura, which forever cursed them with skin as black as ash, and eyes red with fire. They were from then on known as the Dunmer.
	The Dunmer have always had a grim outlook, which may either be due to their unfortunate past, or perhaps a cause for it. They are generally disdainful, and distrusting of other races and those born outside of Morrowind, which they refer to as outlanders. Nationalistic and proud, the Dunmer are also ruthless and cruel, but they are also exceptionally loyal and have strong family values maintained by ancestral worship. They are not quick to trust anyone who claims to be a friend, but once a Dunmer gives someone their loyalty, the Dunmer is a firm friend or ally for life.
	Another dark side of Dunmer history is their extensive use of slavery. Mostly Argonian and Khajiit slaves were used, but so were men and mer in rare cases. Their vengeful nature and long history of ill repute prevents them from gaining significant influence with the other nations.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Balanced Warriors</name>
      <text>Dunmer are exceptionally well rounded warriors. Notable for their powerful intellect, agile physique, and natural strength, Dunmer are exceptional militants, mercenaries, and warriors.
	With the destruction of Vvardenfell and the Argonian invasion, many Dunmer have fled their homeland, trying to make their own way in the world. Their natural martial gifts and resilient heritage makes them strong survivors.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Dunmer Names</name>
      <text>Dunmer typically have given names and family names. Those that are the traditional inhabitants of Vvardenfell, known as Ashlanders, also have unique tribe names.

Male Names:
Alanil, Aren, Balyn, Boler, Dathus, Evo, Fevris, Gaelion, Hort, Liero, Meryn, Nels, Orval, Ranor, Sarayn, Tavryn, Tendris, Traven, Uthrel, Varon, Vedam

Female Names:
Almsi, Amili, Arara, Badala, Balynu, Bronosa, Dalyne, Diren, Ethal, Faras, Gadela, Gelaa, Hlava, Indrasi, Madrana, Nela, Orea, Rila, Sia, Teranya, Urila, Valdrana, Wren

Family Names:
Andrano, Arvel, Belas, Dralas, Darethi, Drethen, Falen, Galen, Helvi, Hlaalo, Indaren, Marvel, Moren, Nelas, Omoril, Ralas, Romori, Rothandus, Sarandas, Selaren, Telas, Uveran, Varyon, Veleth

Ashlander Names:
Addarari, Asserbassalit, Assunudadnud, Daririnaddunumm, Esatliballit, Gilu, Hairshashishi, Kil, Mirshamammu, Nerendus, Rapli, Serimilk, Timmiririan, Yassabisun, Zabamat</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 1, your Intelligence score increases by 1, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>As all elves, Dunmer are long lived, maturing at the same rate as humans, but possibly living longer than 300 years.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Dunmer tend to be neutral with a propensity for chaos. They have rejected many of the traditions that were set before them, while adopting their new customs of their own.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Ancestor Guardian</name>
      <text>As a reaction, you gain advantage on saving throws against spells that deal damage until the start of your next turn. You can use this trait a number of times equal to your Endurance modifier (minimum of 1). You regain all expended uses at the end of a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Ashlander</name>
      <text>You have a natural resistance to fire damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Dunmer Combat Training</name>
      <text>You are proficient in Long Blade, Marksman, and Short Blade.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Skill Proficiency</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Athletics skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Dunmeri.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Imperial (Colovian) (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
    <weapons>Longsword</weapons>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Also known as Cyrodiils, Cyrodilics, Cyro-Nordics and Imperial Cyrods, the well-educated and well-spoken Imperials are the natives of the civilized, cosmopolitan province of Cyrodiil. Imperials are also known for the discipline and training of their citizen armies, and their respect for the rule of law. Though physically less imposing than the other races, the Imperials have proved to be shrewd diplomats and traders, and these traits, along with their remarkable skill and training as light infantry, have enabled them to subdue all the other nations and races and erect the monument to peace and prosperity that comprises the Glorious Empire. Their hegemony has waxed and waned throughout the eras, and most historians refer to three distinct Empires, the ends of which each mark a new epoch in Tamrielic history.

The Cyro-Nords that settled in the west created the Colovian Estates, and in turn call themselves Colovians. They are typically more rugged and hardy than their Nibenese counterparts. They are uncomplicated, self-sufficient, and extremely loyal to other Colovians.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>From Slave to Master</name>
      <text>When the Imperial race emerged from the original Nibenese tribesman and the Nedic immigrants, they were subjugated by the Ayleids, or Wild Elves of Cyrodiil. They remained as slaves for decades before creating a rebellion that overthrew their elven masters, creating the first human empire. Although short lived, this early empire was disrupted through civil war, splitting Cyrodiil into two distinct cultures: the Eastern Nibenese and the Western Colovians. Since then, the Imperials and their ever changing Empire have had some part in the birth of each Era.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Diplomats and Soldiers</name>
      <text>Known for their impressive citizen armies, the Imperials are exceptionally disciplined and treat the law with the utmost respect. Banners of the Imperial Empire can be found in nearly every province of Tamriel, although recent years have proven to be a struggle to maintain their power.
	As shrewd diplomats and remarkable negotiators, the Imperials have had great success subduing other nations, bringing peace and prosperity to many societies. When their authority is questioned, their martial prowess and extraordinary organization of their military usually makes quick work of any dissenters.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Imperial Names</name>
      <text>Imperials have both given names and family names.

Male Names:
Aventus, Baro, Caius, Decentius, Ennodius, Floretius, Gaius, Helvius, Iniel, Janus, Kastav, Luther, Mallus, Nermus, Octavius, Pelagius, Rallus, Sergio, Titus, Valgus, Xander, Zedrick

Female Names:
Alexia, Astria, Britta, Cania, Dynari, Ettiene, Faustina, Gemma, Herminia, Isobel, Julitta, Lyra, Mariana, Nebia, Peregrina, Rona, Selena, Tertia, Una, Viera, Vitrroia, Ysabel

Family Names:
Aerius, Amatius, Berne, Caro, Deltian, Felannus, Gratius, Herennius, Jannus, Loran, Mallius, Nuccius, Rian, Silver, Tunifus, Urgelian, Valga, Wavrick</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>As a human race, Imperials live to an average age of 100.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment </name>
      <text>The militant Imperials are often lawful good, but sometimes lean towards neutral, given their stringent laws and institutions.
Any Lawful Alignment</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Diplomat</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Imperial Cunning</name>
      <text>When you make an Intelligence, Personality, or Willpower saving throw, you can use your reaction to gain advantage on the roll. Once you use this trait, you must complete a long rest before you are able to use it again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Imperial Luck</name>
      <text>You gain two Luck Dice, which is a d6. You can expend one Luck Dice to add it to an attribute check, attack roll, or saving throw you make. You can wait until after you roll the d20 before deciding to use the Luck Dice, but must decide before the GM determines whether the roll succeeds or fails. You regain your expended Luck Dice when you finish a long rest. You can never have more than two Luck Dice from this trait at a time.</text>
      <roll description="Luck">1d6</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Legion Combat Training</name>
      <text>You are proficient in Blunt, Hand-to-Hand, and Long Blade.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Star of the West</name>
      <text>Your hardy upbringing lets you push past the normal boundaries of exhaustion. When you are exhausted, you suffer the effects of one level less than your current level of exhaustion. For example, at 1st level, you suffer no adverse effects.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and two standard languages of your choice. Imperials typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Imperial (Nibenese) (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Charisma +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
    <weapons>Longsword</weapons>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Also known as Cyrodiils, Cyrodilics, Cyro-Nordics and Imperial Cyrods, the well-educated and well-spoken Imperials are the natives of the civilized, cosmopolitan province of Cyrodiil. Imperials are also known for the discipline and training of their citizen armies, and their respect for the rule of law. Though physically less imposing than the other races, the Imperials have proved to be shrewd diplomats and traders, and these traits, along with their remarkable skill and training as light infantry, have enabled them to subdue all the other nations and races and erect the monument to peace and prosperity that comprises the Glorious Empire. Their hegemony has waxed and waned throughout the eras, and most historians refer to three distinct Empires, the ends of which each mark a new epoch in Tamrielic history.

The Imperials that settled in the East, by the Nibenay, became the Nibenese. This area was brought together by the Alessian Order and maintains strong merchant guilds. Nibenese are proud cosmopolitan people who maintain strong relationships with the other provinces through merchant guilds. They are more given to the studies of magic, philosophy, and the evolution of ancient tradition. Many outfit themselves in garish clothing, tattoos, and brandings.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>From Slave to Master</name>
      <text>When the Imperial race emerged from the original Nibenese tribesman and the Nedic immigrants, they were subjugated by the Ayleids, or Wild Elves of Cyrodiil. They remained as slaves for decades before creating a rebellion that overthrew their elven masters, creating the first human empire. Although short lived, this early empire was disrupted through civil war, splitting Cyrodiil into two distinct cultures: the Eastern Nibenese and the Western Colovians. Since then, the Imperials and their ever changing Empire have had some part in the birth of each Era.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Diplomats and Soldiers</name>
      <text>Known for their impressive citizen armies, the Imperials are exceptionally disciplined and treat the law with the utmost respect. Banners of the Imperial Empire can be found in nearly every province of Tamriel, although recent years have proven to be a struggle to maintain their power.
	As shrewd diplomats and remarkable negotiators, the Imperials have had great success subduing other nations, bringing peace and prosperity to many societies. When their authority is questioned, their martial prowess and extraordinary organization of their military usually makes quick work of any dissenters.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Imperial Names</name>
      <text>Imperials have both given names and family names.

Male Names:
Aventus, Baro, Caius, Decentius, Ennodius, Floretius, Gaius, Helvius, Iniel, Janus, Kastav, Luther, Mallus, Nermus, Octavius, Pelagius, Rallus, Sergio, Titus, Valgus, Xander, Zedrick

Female Names:
Alexia, Astria, Britta, Cania, Dynari, Ettiene, Faustina, Gemma, Herminia, Isobel, Julitta, Lyra, Mariana, Nebia, Peregrina, Rona, Selena, Tertia, Una, Viera, Vitrroia, Ysabel

Family Names:
Aerius, Amatius, Berne, Caro, Deltian, Felannus, Gratius, Herennius, Jannus, Loran, Mallius, Nuccius, Rian, Silver, Tunifus, Urgelian, Valga, Wavrick</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>As a human race, Imperials live to an average age of 100.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment </name>
      <text>The militant Imperials are often lawful good, but sometimes lean towards neutral, given their stringent laws and institutions.
Any Lawful Alignment</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Diplomat</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Imperial Cunning</name>
      <text>When you make an Intelligence, Personality, or Willpower saving throw, you can use your reaction to gain advantage on the roll. Once you use this trait, you must complete a long rest before you are able to use it again.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Imperial Luck</name>
      <text>You gain two Luck Dice, which is a d6. You can expend one Luck Dice to add it to an attribute check, attack roll, or saving throw you make. You can wait until after you roll the d20 before deciding to use the Luck Dice, but must decide before the GM determines whether the roll succeeds or fails. You regain your expended Luck Dice when you finish a long rest. You can never have more than two Luck Dice from this trait at a time.</text>
      <roll description="Luck">1d6</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Legion Combat Training</name>
      <text>You are proficient in Blunt, Hand-to-Hand, and Long Blade.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Voice of the Emperor</name>
      <text>You know the friends cantrip. Additionally, once between long rests, you are able to use this cantrip without your target knowing it was cast on them.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and two standard languages of your choice. Imperials typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Khajiit (Cathay/Cathay-raht) (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>35</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Khajiit are a race of feline humanoids hailing from the province of Elsweyr, well-known for their keen intelligence and agility. While these traits make them superb thieves and acrobats, Khajiit are also fearsome warriors. However, strenuous training must typically be undertaken to make wielding magic a serious option, either in passive or aggressive actions. Khajiit are said to rarely take to the sea, though piracy and the skooma trade does draw some to work as sailors.
	Physiologically, Khajiit differ greatly from both the varied races of man and mer, not only in their skeletal structure (possessing a tail and, in some forms, a digitigrade stance, i.e. toe walking) and dermal makeup (the "fur" that covers their bodies) but in their digestion and metabolism as well. The Khajiit, along with the Argonians and the Imga, make up the so called 'beast races' of the Empire, due to their anthropomorphic qualities. Khajiit have a lifespan similar to that of humans. It is currently unclear whether a successful union between Khajiit and other races may occur, for no well-documented cases exist despite rumors. The divergent appearance and mannerisms of the Khajiit often lead bigoted members of other races to look down on them.

Similar to the Suthay-raht in appearance and bi-pedalism, however, they possess greater stature and strength. Cathay-raht are larger and more powerful and are often described as "jaguar-men".

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Children of the Moon</name>
      <text>Bound to the lunar lattice, a mysterious force understood by the Khajiit, the phases of the two moons at the time of their birth determines the form, or 'breed', a Khajiit will assume. All newborns look alike, much smaller than the other races of Tamriel, but the early days of their life begin to give way to their future form. There are rumored to be more than twenty forms of Khajiit, but most common are Alfiq, Cathay, Dagi, Ohmes, Pahmar, Senche, Suthay, and Tojay. The humanoid forms are described in further detail in the subrace section.
	Khajiit differ greatly from all other races, most obviously with their catlike form, tail, fur, and digitigrade stance. Although typical of most humanoid Khajiit, some sub-species, such as the Ohmes, appear more similar to the Bosmer than to their own brothers and sisters. Their physical appearance isn't their only physiological differences. Even the digestive systems and metabolisms are different from most other races, allowing them to have a stronger resilience to substances like moon sugar.
	Bright textiles and shiny objects are desired by Khajiit. They dress in cloth shawls of brilliant colors, known as a budi, which helps defend themselves from the sun. They adorn themselves with sparkling jewelry and trinkets, and are known to wear flowers and herbs in their braided fur. The breeds that do not grow fur typically tattoo themselves with cultural or religious symbols to resemble their cousins.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Holy Moons</name>
      <text>A large part of the Khajiit religion is worship of the two moons of Tamriel. This is an obvious path, given how much the moons affect the lives of every Khajiit. Another significant part of the Khajiit lifestyle is the harvest and ingestion of a powerful and addictive substance called moon-sugar. This substance is known to be crystallized moonlight, which they believe by ingesting, they are absorbing a part of the eternal souls of the moon gods, Jone and Jode.
	When moon-sugar is ingested, it causes fits of ecstasy and abandon. Paired with the highly addictive nature, it is common for Khajiit settlements to be littered with cat-men shivering in the grips of sugar fits.
	Nevertheless, moon-sugar is a daily part of Khajiit life, and serves as their chief export. Their affection for moon-sugar has developed a sweet tooth, and the Khajiit diet is invariably sweet. Candies, cakes, puddings, and sugared meats are staples in Khajiit cuisine. This fare is usually laced with powdered moon-sugar, and the other races would be wise to never accept a sweet roll from a cat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Social Duality</name>
      <text>The societies of Khajiit are lead by a unique breed of Khajiit known as the Mane, born under the aligned moons. Tradition states that only one mane can be alive at a time and it is believed that each mane is a reincarnation of the previous.
	Khajiit civilizations are divided into two specific cultures. The jungles of Elsweyr are civil and are formed around an agrarian aristocracy, whereas the northern wastes and grasslands tend to be nomadic, pride-centric groups that contest for territory.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Guardians and Charlatans</name>
      <text>Khajiit, who are commonly targeted for racial discrimination, have had to deal with being kidnapped and sold into slavery. This harsh reality has made them take self defense very seriously. The majority of Khajiit use their claws as weapons, and many have formed groups that utilize their natural gifts in various forms of martial arts.
	Other Khajiit welcome the black market with open paws, taking to a life of piracy, smuggling moon-sugar, and the more potent skooma, to the many different lands. Khajiit's natural abilities make them superb thieves and acrobats, as well as fearsome warriors.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Khajiit Names</name>
      <text>Each Khajiit has a single name in their language, Ta'agra, but it is also common for a Khajiit to go by their Tamrielic name, usually given to them by men or mer. These common names are typically descriptive of their personality or quirks.

Male Names:
Akrah, Azbishan, Balag, Dazur, Eilun, Fa'alar, Ghadar, Hilan, Jahirr, Khasar, Lansur, Maniz, Malirzzaka, Nakkhu, Oblan, Pinar, Rakhad, Razur, Sabra, Tabil, Urjen, Vashpar, Yan, Zaban, Zino

Female Names:
Abizah, Azum, Bakkhara, Bindu, Darali, Elamusa, Fedura, Hani, Inama, Kala, Kiasha, Manabi, Mura, Nayya, Pinirai, Samati, Sebazi, Shuzura, Tahara, Tohiba, Urbani, Vaifa, Yana, Zara, Zurka

Tamrielic Names:
Ashenfur, Black-Paw, Clevereyes, Dawnwalker, Dusty-Claw, Elf-Biter, Firebreath, Four-Toes, Iron-Ear, Kink Tail, Silvertongue, Soft-Fur, Sugar-Claws, Tender-Paws, Wet-Whiskers

Khajiit Honorifics:
Khajiit often, but not always, have either a prefix or a suffix, or sometimes both, as part of their name, usually separated by an apostrophe. The titles are typically meant to represent a part of their personality or traits. Some Khajiit believe having both a prefix and a suffix is a sign of arrogance and pride.

Khajiit Honorifics:
d10 | Title | Meaning
1 | Dar | Thief
2 | Do | Warrior
3 | Dra | Wise
4 | Dro | Grandparent
5 | J/Ja/Ji	 | Youth
6 | Jo/Ko | Wizard
7 | La/Lo | Promiscuous
8 | M/Ma | Child or Apprentice
9 | Ra/Ri | Leader
10 | S | Adult</text>
      <roll description="Title">1d10</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Khajiit Personality</name>
      <text>A Khajiit might have motivations and quirks much different from an elf or a human with a similar background. You can use the following table to customize your character in addition to the trait, ideal, bond, and flaw from your background.

Khajiit Quirks:
d10 | Quirk
1 | You miss your tropical home and complain endlessly about the freezing weather, even in summer.
2 | You never wear the same outfit twice, unless you absolutely must.
3 | You have a minor phobia of water and hate getting wet.
4 | Your tail always betrays your inner thoughts.
5 | You purr loudly when you are happy.
6 | You keep a small ball of yarn in your hand, which you constantly fidget with.
7 | You are always in debt, since you spend your gold on food and drink made from moon sugar.
8 | When talking about something you're obsessed with, you speak quickly and never pause and others can't understand you.
9 | You are a font of random trivia from the lore and stories you have discovered.
10 | You can't help but pocket interesting objects you come across.</text>
      <roll description="Quirk">1d10</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Different Khajiit born under different cycles have significantly different life spans. They can range from 150 to 400 years, if not more.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Khajiit tend toward chaotic alignments, as they let impulse and fancy guide their decisions. They are rarely evil, except for those driven by greed or other dark impulses.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 35 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Eyes of Fear</name>
      <text>You know how to use your cat-like eyes to demoralize others. You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Eyes of Night</name>
      <text>Your khajiit ancestry grants you superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Quick Claws</name>
      <text>Because of your claws, you have a climbing speed of 20 feet. In addition, your claws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal slashing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</text>
      <roll description="Unarmed Bludgeoning Damage">1d4+%1</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Savage Attacks</name>
      <text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon's damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Ta'agra. Ta'agra script combines unique and fluid motions. Artistic interpretation is praised and varies greatly between authors.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Khajiit (Dagi/Dagi-raht) (HB)</name>
    <size>S</size>
    <speed>35</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Khajiit are a race of feline humanoids hailing from the province of Elsweyr, well-known for their keen intelligence and agility. While these traits make them superb thieves and acrobats, Khajiit are also fearsome warriors. However, strenuous training must typically be undertaken to make wielding magic a serious option, either in passive or aggressive actions. Khajiit are said to rarely take to the sea, though piracy and the skooma trade does draw some to work as sailors.
	Physiologically, Khajiit differ greatly from both the varied races of man and mer, not only in their skeletal structure (possessing a tail and, in some forms, a digitigrade stance, i.e. toe walking) and dermal makeup (the "fur" that covers their bodies) but in their digestion and metabolism as well. The Khajiit, along with the Argonians and the Imga, make up the so called 'beast races' of the Empire, due to their anthropomorphic qualities. Khajiit have a lifespan similar to that of humans. It is currently unclear whether a successful union between Khajiit and other races may occur, for no well-documented cases exist despite rumors. The divergent appearance and mannerisms of the Khajiit often lead bigoted members of other races to look down on them.

Dagi live in the trees of the Tenmar forest. Due to their smaller size and light weight, they are able to dwell in the higher branches which even the Bosmer cannot reach. The Dagi have a natural affinity for magic, and are known spellcasters, a characteristic often taken advantage of in Khajiiti battle-tactics.
	The Dagi-raht are similar in all respects, while their size is somewhat larger.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Children of the Moon</name>
      <text>Bound to the lunar lattice, a mysterious force understood by the Khajiit, the phases of the two moons at the time of their birth determines the form, or 'breed', a Khajiit will assume. All newborns look alike, much smaller than the other races of Tamriel, but the early days of their life begin to give way to their future form. There are rumored to be more than twenty forms of Khajiit, but most common are Alfiq, Cathay, Dagi, Ohmes, Pahmar, Senche, Suthay, and Tojay. The humanoid forms are described in further detail in the subrace section.
	Khajiit differ greatly from all other races, most obviously with their catlike form, tail, fur, and digitigrade stance. Although typical of most humanoid Khajiit, some sub-species, such as the Ohmes, appear more similar to the Bosmer than to their own brothers and sisters. Their physical appearance isn't their only physiological differences. Even the digestive systems and metabolisms are different from most other races, allowing them to have a stronger resilience to substances like moon sugar.
	Bright textiles and shiny objects are desired by Khajiit. They dress in cloth shawls of brilliant colors, known as a budi, which helps defend themselves from the sun. They adorn themselves with sparkling jewelry and trinkets, and are known to wear flowers and herbs in their braided fur. The breeds that do not grow fur typically tattoo themselves with cultural or religious symbols to resemble their cousins.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Holy Moons</name>
      <text>A large part of the Khajiit religion is worship of the two moons of Tamriel. This is an obvious path, given how much the moons affect the lives of every Khajiit. Another significant part of the Khajiit lifestyle is the harvest and ingestion of a powerful and addictive substance called moon-sugar. This substance is known to be crystallized moonlight, which they believe by ingesting, they are absorbing a part of the eternal souls of the moon gods, Jone and Jode.
	When moon-sugar is ingested, it causes fits of ecstasy and abandon. Paired with the highly addictive nature, it is common for Khajiit settlements to be littered with cat-men shivering in the grips of sugar fits.
	Nevertheless, moon-sugar is a daily part of Khajiit life, and serves as their chief export. Their affection for moon-sugar has developed a sweet tooth, and the Khajiit diet is invariably sweet. Candies, cakes, puddings, and sugared meats are staples in Khajiit cuisine. This fare is usually laced with powdered moon-sugar, and the other races would be wise to never accept a sweet roll from a cat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Social Duality</name>
      <text>The societies of Khajiit are lead by a unique breed of Khajiit known as the Mane, born under the aligned moons. Tradition states that only one mane can be alive at a time and it is believed that each mane is a reincarnation of the previous.
	Khajiit civilizations are divided into two specific cultures. The jungles of Elsweyr are civil and are formed around an agrarian aristocracy, whereas the northern wastes and grasslands tend to be nomadic, pride-centric groups that contest for territory.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Guardians and Charlatans</name>
      <text>Khajiit, who are commonly targeted for racial discrimination, have had to deal with being kidnapped and sold into slavery. This harsh reality has made them take self defense very seriously. The majority of Khajiit use their claws as weapons, and many have formed groups that utilize their natural gifts in various forms of martial arts.
	Other Khajiit welcome the black market with open paws, taking to a life of piracy, smuggling moon-sugar, and the more potent skooma, to the many different lands. Khajiit's natural abilities make them superb thieves and acrobats, as well as fearsome warriors.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Khajiit Names</name>
      <text>Each Khajiit has a single name in their language, Ta'agra, but it is also common for a Khajiit to go by their Tamrielic name, usually given to them by men or mer. These common names are typically descriptive of their personality or quirks.

Male Names:
Akrah, Azbishan, Balag, Dazur, Eilun, Fa'alar, Ghadar, Hilan, Jahirr, Khasar, Lansur, Maniz, Malirzzaka, Nakkhu, Oblan, Pinar, Rakhad, Razur, Sabra, Tabil, Urjen, Vashpar, Yan, Zaban, Zino

Female Names:
Abizah, Azum, Bakkhara, Bindu, Darali, Elamusa, Fedura, Hani, Inama, Kala, Kiasha, Manabi, Mura, Nayya, Pinirai, Samati, Sebazi, Shuzura, Tahara, Tohiba, Urbani, Vaifa, Yana, Zara, Zurka

Tamrielic Names:
Ashenfur, Black-Paw, Clevereyes, Dawnwalker, Dusty-Claw, Elf-Biter, Firebreath, Four-Toes, Iron-Ear, Kink Tail, Silvertongue, Soft-Fur, Sugar-Claws, Tender-Paws, Wet-Whiskers

Khajiit Honorifics:
Khajiit often, but not always, have either a prefix or a suffix, or sometimes both, as part of their name, usually separated by an apostrophe. The titles are typically meant to represent a part of their personality or traits. Some Khajiit believe having both a prefix and a suffix is a sign of arrogance and pride.

Khajiit Honorifics:
d10 | Title | Meaning
1 | Dar | Thief
2 | Do | Warrior
3 | Dra | Wise
4 | Dro | Grandparent
5 | J/Ja/Ji	 | Youth
6 | Jo/Ko | Wizard
7 | La/Lo | Promiscuous
8 | M/Ma | Child or Apprentice
9 | Ra/Ri | Leader
10 | S | Adult</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Khajiit Personality</name>
      <text>A Khajiit might have motivations and quirks much different from an elf or a human with a similar background. You can use the following table to customize your character in addition to the trait, ideal, bond, and flaw from your background.

Khajiit Quirks:
d10 | Quirk
1 | You miss your tropical home and complain endlessly about the freezing weather, even in summer.
2 | You never wear the same outfit twice, unless you absolutely must.
3 | You have a minor phobia of water and hate getting wet.
4 | Your tail always betrays your inner thoughts.
5 | You purr loudly when you are happy.
6 | You keep a small ball of yarn in your hand, which you constantly fidget with.
7 | You are always in debt, since you spend your gold on food and drink made from moon sugar.
8 | When talking about something you're obsessed with, you speak quickly and never pause and others can't understand you.
9 | You are a font of random trivia from the lore and stories you have discovered.
10 | You can't help but pocket interesting objects you come across.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Dagi average about 3 to 4 feet tall and weigh around 40 pounds. Your size is small.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 35 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Different Khajiit born under different cycles have significantly different life spans. They can range from 150 to 400 years, if not more.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Khajiit tend toward chaotic alignments, as they let impulse and fancy guide their decisions. They are rarely evil, except for those driven by greed or other dark impulses.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Eyes of Fear</name>
      <text>You know how to use your cat-like eyes to demoralize others. You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Eyes of Night</name>
      <text>Your khajiit ancestry grants you superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Quick Claws</name>
      <text>Because of your claws, you have a climbing speed of 20 feet. In addition, your claws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal slashing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</text>
      <roll description="Unarmed Bludgeoning Damage">1d4+%1</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Natrual Magic</name>
      <text>You know the thaumaturgy cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the witch bolt spell as a 2nd level spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the darkness spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting attribute for these spells.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Ta'agra. Ta'agra script combines unique and fluid motions. Artistic interpretation is praised and varies greatly between authors.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Khajiit (Ohmes/Ohmes-raht) (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>35</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Charisma +1</ability>
    <proficiency>Deception, Intimidation, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Khajiit are a race of feline humanoids hailing from the province of Elsweyr, well-known for their keen intelligence and agility. While these traits make them superb thieves and acrobats, Khajiit are also fearsome warriors. However, strenuous training must typically be undertaken to make wielding magic a serious option, either in passive or aggressive actions. Khajiit are said to rarely take to the sea, though piracy and the skooma trade does draw some to work as sailors.
	Physiologically, Khajiit differ greatly from both the varied races of man and mer, not only in their skeletal structure (possessing a tail and, in some forms, a digitigrade stance, i.e. toe walking) and dermal makeup (the "fur" that covers their bodies) but in their digestion and metabolism as well. The Khajiit, along with the Argonians and the Imga, make up the so called 'beast races' of the Empire, due to their anthropomorphic qualities. Khajiit have a lifespan similar to that of humans. It is currently unclear whether a successful union between Khajiit and other races may occur, for no well-documented cases exist despite rumors. The divergent appearance and mannerisms of the Khajiit often lead bigoted members of other races to look down on them.

The Ohmes generally look more similar to the Bosmer, although slightly smaller in stature. Many Ohmes will paint or tattoo their faces to resemble their feline heritage. Unlike other Khajiit, they have no fur, no tail, or any other distinguishable Khajiit feature.
	Ohmes-raht have slightly larger builds than their ohmes cousins, usually similar in size and appearance of men, other than their short light fur and tails. Also similar to men, the Ohmes-raht walk on their heels as opposed to the balls of their feet like many other species of Khajiit.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Children of the Moon</name>
      <text>Bound to the lunar lattice, a mysterious force understood by the Khajiit, the phases of the two moons at the time of their birth determines the form, or 'breed', a Khajiit will assume. All newborns look alike, much smaller than the other races of Tamriel, but the early days of their life begin to give way to their future form. There are rumored to be more than twenty forms of Khajiit, but most common are Alfiq, Cathay, Dagi, Ohmes, Pahmar, Senche, Suthay, and Tojay. The humanoid forms are described in further detail in the subrace section.
	Khajiit differ greatly from all other races, most obviously with their catlike form, tail, fur, and digitigrade stance. Although typical of most humanoid Khajiit, some sub-species, such as the Ohmes, appear more similar to the Bosmer than to their own brothers and sisters. Their physical appearance isn't their only physiological differences. Even the digestive systems and metabolisms are different from most other races, allowing them to have a stronger resilience to substances like moon sugar.
	Bright textiles and shiny objects are desired by Khajiit. They dress in cloth shawls of brilliant colors, known as a budi, which helps defend themselves from the sun. They adorn themselves with sparkling jewelry and trinkets, and are known to wear flowers and herbs in their braided fur. The breeds that do not grow fur typically tattoo themselves with cultural or religious symbols to resemble their cousins.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Holy Moons</name>
      <text>A large part of the Khajiit religion is worship of the two moons of Tamriel. This is an obvious path, given how much the moons affect the lives of every Khajiit. Another significant part of the Khajiit lifestyle is the harvest and ingestion of a powerful and addictive substance called moon-sugar. This substance is known to be crystallized moonlight, which they believe by ingesting, they are absorbing a part of the eternal souls of the moon gods, Jone and Jode.
	When moon-sugar is ingested, it causes fits of ecstasy and abandon. Paired with the highly addictive nature, it is common for Khajiit settlements to be littered with cat-men shivering in the grips of sugar fits.
	Nevertheless, moon-sugar is a daily part of Khajiit life, and serves as their chief export. Their affection for moon-sugar has developed a sweet tooth, and the Khajiit diet is invariably sweet. Candies, cakes, puddings, and sugared meats are staples in Khajiit cuisine. This fare is usually laced with powdered moon-sugar, and the other races would be wise to never accept a sweet roll from a cat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Social Duality</name>
      <text>The societies of Khajiit are lead by a unique breed of Khajiit known as the Mane, born under the aligned moons. Tradition states that only one mane can be alive at a time and it is believed that each mane is a reincarnation of the previous.
	Khajiit civilizations are divided into two specific cultures. The jungles of Elsweyr are civil and are formed around an agrarian aristocracy, whereas the northern wastes and grasslands tend to be nomadic, pride-centric groups that contest for territory.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Guardians and Charlatans</name>
      <text>Khajiit, who are commonly targeted for racial discrimination, have had to deal with being kidnapped and sold into slavery. This harsh reality has made them take self defense very seriously. The majority of Khajiit use their claws as weapons, and many have formed groups that utilize their natural gifts in various forms of martial arts.
	Other Khajiit welcome the black market with open paws, taking to a life of piracy, smuggling moon-sugar, and the more potent skooma, to the many different lands. Khajiit's natural abilities make them superb thieves and acrobats, as well as fearsome warriors.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Khajiit Names</name>
      <text>Each Khajiit has a single name in their language, Ta'agra, but it is also common for a Khajiit to go by their Tamrielic name, usually given to them by men or mer. These common names are typically descriptive of their personality or quirks.

Male Names:
Akrah, Azbishan, Balag, Dazur, Eilun, Fa'alar, Ghadar, Hilan, Jahirr, Khasar, Lansur, Maniz, Malirzzaka, Nakkhu, Oblan, Pinar, Rakhad, Razur, Sabra, Tabil, Urjen, Vashpar, Yan, Zaban, Zino

Female Names:
Abizah, Azum, Bakkhara, Bindu, Darali, Elamusa, Fedura, Hani, Inama, Kala, Kiasha, Manabi, Mura, Nayya, Pinirai, Samati, Sebazi, Shuzura, Tahara, Tohiba, Urbani, Vaifa, Yana, Zara, Zurka

Tamrielic Names:
Ashenfur, Black-Paw, Clevereyes, Dawnwalker, Dusty-Claw, Elf-Biter, Firebreath, Four-Toes, Iron-Ear, Kink Tail, Silvertongue, Soft-Fur, Sugar-Claws, Tender-Paws, Wet-Whiskers

Khajiit Honorifics:
Khajiit often, but not always, have either a prefix or a suffix, or sometimes both, as part of their name, usually separated by an apostrophe. The titles are typically meant to represent a part of their personality or traits. Some Khajiit believe having both a prefix and a suffix is a sign of arrogance and pride.

Khajiit Honorifics:
d10 | Title | Meaning
1 | Dar | Thief
2 | Do | Warrior
3 | Dra | Wise
4 | Dro | Grandparent
5 | J/Ja/Ji	 | Youth
6 | Jo/Ko | Wizard
7 | La/Lo | Promiscuous
8 | M/Ma | Child or Apprentice
9 | Ra/Ri | Leader
10 | S | Adult</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Khajiit Personality</name>
      <text>A Khajiit might have motivations and quirks much different from an elf or a human with a similar background. You can use the following table to customize your character in addition to the trait, ideal, bond, and flaw from your background.

Khajiit Quirks:
d10 | Quirk
1 | You miss your tropical home and complain endlessly about the freezing weather, even in summer.
2 | You never wear the same outfit twice, unless you absolutely must.
3 | You have a minor phobia of water and hate getting wet.
4 | Your tail always betrays your inner thoughts.
5 | You purr loudly when you are happy.
6 | You keep a small ball of yarn in your hand, which you constantly fidget with.
7 | You are always in debt, since you spend your gold on food and drink made from moon sugar.
8 | When talking about something you're obsessed with, you speak quickly and never pause and others can't understand you.
9 | You are a font of random trivia from the lore and stories you have discovered.
10 | You can't help but pocket interesting objects you come across.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Different Khajiit born under different cycles have significantly different life spans. They can range from 150 to 400 years, if not more.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Khajiit tend toward chaotic alignments, as they let impulse and fancy guide their decisions. They are rarely evil, except for those driven by greed or other dark impulses.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 35 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Eyes of Fear</name>
      <text>You know how to use your cat-like eyes to demoralize others. You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Eyes of Night</name>
      <text>Your khajiit ancestry grants you superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Ambassador</name>
      <text>Your elven-like form makes you a natural ambassador to the other races. You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills. If you're already proficient in either skill, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with that skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Deception, Perception</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Ohmes Combat Training</name>
      <text>The Ohmes do not have natural claws, like other Khajiit, so they don't benefit from the Quick Claws trait, but they are still proficient in Hand-to-Hand and Short Blade to make up for their natural handicap.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Ta'agra. Ta'agra script combines unique and fluid motions. Artistic interpretation is praised and varies greatly between authors.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Khajiit (Suthay/Suthay-raht) (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>35</speed>
    <ability>Dexterity +2, Constitution +1</ability>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Khajiit are a race of feline humanoids hailing from the province of Elsweyr, well-known for their keen intelligence and agility. While these traits make them superb thieves and acrobats, Khajiit are also fearsome warriors. However, strenuous training must typically be undertaken to make wielding magic a serious option, either in passive or aggressive actions. Khajiit are said to rarely take to the sea, though piracy and the skooma trade does draw some to work as sailors.
	Physiologically, Khajiit differ greatly from both the varied races of man and mer, not only in their skeletal structure (possessing a tail and, in some forms, a digitigrade stance, i.e. toe walking) and dermal makeup (the "fur" that covers their bodies) but in their digestion and metabolism as well. The Khajiit, along with the Argonians and the Imga, make up the so called 'beast races' of the Empire, due to their anthropomorphic qualities. Khajiit have a lifespan similar to that of humans. It is currently unclear whether a successful union between Khajiit and other races may occur, for no well-documented cases exist despite rumors. The divergent appearance and mannerisms of the Khajiit often lead bigoted members of other races to look down on them.

Similar in height to the Ohmes but that is mostly where the similarities end. The Suthay are much more cat-like in appearance with their high set ears and feline facial features, along with a long tail and digitigrade legs.
	Suthay-raht are nearly the same as the Suthay in all their features except their stature closer resembles the height of men. The Suthay-raht are the most common breed of Khajiit outside of Elsweyr.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Children of the Moon</name>
      <text>Bound to the lunar lattice, a mysterious force understood by the Khajiit, the phases of the two moons at the time of their birth determines the form, or 'breed', a Khajiit will assume. All newborns look alike, much smaller than the other races of Tamriel, but the early days of their life begin to give way to their future form. There are rumored to be more than twenty forms of Khajiit, but most common are Alfiq, Cathay, Dagi, Ohmes, Pahmar, Senche, Suthay, and Tojay. The humanoid forms are described in further detail in the subrace section.
	Khajiit differ greatly from all other races, most obviously with their catlike form, tail, fur, and digitigrade stance. Although typical of most humanoid Khajiit, some sub-species, such as the Ohmes, appear more similar to the Bosmer than to their own brothers and sisters. Their physical appearance isn't their only physiological differences. Even the digestive systems and metabolisms are different from most other races, allowing them to have a stronger resilience to substances like moon sugar.
	Bright textiles and shiny objects are desired by Khajiit. They dress in cloth shawls of brilliant colors, known as a budi, which helps defend themselves from the sun. They adorn themselves with sparkling jewelry and trinkets, and are known to wear flowers and herbs in their braided fur. The breeds that do not grow fur typically tattoo themselves with cultural or religious symbols to resemble their cousins.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Holy Moons</name>
      <text>A large part of the Khajiit religion is worship of the two moons of Tamriel. This is an obvious path, given how much the moons affect the lives of every Khajiit. Another significant part of the Khajiit lifestyle is the harvest and ingestion of a powerful and addictive substance called moon-sugar. This substance is known to be crystallized moonlight, which they believe by ingesting, they are absorbing a part of the eternal souls of the moon gods, Jone and Jode.
	When moon-sugar is ingested, it causes fits of ecstasy and abandon. Paired with the highly addictive nature, it is common for Khajiit settlements to be littered with cat-men shivering in the grips of sugar fits.
	Nevertheless, moon-sugar is a daily part of Khajiit life, and serves as their chief export. Their affection for moon-sugar has developed a sweet tooth, and the Khajiit diet is invariably sweet. Candies, cakes, puddings, and sugared meats are staples in Khajiit cuisine. This fare is usually laced with powdered moon-sugar, and the other races would be wise to never accept a sweet roll from a cat.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Social Duality</name>
      <text>The societies of Khajiit are lead by a unique breed of Khajiit known as the Mane, born under the aligned moons. Tradition states that only one mane can be alive at a time and it is believed that each mane is a reincarnation of the previous.
	Khajiit civilizations are divided into two specific cultures. The jungles of Elsweyr are civil and are formed around an agrarian aristocracy, whereas the northern wastes and grasslands tend to be nomadic, pride-centric groups that contest for territory.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Guardians and Charlatans</name>
      <text>Khajiit, who are commonly targeted for racial discrimination, have had to deal with being kidnapped and sold into slavery. This harsh reality has made them take self defense very seriously. The majority of Khajiit use their claws as weapons, and many have formed groups that utilize their natural gifts in various forms of martial arts.
	Other Khajiit welcome the black market with open paws, taking to a life of piracy, smuggling moon-sugar, and the more potent skooma, to the many different lands. Khajiit's natural abilities make them superb thieves and acrobats, as well as fearsome warriors.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Khajiit Names</name>
      <text>Each Khajiit has a single name in their language, Ta'agra, but it is also common for a Khajiit to go by their Tamrielic name, usually given to them by men or mer. These common names are typically descriptive of their personality or quirks.

Male Names:
Akrah, Azbishan, Balag, Dazur, Eilun, Fa'alar, Ghadar, Hilan, Jahirr, Khasar, Lansur, Maniz, Malirzzaka, Nakkhu, Oblan, Pinar, Rakhad, Razur, Sabra, Tabil, Urjen, Vashpar, Yan, Zaban, Zino

Female Names:
Abizah, Azum, Bakkhara, Bindu, Darali, Elamusa, Fedura, Hani, Inama, Kala, Kiasha, Manabi, Mura, Nayya, Pinirai, Samati, Sebazi, Shuzura, Tahara, Tohiba, Urbani, Vaifa, Yana, Zara, Zurka

Tamrielic Names:
Ashenfur, Black-Paw, Clevereyes, Dawnwalker, Dusty-Claw, Elf-Biter, Firebreath, Four-Toes, Iron-Ear, Kink Tail, Silvertongue, Soft-Fur, Sugar-Claws, Tender-Paws, Wet-Whiskers

Khajiit Honorifics:
Khajiit often, but not always, have either a prefix or a suffix, or sometimes both, as part of their name, usually separated by an apostrophe. The titles are typically meant to represent a part of their personality or traits. Some Khajiit believe having both a prefix and a suffix is a sign of arrogance and pride.

Khajiit Honorifics:
d10 | Title | Meaning
1 | Dar | Thief
2 | Do | Warrior
3 | Dra | Wise
4 | Dro | Grandparent
5 | J/Ja/Ji	 | Youth
6 | Jo/Ko | Wizard
7 | La/Lo | Promiscuous
8 | M/Ma | Child or Apprentice
9 | Ra/Ri | Leader
10 | S | Adult</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Khajiit Personality</name>
      <text>A Khajiit might have motivations and quirks much different from an elf or a human with a similar background. You can use the following table to customize your character in addition to the trait, ideal, bond, and flaw from your background.

Khajiit Quirks:
d10 | Quirk
1 | You miss your tropical home and complain endlessly about the freezing weather, even in summer.
2 | You never wear the same outfit twice, unless you absolutely must.
3 | You have a minor phobia of water and hate getting wet.
4 | Your tail always betrays your inner thoughts.
5 | You purr loudly when you are happy.
6 | You keep a small ball of yarn in your hand, which you constantly fidget with.
7 | You are always in debt, since you spend your gold on food and drink made from moon sugar.
8 | When talking about something you're obsessed with, you speak quickly and never pause and others can't understand you.
9 | You are a font of random trivia from the lore and stories you have discovered.
10 | You can't help but pocket interesting objects you come across.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Different Khajiit born under different cycles have significantly different life spans. They can range from 150 to 400 years, if not more.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Khajiit tend toward chaotic alignments, as they let impulse and fancy guide their decisions. They are rarely evil, except for those driven by greed or other dark impulses.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 35 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Eyes of Fear</name>
      <text>You know how to use your cat-like eyes to demoralize others. You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Eyes of Night</name>
      <text>Your khajiit ancestry grants you superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Quick Claws</name>
      <text>Because of your claws, you have a climbing speed of 20 feet. In addition, your claws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal slashing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</text>
      <roll description="Unarmed Bludgeoning Damage">1d4+%1</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Natural Bandit</name>
      <text>You are able to use your claws as thieves' tools. You can add your proficiency modifier to any check using your claws in this way, even if you are not proficient in thieves' tools.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Feline Agility</name>
      <text>Your reflexes and agility allow you to move with a burst of speed. When you move on your turn in combat, you can double your speed until the end of the turn. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you move 0 feet on one of your turns.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Ta'agra. Ta'agra script combines unique and fluid motions. Artistic interpretation is praised and varies greatly between authors.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Nord (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +2, Strength +1</ability>
    <resist>cold</resist>
    <weapons>Battleaxe, Handaxe, Greataxe, Spear</weapons>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Nords are the children of the sky, a race of tall and fair-haired humans from Skyrim who are known for their incredible resistance to cold and magical frost. They are fierce, strong, and enthusiastic warriors. Many become renowned warriors, soldiers, and mercenaries all over Tamriel. Eager to augment their martial skills beyond the traditional methods of Skyrim, they excel in all manner of warfare and are known as militant people by their neighbors. Nords are also natural seamen and have benefited from nautical trade since their first migrations from Atmora. They captain and crew many merchant fleets and may be found all along the coasts of Tamriel.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Strong Wills and Strong Arms</name>
      <text>Nords are the tallest of the human races and have fair skin and fair colored hair. They are known for their powerful physique and modest intellect.
	Nords are fierce competitors and strongly believe in fighting for status and for sport. Favoring brute strength over wit, the Nords are suspicious of mages and don't believe in using social status or wealth to garner favor. It is very common for Nords to have scars and bruises or be seen walking out of a tavern with a bloody nose and a flagon of ale.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Born for Battle</name>
      <text>Fierce warriors and enthusiastic soldiers, Nords can be found throughout Tamriel, offering their talents as mercenaries and sellswords. Proving oneself in battle is a way for any Nord to increase their status. Raised from birth, they are always searching for new ways to increase their martial skills.
	Nords are also talented sailors. They are known to have dominated warring nations with their natural talent at sea and have been vanguards of nautical trade.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Nord Names</name>
      <text>Every Nord has a given name, but only some Nords have clan names. Sometimes, a Nord will be given a title, which can be used before or after their given name. A title is usually a description of a great feat or a personality trait. Such as Heinrich the Ugly or Lyra Wolf-Child.

Male Names:
Arnbjorn, Balbus, Carsten, Daglin, Erik, Fjol, Gunder, Hans, Iver, Jayred, Keld, Larthjar, Manheim, Nels, Olav, Regner, Sten, Torbal, Ulfgar, Valdemar, Wilmuth, Yngvar

Female Names:
Aeta, Bergritte, Dagny, Elda, Fryssa, Greidil, Hilde, Igna, Jala, Katria, Lillith, Margret, Nura, Olga, Ruki, Svenja, Temba, Una, Vori, Ysolda

Clan Names:
Blackthorn, Ebonhand, Firebeard, Hairy-Breeks, Ironhand, Long-Tooth, Ravencrone, Stonearm, Twice-Killed, War-Bear, Windcaller</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Nords, like most men are not particularly long lived, and they mature at a normal rate, and almost never live longer than a century.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Most Nords are hardworking and good-hearted. They take comfort in their traditions and are distrusting of outsiders. They tend toward the good alignments.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Atmoran Ancestry</name>
      <text>Your ancestral history of living in harsh, northern climates has given you resistance to cold damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Battlecry</name>
      <text>As an action, you shout a battle cry that strikes fear into an enemy. Choose one creature that is within 60 feet of you than can see and hear you. That target must succeed on a Willpower saving throw or become frightened of you. The DC of this save is equal to 8 + your Endurance modifier + your proficiency modifier. The frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of it's turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Equipment Proficiency</name>
      <text>You are proficient with Axes and Spears.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Toughness</name>
      <text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
      <modifier category="bonus">hp +1</modifier>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Orsimer (City) (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +1, Wisdom +1, Intelligence +1</ability>
    <resist>force</resist>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <tools>Smith's Tools</tools>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Origins of the Pariah Folk:
Orcs were born during the latter days of the Dawn Era. History has mislabeled them beastfolk, related to the goblin races, but the Orcs are actually the children of Trinimac, strongest of the Aldmeri ancestor spirits. When Trinimac was eaten by the Daedric Prince Boethiah and transformed in that foul god's insides, the Orcs were transformed as well. The ancient name for the 'Orsimer,' which means 'The Pariah Folk.' They now follow Malauch, better known as Malacath, the remains of Trinimac.

Not all Orcs choose to live in the strongholds. Those who choose to live in the cities live a much more cosmopolitan life, but they are derided by other Orcs for doing so.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Strength and Steel</name>
      <text>Orcish armorers are prized for their craftsmanship, and Orc warriors in heavy armor are among the finest front-line troops in the Empire. Most Imperial citizens regard Orc society as rough and cruel, but there is much to admire in their fierce tribal loyalties and generous equality of rank and respect among the sexes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>The Moving City</name>
      <text>Orsinium, which literally translates to "Orc-Town" in Aldmeris, is the city of the Orsimer and the provincial seat of what was called Wrothgar, or in the late Third Era, the Orsinium Area. It has a history of being sacked and rebuilt, as Orcs are often at odds with their neighbors. In the Second Era, it was located in the eastern part of the Wrothgar region of High Rock. In the late Third Era, it was located between Wayrest, Menevia, and the Wrothgarian Mountains, but it was sacked in the early Fourth Era. It reemerged in between Hammerfell and Skyrim later on in the era.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>A Culture of Conflict</name>
      <text>Most people consider their society as rough and cruel, but it's been a lifestyle of necessity. With their cities and strongholds being under constant attack throughout their history, every tribe member is trained at birth for battle and war.
	The strongest of warriors becomes chief of their stronghold. The women are either wives of the chief or his daughters, with the only exception of the shaman, who takes care of spiritual matters. Only the strongest males are allowed to mate to keep the tribe strong.
	The Orcs do not follow the laws of man, but they follow the code of Malacath, which states: Do not steal, do not kill your kin, do not attack without cause. Those who break these rules must pay the Blood Price.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Orsimer Names</name>
      <text>An Orc has a given name and a family name. Orc family names are always prefixed depending on gender. "Gro-" for males and "Gra-" for females. A child will take the fathers name if male, or the mothers name if female. Some orcs take the family name of their stronghold where they are born.

Male Names:
Agronak, Bazur, Bogrum, Dubok, Dul, Gaturn, Ghorub, Gogron, Grommok, Hanz, Krognak, Kurz, Lumdum, Luronk, Magra, Magub, Maknok, Orok, Rugdumph, Shagol, Ulmug, Urbul, Ushnar

Female Names:
Batul, Borba, Bumph, Homraz, Mazoga, Mog, Mor, Oghash, Orag, Rogbut, Rogmesh, Snak, Ugak, Umar, Umog

Family Names:
Agamph, Barak, Buglump, Bura, Cromgog, Dragol, Galash, Gharz, Glurzog, Hubrag, Khash, Murgak, Muzgol, Naybek, Orkul, Orkulg, Rugdush, Shadborgob, Shura, Ugdub, Uzgash, Yarug</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 1, your Wisdom score increases by 1, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>While they are Mer, Orcs do not live as long as their distant cousins. They could live up to 80 years old, but the Code of Malacath demands that an old Orc should end his life before he becomes weak and a burden to his clan. They rarely live longer than 50 years. They reach adulthood at age 16.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>The Orsimer are mostly lawful neutral. Orcs follow a code and are often extremely beholden to their traditions. They are dedicated to the strength of their clan over individuals.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Tool Proficiency </name>
      <text>These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan's tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft. Each type of artisan's tools requires a separate proficiency.

You are proficient with smith tools</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Aggressive </name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Berserk</name>
      <text>As an action, for the next minute, you gain temporary hit points equal to twice your character level. Additionally, you gain advantage on one attack on each of your turns. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Blood-Kin</name>
      <text>You share kindred blood with all of your orc brothers and sisters. Using Honor or Strength, you may be able to avoid conflict with other Orcs.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Orcish Resilience</name>
      <text>Your tough mind and body grants you resistance to force damage.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Orcish. Orcish is a harsh, grating language with hard consonants.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Orsimer (Wild) (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +1, Wisdom +1, Strength +1</ability>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <tools>Smith's Tools</tools>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Origins of the Pariah Folk
Orcs were born during the latter days of the Dawn Era. History has mislabeled them beastfolk, related to the goblin races, but the Orcs are actually the children of Trinimac, strongest of the Aldmeri ancestor spirits. When Trinimac was eaten by the Daedric Prince Boethiah and transformed in that foul god's insides, the Orcs were transformed as well. The ancient name for the 'Orsimer,' which means 'The Pariah Folk.' They now follow Malauch, better known as Malacath, the remains of Trinimac.

Traditional Orc society is centered around living in stronghold settlements. These independent villages follow the Code of Malacath, and the strength of each tribe depends on their strongest warrior.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Strength and Steel</name>
      <text>Orcish armorers are prized for their craftsmanship, and Orc warriors in heavy armor are among the finest front-line troops in the Empire. Most Imperial citizens regard Orc society as rough and cruel, but there is much to admire in their fierce tribal loyalties and generous equality of rank and respect among the sexes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>The Moving City</name>
      <text>Orsinium, which literally translates to "Orc-Town" in Aldmeris, is the city of the Orsimer and the provincial seat of what was called Wrothgar, or in the late Third Era, the Orsinium Area. It has a history of being sacked and rebuilt, as Orcs are often at odds with their neighbors. In the Second Era, it was located in the eastern part of the Wrothgar region of High Rock. In the late Third Era, it was located between Wayrest, Menevia, and the Wrothgarian Mountains, but it was sacked in the early Fourth Era. It reemerged in between Hammerfell and Skyrim later on in the era.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>A Culture of Conflict</name>
      <text>Most people consider their society as rough and cruel, but it's been a lifestyle of necessity. With their cities and strongholds being under constant attack throughout their history, every tribe member is trained at birth for battle and war.
	The strongest of warriors becomes chief of their stronghold. The women are either wives of the chief or his daughters, with the only exception of the shaman, who takes care of spiritual matters. Only the strongest males are allowed to mate to keep the tribe strong.
	The Orcs do not follow the laws of man, but they follow the code of Malacath, which states: Do not steal, do not kill your kin, do not attack without cause. Those who break these rules must pay the Blood Price.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Orsimer Names</name>
      <text>An Orc has a given name and a family name. Orc family names are always prefixed depending on gender. "Gro-" for males and "Gra-" for females. A child will take the fathers name if male, or the mothers name if female. Some orcs take the family name of their stronghold where they are born.

Male Names:
Agronak, Bazur, Bogrum, Dubok, Dul, Gaturn, Ghorub, Gogron, Grommok, Hanz, Krognak, Kurz, Lumdum, Luronk, Magra, Magub, Maknok, Orok, Rugdumph, Shagol, Ulmug, Urbul, Ushnar

Female Names:
Batul, Borba, Bumph, Homraz, Mazoga, Mog, Mor, Oghash, Orag, Rogbut, Rogmesh, Snak, Ugak, Umar, Umog

Family Names:
Agamph, Barak, Buglump, Bura, Cromgog, Dragol, Galash, Gharz, Glurzog, Hubrag, Khash, Murgak, Muzgol, Naybek, Orkul, Orkulg, Rugdush, Shadborgob, Shura, Ugdub, Uzgash, Yarug</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 1, your Wisdom score increases by 1, and your Strength score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>While they are Mer, Orcs do not live as long as their distant cousins. They could live up to 80 years old, but the Code of Malacath demands that an old Orc should end his life before he becomes weak and a burden to his clan. They rarely live longer than 50 years. They reach adulthood at age 16.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>The Orsimer are mostly lawful neutral. Orcs follow a code and are often extremely beholden to their traditions. They are dedicated to the strength of their clan over individuals.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Tool Proficiency </name>
      <text>These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan's tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft. Each type of artisan's tools requires a separate proficiency.

You are proficient with smith tools</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Aggressive </name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Berserk</name>
      <text>As an action, for the next minute, you gain temporary hit points equal to twice your character level. Additionally, you gain advantage on one attack on each of your turns. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Blood-Kin</name>
      <text>You share kindred blood with all of your orc brothers and sisters. Using Honor or Strength, you may be able to avoid conflict with other Orcs.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Powerful Build</name>
      <text>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</text>
      <special>Powerful Build</special>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Orcish. Orcish is a harsh, grating language with hard consonants.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Orsimer (Wood) (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Constitution +1, Wisdom +1, Dexterity +1</ability>
    <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    <tools>Smith's Tools</tools>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Origins of the Pariah Folk
Orcs were born during the latter days of the Dawn Era. History has mislabeled them beastfolk, related to the goblin races, but the Orcs are actually the children of Trinimac, strongest of the Aldmeri ancestor spirits. When Trinimac was eaten by the Daedric Prince Boethiah and transformed in that foul god's insides, the Orcs were transformed as well. The ancient name for the 'Orsimer,' which means 'The Pariah Folk.' They now follow Malauch, better known as Malacath, the remains of Trinimac.

Valenwood is typically home to the Bosmer, but many tribes of Orcs have made this forested province their home. Like other Orcs, they prize strength and honor, but to the Wood Orcs this means having agility and mobility as much as it does muscular power and endurance.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Strength and Steel</name>
      <text>Orcish armorers are prized for their craftsmanship, and Orc warriors in heavy armor are among the finest front-line troops in the Empire. Most Imperial citizens regard Orc society as rough and cruel, but there is much to admire in their fierce tribal loyalties and generous equality of rank and respect among the sexes.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>The Moving City</name>
      <text>Orsinium, which literally translates to "Orc-Town" in Aldmeris, is the city of the Orsimer and the provincial seat of what was called Wrothgar, or in the late Third Era, the Orsinium Area. It has a history of being sacked and rebuilt, as Orcs are often at odds with their neighbors. In the Second Era, it was located in the eastern part of the Wrothgar region of High Rock. In the late Third Era, it was located between Wayrest, Menevia, and the Wrothgarian Mountains, but it was sacked in the early Fourth Era. It reemerged in between Hammerfell and Skyrim later on in the era.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>A Culture of Conflict</name>
      <text>Most people consider their society as rough and cruel, but it's been a lifestyle of necessity. With their cities and strongholds being under constant attack throughout their history, every tribe member is trained at birth for battle and war.
	The strongest of warriors becomes chief of their stronghold. The women are either wives of the chief or his daughters, with the only exception of the shaman, who takes care of spiritual matters. Only the strongest males are allowed to mate to keep the tribe strong.
	The Orcs do not follow the laws of man, but they follow the code of Malacath, which states: Do not steal, do not kill your kin, do not attack without cause. Those who break these rules must pay the Blood Price.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Orsimer Names</name>
      <text>An Orc has a given name and a family name. Orc family names are always prefixed depending on gender. "Gro-" for males and "Gra-" for females. A child will take the fathers name if male, or the mothers name if female. Some orcs take the family name of their stronghold where they are born.

Male Names:
Agronak, Bazur, Bogrum, Dubok, Dul, Gaturn, Ghorub, Gogron, Grommok, Hanz, Krognak, Kurz, Lumdum, Luronk, Magra, Magub, Maknok, Orok, Rugdumph, Shagol, Ulmug, Urbul, Ushnar

Female Names:
Batul, Borba, Bumph, Homraz, Mazoga, Mog, Mor, Oghash, Orag, Rogbut, Rogmesh, Snak, Ugak, Umar, Umog

Family Names:
Agamph, Barak, Buglump, Bura, Cromgog, Dragol, Galash, Gharz, Glurzog, Hubrag, Khash, Murgak, Muzgol, Naybek, Orkul, Orkulg, Rugdush, Shadborgob, Shura, Ugdub, Uzgash, Yarug</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Constitution score increases by 1, your Wisdom score increases by 1, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>While they are Mer, Orcs do not live as long as their distant cousins. They could live up to 80 years old, but the Code of Malacath demands that an old Orc should end his life before he becomes weak and a burden to his clan. They rarely live longer than 50 years. They reach adulthood at age 16.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>The Orsimer are mostly lawful neutral. Orcs follow a code and are often extremely beholden to their traditions. They are dedicated to the strength of their clan over individuals.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Tool Proficiency </name>
      <text>These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan's tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft. Each type of artisan's tools requires a separate proficiency.

You are proficient with smith tools</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Aggressive </name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Berserk</name>
      <text>As an action, for the next minute, you gain temporary hit points equal to twice your character level. Additionally, you gain advantage on one attack on each of your turns. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Blood-Kin</name>
      <text>You share kindred blood with all of your orc brothers and sisters. Using Honor or Strength, you may be able to avoid conflict with other Orcs.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Menacing</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="subspecies">
      <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
      <text>You have advantage on Willpower (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Orcish. Orcish is a harsh, grating language with hard consonants.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
  <race>
    <name>Redguard (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <ability>Strength +1, Dexterity +1, Constitution +1</ability>
    <resist>disease</resist>
    <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
    <weapons>Longsword, Shortsword</weapons>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Redguards are the most naturally talented warriors in Tamriel. The dark-skinned, wiry-haired men of Hammerfell seem born to battle, though their pride and fierce independence of spirit makes them more suitable as scouts or skirmishers, or as free-ranging heroes and adventurers, than as rank-and-file soldiers. In addition to their cultural affinities for many armor styles and weapons (particularly swords), Redguards are also physically blessed with hardy constitutions, resistance to poison, and quickness of foot. Redguards do not share the same blood as the other human races, and they have no known connection with the ancestral Nordic homeland of Atmora.
	The Redguard's innate agility and prolific level of endurance allows them to excel in any activity that demands sustained effort, most notably combat. They are likewise blessed with a very hardy constitution that allows them to resist poison and disease.
	The Redguards skin tone can range from light brown to nearly black and their hair texture ranges from thick and wavy to tightly curled and wiry. Redguards are also largely average in height, well muscled and sturdy, much like the Nords and the Orcs.

Source:	The Elder Scrolls: Delvebound (Homebrew)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Paragons of War</name>
      <text>The most naturally talented warriors in Tamriel, the dark-skinned, wiry-haired Redguards of Hammerfell seem born to battle, though their pride and fierce independence of spirit makes them more suitable as scouts or skirmishers, or as free-ranging heroes and adventurers, than as rank-and-file soldiers. In addition to their cultural affinities for many weapon and armor styles, Redguards are also physically blessed with hardy constitutions and quickness of foot.
	Custom and dress differ by district; the Redguards of Elinhir are Colovian in fashion and taste, while some in Rihad go naked in the streets. In demeanor, they are haughty and easily provoked, and, obsessed with personal honor.
	There is no standing army in Hammerfell, only paid militias of the oft-contested border-states and along its coastline. Ancient tradition has predisposed the Redguards to knightly order, though, customarily in the service of royal families. Initiates of these orders must prove themselves in dangerous, even deadly, tests of skill.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Lost Continent</name>
      <text>More than three thousand years ago, the continent of Yokuda suffered a cataclysm that sunk most of it into the sea, driving its people towards Tamriel. A large group of the Yokudans, called the Ra Gada, forged forward in a bloody wave, quickly slaughtering the beastfolk and Nedic villagers, paving safe travel for the Yokudans that stayed behind. The fierce Ra Gada became, phonetically, the Redguards, a name that has since spread to designate the Tamrielic-Yokudan race in general.
	They ultimately displaced the Nedic peoples, as their agriculture and society quickly adapted to Hammerfell's harsh environment. They took much from Nedic customs, religion, and language for themselves and their contact with the surrounding Bretons and Colovians hastened their assimilationinto Tamrielic culture.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Redguard Names</name>
      <text>Redguards have only their given name. Through marriage, they sometimes will take the family name.

Male Names:
Amir, Azzada, Baurus, Cyrus, Daron, Ennis, Falion, Garry, Hillod, Ian, Jawana, Kayd, Lesley, Nazir, Neville, Pyke, Roderick, Shamar, Talib, Wayn

Female Names:
Anora, Braith, Caminda, Dahlia, Eriana, Gwen, Hussonia, Iman, Jamie, Kerah, Kiara, Lette, Minerva, Niyya, Oleta, Rona, Shelley, Tavia, Umana, Zaria</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Ability Score Increase</name>
      <text>Your Strength score increases by 1, your Dexterity score increases by 1, and your Constitution score increases by 1.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Redguards age as the rest of the the human races, rarely living over a century.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment </name>
      <text>Redguards mostly follow the good alignments. Many of the people of Hammerfell strictly follow their laws, while nearly an equal amount disregard them entirely.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Adrenaline Rush</name>
      <text>When you use this trait, your combat awareness increases for the next minute. You gain a +10 bonus to your initiative, your speed is increased by 10 feet, and you can add a d4 to all of your attack and damage rolls. Additionally, at the start of combat, when you roll initiative, you can use your reaction to immediately use this trait. You can't use this trait again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Redguard Combat Training</name>
      <text>You are proficient in Long Blade and Short Blade.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Skill Proficiency</name>
      <text>You gain proficiency in the Athletics skill.</text>
      <proficiency>Athletics</proficiency>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Yokudan Lineage</name>
      <text>Thanks to your Yokudan heritage, you have advantage on saving throws against being diseased.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages </name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Tamrielic and Yoku. Yoku is a direct language that is incredibly reliant on context. Similar to Redguards themselves, their language is straightforward and doesn't concern itself with unnecessary things.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
