<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Monk [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Monk Subclass: Warrior of Venom (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Monk Subclass: Warrior of Venom (UA)</name>
        <text>Channel the Cauldron of Your Own Toxicity

Warriors of Venom pollute their internal reservoirs of power to become poison incarnate. Through years of focus and the study of poison in all its forms, these Monks learn to harness their own toxicity to impair and envenom foes. Contact with a Warrior of Venom-even the slightest touch or a single drop of blood—can be as deadly as a viper's bite.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Envenom Weapon (Warrior of Venom (UA))</name>
        <text>At the start of your turn, you can expend 1 Focus Point to apply a toxin produced from your blood to one Monk weapon that you're holding. A creature that takes damage from the weapon is subjected to one of the following toxin effects (choose when you apply the toxin):

	Slowing Toxin. Until the start of your next turn, the target's Speed is halved; it can't take Reactions; and it can take either an action or a Bonus Action on its turn, not both.

	Venom. The target takes Poison damage equal to two rolls of your Martial Arts die.

The toxin retains potency for 1 minute or until a creature takes damage from the weapon.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Potent Arsenal (Warrior of Venom (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain a Poisoner's Kit, and you have proficiency with it. When creating a Basic Poison, you can do so over the course of 1 day (8 hours of work). Additionally, whenever you deal Poison damage with a Monk feature or a Monk weapon, you can change that damage type to Acid.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Toxic Touch (Warrior of Venom (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Magic action, you can expend 1 Focus Point to apply a potent toxin to a creature you touch. The target makes a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target has the Poisoned condition for 1 minute.
	While Poisoned, the target is affected by one of the following effects of your choice:

	Intoxicant. The target has the Charmed condition for the duration or until you or your allies deal damage to the target.

	Sedative. The creature falls asleep and has the Unconscious condition for the duration. Another creature can use an action to shake it awake and remove the condition.

	Truth Serum. The target can't knowingly communicate a lie for the duration.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Toxin Refiner (Warrior of Venom (UA))</name>
        <text>Your body can filter poison. You gain Immunity to Poison damage. Whenever you are subjected to Poison damage, your Envenom Weapon options each deal extra Poison damage equal to one roll of your Martial Arts die, and you can't gain this benefit again until the end of your next turn. In addition, whenever you ingest a poison, you regain a number of Hit Points equal to one roll of your Martial Arts die.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 11: Toxic Blood (Warrior of Venom (UA))</name>
        <text>Enemies draw your toxic blood at their own peril. Whenever a creature hits you with a melee attack roll, the attacker takes 1d6 Poison damage. If you are Bloodied, the attacker instead takes Poison damage equal to one roll of your Martial Arts die.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Poison Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 17: Hallucinogenic Breath (Warrior of Venom (UA))</name>
        <text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can expend 2 Focus Points and replace one of your attacks with an exhalation of hallucinogenic vapors at one creature you can see within 30 feet. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes Poison damage equal to three rolls of your Martial Arts die and has the Frightened condition for 1 minute or until the target takes damage. While Frightened, the target takes the Dash action and moves away from you by the safest route on each of its turns unless there is nowhere to move. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage only.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
