<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Warlock [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Warlock Subclass: Primordial Patron (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Warlock Subclass: Primordial Patron (UA)</name>
        <text>Invoke Scions of Elemental Chaos

Your pact draws on the Inner Planes, the realms of elemental forces and the building blocks of the multiverse. Warlocks of this pact act as heralds of ancient and destructive scions of air, earth, fire, and water-such as the Elemental Evils. These Warlocks prepare the way for their patrons' eventual arrival on the Material Plane by creating elemental nodes, areas suffused with energy from the Elemental Planes.
	When you choose this subclass, choose an element from the Primordial Patrons table, which suggests potential patrons and determines the damage type for certain subclass features.

Primordial Patrons:
Element |  Example Patrons | Damage Type
Air | Akadi, Yan-C-Bin | Thunder
Earth | Ogrémoch, Grumbar | Acid
Fire | Imix, Kossuth, Zaaman Rul | Fire
Water | Istishia, Olhydra | Cold

The capricious nature of elemental alliances extends to your pact. You can change your chosen element—and your patron—whenever you gain a level.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 4 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Elemental Node (Primordial Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Magic action, you can create a 5-foot-radius Sphere of elemental magic centered on a point you can see within 60 feet of yourself. The magic of this elemental node resembles your chosen element. On later turns, you can take a Bonus Action to move the node up to 30 feet.
	When the node appears, each creature other than you in the node makes a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 1d6 damage of your chosen element's type on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature also makes this save when the node moves into its space and when it enters the node or ends its turn there. A creature makes this save only once per turn.
	The node lasts for 1 minute, until you dismiss it (no action required), or until you use this feature to create another node. Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you complete a Short or Long Rest unless you expend a Pact Magic spell slot (no action required) to restore your use of it.
	The node's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach Warlock levels 6 (2d6) and 14 (3d6).

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 4 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Elemental Damage" level="3">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="Elemental Damage" level="6">2d6</roll>
        <roll description="Elemental Damage" level="14">3d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Elemental Spells (Primordial Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>The magic of your patron ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Warlock level specified in the Elemental Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed primordial spells prepared, along with the spells corresponding to your chosen element.

Elemental Spells:
Warlock Level | Primordial Spells | Air Spells | Earth Spells | Fire Spells | Water Spells
3 | Chromatic Orb, Darkvision | Feather Fall, Shatter | Entangle, Knock | Burning Hands, Heat Metal | Alter Self, Ice Knife
5 | Elemental Weapon | Fly | Plant Growth | Fireball | Water Walk
7 | Summon Elemental (the spirit's element matches your chosen element) | Freedom of Movement | Vitriolic Sphere | Wall of Fire | Control Water
9 | Commune with Nature | Steel Wind Strike | Wall of Stone | Flame Strike | Cone of Cold

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 4 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Elemental Haven (Primordial Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Elemental Node shields you from harm. You gain the following benefits.

	Elemental Protection. While you're within your node, you have a bonus to AC equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1).

	Elemental Teleport. As a Bonus Action, you can teleport into your node or the nearest unoccupied space within 5 feet of it. You can use this benefit a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 4 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Primeval Protection (Primordial Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the following benefits.

	Elemental Fortitude. You have Resistance to your chosen element's damage type. Additionally, while within your Elemental Node, you have Immunity to that damage type.

	Node Improvement. Your Elemental Node is now a 10-foot-radius Sphere.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 5 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Elemental Harbinger (Primordial Patron (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Elemental Node can usher in the mightiest of elementals, granting you the following benefits.

	Elemental Vortex. Whenever you expend a Pact Magic spell slot while you're within your Elemental Node, you can attempt to pull a creature into the node. One creature you choose within 30 feet of the node must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pulled up to 15 feet toward the node's center.

	Node Improvement. Your Elemental Node now lasts for up to 1 hour.

	Primordial Herald. While you're within your node's area, you can cast the Planar Ally spell without expending a spell slot. When you cast the spell in this way, you speak the name of your patron.

Once you use this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish 2d4 Long Rests.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 5 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Long Rests">2d4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Chromatic Orb [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Darkvision [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Feather Fall [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shatter [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Entangle [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Knock [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Burning Hands [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Heat Metal [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Alter Self [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ice Knife [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Elemental Weapon [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fly [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Plant Growth [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fireball [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Water Walk [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Summon Elemental [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Freedom of Movement [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Vitriolic Sphere [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Fire [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Control Water [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Commune with Nature [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Steel Wind Strike [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Wall of Stone [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Flame Strike [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cone of Cold [5.5e]</name>
    <classes>Warlock [5.5e] (Primordial Patron (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Elemental Overflow (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: Level 5+ Warlock

Choose a damage type: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Thunder. Whenever you cast a spell that deals the chosen damage type, you can cause elemental energy to wreathe you until the end of your next turn. For the duration, whenever a creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack roll, that creature takes 1d4 damage of the chosen damage type.

	Repeatable. You can gain this invocation more than once. Each time you do so, choose a different damage type.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 5 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <roll description="Elemental Damage">1d4</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Invocation: Elemental Transmutation (UA) [5.5e]</name>
    <level>0</level>
    <classes>Eldritch Invocations [5.5e]</classes>
    <text>Prerequisite: Level 2+ Warlock

Choose a damage type: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Thunder. Once per turn, whenever you deal damage of any of the above types, you can deal the chosen damage type instead.

Source:	Villainous Options 2 p. 5 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
    <roll description="Elemental Damage">1d4</roll>
  </spell>
</compendium>
