<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Almsgiver</name> 
    <proficiency>Insight, Religion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Almsgivers, as one would expect, come in many different flavors; yet they all find themselves dedicating their lives to philanthropic ventures or making charitable donations to the needy through their talents, money or time - wherever they are found. Some almsgivers study to eventually become healers or priests, others join or use their families wealth to fund organizations which are able to cross borders. There is also a rare sub-class of these dedicated humanitarians who take up arms against those who ashamedly take advantage of the poor. It is a natural step up from charity worker to adventurer, as the poor, the needy and the hungry are never far from sight.</text> 
      <text>    Why did you take the life of an almsgiver and charity worker? Did you come from a religious background? Were you once rich yourself? Did your compassion for all creatures offer you no alternative, but to become part of an altruist organization which could reach across the borders of neighboring communities and kingdoms? Discuss with your DM to determine the reason for your charity work, or you can roll on the table below to determine how your altruism manifested itself.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>• Skill Proficiencies: Insight, Religion</text>
      <text>• Tool Proficiencies: Herbalism Kit</text>
      <text>• Equipment: Herbalism Kit, winter blanket, a notebook full of herbal remedies and favorite prayers, cooking pots, set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 5gp.</text>
      <text>Source: Monsters Without Borders v1.2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Feed the Many</name>
      <text>When you cook a meal, you may use herbs, meat off-cuts and other daily gathered ingredients to increase the number of portions of food you can prepare to double. Thus you are able to provide sustenance for twice the number of people as you have cooked food portions for.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Almsgivers are naturally empathic towards those in need. They feel the pain of others intimately, so much so that they can go to great lengths to alleviate it. They very often have a gathering of like-minded comrades or cohorts who they readily turn to for help. They are also very well respected, or even loved in certain towns, groups or factions. In their never-ending desire to unburden the suffering of others, not every almsgiver remains on the side of the law though; using their knowledge, connections and friends to help steal from the most fortunate in society, to give to the poor. However, one thing is for certain, almsgivers have a higher sense of purpose than most, with many of them finding solace in religion.</text>
      <text>d8 | Personality Trait</text>
      <text>1 | I feel tremendous empathy for all who suffer.</text>
      <text>2 | My mind is always ticking over, with grand plans and new ways to help others.</text>
      <text>3 | I seek no rewards for what I do and would rather remain an unknown benefactor.</text>
      <text>4 | I treat people the way I’d like to be treated myself.</text>
      <text>5 | I feel more comfortable amongst common-folk and speak their language well.</text>
      <text>6 | I get a sense of power/accomplishment by giving to those people who are needier than I.</text>
      <text>7 | I feel queasy around too much blood and gore.</text>
      <text>8 | I have a particular affinity for animals who need my charity.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>d6 | Ideal</text>
      <text>1 | Faith. I believe that a power greater than all of us works through my actions. (Lawful)</text>
      <text>2 | People. I like seeing the look of appreciation in the eyes of the people who I help. (Neutral)</text>
      <text>3 | Compassion. There are many who are less fortunate than us, and I wish to bring happiness to them all. (Good)</text>
      <text>4 | Community. Strengthening the bonds between communities is our greatest responsibility as a civilized race. (Lawful)</text>
      <text>5 | Restitution. Sometimes we must turn to slightly less savory methods as recompense for others injury or loss. (Chaotic)</text>
      <text>6 | Fairness. Everybody deserves a little charity every now and again. (Good)</text>
      <text/>
      <text>d6 | Bond</text>
      <text>1 | I am strong enough physically, emotionally and spiritually to provide aid for others. It is my duty and responsibility to help those in need.</text>
      <text>2 | My war-torn home village/town taught me to stand up for what I believe in and treat those in pain with kindness and respect.</text>
      <text>3 | I am forever searching for salvation/happiness/ spiritual enlightenment after a great sadness tore my life asunder.</text>
      <text>4 | If it wasn’t for the orphanage/temple I grew up in, I would have never been able to help so many people. I owe them everything.</text>
      <text>5 | I lost my family to famine. None shall go hungry if I can ever help it.</text>
      <text>6 | I must use my connections and talents to make a name for myself, so I can help others more.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>d6 | Flaw</text>
      <text>1 | I feel guilty that I came from a wealthy community.</text>
      <text>2 | Due to constantly working with the poor, I have developed a dependency on a particular drug.</text>
      <text>3 | I find it very uncomfortable to be around children or young adults.</text>
      <text>4 | I have a homeless brother/sister who is in need of constant support.</text>
      <text>5 | I had an affair with another almsgiver, who now hates me.</text>
      <text>6 | I am told a great many secrets… but never seem to keep them for long.</text>
    </trait>
  </background> <!-- Almsgiver -->
  <background>
    <name>Healer</name> 
    <proficiency>Medicine, Investigation</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You work to heal people of all types of ailments, from plagues to broken bones, to sprains and stab wounds. You studied the arts of healing from books or from watching others, and you have done much practical work. Many are better off for the remedies you have administered.</text> 
      <text>    You may have worked as part of an organization, devising medicines as a group, or as an individual, healing who you saw fit.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>• Skill Proficiencies: Medicine, Investigation</text>
      <text>• Tool Proficiencies: Herbalism kit, weaver’s tools</text>
      <text>• Equipment: Herbalism kit, a healer’s kit, a small knife, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15gp.</text>
      <text>Source: Monsters Without Borders v1.2</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty</name>
      <text>Though healers help many people, all have one service that they perform in particular or one group of people that they work with most often. An event such as a plague, natural disaster, or war could also influence what services you performed most regularly. Choose the service you most commonly administered, or roll on the table below (d8):</text>
      <text>1. Animal Attacks</text>
      <text>2. Battle Wounds</text>
      <text>3. Broken Bones</text>
      <text>4. Common Illnesses</text>
      <text>5. General Aches</text>
      <text>6. Infected Wounds</text>
      <text>7. Infectious Diseases</text>
      <text>8. Midwifery</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Medical Experience</name>
      <text>You can identify wounds, illnesses, infections and other ailments with inspection and know how to fix them. In addition, you know the properties of many herbs and where you can acquire them.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>A healer is efficient and caring, able to set their mind to a task and to act with empathy. They are well-used to death, yet feel obliged to prevent it. Their care for others is a key aspect of their personalities, though it can often be a downfall.</text>
      <text>d8 | Personality Trait</text>
      <text>1 | I will always help those in need.</text>
      <text>2 | I treat everyone with kindness.</text>
      <text>3 | I always refuse coin for my services, preferring a meal, board or common supplies.</text>
      <text>4 | I ask a lot of questions to everyone I encounter to ensure they are healthy.</text>
      <text>5 | I refuse to touch anyone or go into dirty places.</text>
      <text>6 | I swear by a particular remedy and encourage its use in every situation.</text>
      <text>7 | I am incredibly sympathetic to those who have lost loved ones.</text>
      <text>8 | I always wear something that identifies myself as a healer, allowing me to be sought out by those who need help.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>d6 | Ideal</text>
      <text>1 | Charity. We all have a role to play in the welfare of others. (Good)</text>
      <text>2 | Vitality. I will do whatever it takes to gain eternal life. (Neutral)</text>
      <text>3 | Discovery. We have the power to uncover new truths about our physical bodies. We just have to explore. (Any)</text>
      <text>4 | Power. If I understand what keeps us alive, I will gain the truest mastery over death and pain. (Evil)</text>
      <text>5 | Procedure. There is a way in which things must be done, and we all must heed it. (Lawful)</text>
      <text>6 | Decision. Some people deserve saving. Others don’t. We all deserve the ability to choose. (Chaotic)</text>
      <text/>
      <text>d6 | Bond</text>
      <text>1 | I will always help the sick and injured.</text>
      <text>2 | I feel guilty over someone's death. Their family is my responsibility.</text>
      <text>3 | I am working on a series of tomes detailing commons illnesses and how to heal them.</text>
      <text>4 | A loved one is afflicted with a rare illness. I will find a cure.</text>
      <text>5 | I will never forget a loved one who died of an illness, and I frequently visit their grave.</text>
      <text>6 | No one living in my place of birth will die of a disease I can cure.</text>
      <text/>
      <text>d6 | Flaw</text>
      <text>1 | I feel terribly guilty whenever someone else is in pain.</text>
      <text>2 | If I help others, I might fail. I suppose I can't help them, then.</text>
      <text>3 | have a weakness for the feeble, and try to help them even when it is undeserved.</text>
      <text>4 | I am very hard on myself and become desolate when I fail.</text>
      <text>5 | I love to cause injury as much as I love healing it.</text>
      <text>6 | I am terribly frightened of death.</text>
    </trait>
  </background> <!-- Healer -->
</compendium>
