<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Paladin</name>
    <!-- Sacred Oath: Oath of the Grave (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sacred Oath: Oath of the Grave (HB)</name>
        <text>The Oath of the Grave is a seldom practised tradition, most commonly reserved for the followers of the Raven Queen. Sometimes called winter knights, black knights, or grave knights, these paladins serve as protectors of the sacred passings into the afterlife. They constantly struggle against the forces of undeath, as they see them as the most unholy abominations that blight this land. They adorn themselves with images of death and winter — skulls, ravens, or similar symbols of their patron gods.

Tenets of the Grave:
The tenets of the Oath of the grave have been passed down for generations. This oath emphasizes the passing between the warmth of life to the everlasting cold of death, and punishes those that defile this passing with the unholy raising of undead.

Annihilate the Unholy. The undead and those who foster them are unholy and wicked. Destroy them before they defile more than they have already Preserve the Righteous. Death should not come early to those who have led a blessed life. Preserve the righteous, so they may live on without fear.

Let Souls Pass On. Every soul deserves its place in the afterlife. When you see a creature forced into undeath, let its soul go free.

Accept Death. Death comes to all eventually. Accept it, and you will find a place in the afterlife.

Oath Spells:
You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed in the Oath of the Grave Spells table. See the Sacred Oath class feature for how oath spells work.

Oath of the Grave Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3rd | inflict wounds, ice knife
5th | gentle repose, Snilloc's snowball swarm
9th | sleet storm, speak with dead
13th | blight, ice storm
17th | cone of cold, destructive wave

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Channel Divinity: Icy Repose (Oath of the Grave (HB))</name>
        <text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer against undeath, using your Channel Divinity. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it takes cold damage equal to your paladin level, and is frozen for 1 minute or until it takes damage again.
	A frozen creature is affected by the petrified condition until the frozen effect ends, at which point the creature is freed and able to act normally.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Channel Divinity: Restbringer (Oath of the Grave (HB))</name>
        <text>As action, you can imbue one weapon that you are holding with necrotic energy, using your Channel Divinity. For 1 minute, you add 1 + your Charisma modifier necrotic damage (minimum 1) to your damage rolls made with that weapon. Additionally, hitting a target with the weapon marks them until the end of your next turn. A marked target can't regain hit points, and if it dies while marked, it can't become undead.
	You can end this effect on your turn as part of any other action. If you are no longer holding or carrying this weapon, or if you fall unconscious, this effect ends.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Aura of Preservation (Oath of the Grave (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 7th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you have resistance to necrotic damage, and cannot be charmed, frightened, or possessed by undead creatures.
	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Soul of Demise (Oath of the Grave (HB))</name>
        <text>By 15th level, your restbringer feature has become far more powerful. The duration of restbringer increases to 10 minutes, and any creature marked by the feature has their speed reduced by 10 feet. Additionally, if a marked creature dies, that creature can't be raised from the dead for the next 30 days, outside of using a wish spell.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Reaper of Winter (Oath of the Grave (HB))</name>
        <text>At 20th level, as an action, you can surround yourself with a deathly chill. For 1 minute, swirls of chilling wind surround you in a 30 foot radius.
	Whenever an enemy creature starts its turn in the area, the creature takes 10 cold damage and their movement speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of their next turn.
	In addition, whenever a creature dies within the area, you gain 20 temporary hit points.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 15 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Reaper of Winter</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Oath of the Grave (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Inflict Wounds</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ice Knife</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Gentle Repose</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Snilloc's Snowball Swarm</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sleet Storm</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Speak with Dead</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blight</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Ice Storm</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cone of Cold</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Destructive Wave</name>
    <classes>Paladin (Oath of the Grave (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
