<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Sorcerer</name>
    <!-- Sorcerous Origin: Deathtouched (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerous Origin: Deathtouched (HB)</name>
        <text>Your innate magic comes from a past encounter with death. Most often, this origin is traced back to surviving an attack from an undead, such as a vampire's bite, a ghost's possession, or a specter's life drain. Or, it could have originated from an imperfect revival or near-death experience. Regardless of the way you attained this dark magic, it now dictates your life and greatly augments your power.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Ghostly Body (Deathtouched (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting when you choose this origin at 1st level, your body becomes imbued with dark power. Your hit point maximum is increased by 1, and increases by 1 again whenever you gain a level in this class.
	Additionally, this power allows your body to slowly fade into invisibility. If you remain still for 1 minute while in dim light or darkness, you become invisible until you move, enter bright light, or use an action, bonus action, or reaction.
	When you reach 3rd level in this class, you can use your bonus action and spend 1 sorcery point to activate this feature without waiting a minute, causing you to immediately become invisible.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Memories of the Fallen (Deathtouched (HB))</name>
        <text>Also at 1st level, you gain the ability to access the memories of the deceased. By performing a 1 minute ritual on a corpse, you can gain insight into how that creature died. If you already witnessed that creature's death, you instead gain another random memory from that creature, as determined by your DM. This feature can only be used once per corpse.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Necrotic Affinity (Deathtouched (HB))</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you learn two Necromancy spells from any class. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you may choose one of these Necromancy spells and replace it with another Necromancy spell from any class. The chosen spells count as sorcerer spells for you but don't count against the number of sorcerer spells you know.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Incorporeal Figure (Deathtouched (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, you have the ability to become temporarily incorporeal. As a bonus action on your turn, you can spend 2 sorcery points to become incorporeal, gaining the ability to move through objects as if the objects were difficult terrain, and you become immune to the grappled and restrained conditions. For the duration, your movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks, and your speed is increased by 15 feet.
	The incorporeal effect ends at the end of your next turn. If you are inside an object when the effect ends, you are ejected to the nearest empty space and take 1d10 force damage.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Force Damage">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Possession (Deathtouched (HB))</name>
        <text>At 18th level, you gain the ability to take control of another creature's body. As an action, you can spend 5 sorcery points to attempt to possess a creature of size Large or smaller within 5 feet of you. That creature must succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC or be possessed for up to 1 hour. On a success, you then disappear, and the target is incapacitated and loses control of its body. While possessing a creature, you can't be targeted by any attack, spell, or other effect, and you retain your alignment, Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma. You otherwise use the possessed target's statistics, but don't gain access to the target's knowledge, class features, or proficiencies.
	At the start of each of your turns, if the possessed creature has been damaged at least once since the end of your last turn it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on a success. You may also end the effect using your bonus action. A target is immune to Possession for 24 hours after succeeding on the saving throw

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 18 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Sorcerous Origin: Vampiric Bloodline (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sorcerous Origin: Vampiric Bloodline (HB)</name>
        <text>Your innate magic stems from the mingling of your bloodline with the blood of a vampire. Some sorcerers with this origin can trace their powers back to an ancient bargain with a powerful vampire. When a vampire takes particular interest in a mortal being, they may allow that humanoid to have a taste of their blood, granting them a semblance of power. This ritual is seldom practiced, and few vampires would even dare to try it. But this is not the only way to gain this origin, as many of these sorcerers can trace their powers to a near-death experience with a vampire. Whatever the case, vampiric magic permeates your blood, and your very being.
	Vampiric sorcerers most often try to hide their ancestry, since their origins can make them as reviled as the vampires that spawned them. However, a select few embrace their vampiric ancestry, and may even seek to become true vampires in death.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Denizen of the Night (Vampiric Bloodline (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting when you choose this origin at 1st level, you gain Darkvision out to a range of 30 feet, as described in chapter 8 of the Player's Handbook.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Martial Prowess (Vampiric Bloodline (HB))</name>
        <text>Also at 1st level, your vampiric ancestry grants you increased effectiveness in melee combat. You gain proficiency in light and medium armor. Also, as long as you aren't wielding a shield, you can fight with vampiric claws. Your claws are unarmed strikes that deal slashing damage, use a d6 as their damage die, and use your Charisma instead of Strength for their attack and damage rolls.
	The damage die of this attack increases when you reach certain levels in this class. Its damage die becomes a d8 at 6th level, and a d10 at 14th level. Additionally, starting at 6th level these attacks count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to non-magical attacks and damage.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Unarmed Slashing Damage" level="1">1d6</roll>
        <roll description="Unarmed Slashing Damage" level="6">1d8</roll>
        <roll description="Unarmed Slashing Damage" level="14">1d10</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Vampiric Regeneration (Vampiric Bloodline (HB))</name>
        <text>At 6th level, you gain a semblance of the regenerative abilities of a vampire. At the start of each of your turns, you gain a number of temporary hit points equal to a third of your sorcerer level if you aren't in sunlight or running water.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Deadly Bite (Vampiric Bloodline (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn and attack with your claws, you can make a second attack with your bite as part of the same action. Your bite deals the same damage as your claws, except its damage type is piercing. If you hit a creature with your bite, you can spend 1 sorcery point to regain 1 + your Charisma modifier hit points (minimum 1). If you have the extra attack feature, these features don't add together.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Shapechanger (Vampiric Bloodline (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 14th level, you can use your bonus action to polymorph into a Tiny bat or back into your true form.
	While in bat form, you can't speak, attack, or cast spells, your walking speed is 5 feet, and you have a flying speed of 30 feet. Your statistics, other than your size and speed, are unchanged. Anything you are wearing or carrying transforms with you.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Unholy Thrall (Vampiric Bloodline (HB))</name>
        <text>At 18th level, you gain the ability to raise a dead humanoid as your vampiric thrall. If a humanoid that has been hit with your bite within the past 10 minutes dies, you can bury the creature in the ground and spend 5 sorcery points to begin an arcane ritual. After 1 hour, the creature rises as a vampire spawn under your control (see page 298 of the Monster Manual).
	At the end of each long rest, after you regain your sorcery points, you can immediately spend 5 sorcery points to reestablish your control over the spawn. If you choose not to, the spawn dies. Raising a new spawn also causes the previous spawn to die.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 19 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
