<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Cleric</name>
    <!-- Divine Domain: Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain: Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB)</name>
        <text>The gods of blood are patrons of all varieties of slaughter—including war, battle, murder, and even hunting and accept any shedding of blood as an offering to their domain. They are the patrons of warriors, particularly those of a more chaotic disposition. While many clerics that follow a blood deity resemble deranged, blood-thirsty cultists, others are comparable to the followers of particularly violent war deities. Examples of the deities of this domain are Bhaal, the Lord of Murder, and Shezmu, the Lord of Blood

Blood Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
1st | bloodburn†, cruorwhip†
3rd | blood seal†, sanguine rope†
5th | blood sight†, tides of blood†
7th | draining thread†, sanguine sanctum†
9th | bloodcurse†, dominate person

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Cantrip (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain the bloodletting cantrip if you don't already know it.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wrath of the Blood God (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Also at 1st level, you can cause the blood of your enemies to lash out at surrounding creatures, draining the life from them. When a hostile creature you can see within 30 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points or subjected to a critical hit, you can use your reaction to unleash a burst of necrotic energy from its wounds. Constructs, elementals, and undead are invalid targets. Each creature of your choice within 10 feet of the target, which can include the target, must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d4 necrotic damage on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">2d4</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Wrath of the Blood God</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Channel Divinity: Drain Spirits (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to sap the life of nearby creatures, using their vitality to heal a portion of your wounds.
	As an action, you present your holy symbol, and each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes necrotic damage equal to 1d8 + half your cleric level on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that has total cover from you is not affected. You regain hit points equal to the damage dealt, up to a maximum of three times your cleric level.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll>1d8+½%7</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Sacrificial Healer (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, you can augment your healing spells through sacrifice. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hit points, you can choose one creature within 15 feet of you that the spell affected. You spend a number of your hit points, and that creature regains additional hit points equal to the amount you spent, plus temporary hit points equal to half that amount. The temporary hit points last until the start of your next turn.
	The number of hit points you spend can't exceed the amount of hit points restored to the target by the triggering spell.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Potent Spellcasting (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>At 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any Cleric cantrip.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Eternal Bloodshed (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Beginning at 17th level, the dark magic you cast can cause deep, gushing wounds to appear on the body of an affected creature. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that deals necrotic damage or has the hemomancy tag, you can force one creature that took damage from the spell to make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature is wounded for 1 minute. The wound ends early if the creature receives magical healing, uses their action to staunch the wound, or if you use this feature again.
	While the wound lasts, the wounded creature takes 1d10 necrotic damage at the start of each of its turns, and it has disadvantage on saving throws against any spell that deals necrotic damage or has the hemomancy tag.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 10 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Divine Domain: Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Lunar Radiance (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Also at 1st level, you can empower your attacks with moonlight. Once per turn when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can force them to become basked in moonlight. The next attack roll made against this target before the end of your next turn has advantage, and deals an additional 1d6 radiant damage on a hit.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Radiant Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Domain: Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB)</name>
        <text>Gods of the night such as Selûne, Shar, Tharizdon, Takhisis, and Hecate serve as both creators of light and harbingers of darkness, with moon goods focusing on the former and darkness gods on the latter. These gods serve as patrons of all alignments;
their clerics serve as both righteous defenders of the weak, as well as deceptive thieves and assassins. Either way, these clerics excel in both melee combat and spellcasting, always using the cover of darkness to their advantage in both their battles and their attempts at subterfuge.

Night Domain Spells:
Cleric Level | Spells
1st | sleep, cause fear
3rd | darkness, moonbeam
5th | fear, feign death
7th | greater invisibility, rend shadows†
9th | dream, shadow stride†

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Bonus Proficiencies (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and the Stealth skill.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
        <proficiency>Stealth</proficiency>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Channel Divinity: Midnight Gloom (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to harness the black gloom of midnight, banishing light and draining the life of your foes.
	As an action, you present your holy symbol and all lights within 30 feet of you, magical or non-magical, are instantly put out. Additionally, each hostile creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes necrotic damage equal to 2d6 + your cleric level on a failed saving throw, and loses any darkvision they have for 1 minute. On a successful save, they take half as much damage and suffer no other effects. A creature can repeat this saving throw at the start of each of its turns, regaining their darkvision on a success.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">2d6+%7</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Moonlight Strike (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Starting at 6th level, when you deal radiant damage to a creature you may choose to have it emit dim light in a 10 foot radius until the end of your next turn. The affected creature can't benefit from being invisible, has its speed reduced by 10 feet, and if the creature is a shapeshifter it immediately shifts to its original form and can't assume a different form until the light dissipates.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Divine Strike (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Extra Radiant Damage" level="8">1d8</roll>
        <roll description="Extra Radiant Damage" level="12">2d8</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Nightstalker (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</name>
        <text>Beginning at 17th level, when you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible. You remain invisible until you make an attack, cast a spell, or are in an area of bright light.

Source:	Dark Arts Player's Companion p. 11 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Bloodburn (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cruorwhip (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blood Seal (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sanguine Rope (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blood Sight (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tides of Blood (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Draining Thread (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sanguine Sanctum (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Bloodcurse (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dominate Person</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Blood Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Sleep</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Cause Fear</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Darkness</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Moonbeam</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fear</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Feign Death</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Greater Invisibility</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Rend Shadows (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Dream</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Shadow Stride (HB)</name>
    <classes>Cleric (Night Domain (Dark Arts) (HB))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
