<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Aarakocra (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Aarakocra are birdlike folk who soar the skies of the countless worlds and the endless expanse of the Elemental Plane of Air. They often resemble avians common to the lands where they dwell—some resemble hawks or condors, while others appear similar to hummingbirds or archaeopteryxes. In many lands, Aarakocra tell of their ancient heroics resisting the wicked Queen of Chaos alongside the mysterious Wind Dukes of Aaqa.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Elemental</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Small or Medium (2-3 feet or 4-5 feet)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft., Fly 30 ft. (See Flight)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Perception</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Flight</name>
      <text>You have a flying speed equal to your speed. You cannot benefit from this speed while wearing medium or heavy armor.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Talons</name>
      <text>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d6 slashing damage instead of the normal bludgeoning damage. This is a Strength-based attack, and you are proficient with it.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Windcaller</name>
      <text>Your affinity with the Elemental Plane of Air grants you certain magical gifts:

	• You know the Elementalism cantrip, which you can cast at will.
	• At 3rd level, you learn Expeditious Retreat.
	• At 5th level, you learn Gust of Wind.

You always have these spells prepared. You can cast each of them once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast a spell using this trait, you choose Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma as your spellcasting ability (choose the ability when you create your Aarakocra).</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
