<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<notes version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <note>
    <title>Backstory</title>
    <text>Your character's origin story or background goes here.</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Allies and Organizations</title>
    <text>People your character is familiar with.</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Treasure</title>
    <text>Treasures and Trinkets</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Roleplaying Characteristics</title>
    <text>Alignment:


Personality Traits:


Ideals:


Bonds:


Flaws:

</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Actions (1 per turn)</title>
    <text>	• Attack: Roll to hit, melee or ranged. Some classes and creatures make extra attacks at higher levels with this action.
	• Dash: Double Speed this turn.
	• Disengage: Avoiding all opportunity attacks while moving; "defensive retreat."
	• Dodge: Give attackers disadvantage.
	• Escape: Try to break free from grapple.
	• Grapple: SPecial melee attack.
	• Help: Give an ally advantage on one ability check or attack roll.
	• Hide: Stealth allowed only if unobserved.
	• Ready: Plan to take action as a reaction when trigger occurs.
	• Search: Perception or Investigation check.
	• Shove: Special melee attack.
	• Stabilize: DC 10 Medicine check to aid 0HP dying creature; automatic success if using healer's kit.
	• Use an Object: Pick a lock, activate magical item, cover a hooded lantern, etc.
	• Use Potion: Drink or administer.
	• Use Shield: Equip or drop a shield.

	• Cast Spell: If casting time 1 action.
		• (Action Spell)

	• List other Action features here.</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Concentration Spells</title>
    <text>The spells your character knows which use concentration.

	• (Concentration Spell)</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Bonus Actions (up to 1 per turn)</title>
    <text>	• Offhand attack: If doing Attack as action, may make one attack this turn if light weapon in other hand.

	• Cast Spell: If casting time 1 bonus action, and not cast a leveled spell in action.
		• (Bonus Action Spell)

	• List other bonus action features here.</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Reactions (1 between turns)</title>
    <text>	• Opportunity Attack: May make one attack if enemy moves out of reach.
	• Readied Action: After trigger occurs, else action wasted.

	• Cast Spell: If casting time 1 reaction.
		• (Reaction Spell)</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Free Actions</title>
    <text>	• Concentration (Maintain A Spell): Ends if caster starts another concentration spell, or the caster is incapacitated, stunned, unconscious, or killed. If caster takes damage, a Constitution saving throw is needed to avoid immediately ending spell. DC is equal to 10 or half damage taken, whichever is greater. Each hit needs a separate saving throw check.
	• Interacting With An Object: Generally part of another Movement or Action. Examples: Draw one weapon, drop a held object, or open an unlocked door.</text>
  </note>
  <note>
    <title>Movements (limited by Speed)</title>
    <text>	• Move: Distance equal to Speed.
	• Crawl, Climb, Swim, Squeeze, Move Across Difficult Terrain or Move While Grappling: "Half speed," uses up 10 ft. of Speed per 5 ft. distance.
	• Drop Prone: No cost to Speed.
	• Stand Up: From Prone position/condition, costs half Speed that turn.
	• Take Cover: At end of move, half cover gives +2 to Armor Class and Dexterity saving throws; three-quarter cover gives +5 AC and Dex saves.</text>
  </note>
</notes>
