<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Kuo-Toa [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Religion</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>The Kuo-Toa are a twisted, aquatic people warped by centuries of madness and exposure to their own insecurities. Once a peaceful coastal species, they claim to be the remnants of a powerful undersea empire that was betrayed and destroyed by surface-dwelling species. While no records of such an empire exist outside Kuo-Toa myths, they fiercely cling to this belief. Whether rooted in truth or delusion, this paranoia fuels their deep mistrust of land-dwellers. Many Kuo-Toa view outsiders as agents of the surface conspiracy and are quick to react with hostility or suspicion.
	Despite their fractured minds, Kuo-Toa possess a unique awareness of otherworldly entities, and some are even known to create false deities through sheer belief.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Aberration</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft., Swim 30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Darkvision</name>
      <text>60 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiency</name>
      <text>Religion</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Languages</name>
      <text>Undercommon, Primordial (Aquan)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Amphibious</name>
      <text>You can breathe both air and water.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Otherworldly Perception</name>
      <text>As a bonus action, you can heighten your awareness to gain truesight out to a range of 30 feet for 1 minute. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Slippery</name>
      <text>You have Advantage on saving throws to avoid or remove the Grappled condition.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Sunlight Anathema</name>
      <text>The light of the sun disorients you. While in direct sunlight, you cannot add your Dexterity modifier to your Armor Class (if applicable).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Net Master</name>
      <text>You have learned to wield nets with deadly precision.

	• When you make an attack with a Net, you add your Strength modifier as well as your Dexterity modifier when calculating the Dexterity saving throw DC to avoid being restrained.
	• The escape DC for a Net you throw is equal to 10 + your Strength modifier.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Spurious Blessing</name>
      <text>You know the Sacred Flame cantrip. However, when you cast it, the spell deals cold damage instead of radiant.
	You always have this cantrip prepared. When you cast a spell using this trait, you choose Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma as your spellcasting ability (choose the ability when you create your Kuo-Toa).</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
