<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Githyanki (HB) [5.5e]</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <resist>psychic</resist>
    <proficiency>History</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Githyanki are astral warriors and seekers of knowledge, shaped by a history of oppression and conquest. Once enslaved by the mind flayers, they broke free and carved a place for themselves in the Astral Plane, where time barely touches them. Each Githyanki carries the echoes of countless past lives, their martial prowess and psionic abilities honed over centuries of astral warfare. Despite their rigid society and militant traditions, some Githyanki venture into the Material Plane to seek knowledge, power, or a destiny of their own.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Aberration</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (about 5 to 7 feet)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>History</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Resistances</name>
      <text>Psychic Damage</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Githyanki Psionics</name>
      <text>Your affinity with the Astral Plane grants you certain magical gifts:

	• You know the Mage hand cantrip, which you can cast at will. When you do, the hand is invisible.
	• At 3rd level, you learn Jump.
	• At 5th level, you learn Misty Step.

You always have these spells prepared. You can cast each of them once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. When you cast a spell using this trait, you choose Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma as your spellcasting ability (choose the ability when you create your Githyanki).</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Astral Knowledge</name>
      <text>As a bonus action while wielding a weapon, you can briefly access a reservoir of experience from entities connected to the Astral Plane. For 1 minute, you gain access to the Weapon Mastery Property of the weapon you were wielding when you activated this ability. Once you use this ability, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Practiced Mind</name>
      <text>When making a d20 test with a set of tools, you can use Intelligence instead of the usual ability associated with that tool. Additionally, once per long rest, you can make a d20 test with a tool you are not proficient with as if you were proficient.</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
