<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Barbarian [2024]</name>
    <!-- Barbarian Subclass: Path of the Spiritual Guardian (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Barbarian Subclass: Path of the Spiritual Guardian (UA)</name>
        <text>Call on the Spirits for Combat Aid

Barbarians who walk the Path of the Spiritual Guardian call upon spirits—whether bestial spirits of nature, spirits of departed ancestors, or spirits of raw elemental power—to guide and protect them. When these Barbarians rage, they contact the realm of the spirits and call on them for aid.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 1 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Spiritual Protectors (Path of the Spiritual Guardian (UA))</name>
        <text>Your Rage summons spectral warriors to your aid. While your Rage is active, when you hit a creature with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, it becomes the target of the spirits, which cause one of the following effects of your choice.

Distract. Until the start of your next turn, the target has Disadvantage attack rolls against targets other than you or another Barbarian who has this feature.

Protect. Until the end of the target's next turn, the next time it hits a creature other than you with an attack roll, that creature has Resistance to the damage dealt by the attack.

Strike. The target takes an extra 1d6 damage, which can be Acid, Cold, Fire, Force, Lightning, or Thunder damage (your choice).

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 1 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Extra Damage">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Spirit Shield (Path of the Spiritual Guardian (UA))</name>
        <text>Your guardian spirits can provide supernatural protection to those you defend. While your Rage is active, when another creature you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can take a Reaction to reduce that damage. To determine the amount the damage is reduced by, roll a number of d6s equal to your Rage Damage bonus, and add them together.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Damage Reduction" level="3">2d6</roll>
        <roll description="Damage Reduction" level="9">3d6</roll>
        <roll description="Damage Reduction" level="16">4d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Consult The Spirits (Path of the Spiritual Guardian (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain the ability to consult with your guardian spirits. When you do so, you cast the Augury or Clairvoyance spell, without expending a spell slot or needing Material components. Rather than creating a spherical sensor, this use of Clairvoyance invisibly summons one of your guardian spirits to the chosen location. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
	After you cast either spell in this way, you can't use this feature again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Vengeful Spirits (Path of the Spiritual Guardian (UA))</name>
        <text>When you make an attack roll with a Melee weapon as part of the Attack action and roll 18-20 on the d20, you can make one additional attack roll with the same weapon as part of that action. Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until the start of your next turn.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <!-- Barbarian Subclass: Path of the Storm Herald (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Barbarian Subclass: Path of the Storm Herald (UA)</name>
        <text>Wield the Fury of the Storm

Barbarians who follow the Path of the Storm Herald learn to harness their Rage into a mantle of primal magic that swirls around them like a storm. When in their Rage, these Barbarians tap into the elemental forces of nature to create powerful magical effects.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Storm Aura (Path of the Storm Herald (UA))</name>
        <text>Whenever you activate your Rage, choose Desert, Sea, or Tundra. You extend an aura in a 10-foot Emanation originating from yourself for the duration of your Rage.
	Your aura has an effect that activates when you enter your Rage, and you can activate the effect again on each of your turns as a Bonus Action. Your aura's effect depends on the chosen environment, as detailed below.
	If your aura's effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 plus your Proficiency bonus plus your Constitution modifier.

Desert. When this effect is activated, roll a number of d4s equal to your Rage Damage bonus, and add them together. Each creature in the aura must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take Fire damage equal to the number rolled. You can choose one creature you can see in your aura to automatically succeed on this saving throw.

Sea. When this effect is activated, roll a number of d6s equal to your Rage Damage bonus, and add them together. You can then hurl a bolt of lightning at one other creature you can see within your aura. The target makes a Dexterity saving throw, taking Lightning damage equal to the number rolled on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.

Tundra. When this effect is activated, roll a number of d4s equal to your Rage Damage bonus, and add them together. You can choose one other creature you can see within your aura to harry with icy spirits. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or it subtracts the number rolled from the next damage roll it makes before the start of your next turn.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Fire Damage" level="3">2d4</roll>
        <roll description="Fire Damage" level="9">3d4</roll>
        <roll description="Fire Damage" level="16">4d4</roll>
        <roll description="Lightning Damage" level="3">2d6</roll>
        <roll description="Lightning Damage" level="9">3d6</roll>
        <roll description="Lightning Damage" level="16">4d6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Storm Soul (Path of the Storm Herald (UA))</name>
        <text>The storm grants you benefits even when your aura isn't active. The benefits are based on the environment you chose for your Storm Aura the last time you entered your Rage.

Desert. You gain Resistance to Fire damage. As a Magic action, you can touch a flammable object that isn't being worn or carried by anyone else fand cause the object to start burning.

Sea. You gain Resistance to Lightning damage, and you can breathe underwater. You also gain a Swim Speed equal to your Speed.

Tundra. You gain Resistance to Cold damage. As a Magic action, you can touch water and turn a 5-foot Cube of it into ice, which melts after 1 minute. This action fails if a creature is in the Cube.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 2 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Shielding Storm (Path of the Storm Herald (UA))</name>
        <text>You can use your mastery of the storm to protect others. Each creature of your choice within your Storm Aura has the damage Resistance you have from the Storm Soul feature.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: Raging Storm (Path of the Storm Herald (UA))</name>
        <text>The power of the storm you channel grows mightier, lashing out at your foes. The effect is based on the environment you choose for your Storm Aura.

Desert. Once per turn, when a creature you can see fails its saving throw against your Storm Aura effect, you can cause it to start burning for 1 minute or until your Rage ends. A burning creature takes an extra 1d4 Fire damage (2d4 Fire damage total) at the start of each of its turns.

Sea. Whether the target fails or succeeds on its saving throw against your Storm Aura effect, a bolt of lightning leaps from the target to another target of your choice, which must be within 30 feet of the first target. The new target makes the same Dexterity saving throw as the first target.

Tundra. Once per turn, when a creature you can see fails its saving throw against your Storm Aura effect, you can cause it to take 2d4 Cold damage and its Speed is halved until the end of its next turn.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 3 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Fire Damage">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Fire Damage">2d4</roll>
        <roll description="Cold Damage">2d4</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
