<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Paladin [2024]</name>
    <!-- Paladin Subclass: Oathbreaker (UA) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Paladin Subclass: Oathbreaker (UA)</name>
        <text>Obtain Great Power at Any Cost

The power of a Paladin's oath is so great that it holds a distorted power even when it is violated. When a Paladin betrays the tenets of their oath because of corruption, pride, or thirst for power, they lose the blessing granted by their original oath but sometimes take on the sinister blessing of the Oathbreaker in its place. Oathbreakers use fear and overwhelming power to achieve their goals. While many Oathbreakers are beyond redemption, some Paladins bend this oath to achieve a great and noble deed to atone for their past evils.
	At the DM's discretion, a Paladin of any level who violates the tenets of their oath can lose the benefits granted by their original subclass and gain the features of the Oathbreaker subclass instead. Alternatively, a Paladin can choose this subclass at level 3 based on the character's backstory of falling from grace.
	These Paladins often share the following tenets:

	• Fear is a tool in the hands of the powerful.
	• Strive for power at any cost.
	• Do what must be done, but never lose sight of your goal.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 5 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Conjure Undead (Oathbreaker (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can expend one use of your Channel Divinity to summon a number of Undead equal to half your Charisma modifier (round up; minimum of one Undead summoned). Each Undead appears in an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of you and is a type of your choice: Skeleton or Zombie (see appendix B of the Player's Handbook [2024] for the stat blocks). The Undead are under your control for 1 minute, after which they dissolve into ash.
	Each Undead is an ally to you and your allies. In combat, the Undead shares your Initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys your verbal commands (no action required by you). If you don't issue any, it takes the Dodge action and uses its movement to avoid danger.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 5 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Dreadful Aspect (Oathbreaker (UA))</name>
        <text>Immediately after you cast Divine Smite, you can expend one use of your Channel Divinity to channel a burst of magical menace. Each creature of your choice in a 30-foot Emanation originating from you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition for 1 minute. A Frightened creature repeats the save at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Oathbreaker Spells (Oathbreaker (UA))</name>
        <text>The magic of your oath ensures you always have certain spells ready; when you reach a Paladin level specified in the Oathbreaker Spells table, you thereafter always have the listed spells prepared.

Oathbreaker Spells:
Paladin Level | Spells
3 | Hellish Rebuke, Witch Bolt
5 | Crown of Madness, Darkness
9 | Fear, Summon Undead
13 | Blight, Phantasmal Killer
17 | Contagion, Steel Wind Strike

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 7: Aura of Hate (Oathbreaker (UA))</name>
        <text>When you, as well as any Fiend or Undead in your Aura of Protection that is an ally, hits a creature with a melee attack, that attack deals extra Necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 15: Supernatural Resistance (Oathbreaker (UA))</name>
        <text>You gain Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 20: Dread Lord (Oathbreaker (UA))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you can imbue your Aura of Protection with unholy gloom, granting the benefits below for 10 minutes or until you end them (no action required). Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of it by expending a level 5 spell slot (no action required).

Darkness. Magical Darkness fills your Aura of Protection. You and allies in your Aura of Protection can see within this magical Darkness.

Fear. Whenever a creature with the Frightened condition starts its turn in your Aura of Protection, that creature takes 4d10 Psychic damage.

Shadow Strike. As a Bonus Action, you can make a melee spell attack, shaping the gloom exuding from you into a blade that targets one creature in your Aura of Protection. On a hit, the attack deals Necrotic damage equal to 3d10 plus your Charisma modifier.

Source:	Subclasses Update p. 6 (Unearthed Arcana)</text>
        <roll description="Psychic Damage">4d10</roll>
        <roll description="Necrotic Damage">3d10+%6</roll>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
  <spell>
    <name>Hellish Rebuke [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Witch Bolt [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Crown of Madness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Darkness [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Fear [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Summon Undead [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Blight [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Phantasmal Killer [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Contagion [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Steel Wind Strike [2024]</name>
    <classes>Paladin [2024] (Oathbreaker (UA))</classes>
  </spell>
</compendium>
