<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Aven</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>25</speed>
    <ability>Dex 2, Wis 2</ability>
    <proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
    <spellAbility />
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Aven have humanlike bodies, arms, and legs, along with birdlike wings and heads. Two distinct varieties of aven are found in Naktamun. One has the head of a hawk or similar bird of prey, with short wings allowing fast flight. The other variety has the head of an ibis atop a long neck, with wide, angular wings better suited to soaring. All aven have lean bodies with feathers extending from their heads down to their shoulders.

Aven delight in flying above their foes, using their superior mobility to confound and outpace their opponents. They love soaring through the sky as well, though the Hekma limits their altitude. Like all people of Naktamun, they are grateful for the Hekma's protective magic, of course. But they keenly anticipate the hour when the God-Pharaoh will return and dissolve the veil, letting them fly without limit in the afterlife.

Source:	Plane Shift: Dominaria p. 6</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Age</name>
      <text>Like humans, aven reach adulthood in their late teens and can live into their 80s.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Alignment</name>
      <text>Aven are inclined toward the lawful good alignment of the Church of Serra
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Aven stand from 5 to 6 feet tall, but their bodies are slender and their bones are partially hollow to facilitate their flight. Your size is Medium.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Flight</name>
      <text>You have a flying speed of 30 feet. You can't use your flying speed while you wear medium or heavy armor. (If your campaign uses the variant rule for encumbrance, you can't use your flying speed if you are encumbered.)
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Hawkeyed</name>
      <text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill. In addition, attacking at long range doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.
</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Aven.
</text>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
