<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <background>
    <name>Displaced (UA)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You don't belong in this world. You come from an alien realm where magic doesn't exist, technology is far more advanced, and the adventures you now face are confined only to fiction. You don't know how you were transported to this world or why you were brought here, but you are trying to make the best of a perplexing situation.

Consider how long you have been here, and how you have managed to procure the powers associated with your class since arriving. Have you been stuck here for years, learning the art of some class as a way to survive? Did you appear not only in an unfamiliar place but also in an unfamiliar body, maybe of some inhuman race that doesn't exist in your own world, which comes with instinctual powers and talents that you're still learning to command? Also think about your previous life, what skills it would have taught you and how those now apply to your new life.

	• Skill Proficiencies: Any two skills that are not Arcana, History, or Religion
	• Tool Proficiencies: Two of your choice from the following: any artisan's tools besides alchemist's supplies, any musical instrument, any gaming set
	• Equipment: A mobile phone with 0% battery, a wallet with dozen banknotes of a currency not accepted in this world, a ring of keys, set of strange clothes, and a pouch of 10 gp

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Displaced p. 1</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Modern Knowledge</name>
      <text>While you came into this unfamiliar world without a copper piece to your name, the advanced knowledge you brought with you has given you something of value to offer. You are well versed in a field that is farther advanced in your original world than the world you are in now. It could be medicine, mathematics, engineering, a craft, or anything else that makes sense for your character.

In order to secure a life for yourself, you contributed this knowledge to some organization that it was relevant to. For example, you might have taught a university the secrets of calculus, or instructed a blacksmith's guild in how to make stronger steel. The organization considers themselves indebted to you for your contribution, and are willing to support you (but only you) at a modest lifestyle. They consider you a member of their organization, although you may have to pay monthly dues to gain the full benefits of membership.

The technology you introduced may cause a disruption in the world and its balance of power. Discuss with your DM what impact your knowledge has on the world now that it has been introduced, if any.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Variant Feature: I've read the handbook!</name>
      <text>Because displaced characters are implied to have come from modern day Earth, there is a chance that they may have played Dungeons and Dragons as a game. This could potentially give an excuse for the character to know things about game mechanics and monsters that would otherwise seem like metagaming. Make sure your DM is comfortable with your character having this sort of knowledge in-game before characterizing them that way.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Displaced characters are strangers in a strange land, stuck in a place where everything they thought was fictional is now real. They might see this as a call to action to become a protagonist like in all the stories they grew up with, or they may only care about making it out of these adventures alive. Either way, they are defined by a culture that those around them can't come close to relating to.

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | I'm taking this predicament as a chance to reinvent myself and be a better, stronger person.
2 | I have trouble pronouncing all these weird fantasy names.
3 | Back home I was nobody, so I'm amazed whenever I pull off something crazy and heroic.
4 | When someone asks me where I'm from, I tell the truth. They never believe me.
5 | I frequently make pop culture references that no one else understands.
6 | I channel my favorite fictional hero in battle to give myself courage.
7 | Since I'm clearly the protagonist of an isekai anime, I frequently flirt with the natives to get my harem started.
8 | I hate camping.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Heroism. Now that I have the power to be a hero, I want to use it for good. (Good)
2 | Fun. While I'm here, might as well explore and go on crazy adventures. (Chaotic)
3 | Domination. With my modern mind and technology, I could bring this barbaric world to its knees. (Evil)
4 | Discovery. The mysteries of this new world never cease to amaze me. (Any)
5 | Progression. This place has some backwards attitudes and political systems, and I intend to bring everyone up to my modern standards. (Lawful)
6 | Safety. I don't want to die! (Neutral)

d6 | Bond
1 | I will do whatever it takes to get back home.
2 | I try my best to be a representative for my world that my people could be proud of.
3 | Magic fascinates me, and I want to understand how it works, maybe even scientifically.
4 | I want to build a life for myself that is as comfortable as what I used to have.
5 | The friends I've made in this world mean more to me than the ones I had back home.
6 | I owe my life to the kind people who took me in after I arrived in this world.

d6 | Flaw
1 | I cower in the face of real danger.
2 | I'm convinced that I'm delusional, and that nothing I do in this world really matters.
3 | I don't know how to research anything without the help of the internet.
4 | I make up stories about who I am and where I'm from to avoid questioning, and I've lost track of my lies.
5 | My survival instincts leave much to be desired.
6 | I haven't adjusted to the lower standard of living in this world well, and I'm easily won over by the promise of luxuries.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>

  <background>
    <name>Mad Scientist (UA)</name>
    <proficiency/>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Scientists are people that believe discovery and invention are vital to progress, and seek knowledge about the world in which they live. You are one of these people... but you take things a bit too far. To most people, your ideas are crazy: unnecessary at best, and reprehensible at worst. Because of this, you're shunned by your community, though whether your "madness" is legitimate or just a label slapped on you by people who don't understand is up to you. 

You will want to discuss the reason(s) you left your home with your Dungeon Master. Did people harass you, or ignore you altogether? Were you run out of town for your bizarre experiments, or did you take your leave to try to find like-minded people? Are you searching for something obscure, or do you simply wish for freedom to study what and how you please?

	• Skill Proficiencies: Choose two from Arcana, History, Investigation, Nature, Animal Handling, and Medicine
	• Tool Proficiencies: Choose two from Alchemist's Supplies, Brewer's Supplies, Carpenter's Tools, Cook's Utensils, Mason's Tools, Smith's Tools, Tinker's Tools, Herbalism Kit, and Poisoner's Kit
	• Equipment: A set of common clothes, two sets of tools you are proficient with, a book on your field of study, an abacus, a piece of chalk, and a pouch containing 10 gp

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Mad Scientist p. 1</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Quick Study</name>
      <text>Others may criticize or mock your obsession, but your dedication has paid off. It takes you half the time it normally would to identify, repair, or glean information from an object, a specimen, or writings related to your field of study.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Specialty</name>
      <text>Every scientist has a specialty, even the "mad" ones. Choose a field of scientific study, or roll on the table below.

Mad Scientist Specialty:
d6 | Field of Study
1 | Medicine
2 | Mechanical engineering
3 | Botany
4 | Zoology
5 | Chemistry
6 | Earth science</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>Though they may have much in common, these are not the types of scholars that fill the halls of universities. They are radical free thinkers who are defined by ostracization. Greater society dismisses their ideas and goals as anything from foolish to evil, leaving them to work in their makeshift laboratories alone, for hours, days, or weeks at a time. They're obsessed. They're dedicated. Their ideas are strange — but rest assured, no two are the same.

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | My creations are my children, and I treat them as such.
2 | I am dismissive of magic.
3 | I'm constantly covered in grime from my work and I am completely unbothered by this.
4 | Explosions, while not ideal, are very, very cool.
5 | I'll act madder than I actually am to get out of things.
6 | I'm lost in my thoughts more often than not.
7 | I always think there's room for improvement.
8 | I care about what people think much more than I let on.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Knowledge. I need to learn everything I can, even if others don't understand. (Neutral)
2 | Progress. I want the world to move forward, towards being a better place. (Good)
3 | Power. What I learn will help me rule over those who doubted me. (Evil)
4 | Freedom. Discovery and invention should not be restricted. (Chaotic)
5 | Method. There is a right way to do things. (Lawful)
6 | Legacy. I want to be remembered when I depart this plane. (Any)

d6 | Bond
1 | My work is of the utmost importance. I can't let how others see me get in the way.
2 | I'm working toward one specific discovery that will change everything.
3 | I will protect my journals at any cost.
4 | My experiments drove away someone I love. I hope to win them back by vindicating myself.
5 | I will return to the community that shunned me as a hero.
6 | My studies are my life. I don't have anything else.

d6 | Flaw
1 | I'm always trying to upgrade my party's gear, even when they don't ask me to. (Or want me to.)
2 | I don't have time for tact.
3 | Good luck trying to shut me up once I get talking about my studies.
4 | I am particularly territorial of my workspace: trespassers will be persecuted.
5 | My intellectual curiosity often supersedes my survival instincts.
6 | I'm very sensitive about my work and do not take criticism well.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>

  <background>
    <name>Traveling Cook (UA)</name>
    <proficiency>Performance, Survival</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You've travelled the world in pursuit of your culinary passions, and have learned much from your journeys. You go wherever great food takes you, spreading your knowledge and hoping to pick up some things along the way.

	• Skill Proficiencies: Performance, Survival
	• Tool Proficiencies: Cook's Utensils
	• Languages: You know most food and cooking terms from all standard languages
	• Equipment: A set of cook's utensils, traveler's clothes, an iron pot, a jar of spices, a small leather book of collected recipes, and a pouch containing 10 gp

Source:	Unearthed Arcana: Petes Mgeets</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Guided by Taste</name>
      <text>What is your purpose in traveling for food? Are you a world-renowned gourmet chef? Perhaps a novice looking to learn the dishes of various cultures? Chose a reason for venturing out into the world of taste or roll on the following table to decide for you.

Purpose for Travel:
d6 | Purpose for Travel
1 | I am a famous chef who tours the world to the delight of my adoring fans.
2 | I am an apprentice who is looking to expand my horizons by learning from the various cultures and cuisines this world has to offer.
3 | I am a food enthusiast on a mission to try the most talked about dishes in the land, stopping at every decent establishment along the way.
4 | I am a merchant who brings my craft wherever I go. I won't rest until everyone has tried my signature dishes.
5 | I believe there's nothing a good meal can't fix, and I travel the world to feed every hungry mouth who will let me.
6 | I know there's more to cooking than what they teach in school. I travel the world to find the strangest magical ingredients and meals I can manage to get my hands on.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Taste Analysis</name>
      <text>You've tasted many different cuisines in your travels, and have developed a knack for flavor recognition. You have the ability to determine exactly what non-magical ingredients were used in any food you taste, and can recreate an almost identical meal when given the right ingredients.

If these are ingredients you're very familiar with (such as ingredients from your homeland or meals you prepare often), then you can even make a meal that exceeds the original in terms of flavor and quality.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Characteristics</name>
      <text>There are many flavors of Traveling Cook, but a love of food binds them together. What kind of cook will you be? Is food your hobby? Or does it drive everything you do?

d8 | Personality Trait
1 | I'm always happy as long as food is involved.
2 | Food safety is my number one concern, I don't eat anything I'm not sure of.
3 | I'm much happier cooking the food than eating it.
4 | I prefer to just get cooking and wing it.
5 | I have a favorite ingredient I throw into as many meals as I can.
6 | I have a warm presence and people enjoy my company.
7 | I'd rather go hungry than eat a poor meal.
8 | I'm always planning my next meal, even when I'm still eating the current one.

d6 | Ideal
1 | Culture. This world's diversities should be celebrated, we all can learn from each other and grow. (Any)
2 | Aspiration. I'm always working to improve my skills first and foremost. (Any)
3 | Tradition. I aim to spread the methods and knowledge that were passed on to me. (Lawful)
4 | Knowledge. I'm constantly seeking new techniques and information. (Any)
5 | Creativity. I aim to try something new every time, and never repeat. (Chaotic)
6 | Charity. I'm always available to provide for those in need. (Good)

d6 | Bond
1 | My cookbook is my greatest treasure, and filling it out is my life's dream.
2 | I want to become rich and famous off my cooking.
3 | I want to start a restaurant with all the dishes I've learned, and keep it safe for years to come.
4 | I'm searching the world for a mythical ingredient, and will stop at nothing to find it.
5 | The friends I travel with mean the world to me, and I'd do anything for them.
6 | I want to one day return home and make a dish that will make my mentor proud.

d6 | Flaw
1 | I never think anything I make is good enough.
2 | I despise bad cooking, but not as much as I despise the cooks who made it.
3 | I never make a meal for free, they're lucky I'm even letting them pay!
4 | I always cook alone, I don't trust any amateur's meals.
5 | I don't like anyone who doesn't like my food.
6 | Nothing will stop me from eating what I want to eat, even the law.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>
</compendium>
