<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <class>
    <name>Wizard [5.5e]</name>
    <!-- Wizard Subclass: Compeller (HB) -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Wizard Subclass: Compeller (HB)</name>
        <text>Charm the Scales Off a Snake

As a Compeller you specialize in Enchantment magic, a school focused on spells that captivate and control.

"If a Compeller is distrusted," it is often said, "they must not be very good at it!" Then the Compeller smiles, and everyone laughs and lowers their weapons.

Source:	Compeller by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Enchantment Savant (Compeller (HB))</name>
        <text>Choose two Wizard spells from the Enchantment school, each of which must be no higher than level 2, and add them to your spellbook for free.
	In addition, whenever you gain access to a new level of spell slots in this class, you can add one Wizard spell from the Enchantment school to your spellbook for free. The chosen spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	Lastly, any non-Enchantment Wizard spell can be treated as an Enchantment spell for you if it imposes a Wisdom saving throw on a creature when cast.

Source:	Compeller by Niall Keegan by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 3: Dazzle (Compeller (HB))</name>
        <text>As a Bonus Action, you flick a tangled thread of Enchantment magic at one creature you can see within 60 feet, briefly muddling its instincts. The target subtracts 1d4 from the result of the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn; or it subtracts 1d6 if that saving throw is made to resist the effects of an Enchantment spell. A creature can only be affected by one use of Dazzle at a time.
	You can use this feature a number of times per day equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you complete a Long Rest.

Source:	Compeller by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
        <roll description="Subtract from Roll">1d4</roll>
        <roll description="Subtract from Roll">1d6</roll>
      </feature>
      <counter>
        <name>Dazzle</name>
        <value>1</value>
        <reset>L</reset>
        <subclass>Compeller (HB)</subclass>
      </counter>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Slip of the Mind (Compeller (HB))</name>
        <text>When your Concentration on a spell ends, you can take a Reaction to force creatures Charmed by that spell to each make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature does not remember that you cast the spell; on a success, the spell ends normally for them.

Source:	Compeller by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 6: Mental Barricade (Compeller (HB))</name>
        <text>Whenever you make a Wisdom saving throw, you can add your Intelligence modifier to the result.

Source:	Compeller by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 10: Compelling Weave (Compeller (HB))</name>
        <text>When a creature makes an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw at the end of its turn to end an ongoing effect of one of your spells, it makes the roll with Disadvantage.

Source:	Compeller by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Level 14: All-Charmer (Compeller (HB))</name>
        <text>Your spells ignore creatures' Immunity to the Charmed condition; instead, creatures with Immunity to the Charmed condition have Advantage on saving throws against being Charmed by your spells.

Source:	Compeller by Niall Keegan p. 2 (Homebrew)</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>
