<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <spell>
    <name>Void Star [5.5e]</name>
    <level>7</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>120 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a fragment of a meteor)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>School: Necromancy, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You conjure forth a fragment of a dark star and launch it at one creature that you can see within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 6d12 Necrotic damage. At the end of the target's next turn, it takes 3d12 Necrotic damage, and you regain Hit Points equal to the amount of Necrotic damage dealt.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: The damage (both initial and later) increases by 1d12 for each spell slot level above 7.

Source:	DND Beyond Drops - June</text>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="7">6d12</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="8">7d12</roll>
    <roll description="Necrotic Damage" level="9">8d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Tortoise Shell [5.5e]</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>A</school>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>Touch</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>School: Abjuration, Touch Spells, Artificer, Druid, Ranger</classes>
    <text>You touch a willing creature. Until the spell ends, the target's skin hardens into a tortoise shell, and the target gains a +3 bonus to AC. If the target moves, the bonus becomes +1 instead until the start of its next turn.

Source:	DND Beyond Drops - June</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Searing Orb</name>
    <level>2</level>
    <school>EV</school>
    <time>action</time>
    <range>60 feet</range>
    <components>S, M (metallic flakes and a pinch of phosphorus)</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <classes>School: Evocation, Cleric, Paladin</classes>
    <text>You create and hurl a pulsing orb of energy at one creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 3d4 Radiant damage. Hit or miss, the orb then explodes in a flash of light. The target and each creature within 10 feet of it make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature has the Blinded condition until the end of its next turn.

Using a Higher-Level Spell Slot: The damage increases by 1d4 for each spell slot level above 2.

Source:	DND Beyond Drops - June</text>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage" level="2">3d4</roll>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage" level="3">4d4</roll>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage" level="4">5d4</roll>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage" level="5">6d4</roll>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage" level="6">7d4</roll>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage" level="7">8d4</roll>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage" level="8">9d4</roll>
    <roll description="Radiant Damage" level="9">10d4</roll>
  </spell>
</compendium>
