<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  <race>
    <name>Minotaur [5.5e] (HB)</name>
    <displayname>Minotaur</displayname>
    <ancestry>Minotaur</ancestry>
    <size>M</size>
    <speed>30</speed>
    <proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>Minotaurs are formidable beings shaped by their labyrinthine heritage and the twisted influence of Baphomet, the Horned King. Towering over most humanoids, they possess the strength of a bull and a mind sharpened by primal instinct. Minotaurs are often found in sprawling labyrinths, serving as both hunters and guardians.
	Despite their imposing nature, Minotaurs are not inherently violent. Many live by a strict code of honor, blending their strength with strategy. However, whispers of Baphomet's influence linger within their culture, offering dark boons to those who embrace his chaotic power.
	Minotaurs are natural pathfinders, their uncanny sense of direction making them excellent trackers and survivalists.

Source:	Sewage Orc</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="description">
      <name>Playing a Minotaur</name>
      <text>While Minotaurs trace their lineage back to the Abyss and the demon lord Baphomet, the Minotaurs found on the Material Plane are a divergent subspecies. These Minotaurs have lived far from the influence of their Abyssal cousins, forging their own path in the mortal world.
	Unlike the brutal, bloodthirsty Minotaurs of the Abyss, Material Plane Minotaurs are smaller in stature and more adaptable in temperament. While still proud and fiercely independent, they are typically more welcoming of outsiders and willing to form bonds with other societies.
	Many Minotaurs struggle with the dark whispers of their heritage, but they often channel this inner turmoil into strength, embracing discipline and personal codes of honor to resist Baphomet's influence. As a Minotaur adventurer, you embody this balance — a formidable warrior shaped by tradition, yet free to forge your own destiny.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Creature Type</name>
      <text>Monstrosity</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Size</name>
      <text>Medium (5-7 feet)</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Speed</name>
      <text>30 ft.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Survival</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Languages</name>
      <text>Abyssal, Minotaur</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Horns</name>
      <text>Your horns are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal 1d6 + your Strength modifier piercing damage instead of the normal bludgeoning damage.
	Once per turn when you hit a Large or smaller creature with your horns, you can push the target 10 feet away from you.</text>
      <roll description="Unarmed Piercing Damage">1d6+%1</roll>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Goring Rush</name>
      <text>When you take the Dash action on your turn, you can make one melee attack with your horns as part of the same action.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait category="species">
      <name>Baphomet's Blessing</name>
      <text>The chaotic power of Baphomet lingers in your blood, manifesting in various gifts. At 1st level, choose one of the following traits. You gain a second trait from this list once you reach 5th level.

	Grievous Strike. When you score a critical hit with your horns, you deal an additional 1d8 piercing damage.

	Sure-Footed. Non-magical difficult terrain doesn't cost you extra movement.

	Baphomet's Favor. When you make an attack roll against a creature and miss, you can use your reaction to reroll the attack roll. You must use the second roll. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.

	Abyssal Resilience. When you are forced to make a saving throw against a spell or effect that deals psychic or necrotic damage, you can roll a d4 and add the result to your saving throw.

	Raging Fury. When you gain the bloodied condition for the first time in an encounter, you have advantage on the next attack roll you make on your next turn. If you hit with this attack, you deal additional damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</text>
      <roll description="Extra Piercing Damage">1d8</roll>
      <roll description="Add to Saving Throw">1d4</roll>
    </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
